<doc><id>administrative_distance</id><concept_name>administrative distance</concept_name><wiki>Administrative distance (AD) or route preference[1] is a number of arbitrary unit assigned to dynamic routes, static routes and directly-connected routes. The value is used in routers to rank routes from most preferred (low administrative distance value) to least preferred (high administrative distance value).[2][3] When multiple paths to the same destination are available in its routing table, the router uses the route with the lowest administrative distance. 
Router vendors typically design their routers to assign a default administrative distance to each kind of route. For example Cisco routers, routes issued by OSPF have a lower default administrative distance than routes issued by the Routing Information Protocol. By default, OSPF has a default administrative distance of 110 and RIP has a default administrative distance of 120. Administrative distance values can, however, usually be adjusted manually by a network administrator.[2]
The administrative distance (AD) value is assigned by the router on a per-protocol basis. Routers, by design, should not install multiple routes into the routing table as this has the potential to cause routing loops.[2] While a router may run multiple routing protocols on the same device, it is necessary for the router to implement a process to ensure that multiple routes, pointing to the same destination do not simultaneously exist in the routing table. Each process running on a router advertises its administrative distance value to the local router. The router uses this value to determine which route should be used. Once a route has been selected, the routing information database is updated. If two routes have the same administrative distance, the router uses its vendor-specific algorithm to determine which route should be installed.[2] Cisco routers simply ignore the values and fall back to the default values, which are never the same.[4]
The router will usually compare administrative distances to determine which protocol has the lowest value. The router prefers protocols that have a lower assigned administrative distance. For example, OSPF has a default distance of 110, so it is preferred by the router process, over RIP, which has a default distance of 120. The administrator can arbitrarily reconfigure the administrative distances, which affects the ranking of the preferred routes by the routing process. On Cisco routers, static routes have an administrative distance of 1, making them preferred over routes issued by a dynamic routing protocol. The administrative distance is a value that is always only referenced by the local router itself. The administrative distance is not advertised on the network.[2]
</wiki></doc>