<doc><id>arbitrariness</id><concept_name>arbitrariness</concept_name><wiki>Arbitrariness is the quality of being "determined by chance, whim, or impulse, and not by necessity, reason, or principle". It is also used to refer to a choice made without any specific criterion or restraint.[1][2]
Arbitrary decisions are not necessarily the same as random decisions.  For example, during the 1973 oil crisis, Americans were allowed to purchase gasoline only on odd-numbered days if their license plate was odd, and on even-numbered days if their license plate was even. The system was well-defined and not random in its restrictions; however, since license plate numbers are completely unrelated to a person's fitness to purchase gasoline, it was still an arbitrary division of people.  Similarly, schoolchildren are often organized by their surname in alphabetical order, a non-random yet an arbitrary method&#8212;at least in cases where surnames are irrelevant.
Arbitrary actions are closely related to teleology, the study of purpose.  Actions lacking a telos, a goal, are necessarily arbitrary. With no end to measure against, there can be no standard applied to choices, so all decisions are alike. Note that arbitrary or random methods in the standard sense of arbitrary may not qualify as arbitrary choices philosophically, if they were done in furtherance of a larger purpose (such as the examples above for the purposes of establishing discipline in school and avoiding overcrowding at gas stations).
Nihilism is the philosophy that believes that there is no purpose in the universe, and that every choice is arbitrary.[3] According to nihilism, the universe contains no value and is essentially meaningless. Because the universe and all of its constituents contain no higher goal for us to make subgoals from, all aspects of human life and experiences are completely arbitrary. There is no right or wrong decision, thought or practice, and whatever choice a human being makes is just as meaningless and empty as any other choice he or she could have made.[4]
</wiki></doc>