<doc><id>archaism</id><concept_name>archaism</concept_name><wiki>In language, an archaism (from the Ancient Greek: &#7936;&#961;&#967;&#945;&#970;&#954;&#972;&#962;, archa&#239;k&#243;s, 'old-fashioned, antiquated', ultimately &#7936;&#961;&#967;&#945;&#8150;&#959;&#962;, archa&#238;os, 'from the beginning, ancient') is a word, a sense of a word, or a style of speech or writing that belongs to a historical epoch long beyond living memory, but that has survived in a few practical settings or affairs. Lexical archaisms are single archaic words or expressions used regularly in an affair (e.g. religion or law) or freely; literary archaism is the survival of archaic language in a traditional literary text such as a nursery rhyme or the deliberate use of a style characteristic of an earlier age&#8212;for example, in his 1960 novel The Sot-Weed Factor, John Barth writes in an 18th-century style.[1]  Archaic words or expressions may have distinctive emotional connotations&#8212;some can be humorous (forsooth), some highly formal (What say you?), and some solemn (With thee do I plight my troth).
Archaisms are most frequently encountered in history, poetry, fantasy literature, law, philosophy, science, technology, geography and ritual writing and speech. Archaisms are kept alive by these ritual and literary uses and by the study of older literature. Should they remain recognised, they can potentially be revived.
Because they are things of continual discovery and re-invention, science and technology have historically generated forms of speech and writing which have dated and fallen into disuse relatively quickly. However, the emotional associations of certain words have kept them alive, for example: 'Wireless' rather than 'Radio' for a generation of British citizens who lived through the Second World War, even though the older word 'wireless' is an archaism, and in recent years the term has gained renewed popularity.
A similar desire to evoke a former age means that archaic place names are frequently used in circumstances where doing so conveys a political or emotional subtext, or when the official new name is not recognised by all (for example: 'Madras' rather than 'Chennai'). So, a restaurant seeking to conjure up historic associations might prefer to call itself Old Bombay or refer to Persian cuisine in preference to using the newer place name. A notable contemporary example is the name of the airline Cathay Pacific, which uses the archaic Cathay ("China").
</wiki></doc>