<doc><id>arithmetic_operation</id><concept_name>arithmetic operation</concept_name><wiki>Arithmetic (from the Greek &#7936;&#961;&#953;&#952;&#956;&#972;&#962; arithmos, "number" and &#964;&#953;&#954;&#942; [&#964;&#941;&#967;&#957;&#951;], tik&#233; [t&#233;chne], "art") is a branch of mathematics that consists of the study of numbers, especially the properties of the traditional operations on them&#8212;addition, subtraction, multiplication and division. Arithmetic is an elementary part of number theory, and number theory is considered to be one of the top-level divisions of modern mathematics, along with algebra, geometry, and analysis. The terms arithmetic and higher arithmetic were used until the beginning of the 20th&#160;century as synonyms for number theory and are sometimes still used to refer to a wider part of number theory.[1]
The prehistory of arithmetic is limited to a small number of artifacts which may indicate the conception of addition and subtraction, the best-known being the Ishango bone from central Africa, dating from somewhere between 20,000 and 18,000&#160;BC, although its interpretation is disputed.[2]
The earliest written records indicate the Egyptians and Babylonians used all the elementary arithmetic operations as early as 2000&#160;BC. These artifacts do not always reveal the specific process used for solving problems, but the characteristics of the particular numeral system strongly influence the complexity of the methods. The hieroglyphic system for Egyptian numerals, like the later Roman numerals, descended from tally marks used for counting. In both cases, this origin resulted in values that used a decimal base but did not include positional notation. Complex calculations with Roman numerals required the assistance of a counting board or the Roman abacus to obtain the results.
Early number systems that included positional notation were not decimal, including the sexagesimal (base&#160;60) system for Babylonian numerals and the vigesimal (base&#160;20) system that defined Maya numerals. Because of this place-value concept, the ability to reuse the same digits for different values contributed to simpler and more efficient methods of calculation.
</wiki></doc>