<doc><id>asimo</id><concept_name>asimo</concept_name><wiki>ASIMO (Advanced Step in Innovative Mobility) is a humanoid robot created by Honda in 2000. It is currently displayed in the Miraikan museum in Tokyo, Japan. The name was chosen in honor of Isaac Asimov.[1]
Honda began developing humanoid robots in the 1980s, including several prototypes that preceded ASIMO. It was the company's goal to create a walking robot. E0 was the first bipedal (two-legged) model produced as part of the Honda E series, which was an early experimental line of self-regulating, humanoid walking robot with wireless movements created between 1986 and 1993.[2][3]
This was followed by the Honda P series of robots produced from 1993 through 1997. The research made 
on the E- and P-series led to the creation of ASIMO. Development began at Honda's Wako Fundamental Technical Research Center in Japan in 1999 and ASIMO was unveiled in October 2000.[4][5] ASIMO is an acronym which stands for Advanced Step in Innovative Mobility.[6] The Japanese word Asi also stands for 'leg' and Mo for 'mobility'. ASIMO is pronounced as 'ashimo' and means 'also legs'. 
In 2018, Honda ceased the commercial development of ASIMO, although it will continue to be developed as a research platform and make public appearances.[7]
ASIMO stands 130&#160;cm (4&#160;ft 3&#160;in) tall and weighs 54&#160;kg (119&#160;lb). Research conducted by Honda found that the ideal height for a mobility assistant robot was between 120&#160;cm and the height of an average adult, which is conducive to operating door knobs and light switches.[2][8] ASIMO is powered by a rechargeable 51.8&#160;V lithium-ion battery with an operating time of one hour. Switching from a nickel metal hydride in 2004 increased the amount of time ASIMO can operate before recharging.[9] ASIMO has a three-dimensional computer processor that was created by Honda and consists of a three stacked die, a processor, a signal converter and memory.[10] The computer that controls ASIMO's movement is housed in the robot's waist area and can be controlled by a PC, wireless controller, or voice commands.[11]
</wiki></doc>