<doc><id>baby_boomers</id><concept_name>baby boomers</concept_name><wiki>

Baby boomers (boomers for short) are the demographic cohort following the Silent Generation and preceding Generation X. The generation is most often defined as individuals born between 1946 and 1964, during the post&#8211;World War II baby boom.[1] The baby boom has been described variously as a "shockwave"[2] and as "the pig in the python";[3] in particular, 76 million Americans were born during this timeframe.
In the 1960s and 1970s, as this relatively large number of young people entered their teens and young adulthood&#8212;the oldest turned 18 in 1964&#8212;they, and those around them, created a very specific rhetoric around their cohort and the changes brought about by their size in numbers, such as the counterculture of the 1960s.[4] This rhetoric had an important impact in the perceptions of the boomers, as well as society's increasingly common tendency to define the world in terms of generations, which was a relatively new phenomenon. As a group, baby boomers were wealthier, more active and more physically fit than any preceding generation and were the first to grow up genuinely expecting the world to improve with time.[3] However, this generation also has been criticized often for its increases in consumerism which others saw as excessive.[5]. Baby boomers are often the parents of Millennials and Generation X and sometimes older members of Generation Z.
The term baby boom refers to a noticeable increase in the birth rate. The post-World War II population increase was described as a "boom" by various newspaper reporters, including Sylvia F. Porter in a column in the May 4, 1951, edition of the New York Post, based on the increase of 2,357,000 in the population of the U.S. in 1950.[7] The first recorded use of "baby boomer" is in a January 1963 Daily Press article describing a massive surge of college enrollments approaching as the oldest boomers were coming of age.[8][9]  The Oxford English Dictionary dates the modern meaning of the term to a January 23, 1970, article in The Washington Post.[10]
</wiki></doc>