<doc><id>business_rule</id><concept_name>business rule</concept_name><wiki>A business rule defines or constrains some aspect of business and always resolves to either true or false. It specifically involves terms, facts and rules. [1] Business rules are intended to assert business structure or to control or influence the behavior of the business.[2] Business rules describe the operations, definitions and constraints that apply to an organization.  Business rules can apply to people, processes, corporate behavior and computing systems in an organization, and are put in place to help the organization achieve its goals.[citation needed] Even though a system of strategic processes govern business rules, business rules are not strategic themselves; they are directive. [3]
For example, a business rule might state that no credit check is to be performed on return customers.  Other examples of business rules include requiring a rental agent to disallow a rental tenant if their credit rating is too low, or requiring company agents to use a list of preferred suppliers and supply schedules.
While a business rule may be informal or even unwritten, documenting the rules clearly and making sure that they don't conflict is a valuable activity.[citation needed]  When carefully managed, rules can be used to help the organization to better achieve goals, remove obstacles to market growth, reduce costly mistakes, improve communication, comply with legal requirements, and increase customer loyalty.[citation needed] Business rules can also be applied to software, like computing systems.[4] This software helps business organize and achieve their goals by using business rules and business logic.[5]
Business rules  tell an organization what it can do in detail, while strategy tells it how to focus the business at a macro level to optimize results.[citation needed] Put differently, a strategy provides high-level direction about what an organization should do. Business rules provide detailed guidance about how a strategy can be translated to action.
</wiki></doc>