<doc><id>caller_id</id><concept_name>caller id</concept_name><wiki>Caller ID (caller identification, CID), also called calling line identification (CLID),  Calling Line Identification (CLI), calling number delivery (CND), calling number identification (CNID), calling line identification presentation (CLIP), or call display, is a telephone service, available in analog and digital telephone systems, including VoIP, that transmits a caller's telephone number to the called party's telephone equipment when the call is being set up.  The caller ID service may include the transmission of a name associated with the calling telephone number, in a service called CNAM. The service was first defined in 1993 in International Telecommunication Union&#8212;Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) Recommendation Q.731.3.[1]
The recipient may inspect the information before answering the call on a display in the telephone set, on a separately attached device, or on other digital displays, such as cable television sets when telephone and television service is provided by the same vendor.
In some countries, the terms caller display, calling line identification presentation (CLIP), call capture, or just calling line identity are used; call display is the predominant marketing name used in Canada (although some customers still refer to it colloquially as "caller ID"). The concept of calling number identification as a service for POTS subscribers originated from automatic number identification (ANI) as a part of toll free number service in the United States.
However, caller ID and ANI are not equivalent services. ANI was originally a service in a non-electronic central office that identified the telephone number of the line from which a call was originated. Previous to this, the calling number could not be identified electronically. In addition to the caller's telephone number, caller ID may also transmit the subscriber's name, when available. The name can be passed on by the originating central office, or it is obtained from a Line Information Database by the terminating switch. If no name is available, the city, State, Province, or other designation may be sent. Some of these databases may be shared among several companies, each paying every time a name is "extracted". It is for this reason that mobile phone callers appear as "WIRELESS CALLER", or the location where the phone number is registered.
</wiki></doc>