<doc><id>citation_analysis</id><concept_name>citation analysis</concept_name><wiki>Citation analysis is the examination of the frequency, patterns, and graphs of citations in documents. It uses the directed graph of citations &#8212; links from one document to another document &#8212; to reveal properties of the documents.  A typical aim would be to identify the most important documents in a collection.  A classic example is that of the citations between academic articles and books.[1][2] For another example, judges of law support their judgements by referring back to judgements made in earlier cases (see citation analysis in a legal context). An additional example is provided by patents which contain prior art, citation of earlier patents relevant to the current claim.
Documents can be associated with many other features in addition to citations, such as authors, publishers, journals as well as their actual texts.  The general analysis of collections of documents is known as bibliometrics and citation analysis is a key part of that field. For example, bibliographic coupling and co-citation are association measures based on citation analysis (shared citations or shared references). The citations in a collection of documents can also be represented in forms such as a citation graph, as pointed out by Derek J. de Solla Price in his 1965 article "Networks of Scientific Papers".[3]  This means that citation analysis draws on aspects of social network analysis and network science.
An early example of automated citation indexing was CiteSeer, which was used for citations between academic papers, while Web of Science is an example of a modern system which includes more than just academic books and articles reflecting a wider range of information sources. Today, automated citation indexing[4] has changed the nature of citation analysis research, allowing millions of citations to be analyzed for large-scale patterns and knowledge discovery. Citation analysis tools can be used to compute various impact measures for scholars based on data from citation indices.[5][6][7] These have various applications, from the identification of expert referees to review papers and grant proposals, to providing transparent data in support of academic merit review, tenure, and promotion decisions. This competition for limited resources may lead to ethically questionable behavior to increase citations.[8][9]
A great deal of criticism has been made of the practice of naively using citation analyses to compare the impact of different scholarly articles without taking into account other factors which may affect citation patterns.[10] Among these criticisms, a recurrent one focuses on &#8220;field-dependent factors&#8221;, which refers to the fact that citation practices vary from one area of science to another, and even between fields of research within a discipline.[11]
</wiki></doc>