<doc><id>cognition</id><concept_name>cognition</concept_name><wiki>Cognition is "the mental action or process of acquiring knowledge and understanding through thought, experience, and the senses".[1] It encompasses many aspects of intellectual functions and processes such as attention, the formation of knowledge, memory and working memory, judgment and evaluation, reasoning and "computation", problem solving and decision making, comprehension and production of language. Cognitive processes use existing knowledge and generate new knowledge.
Cognitive processes are analyzed from different perspectives within different contexts, notably in the fields of linguistics, anesthesia, neuroscience, psychiatry, psychology, education, philosophy, anthropology, biology, systemics, logic, and computer science.[2] These and other different approaches to the analysis of cognition are synthesised in the developing field of cognitive science, a progressively autonomous academic discipline.
The word cognition comes from the Latin verb cognosco (con, 'with', and gn&#333;sc&#333;, 'know'; itself a cognate of the Greek verb &#947;&#953;(&#947;)&#957;&#974;&#963;&#954;&#969;, gi(g)n&#972;sko, meaning 'I know, perceive'),[3] meaning 'to conceptualize' or 'to recognize'.[4]
The word cognition dates back to the 15th century, when it meant "thinking and awareness".[5] Attention to cognitive processes came about more than eighteen centuries earlier, however, beginning with Aristotle (384&#8211;322 BC) and his interest in the inner workings of the mind and how they affect the human experience. Aristotle focused on cognitive areas pertaining to memory, perception, and mental imagery. He placed great importance on ensuring that his studies were based on empirical evidence, that is, scientific information that is gathered through observation and conscientious experimentation.[6] Two millennia later, the groundwork for modern concepts of cognition was laid during the Enlightenment by thinkers such as John Locke and Dugald Stewart who sought to develop a model of the mind in which ideas were acquired, remembered and manipulated.[7]
</wiki></doc>