<doc><id>cognitive_architecture</id><concept_name>cognitive architecture</concept_name><wiki>A  cognitive architecture refers to both a theory about the structure of the human mind and to a computational instantiation of such a theory used in the fields of artificial intelligence (AI) and computational cognitive science.[1] One of the main goals of a cognitive architecture is to summarize the various results of cognitive psychology in a comprehensive computer model.[citation needed] However, the results need to be formalized so far as they can be the basis of a computer program.[citation needed] The formalized models can be used to further refine a comprehensive theory of cognition, and more immediately, as a commercially usable model.[citation needed] Successful cognitive architectures include ACT-R (Adaptive Control of Thought - Rational) and SOAR.[citation needed]
The Institute of Creative Technologies defines cognitive architecture as: "hypothesis about the fixed structures that provide a mind, whether in natural or artificial systems, and how they work together &#8211; in conjunction with knowledge and skills embodied within the architecture &#8211; to yield intelligent behavior in a diversity of complex environments."[2]
Herbert A. Simon, one of the founders of the field of artificial intelligence, stated that the 1960 thesis by his student Ed Feigenbaum, EPAM provided a possible "architecture for cognition"[3] because it included some commitments for how more than one fundamental aspect of the human mind worked (in EPAM's case, human memory and human learning).
John R. Anderson started research on human memory in the early 1970s and his 1973 thesis with Gordon H. Bower provided a theory of human associative memory.[4] He included more aspects of his research on long-term memory and thinking processes into this research and eventually designed a cognitive architecture he eventually called ACT.  He and his students were influenced by Allen Newell's use of the term "cognitive architecture". Anderson's lab used the term to refer to the ACT theory as embodied in a collection of papers and designs (there was not a complete implementation of ACT at the time).
</wiki></doc>