<doc><id>cognitive_inertia</id><concept_name>cognitive inertia</concept_name><wiki>Cognitive inertia is the tendency for a particular orientation in how an individual thinks about an issue, belief or strategy to endure or resist change.[1][2] The physics term inertia is to emphasize the rigidity and resistance to change in the method of cognitive processing the individual uses, especially after it has been in use for a significant amount of time. Commonly confused with belief perseverance, cognitive inertia is the perseverance of how one interprets information, not the perseverance of the belief itself.[2][3] In clinical and neuroscientific literature cognitive inertia is often defined as a lack of motivation to generate cognitive specific processes to attend to a problem or issue.[4][5]
Cognitive inertia has been implicated in disregard of impending threat to one's health or environment, enduring political values and deficits in task switching.[6][7] Interest in cognitive inertia was largely taken up by economic and industrial psychologists to explain resistance to change in brand loyalty, group brainstorming and business strategies.[8][9][10]&#160; &#160; &#160;
The idea of cognitive inertia has its roots in philosophical epistemology. Early allusions to reduction of cognitive inertia can be found in the Socratic dialogues written by Plato. Socrates  builds his argument by using the detractors beliefs as the premise to his arguments conclusions. In doing so, Socrates reveals the detractors fallacy of thought inducing the detractor to change their mind or face the reality that their thought processes are in contradiction.[11][12] Ways to combat persistence of cognitive style is also seen in Aristotle's syllogistic method which employs logical consistency of the premises to convince an individual of the conclusions validity.[13]
In the beginning of the twentieth century two of the earliest experimental psychologists M&#252;ller and Pilzecker defined perseveration of thought to be, "the tendency of ideas, after once having entered consciousness, to rise freely again in consciousness". M&#252;ller described perseveration by illustrating his own inability to inhibit old cognitive strategies with a syllable switching task while his wife easily switched from one strategy to the next. One of the earliest personality researchers, W. Lankes, more broadly defined perseveration as, "being confined to the cognitive side," and may be, "counteracted by strong will".[14] These early ideas of perseveration were the precursor to how the term cognitive inertia would be used to study certain symptoms in patients with neurodegenerative disorders, rumination and depression.[4][15]&#160; &#160; &#160;
</wiki></doc>