<doc><id>computer_mediated_communication</id><concept_name>computer mediated communication</concept_name><wiki>Computer-mediated communication (CMC) is defined as any human communication that occurs through the use of two or more electronic devices.[1]  While the term has traditionally referred to those communications that occur via computer-mediated formats (e.g., instant messaging, email, chat rooms, online forums, social network services), it has also been applied to  other forms of text-based interaction such as text messaging.[2] Research on CMC focuses largely on the social effects of different computer-supported communication technologies. Many recent studies involve Internet-based social networking supported by social software.
Computer-mediated communication can be broken down into two forms: synchronous and asynchronous.[3] Synchronous computer-mediated communication refers to communication which occurs in real time. All parties are engaged in the communication simultaneously; however, they are not necessarily all in the same location.[4] Examples of synchronous communication are video chats and FaceTime audio calls. On the contrary, asynchronous computer-mediated communication refers to communication which takes place when the parties engaged are not communicating in unison. In other words, the sender does not receive an immediate response from the receiver. Most forms of computer mediated technology are asynchronous.[4] Examples of asynchronous communication are text messages and emails.
Scholars from a variety of fields study phenomena that can be described under the umbrella term of computer mediated communication (CMC) (see also Internet studies). For example, many take a sociopsychological approach to CMC by examining how humans use "computers" (or digital media) to manage interpersonal interaction, form impressions and  form and maintain relationships.[5][6] These studies have often focused on the differences between online and offline interactions, though contemporary research is moving towards the view that CMC should be studied as embedded in everyday life .[7] Another branch of CMC research examines the use of paralinguistic features such as emoticons,[8] pragmatic rules such as turn-taking[9] and the sequential analysis and organization of talk,[10][11] and the various sociolects, styles, registers or sets of terminology specific to these environments (see Leet). The study of language in these contexts is typically based on text-based forms of CMC, and is sometimes referred to as "computer-mediated discourse analysis".[12]
The way humans communicate in professional, social, and educational settings varies widely, depending upon not only the environment but also the method of communication in which the communication occurs, which in this case is through computers or other information and communication technologies (ICTs). The study of communication to achieve collaboration&#8212;common work products&#8212;is termed computer-supported collaboration and includes only some of the concerns of other forms of CMC research.
</wiki></doc>