<doc><id>convex_optimization</id><concept_name>convex optimization</concept_name><wiki>Convex optimization is a subfield of mathematical optimization that studies the problem of minimizing convex functions over convex sets. Many classes of convex optimization problems admit polynomial-time algorithms,[1] whereas mathematical optimization is in general NP-hard.[2][3][4]
Convex optimization has applications in a wide range of disciplines, such as automatic control systems, estimation and signal processing, communications and networks, electronic circuit design,[5] data analysis and modeling, finance, statistics (optimal experimental design),[6] and structural optimization, where the approximation concept has proven to be efficient.[7] [8] 
With recent advancements in computing and optimization algorithms, convex programming is nearly as straightforward as linear programming.[9]
A convex optimization problem is an optimization problem in which the objective function is a convex function and the feasible set is a convex set. A function 



f


{\displaystyle f}

  mapping some subset of 





R


n




{\displaystyle \mathbb {R} ^{n}}

into 




R

&#8746;
{
&#177;
&#8734;
}


{\displaystyle \mathbb {R} \cup \{\pm \infty \}}

 is convex if its domain is convex and for all 



&#952;
&#8712;
[
0
,
1
]


{\displaystyle \theta \in [0,1]}

 and all 



x
,
y


{\displaystyle x,y}

 in its domain, the following condition holds:



f
(
&#952;
x
+
(
1
&#8722;
&#952;
)
y
)
&#8804;
&#952;
f
(
x
)
+
(
1
&#8722;
&#952;
)
f
(
y
)


{\displaystyle f(\theta x+(1-\theta )y)\leq \theta f(x)+(1-\theta )f(y)}

. A set S is convex if for all members 



x
,
y
&#8712;
S


{\displaystyle x,y\in S}

 and all  



&#952;
&#8712;
[
0
,
1
]


{\displaystyle \theta \in [0,1]}

, we have that 



&#952;
x
+
(
1
&#8722;
&#952;
)
y
&#8712;
S


{\displaystyle \theta x+(1-\theta )y\in S}

.
Concretely, a convex optimization problem is the problem of finding some 





x

&#8727;



&#8712;
C


{\displaystyle \mathbf {x^{\ast }} \in C}

 attaining
</wiki></doc>