<doc><id>customer_lifetime_value</id><concept_name>customer lifetime value</concept_name><wiki>In marketing, customer lifetime value (CLV or often CLTV), lifetime customer value (LCV), or life-time value (LTV) is a prediction of the net profit attributed to the entire future relationship with a customer. The prediction model can have varying levels of sophistication and accuracy, ranging from a crude heuristic to the use of complex predictive analytics techniques.
Customer lifetime value can also be defined as the monetary value of a customer relationship, based on the present value of the projected future cash flows from the customer relationship.[citation needed] Customer lifetime value is an important concept in that it encourages firms to shift their focus from quarterly profits to the long-term health of their customer relationships. Customer lifetime value is an important metric because it represents an upper limit on spending to acquire new customers.[1] For this reason it is an important element in calculating payback of advertising spent in marketing mix modeling.
One of the first accounts of the term customer lifetime value is in the 1988 book Database Marketing, which includes detailed worked examples.[2] Early adopters of customer lifetime value models in the 1990s include Edge Consulting and BrandScience.
The purpose of the customer lifetime value metric is to assess the financial value of each customer. Don Peppers and Martha Rogers are quoted as saying, &#8220;some customers are more equal than others.&#8221;[3] Customer lifetime value differs from customer profitability or CP (the difference between the revenues and the costs associated with the customer relationship during a specified period) in that CP measures the past and CLV looks forward. As such, CLV can be more useful in shaping managers&#8217; decisions but is much more difficult to quantify. While quantifying CP is a matter of carefully reporting and summarizing the results of past activity, quantifying CLV involves forecasting future activity.[1]
</wiki></doc>