<doc><id>data_migration</id><concept_name>data migration</concept_name><wiki>Data migration is the process of selecting, preparing, extracting, and transforming data and permanently transferring it from one computer storage system to another. Additionally, the validation of migrated data for completeness and the decommissioning of legacy data storage are considered part of the entire data migration process.[1][2] Data migration is a key consideration for any system implementation, upgrade, or consolidation, and it is typically performed in such a way as to be as automated as possible, freeing up human resources from tedious tasks. Data migration occurs for a variety of reasons, including server or storage equipment replacements, maintenance or upgrades, application migration, website consolidation, disaster recovery, and data center relocation.[2]
As of 2011[update], "nearly 40 percent of data migration projects were over time, over budget, or failed entirely."[1][3] As such, to achieve an effective data migration, proper planning is critical. While the specifics of a data migration plan may vary&#8212;sometimes significantly&#8212;from project to project, the computing company IBM suggests there are three main phases to most any data migration project: planning, migration, and post-migration.[2] Each of those phases has its own steps. During planning, dependencies and requirements are analyzed, migration scenarios get developed and tested, and a project plan that incorporates the prior information is created. During the migration phase, the plan is enacted, and during post-migration, the completeness and thoroughness of the migration is validated, documented, closed out, including any necessary decommissioning of legacy systems.[2] For applications of moderate to high complexity, these data migration phases may be repeated several times before the new system is considered to be fully validated and deployed.
Planning: The data, applications, etc. that will be migrated are selected based on business, project, and technical requirements and dependencies. Hardware and bandwidth requirements are analyzed. Feasible migration and back-out scenarios are developed, as well as the associated tests, automation scripts, mappings, and procedures. Data cleansing and transformation requirements are also gauged for data formats to improve data quality and to eliminate redundant or obsolete information. Migration architecture is decided on and developed, any necessary software licenses are obtained, and change management processes are started.[1][2]
Migration: Hardware and software requirements are validated, and migration procedures are customized as necessary. Some sort of pre-validation testing may also occur to ensure requirements and customized settings function as expected. If all is deemed well, migration begins, including the primary acts of data extraction, where data is read from the old system, and data loading, where data is written to the new system. Additional verification steps ensure the developed migration plan was enacted in full.[1][2]
</wiki></doc>