<doc><id>data_quality</id><concept_name>data quality</concept_name><wiki>Data quality refers to the state of qualitative or quantitative pieces of information. There are many definitions of data quality but data is generally considered high quality if it is "fit for [its] intended uses in operations, decision making and planning".[2][3] Moreover, data is deemed of high quality if it correctly represents the real-world construct to which it refers. Furthermore, apart from these definitions, as the number of data sources increases, the question of internal data consistency becomes significant, regardless of fitness for use for any particular external purpose. People's views on data quality can often be in disagreement, even when discussing the same set of data used for the same purpose.  When this is the case, data governance is used to form agreed upon definitions and standards for data quality.  In such cases, data cleansing, including standardization, may be required in order to ensure data quality.[4]
This list is taken from the online book "Data Quality: High-impact Strategies".[5] See also the glossary of data quality terms.[6]
If the ISO 9000:2015 definition of quality is applied, data quality can be defined as the degree to which a set of characteristics of data fulfills requirements. Examples of characteristics are: completeness, validity, accuracy, consistency, availability and timeliness. Requirements are defined as the need or expectation that is stated, generally implied or obligatory. However, there are also other standards related to data quality. For example, ISO 25012 defines 15 quality dimensions of the data.[11]
Quantity and names of the quality dimensions (characteristics) can also depend on the source of data. For instance, for data in Web 2.0 documents following dimensions can be defined:: accessibility, completeness, credibility, involvement, objectivity, readability, relevance, reputation, style, timeliness, uniqueness, usefulness.[1]
</wiki></doc>