<doc><id>desktop_publishing_software</id><concept_name>desktop publishing software</concept_name><wiki>Desktop publishing (DTP) is the creation of documents using page layout software on a personal ("desktop") computer. It was first used almost exclusively for print publications, but now it also assists in the creation of various forms of online content.[1] Desktop publishing software can generate layouts and produce typographic-quality text and images comparable to traditional typography and printing. Desktop publishing is also the main reference for digital typography. This technology allows individuals, businesses, and other organizations to self-publish a wide variety of content, from menus to magazines to books, without the expense of commercial printing.[2]
Desktop publishing often requires the use of a personal computer and WYSIWYG page layout software to create documents for either large-scale publishing or small-scale local multifunction peripheral output and distribution &#8212; although a non-WYSIWYG system such as LaTeX could also be used for the creation of highly-structured and technically-demanding documents as well.[3] Desktop publishing methods provide more control over design, layout, and typography than word processing. However, word processing software has evolved to include most, if not all, capabilities previously available only with professional printing or desktop publishing.[4]
The same DTP skills and software used for common paper and book publishing are sometimes used to create graphics for point of sale displays, presentations, infographics, brochures, business cards, promotional items, trade show exhibits, retail package designs and outdoor signs. Although what is classified as "DTP software" is usually limited to print and PDF publications, DTP isn't limited to print. The content produced by desktop publishers may also be exported and used for electronic media. The job descriptions that include "DTP," such as DTP artist, often require skills using software for producing e-books, web content, and web pages, which may involve web design or user interface design for any graphical user interface.
Desktop publishing was first developed at Xerox PARC in the 1970s.[5][6] A contradictory claim states that desktop publishing began in 1983 with a program developed by James Davise at a community newspaper in Philadelphia.[7] The program Type Processor One ran on a PC using a graphics card for a WYSIWYG display and was offered commercially by Best info in 1984.[8] (Desktop typesetting with only limited page makeup facilities had arrived in 1978&#8211;1979 with the introduction of TeX, and was extended in 1985 with the introduction of LaTeX.)[3]
</wiki></doc>