<doc><id>digital_signal_processor</id><concept_name>digital signal processor</concept_name><wiki>A digital signal processor (DSP) is a specialized microprocessor (or a SIP block) chip, with its architecture optimized for the operational needs of digital signal processing.[1][2] DSPs are fabricated on MOS integrated circuit chips.[3][4] They are widely used in audio signal processing, telecommunications, digital image processing, radar, sonar and speech recognition systems, and in common consumer electronic devices such as mobile phones, disk drives and high-definition television (HDTV) products.[3]
The goal of a DSP is usually to measure, filter or compress continuous real-world analog signals.  Most general-purpose microprocessors can also execute digital signal processing algorithms successfully, but may not be able to keep up with such processing continuously in real-time.  Also, dedicated DSPs usually have better power efficiency, thus they are more suitable in portable devices such as mobile phones because of power consumption constraints.[5] DSPs often use special memory architectures that are able to fetch multiple data or instructions at the same time. DSPs often also implement data compression technology, with the discrete cosine transform (DCT) in particular being a widely used compression technology in DSPs.
Digital signal processing algorithms typically require a large number of mathematical operations to be performed quickly and repeatedly on a series of data samples.  Signals (perhaps from audio or video sensors) are constantly converted from analog to digital, manipulated digitally, and then converted back to analog form. Many DSP applications have constraints on latency; that is, for the system to work, the DSP operation must be completed within some fixed time, and deferred (or batch) processing is not viable.
Most general-purpose microprocessors and operating systems can execute DSP algorithms successfully, but are not suitable for use in portable devices such as mobile phones and PDAs because of power efficiency constraints.[5] A specialized DSP, however, will tend to provide a lower-cost solution, with better performance, lower latency, and no requirements for specialised cooling or large batteries.[citation needed]
</wiki></doc>