<doc><id>digital_agriculture</id><concept_name>digital agriculture</concept_name><wiki>Digital agriculture refers to tools that digitally collect, store, analyze, and share electronic data and/or information along the agricultural value chain. Other definitions, such as those from the United Nations Project Breakthrough,[1] Cornell University,[2] and Purdue University,[3] also emphasize the role of digital technology in the optimization of food systems. &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160;
Sometimes known as &#8220;smart farming&#8221; or &#8220;e-agriculture,&#8221;[4] digital agriculture includes (but is not limited to) precision agriculture. Unlike precision agriculture, digital agriculture impacts the entire agri-food value chain &#8212; before, during, and after on-farm production.[5] Therefore, on-farm technologies, like yield mapping, GPS guidance systems, and variable-rate application, fall under the domain of precision agriculture and digital agriculture. On the other hand, digital technologies involved in e-commerce platforms, e-extension services, warehouse receipt systems, blockchain-enabled food traceability systems, tractor rental apps, etc. fall under the umbrella of digital agriculture but not precision agriculture.
Emerging digital technologies have the potential to change farming beyond recognition.[6] The Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations has referred to this change as a revolution: &#8220;a &#8216;digital agricultural revolution&#8217; will be the newest shift which could help ensure agriculture meets the needs of the global population into the future.&#8221;[7] Other sources label the change as &#8220;Agriculture 4.0,&#8221; indicating its role as the fourth major agricultural revolution.[8] Precise dates of the newest agricultural revolution are unclear. Frankelius considers 2015 as the starting point of the Fourth Agricultural Revolution.[9] Lombardo et al. date the starting point back to 1997, when the first European conference on precision agriculture took place.[10] The World Economic Forum announced that the &#8220;Fourth Industrial Revolution&#8221; (which includes agriculture) will unfold throughout the 21st century, so perhaps 2000 or shortly thereafter marks the beginning of Agriculture 4.0.[11][12]
Agricultural revolutions denote periods of technological transformation and increased farm productivity.[13] Agricultural revolutions include the First Agricultural Revolution, the Arab Agricultural Revolution, the British/Second Agricultural Revolution, the Scottish Agricultural Revolution, and the Green Revolution/Third Agricultural Revolution. Despite boosting agricultural productivity, past agricultural revolutions left many problems unsolved. For example, the Green Revolution had unintended consequences, like inequality and environmental damage. First, the Green Revolution exacerbated inter-farm and interregional inequality,[14] typically biased toward large farmers with the capital to invest in new technologies.[15] Second, critics say its policies promoted heavy input use and dependence on agrochemicals, which led to adverse environmental effects like soil degradation and chemical runoff.[16][17] Digital agriculture technologies have the potential to address negative side effects of the Green Revolution.
</wiki></doc>