<doc><id>digital_preservation</id><concept_name>digital preservation</concept_name><wiki>In library and archival science, digital preservation is a formal endeavor to ensure that digital information of continuing value remains accessible and usable.[1] It involves planning, resource allocation, and application of preservation methods and technologies,[2] and it combines policies, strategies and actions to ensure access to reformatted and "born-digital" content, regardless of the challenges of media failure and technological change. The goal of digital preservation is the accurate rendering of authenticated content over time.[3]
The Association for Library Collections and Technical Services Preservation and Reformatting Section of the American Library Association, defined digital preservation as combination of "policies, strategies and actions that ensure access to digital content over time."[4] According to the Harrod's Librarian Glossary, digital preservation is the method of keeping digital material alive so that they remain usable as technological advances render original hardware and software specification obsolete.[5]
The need for digital preservation mainly arises because of the relatively short lifespan of digial media. Widely used hard drives can become unusable in a few years due to damaged spindle motors, and flash memory (found on SSDs, phones, SD and microSD cards and flash drives) can start to lose data around a year after its last use, depending on its storage temperature. Currently, 5D optical data storage has the potential to store digital data for thousands of years.
Archival appraisal (or, alternatively, selection[6]) refers to the process of identifying records and other materials to be preserved by determining their permanent value. Several factors are usually considered when making this decision.[7] It is a difficult and critical process because the remaining selected records will shape researchers' understanding of that body of records, or fonds. Appraisal is identified as A4.2 within the Chain of Preservation (COP) model[8] created by the InterPARES 2 project.[9] Archival appraisal is not the same as monetary appraisal, which determines fair market value.
Archival appraisal may be performed once or at the various stages of acquisition and processing. Macro appraisal,[10] a functional analysis of records at a high level, may be performed even before the records have been acquired to determine which records to acquire. More detailed, iterative appraisal may be performed while the records are being processed.
</wiki></doc>