<doc><id>EM_algorithm</id><concept_name>EM algorithm</concept_name><wiki>In statistics, an expectation&#8211;maximization (EM) algorithm is an iterative method to find maximum likelihood or maximum a posteriori (MAP) estimates of parameters in statistical models, where the model depends on unobserved latent variables. The EM iteration alternates between performing an expectation (E) step, which creates a function for the expectation of the log-likelihood evaluated using the current estimate for the parameters, and a maximization (M) step, which computes parameters maximizing the expected log-likelihood found on the E step. These parameter-estimates are then used to determine the distribution of the latent variables in the next E step.
The EM algorithm was explained and given its name in a classic 1977 paper by Arthur Dempster, Nan Laird, and Donald Rubin.[1] They pointed out that the method had been "proposed many times in special circumstances" by earlier authors. One of the earliest is the gene-counting method for estimating allele frequencies by Cedric Smith.[2]  A very detailed treatment of the EM method for exponential families was published by Rolf Sundberg in his thesis and several papers[3][4][5] following his collaboration with Per Martin-L&#246;f and Anders Martin-L&#246;f.[6][7][8][9][10][11][12] The Dempster&#8211;Laird&#8211;Rubin paper in 1977 generalized the method and sketched a convergence analysis for a wider class of problems. Regardless of earlier inventions, the innovative Dempster&#8211;Laird&#8211;Rubin paper in the Journal of the Royal Statistical Society received an enthusiastic discussion at the Royal Statistical Society meeting with Sundberg calling the paper "brilliant". The Dempster&#8211;Laird&#8211;Rubin paper established the EM method as an important tool of statistical analysis.
The convergence analysis of the Dempster&#8211;Laird&#8211;Rubin algorithm was flawed and a correct convergence analysis was published by C. F. Jeff Wu in 1983.[13]
Wu's proof established the EM method's convergence outside of the exponential family, as claimed by Dempster&#8211;Laird&#8211;Rubin.[13]
The EM algorithm is used to find (local) maximum likelihood parameters of a statistical model in cases where the equations cannot be solved directly.  Typically these models involve latent variables in addition to unknown parameters and known data observations.  That is, either missing values exist among the data, or the model can be formulated more simply by assuming the existence of further unobserved data points. For example, a mixture model can be described more simply by assuming that each observed data point has a corresponding unobserved data point, or latent variable, specifying the mixture component to which each data point belongs.
</wiki></doc>