<doc><id>end_user</id><concept_name>end user</concept_name><wiki>In product development, an end user (sometimes end-user)[a] is a person who ultimately uses or is intended to ultimately use a product.[1][2][3] The end user stands in contrast to users who support or maintain the product,[4] such as sysops, system administrators, database administrators,[5] information technology experts, software professionals and computer technicians. End users typically do not possess the technical understanding or skill of the product designers,[6] a fact that is easy for designers to forget or overlook, leading to features with which the customer is dissatisfied.[2] In information technology, end users are not "customers" in the usual sense&#8212;they are typically employees of the customer.[7] For example, if a large retail corporation buys a software package for its employees to use, even though the large retail corporation was the "customer" which purchased the software, the end users are the employees of the company who will use the software at work.
Certain American defense-related products and information require export approval from the United States Government under the ITAR and EAR.[8]  In order to obtain a license to export, the exporter must specify both the end user and end use using an end-user certificate.[9] In End-User License Agreements (EULAs), the end user is distinguished from the value-added reseller that installs the software or the organization that purchases and manages the software.[10] In the UK, there exist documents that accompany licenses for products named end user undertaking (EUU).
End users are one of the three major factors contributing to the complexity of managing information systems. The end user's position has changed from a position in the 1950s (where end users did not interact with the mainframe; computer experts programmed and ran the mainframe) to one in the 2010s where the end user collaborates with and advises the management information system and Information Technology department about his or her needs regarding the system or product. This raises new questions such as: Who manages each resource? What is the role of the MIS Department? What is the optimal relationship between the end user and the MIS Department?[11]
The concept of "end user" first surfaced in the late 1980s and has since then raised many debates. One challenge is that the goal is to both give the user more freedom, by adding advanced features and functions (for more advanced users), and add more constraints (to prevent a neophyte user from accidentally erasing an entire company's database).[12]  This phenomenon appeared as a consequence of "consumerization" of computer products and software. In the 1960s and 1970s, computer users were generally programming experts and computer scientists. However, in the 1980s, and especially in the mid- to late 1990s and the early 2000s, everyday, regular people began using computer devices and software for personal and work use. IT specialists need to cope with this trend in various ways. In the 2010s, users now want to have more control over the systems they operate, so they solve their own problems and be able to change, customize and "tweak" the systems to suit their needs. The drawback would be the risk of corruption of the systems and data the user has control of due to his or her lack of knowledge on how to properly operate the computer or software at an advanced level.[13]
</wiki></doc>