<doc><id>enterprise_model</id><concept_name>enterprise model</concept_name><wiki>Enterprise modelling is the abstract representation, description and definition of the structure, processes, information and resources of an identifiable business, government body, or other large organization.[2]
It deals with the process of understanding an organization and improving its performance through creation and analysis of enterprise models. This includes the modelling of the relevant business domain (usually relatively stable), business processes (usually more volatile), and uses of information technology within the business domain and its processes.
Enterprise modelling is the process of building models of whole or part of an enterprise with process models, data models, resource models and or new ontologies etc. It is based on knowledge about the enterprise, previous models and/or reference models as well as domain ontologies using model representation languages.[3] An enterprise in general is a unit of economic organization or activity. These activities are required to develop and deliver products and/or services to a customer. An enterprise includes a number of functions and operations such as purchasing, manufacturing, marketing, finance, engineering, and research and development. The enterprise of interest are those corporate functions and operations necessary to manufacture current and potential future variants of a product.[4]
The term "enterprise model" is used in industry to represent differing enterprise representations, with no real standardized definition.[5] Due to the complexity of enterprise organizations, a vast number of differing enterprise modelling approaches have been pursued across industry and academia.[6] Enterprise modelling constructs can focus upon manufacturing operations and/or business operations; however, a common thread in enterprise modelling is an inclusion of assessment of information technology. For example, the use of networked computers to trigger and receive replacement orders along a material supply chain is an example of how information technology is used to coordinate manufacturing operations within an enterprise.[4]
</wiki></doc>