<doc><id>ethnopoetics</id><concept_name>ethnopoetics</concept_name><wiki>Ethnopoetics is a method of recording text versions of oral poetry or narrative performances (i.e. verbal lore) that uses poetic lines, verses, and stanzas (instead of prose paragraphs) to capture the formal, poetic performance elements which would otherwise be lost in the written texts. The goal of any ethnopoetic text is to show how the techniques of unique oral performers enhance the aesthetic value of their performances within their specific cultural contexts. Major contributors to ethnopoetic theory include Jerome Rothenberg, Dennis Tedlock, and Dell Hymes. Ethnopoetics is considered  a subfield of ethnology, anthropology, folkloristics, stylistics, linguistics, and literature and translation studies.
Jerome Rothenberg  coined the term ethnopoetics in the 1960s. According to Catherine S. Quick, Rothenberg had recognized that &#8220;most translations of Native American oral traditions . . . failed to capture the power and beauty of the oral performances on the written page,&#8221; especially when &#8220;Western poetic styles&#8221; were imposed upon these written texts (1999, 96).[1] Rothenberg&#8217;s influence has increased public awareness of the rich narrative and poetic traditions of cultures all over the world.
The development of ethnopoetics as a separate subfield of study was largely pioneered from the middle of the 20th century by anthropologists and linguists such as Dennis Tedlock and Dell Hymes. Both Tedlock and Hymes used ethnopoetic analysis to do justice to the artistic richness of Native American verbal art, and while they have disagreed on some analytic details, they agree on the fundamental issues and purposes of ethnopoetics.
On the one hand, Dennis Tedlock argues not only that pauses in oral performances indicate where poetic line breaks should occur in the written texts, which he compares to musical scores,[1] but also that words on the page should be formatted to reflect the more subtle qualities of speech used in oral performances. Tedlock explain his perspective in this way,
</wiki></doc>