<doc><id>evolutionary_robotics</id><concept_name>evolutionary robotics</concept_name><wiki>Evolutionary robotics (ER) is a methodology that uses evolutionary computation to develop controllers and/or hardware for autonomous robots. Algorithms in ER frequently operate on populations of candidate controllers, initially selected from some distribution.  This population is then repeatedly modified according to a fitness function.  In the case of genetic algorithms (or "GAs"), a common method in evolutionary computation, the population of candidate controllers is repeatedly grown according to crossover, mutation and other GA operators
and then culled according to the fitness function. The candidate controllers used in ER applications may be drawn from some subset of the set of artificial neural networks, although some applications (including SAMUEL, developed at the Naval Center for Applied Research in Artificial Intelligence) use collections of "IF THEN ELSE" rules as the constituent parts of an individual controller.  It is theoretically possible to use any set of symbolic formulations of a control law (sometimes called a policy in the machine learning community) as the space of possible candidate controllers. Artificial neural networks can also be used for robot learning outside the context of evolutionary robotics.  In particular, other forms of reinforcement learning can be used for learning robot controllers.
Developmental robotics is related to, but differs from, evolutionary robotics. ER uses populations of robots that evolve over time, whereas DevRob is interested in how the organization of a single robot's control system develops through experience, over time.
The foundation of ER was laid with work at the national research council in Rome in the 90s, but the initial idea of encoding a robot control system into a genome and have artificial evolution improve on it dates back to the late 80s.
In 1992 and 1993 three research groups, one surrounding Floreano and Mondada at the EPFL in Lausanne and a second involving Cliff, Harvey, and Husbands from COGS at the University of Sussex and a third from the University of Southern California involved M. Anthony Lewis and Andrew H Fagg reported promising results from experiments on artificial evolution of autonomous robots.[1][2] The success of this early research triggered a wave of activity in labs around the world trying to harness the potential of the approach.
</wiki></doc>