<doc><id>filled_pause</id><concept_name>filled pause</concept_name><wiki>A speech disfluency, also spelled speech dysfluency, is any of various breaks, irregularities, or non-lexical vocables which occur within the flow of otherwise fluent speech. These include "false starts", i.e. words and sentences that are cut off mid-utterance; phrases that are restarted or repeated and repeated syllables; "fillers", i.e. grunts or non-lexical utterances such as "huh", "uh", "erm", "um", "well", "so", "like", and "hmm"; and "repaired" utterances, i.e. instances of speakers correcting their own slips of the tongue or mispronunciations (before anyone else gets a chance to). "Huh" is claimed to be a universal syllable.[1]
Fillers are parts of speech which are not generally recognized as purposeful or containing formal meaning, usually expressed as pauses such as "uh", "like" and "er", but also extending to repairs ("He was wearing a black&#8212;uh, I mean a blue, a blue shirt"), and articulation problems such as stuttering.  Use is normally frowned upon in mass media such as news reports or films, but they occur regularly in everyday conversation, sometimes representing upwards of 20% of "words" in conversation.[2] Fillers can also be used as a pause for thought ("I arrived at, um&#8212;3 o'clock"), and when used in this function are called hesitation markers or planners.[3]
Research in computational linguistics has revealed a correlation between native language and patterns of disfluencies in spontaneously uttered speech.[4] Besides that research, there are other subjective accounts reported by individuals.
According to one commentator,[who?] Americans use pauses such as "um" or "em", the British say "uh" or "eh", the French use "euh", the Germans say "&#228;h" (pronounced eh or er), the Dutch use "eh", Japanese use "&#257;", "an&#333;" or "&#275;to", the Spanish say "ehhh" (also used in Hebrew), "como" (normally meaning 'like'), and Latin Americans but not the Spanish use "este" (normally meaning 'this'). Besides "er" and "uh", the Portuguese use "h&#227;" or "&#233;".
</wiki></doc>