<doc><id>formant</id><concept_name>formant</concept_name><wiki>In speech science and phonetics, a formant is the spectral shaping that results from an acoustic resonance of the human vocal tract.[1][2] However, in acoustics, the definition of a formant sometimes differs as it can be defined as a peak, or local maximum, in the spectrum.[3][4] For harmonic sounds, with this definition, the formant frequency is therefore that of the harmonic partial that is augmented by a resonance. The difference between these two definitions resides in whether "formants" characterise the production mechanisms of a sound or the produced sound itself. In practice, the frequency of a spectral peak differs from the associated resonance frequency, except when, by luck, harmonics are aligned with the resonance frequency.
A room can be said to have formants characteristic of that particular room, due to the way sound reflects from its walls and objects. Room formants of this nature reinforce themselves by emphasizing specific frequencies and absorbing others, as exploited, for example, by Alvin Lucier in his piece I Am Sitting in a Room.
From an acoustic point of view, phonetics had a serious problem with the idea that length of vocal tract changed vowels. It was unclear how they could depend on frequencies when everyone from bass to soprano can make the same vowels. There had to be some way to normalize the frequencies. Hermann suggested a solution to this problem in 1894, coining the term &#8220;formant&#8221;. A vowel, according to him, is a special acoustic phenomenon, depending on the intermittent production of a special partial, or &#8220;formant&#8221;, or &#8220;characteristique&#8221;. The frequency of the &#8220;formant&#8221; may vary a little without altering the character of the vowel. For a, for example, the &#8220;formant&#8221; may vary from 350 to 440 Hz even in the same person.[5]
Formants are distinctive frequency components of the acoustic signal produced by speech or singing. The information that humans require to distinguish between speech sounds can be represented purely quantitatively by specifying peaks in the amplitude or frequency spectrum.
Most of these formants are produced by tube and chamber resonance, but a few whistle tones derive from periodic collapse of Venturi effect low-pressure zones[citation needed]. The formant with the lowest frequency is called F1, the second F2, and the third F3. Most often the two first formants, F1 and F2, are enough to disambiguate the vowel. The relationship between the perceived vowel quality and the first two formant frequencies can be appreciated by listening to "artificial vowels" that are generated by passing a click train (to simulate the glottal pulse train) through a pair of bandpass filters (to simulate vocal tract resonances).
</wiki></doc>