<doc><id>fourier_transform</id><concept_name>fourier transform</concept_name><wiki>The Fourier transform (FT) decomposes a function (often a function of the time, or a signal) into its constituent frequencies. A special case is the expression of a musical chord in terms of the volumes and frequencies of its constituent notes. The term Fourier transform refers to both the frequency domain representation and the mathematical operation that associates the frequency domain representation to a function of time. The Fourier transform of a function of time is itself a complex-valued function of frequency, whose magnitude (modulus) represents the amount of that frequency present in the original function, and whose argument is the phase offset of the basic sinusoid in that frequency. The Fourier transform is not limited to functions of time, but the domain of the original function is commonly referred to as the time domain.  There is also an inverse Fourier transform that mathematically synthesizes the original function from its frequency domain representation.
A sinusoidal curve, with peak amplitude (1), peak-to-peak (2), RMS (3), and wave period (4).
Illustration of phase shift &#952;.
Linear operations performed in one domain (time or frequency) have corresponding operations in the other domain, which are sometimes easier to perform. The operation of differentiation in the time domain corresponds to multiplication by the frequency,[remark 1] so some differential equations are easier to analyze in the frequency domain. Also, convolution in the time domain corresponds to ordinary multiplication in the frequency domain (see Convolution theorem). After performing the desired operations, transformation of the result can be made back to the time domain. Harmonic analysis is the systematic study of the relationship between the frequency and time domains, including the kinds of functions or operations that are "simpler" in one or the other, and has deep connections to many areas of modern mathematics.
</wiki></doc>