<doc><id>friction_stir_welding</id><concept_name>friction stir welding</concept_name><wiki>Friction stir welding (FSW) is a solid-state joining process that uses a non-consumable tool to join two facing workpieces without melting the workpiece material.[1][2] Heat is generated by friction between the rotating tool and the workpiece material, which leads to a softened region near the FSW tool. While the tool is traversed along the joint line, it mechanically intermixes the two pieces of metal, and forges the hot and softened metal by the mechanical pressure, which is applied by the tool, much like joining clay, or dough.[2] It was primarily used on wrought or extruded aluminium and particularly for structures which need very high weld strength. FSW is capable of joining aluminium alloys, copper alloys, titanium alloys, mild steel, stainless steel and magnesium alloys. More recently, it was successfully used in welding of polymers.[3] In addition, joining of dissimilar metals such as aluminium to magnesium alloys has been recently achieved by FSW.[4] Application of FSW can be  found in modern shipbuilding, trains, and aerospace applications.[5][6][7][8][9][10]
It was invented and experimentally proven at The Welding Institute (TWI) in the UK in December 1991. TWI held patents on the process, the first being the most descriptive.[11]
A rotating cylindrical tool with a profiled probe is fed into a butt joint between two clamped workpieces, until the shoulder, which has a larger diameter than the pin, touches the surface of the workpieces. The probe is slightly shorter than the weld depth required, with the tool shoulder riding atop the work surface.[12] After a short dwell time, the tool is moved forward along the joint line at the pre-set welding speed.[13]
Frictional heat is generated between the wear-resistant tool and the work pieces. This heat, along with that generated by the mechanical mixing process and the adiabatic heat within the material, cause the stirred materials to soften without melting. As the tool is moved forward, a special profile on the probe forces plasticised material from the leading face to the rear, where the high forces assist in a forged consolidation of the weld.
</wiki></doc>