<doc><id>fused_filament_fabrication</id><concept_name>fused filament fabrication</concept_name><wiki>Fused filament fabrication (FFF), also known under the trademarked term fused deposition modeling (FDM), sometimes also called filament freeform fabrication, is a 3D printing process that uses a continuous filament of a thermoplastic material.[1] Filament is fed from a large coil through a moving, heated printer extruder head, and is deposited on the growing work. The print head is moved under computer control to define the printed shape. Usually the head moves in two dimensions to deposit one horizontal plane, or layer, at a time; the work or the print head is then moved vertically by a small amount to begin a new layer. The speed of the extruder head may also be controlled to stop and start deposition and form an interrupted plane without stringing or dribbling between sections. "Fused filament fabrication" was coined by the members of the RepRap project to give a phrase that would be legally unconstrained in its use, given trademarks covering "fused deposition modeling".[2]
Fused filament printing is now the most popular process (by number of machines) for hobbyist-grade 3D printing.[3] Other techniques such as photopolymerisation and powder sintering may offer better results, but they are much more costly.
The 3D printer head or 3D printer extruder is a part in material extrusion additive manufacturing responsible for raw material melting and forming it into a continuous profile. A wide variety of filament materials are extruded, including thermoplastics such as acrylonitrile butadiene styrene (ABS)[4], polylactic acid (PLA), high-impact polystyrene (HIPS), thermoplastic polyurethane (TPU) and aliphatic polyamides (nylon).[5]
Fused deposition modeling was developed by S. Scott Crump, co-founder of Stratasys, in 1988.[6][7] With the 2009 expiration of the patent on this technology,[8] people could use this type of printing without paying Stratasys for the right to do so, opening up commercial, DIY, and open-source (RepRap) 3D printer applications. This has led to a two-orders-of-magnitude price drop since this technology's creation.[9] Stratasys still owns the trademark on the term "Fused deposition modeling".[10][11]
</wiki></doc>