<doc><id>gender_differences</id><concept_name>gender differences</concept_name><wiki>Sex differences in humans have been studied in a variety of fields. In humans, biological sex consists of five factors present at birth: the presence or absence of the SRY gene (an intronless sex-determining gene on the Y chromosome), the type of gonads, the sex hormones, the internal reproductive anatomy (such as the uterus), and the external genitalia.[1] Sex determination occurs  solely by the presence or absence of a Y chromosome. Phenotypic sex refers to an individual's sex as determined by their internal and external genitalia, expression of secondary sex characteristics, and behavior.[2]
The sex of the individual can be defined in different ways, giving rise to different conceptual frameworks about what determines sex.[3] Sex differences generally refer to traits that are sexually dimorphic. A subset of such differences is hypothesized to be the product of the evolutionary process of sexual selection.[4][5]
Sex differences in medicine include sex-specific diseases, which are diseases that occur only in people of one sex; and sex-related diseases, which are diseases that are more usual to one sex, or which manifest differently in each sex. For example, certain autoimmune diseases may occur predominantly in one sex, for unknown reasons. 90% of primary biliary cirrhosis cases are women, whereas primary sclerosing cholangitis is more common in men. Gender-based medicine, also called "gender medicine", is the field of medicine that studies the biological and physiological differences between the human sexes and how that affects differences in disease. Traditionally, medical research has mostly been conducted using the male body as the basis for clinical studies. Similar findings are also reported in the sport medicine literature where males typically account for &gt;60% of the individuals studied.[6] The findings of these studies have often been applied across the sexes and healthcare providers have assumed a uniform approach in treating both male and female patients. More recently, medical research has started to understand the importance of taking the sex into account as the symptoms and responses to medical treatment may be very different between sexes.[7]
Neither concept should be confused with sexually transmitted diseases, which are diseases that have a significant probability of transmission through sexual contact.
</wiki></doc>