<doc><id>homophony</id><concept_name>homophony</concept_name><wiki>In music, homophony (/h&#601;&#712;m&#594;f&#601;ni, ho&#650;-, -&#712;m&#594;fni/;[1][2] Greek: &#8001;&#956;&#972;&#966;&#969;&#957;&#959;&#962;, hom&#243;ph&#333;nos, from &#8001;&#956;&#972;&#962;, hom&#243;s, "same" and &#966;&#969;&#957;&#942;, ph&#333;n&#275;, "sound, tone") is a texture in which a primary part is supported by one or more additional strands that flesh out the harmony and often provide rhythmic contrast.[3] This differentiation of roles contrasts with equal-voice polyphony (in which similar lines move with rhythmic and melodic independence to form an even texture) and monophony (in which all parts move in unison or octaves).[4] Historically, homophony and its differentiated roles for parts emerged in tandem with tonality, which gave distinct harmonic functions to the soprano, bass and inner voices.
A homophonic texture may be homorhythmic,[5] which means that all parts have the same rhythm.[6] Chorale texture is another variant of homophony. The most common type of homophony is melody-dominated homophony, in which one voice, often the highest, plays a distinct melody, and the accompanying voices work together to articulate an underlying harmony.[7]
Initially, in Ancient Greece, homophony indicated music in which a single melody is performed by two or more voices in unison or octaves, i.e. monophony with multiple voices. Homophony as a term first appeared in English with Charles Burney in 1776, emphasizing the concord of harmonized melody.[8]
Homophony first appeared as one of the predominant textures in Western classical music during the Baroque period in the early 17th century, when composers began to commonly compose with vertical harmony in mind, the homophonic basso continuo becoming a definitive feature of the style.[7] The choral arrangement of four voices (soprano, alto, tenor, and bass) has since become common in Western classical music.[7] Homophony began by appearing in sacred music, replacing polyphony and monophony as the dominant form, but spread to secular music, for which it is one of the standard forms today.
</wiki></doc>