<doc><id>human_genome_project</id><concept_name>human genome project</concept_name><wiki>The  Human Genome Project (HGP) was an international scientific research project with the goal of determining the  base pairs that make up human DNA, and of identifying and mapping all of the  genes of the human genome from both a physical and  a functional standpoint.[1] It remains the world's largest collaborative biological project.[2] After the idea was picked up in 1984 by the US government when the planning started, the project formally launched in 1990 and was declared complete on April 14, 2003.[3] Funding came from the US government through the National Institutes of Health (NIH) as well as numerous other groups from around the world. A parallel project was conducted outside the government by the Celera Corporation, or Celera Genomics, which was formally launched in 1998. Most of the government-sponsored sequencing was performed in twenty universities and research centers in the United States, the United Kingdom, Japan, France, Germany and China.[4]
The Human Genome Project originally aimed to map the nucleotides contained in a human haploid reference genome (more than three billion).  The "genome" of any given individual is unique; mapping the "human genome" involved sequencing a small number of individuals and then assembling these together to get a complete sequence for each chromosome. Therefore, the finished human genome is a mosaic, not representing any one individual.
The Human Genome Project was a 13-year-long, publicly funded project initiated in 1990 with the objective of determining the DNA sequence of the entire euchromatic human genome within 15 years.[5] In May 1985, Robert Sinsheimer organized a workshop at the University of California, Santa Cruz, to discuss sequencing the human genome,[6] but for a number of reasons the NIH was uninterested in pursuing the proposal. The following March, the Santa Fe Workshop was organized by Charles DeLisi and David Smith of the Department of Energy's Office of Health and Environmental Research (OHER).[7]  At the same time Renato Dulbecco proposed whole genome sequencing in an essay in Science.[8]  James Watson followed two months later with a workshop held at the Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory.
The fact that the Santa Fe workshop was motivated and supported by a Federal Agency opened a path, albeit a difficult and tortuous one,[9] for converting the idea into public policy in the United States.  In a memo to the Assistant Secretary for Energy Research (Alvin Trivelpiece), Charles DeLisi, who was then Director of the OHER, outlined a broad plan for the project.[10]  This started a long and complex chain of events which led to approved reprogramming of funds that enabled the OHER to launch the Project in 1986, and to recommend the first line item for the HGP, which was in President Reagan's 1988 budget submission,[9] and ultimately approved by the Congress.  Of particular importance in Congressional approval was the advocacy of Senator Peter Domenici, whom DeLisi had befriended.[11]  Domenici chaired the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, as well as the Budget Committee, both of which were key in the DOE budget process.  Congress added a comparable amount to the NIH budget, thereby beginning official funding by both agencies.
</wiki></doc>