<doc><id>illiac</id><concept_name>illiac</concept_name><wiki>ILLIAC (Illinois Automatic Computer) was a series of supercomputers built at a variety of locations, some at the University of Illinois at Urbana&#8211;Champaign. In all, five computers were built in this series between 1951 and 1974. Some more modern projects also use the name.
The architecture for the first two UIUC computers was taken from a technical report from a committee at the Institute for Advanced Study (IAS) at Princeton, First Draft of a Report on the EDVAC (1945), edited by John von Neumann (but with ideas from Eckert, Mauchley, and many others.)  The designs in this report were not tested at Princeton until a later machine, JOHNNIAC, was completed in 1953.  However, the technical report was a major influence on computing in the 1950s, and was used as a blueprint for many other computers, including two at the University of Illinois, which were both completed before Princeton finished Johnniac.  The University of Illinois was the only institution to build two instances of the IAS machine.  In fairness, several of the other universities, including Princeton, invented new technology (new types of memory or I/O devices) during the construction of their computers, which delayed those projects.  For ILLIAC I, II, and IV, students associated with IAS at Princeton (Abraham H. Taub, Donald B. Gillies, Daniel Slotnick) played a key role in the computer design(s).[1]
ORDVAC was the first of two computers built under contract at the University of Illinois. ORDVAC was completed the spring of 1951 and checked out in the summer. In the fall it was delivered to the US Army's Aberdeen Proving Grounds and was checked out in roughly one week.  As part of the contract, funds were provided to the University of Illinois to build a second identical computer known as ILLIAC I.
ILLIAC I was built at the University of Illinois based on the same design as the ORDVAC.  It was the first von Neumann architecture computer built and owned by an American university.  It was put into service on September 22, 1952.
</wiki></doc>