<doc><id>image_matching</id><concept_name>image matching</concept_name><wiki>Image registration is the process of transforming different sets of data into one coordinate system. Data may be multiple photographs, data from different sensors, times, depths, or viewpoints.[1] It is used in computer vision, medical imaging,[2] military automatic target recognition, and compiling and analyzing images and data from satellites. Registration is necessary in order to be able to compare or integrate the data obtained from these different measurements.
Image registration or image alignment algorithms can be classified into intensity-based and feature-based.[3] One of the images is referred to as the moving or source and the others  are referred to as the target, fixed or sensed images. Image registration involves spatially transforming the source/moving image(s) to align with the target image. The reference frame in the target image is stationary, while the other datasets are transformed to match to the target.[3] Intensity-based methods compare intensity patterns in images via correlation metrics, while feature-based methods find correspondence between image features such as points, lines, and contours.[3] Intensity-based methods register entire images or sub-images. If sub-images are registered, centers of corresponding sub images are treated as corresponding feature points. Feature-based methods establish a correspondence between a number of especially distinct points in images. Knowing the correspondence between a number of points in images, a geometrical transformation is then determined to map the target image to the reference images, thereby establishing point-by-point correspondence between the reference and target images.[3] Methods combining intensity-based and feature-based information have also been developed.[4]
Image registration algorithms can also be classified according to the transformation models they use to relate the target image space to the reference image space. The first broad category of transformation models includes linear transformations, which include rotation, scaling, translation, and other affine transforms.[5] Linear transformations are global in nature, thus, they cannot model local geometric differences between images.[3]
The second category of transformations allow 'elastic' or 'nonrigid' transformations. These transformations are capable of locally warping the target image to align with the reference image.  Nonrigid transformations include radial basis functions (thin-plate or surface splines, multiquadrics, and compactly-supported transformations[3]), physical continuum models (viscous fluids), and large deformation models (diffeomorphisms).
</wiki></doc>