<doc><id>incentive_plan</id><concept_name>incentive plan</concept_name><wiki>An incentive program is a formal scheme used to promote or encourage specific actions or behavior by a specific group of people during a defined period of time. Incentive programs are particularly used in business management to motivate employees and in sales to attract and retain customers. Scientific literature also refers to this concept as pay for performance.[1]
Employee incentive programs are programs used to increase overall employee performance. While employees tend to approve of incentive programs, only 27% of companies have such programs in place.[2][3] Employee programs are often used to reduce turnover, boost morale and loyalty, improve employee wellness and safety, increase retention, and drive daily employee performance.[4]
Consumer incentive programs are programs targeting the customers of an organization. Increases in a company's customer retention rate as low as 5% tend to increase profits by 25%-125%.[5][6][7] Consumer programs are becoming more widely used as more companies realize that existing customers cost less to reach, cost less to sell, are less vulnerable to attacks from the competition, and buy more over the long term.
Points-based incentive programs are a type of program where participants collect and redeem points for rewards. Points programs may be used to incentivize both employees or consumers.[8] Depending on the program type and the organizational objectives, points can be awarded on a number of criteria including positive employee behavior, the demonstration of organizational values, repeat customer purchases, the sale of new products, increased overall sales, or even the use of proper safety precautions. In addition to point awarding, the levels at which points can be redeemed can be customized by the organization. Points programs are a way for organizations to motivate behavior over time while improving the organizations&#8217; overall performance. Loyalty programs are a frequently used points-based incentive program in which customers that exhibit a certain behavior are rewarded with points, reinforcing that behavior.
</wiki></doc>