<doc><id>indoor_positioning_system</id><concept_name>indoor positioning system</concept_name><wiki>An indoor positioning system (IPS) is a network of devices used to locate people or objects where GPS and other satellite technologies lack precision or fail entirely, such as inside multistory buildings, airports, alleys, parking garages, and underground locations. A large variety of techniques and devices are used to provide indoor positioning ranging from reconfigured devices already deployed such as smartphones, WiFi and Bluetooth antennas, digital cameras, and clocks; to purpose built installations with relays and beacons strategically placed throughout a defined space. IPS has broad applications in commercial, military, retail, and inventory tracking industries. There are several commercial systems on the market, but no standards for an IPS system. Instead each installation is tailored to spatial dimensions, building materials, accuracy needs, and budget constraints. Lights, radio waves, magnetic fields, acoustic signals, and behavioral analytics are all used in IPS networks.[1][2] IPS can achieve position accuracy of 2cm[3], which is on par with RTK enabled GNSS receivers that can achieve 2cm accuracy outdoors.[4]
Indoor positioning systems use different technologies, including distance measurement to nearby anchor nodes (nodes with known fixed positions, e.g. WiFi / LiFi access points, Bluetooth beacons or Ultra-Wideband beacons, such as those used in the VBOX Indoor Positioning System, which offers 2cm accuracy), magnetic positioning, dead reckoning.[5] They either actively locate mobile devices and tags or provide ambient location or environmental context for devices to get sensed.[6]
The localized nature of an IPS has resulted in design fragmentation, with systems making use of various optical,[7] radio,[8][9][10][11][12] or even acoustic[13][14]
technologies.
For smoothing to compensate for stochastic (unpredictable) errors there must be a sound method for reducing the error budget significantly. The system might include information from other systems to cope for physical ambiguity and to enable error compensation.
</wiki></doc>