<doc><id>influencer</id><concept_name>influencer</concept_name><wiki>An Internet celebrity (also known as a social media influencer) is a celebrity who has acquired or developed their fame and notability through the Internet. The rise of social media has helped people increase their outreach to a global audience. Internet celebrities may be recruited by companies for influencer marketing to advertise products to their fans and followers on their platforms. Internet celebrities often function as lifestyle gurus who promote a particular lifestyle or attitude. In this role, they may be crucial influencers or multipliers for trends in genres including fashion, technology, video games, politics, and entertainment.[1]
In 1991 with the wide public availability of the Internet and the World Wide Web, numerous websites were created to serve as forums for topics of shared interest. In some topic areas, this allowed users to get advice and help from experienced users in that field, the type of information that was typically lacking in mainstream print media or corporate websites.[2] Dedicated social media sites arose from these, where users could create profiles and make friends with other users; the first such social media site was SixDegrees.com in 1997.[3] Similarly, websites that supported blogging arose around 1997, and gave a means for users to post long-form articles and stories of their own.[2] Since then, forums, social media, and blogging have become a central part of communication, social life, businesses, and news publishing. Popular social media platforms include Facebook, Instagram, Tik Tok, Twitter, WeChat, WhatsApp, and YouTube.[4]
A 2001 study from Rutgers University had found that people were using "internet forums as influential sources of consumer information". This study suggested that consumers were using Internet forums and social media to make purchasing decisions over traditional advertising and print sources.[5] The early 2000s saw corporate attempts to use the Internet for influencing with some companies engaged with forums for promotion or to offer bloggers free products in exchange for positive reviews. Some of these practices were considered unethical.[2] The Blogstar Network, launched in 2004 by Ted Murphy of MindComet, invited bloggers to a email list to receive paid offers from corporations based on the type of posts they made, such as being paid a few dollars for reviewing a fast-food meal in their blog. Blogstar is considered the first influencer marketing network.[2] Murphy followed Blogstar with PayPerPost, launched in 2006, which paid influential posters at the larger forum and social media sides for each post about a corporate product, with payment rates based on the influencer status of the individual.[2] PayPerPost, while popular and creating a number of other similar programs from other companies, received a great deal of criticism as these influencers were not required to disclose their involvement with PayPerPost as traditional journalism would have,[6] and made the public aware that there was a drive by corporate interests to influence what some people were posting to these sites.[2] Despite concerns, influencing marketing networks continued to grow through the rest of the 2000s and into the 2010s. By 2019, the influencer marketing network sector was estimated as a multibillion dollar industry.[2]
Self-branding, also known as personal branding, describes the development of a public image for commercial gain or social or cultural capital.[7] The rise of social media has been exploited by individuals seeking personal fame and product sales. Platforms such as Instagram, Snapchat, VSCO, and YouTube are the most common social media outlets on which online influencers attempt to build a following. Fame can be attained through different avenues and media forms, including art, humor, modeling, and podcasts. Marketing experts have concluded that "[people no longer] need to be familiar with complex coding languages or other technicalities to build websites because virtually anyone can upload text, pictures, and video instantly to a site from a personal computer or phone. With technological barriers crumbling and its near ubiquity, the web has become the perfect platform for personal branding".[8]
</wiki></doc>