<doc><id>inpainting</id><concept_name>inpainting</concept_name><wiki>Inpainting is a process of restorative conservation where damaged, deteriorating, or missing parts of an artwork are reconstructed, ultimately with the goal of presenting the artwork as it was originally created. This process can be applied to both physical and digital artistic mediums such as oil or acrylic paintings, chemical photographic prints, 3-dimensional sculptures, or digital images and video. In order to preserve the integrity of the original artwork, any treatment applied to physical or digital work should be reversible to the best of the conservators' ability so as to not permanently impact the original piece. Prior to any restoration work, conservators shall proceed under the code of ethics guidelines.[1]
With its roots in physical artwork, such as painting and sculpture, traditional inpainting is performed by a trained art conservator who has carefully studied the artwork to determine the mediums and techniques used in the piece, potential risks of restoration, and ethical appropriateness of treatment. Before beginning any work, the conservator should present a treatment proposal to the owner of the object, whether an individual or institution, to discuss the goals of preserving and presenting the piece for future generations. Depending on the integrity of the object and careful research, the various techniques and mediums used for inpainting are decided.  
Since the mid-1990s, the process of inpainting has evolved to include digital media. More commonly known as image or video interpolation, a form of estimation, digital inpainting includes the use of computer software that relies on sophisticated algorithms to replace lost or corrupted parts of the image data. There are currently many programs in use that are able to reconstruct missing or damaged areas of digital photographs and videos. Most widely known for use with digital images is Adobe Photoshop. Since the digital files are able to be duplicated, any restorative alterations should be made to the duplicate file, while maintaining the original files in an archive.

</wiki></doc>