<doc><id>micromarketing</id><concept_name>micromarketing</concept_name><wiki>
Micromarketing was first referred to in the UK marketing press in November 1988 in respect of the application of geodemographics to consumer marketing.[1] The subject of micromarketing was developed further in an article in February 1990, which emphasised understanding markets at the local level, and also the personalisation of messages to individual consumers in the context direct marketing.[2] Micromarketing has come to refer to marketing strategies which are variously customised to either local markets, to different market segments, or to the individual customer.
Micromarketing is a marketing strategy in which marketing and/or advertising efforts are focused on a small group of tightly targeted consumers. For example, markets can be grouped into narrow clusters based on commitment to a product class or readiness to purchase a given brand. The approach requires a company to define very narrow market segments, and tailor offers or campaigns for that segment. Although, the approach can be more expensive due to customization and difficulties attaining scale economies, advancements in technology have facilitated the delivery of highly customised products to small groups or even individual customers. Nike ID [3] and Shoes of Prey [4] are often cited as practical examples of this approach. It should be evident that micromarketing is closely related to the concept of mass-customisation.
In some of the literature, different labels are used to describe micromarketing. In a seminal article, Kara and Karnak (1997), referred to finer segmentation (FS)  as "the final advancement in market segmentation as it combines the use of differentiated marketing and niche marketing to reach the smallest groups in the marketplace".[5] Richard Tedlow (1993) thought that he detected evidence of what he called hyper-segmentation which he saw as a logical extension of the market segmentation era.[6] These approaches combine multiple segmentation variables in ways that have been elusive within conventional approaches to segmentation.
</wiki></doc>