<doc><id>motion_analysis</id><concept_name>motion analysis</concept_name><wiki>Motion analysis is used in computer vision, image processing, high-speed photography and machine vision that studies methods and applications in which two or more consecutive images from an image sequences, e.g., produced by a video camera or high-speed camera, are processed to produce information based on the apparent motion in the images.  In some applications, the camera is fixed relative to the scene and objects are moving around in the scene, in some applications the scene is more or less fixed and the camera is moving, and in some cases both the camera and the scene are moving.
The motion analysis processing can in the simplest case be to detect motion, i.e., find the points in the image where something is moving.  More complex types of processing can be to track a specific object in the image over time, to group points that belong to the same rigid object that is moving in the scene, or to determine the magnitude and direction of the motion of every point in the image.  The information that is produced is often related to a specific image in the sequence, corresponding to a specific time-point, but then depends also on the neighboring images.  This means that motion analysis can produce time-dependent information about motion.
Applications of motion analysis can be found in rather diverse areas, such as surveillance, medicine, film industry, automotive crash safety,[1] ballistic firearm studies,[2] biological science,[3] flame propagation,[4]  and navigation of autonomous vehicles to name a few examples.
A video camera can be seen as an approximation of a pinhole camera, which means that each point in the image is illuminated by some (normally one) point in the scene in front of the camera, usually by means of light that the scene point reflects from a light source.  Each visible point in the scene is projected along a straight line that passes through the camera aperture and intersects the image plane.  This means that at a specific point in time, each point in the image refers to a specific point in the scene.  This scene point has a position relative to the camera, and if this relative position changes, it corresponds to a relative motion in 3D.  It is a relative motion since it does not matter if it is the scene point, or the camera, or both, that are moving.  It is only when there is a change in the relative position that the camera is able to detect that some motion has happened.  By projecting the relative 3D motion of all visible points back into the image, the result is the motion field, describing the apparent motion of each image point in terms of a magnitude and direction of velocity of that point in the image plane.  A consequence of this observation is that if the relative 3D motion of some scene points are along their projection lines, the corresponding apparent motion is zero.
</wiki></doc>