<doc><id>netbios</id><concept_name>netbios</concept_name><wiki>NetBIOS (/&#712;n&#603;tba&#618;&#594;s/) is an acronym for Network Basic Input/Output System. It provides services related to the session layer of the OSI model allowing applications on separate computers to communicate over a local area network. As strictly an API, NetBIOS is not a networking protocol. Older operating systems[clarification needed] ran NetBIOS over IEEE 802.2 and IPX/SPX using the NetBIOS Frames (NBF) and NetBIOS over IPX/SPX (NBX) protocols, respectively. In modern networks, NetBIOS normally runs over TCP/IP via the NetBIOS over TCP/IP (NBT) protocol. This results in each computer in the network having both an IP address and a NetBIOS name corresponding to a (possibly different) host name.
NetBIOS is a non-routable OSI Session Layer 5 Protocol and a service that allows applications on computers to communicate with one another over a local area network (LAN). NetBIOS was developed in 1983 by Sytek Inc. as an API for software communication over IBM PC Network LAN technology.[1] On PC-Network, as an API alone, NetBIOS relied on proprietary Sytek networking protocols for communication over the wire.[citation needed] Despite supporting a maximum of 80 PCs in a LAN, NetBIOS became an industry standard.[1]
In 1985, IBM went forward with the token ring network scheme and a NetBIOS emulator was produced to allow NetBIOS-aware applications from the PC-Network era to work over this new design. This emulator, named NetBIOS Extended User Interface (NetBEUI), expanded the base NetBIOS API with, among other things, the ability to deal with the greater node capacity of token ring. A new networking protocol, NBF, was simultaneously produced to allow NetBEUI (NetBIOS) to provide its services over token ring &#8211; specifically, at the IEEE 802.2 Logical Link Control layer.
In 1985, Microsoft created a NetBIOS implementation for its MS-Net networking technology. As in the case of IBM's token ring, the services of Microsoft's NetBIOS implementation were provided over the IEEE 802.2 Logical Link Control layer by the NBF protocol.[citation needed] Until Microsoft adopted Domain Name System (DNS) resolution of hostnames Microsoft operating systems used NetBIOS to resolve names in Windows client-server networks.[1]
</wiki></doc>