<doc><id>neurobiotics</id><concept_name>neurobiotics</concept_name><wiki>Neurobiotics is a loose term without strict definition referring to the study of the nervous system in conjunction with technology.[1] Of particular importance in the field of neurobiotics is the brain and its direct interaction with computer systems, as well as methods of externally simulating the brain. Also, a large branch of neurobiotics commonly called neurosimulation, concerns the attempt to produce strong AI by combining neural networks and the basics of psychology.[2]
The term neurobiotics has no documented first use and several sources claim to have 'coined' the term.[3][4] But most likely the term has been invented countless times due to both its Latinate nature and the way the roots have been used in other terms. Neur- meaning nerve and biotic meaning of or related to life.[5] The technological overtones behind neurobiotics probably simply come from the fact that the term sounds modern, most easily explained by memetic theories.
The term is often used only to refer to individual projects or companies, and most who use it are unaware that the term is commonly used.[4] There is no official definition for the term, and since it is frequently reinvented by people, it can refer to a wide range of ideas, concepts, studies and goals. The most definitive source for the term is probably from the private research company NDT Neurobiotics with branches in the University of Colorado at Boulder and Carnegie Mellon. NDT Neurobiotics' primary focus is the creation of strong AI, with a stated company goal of passing the Turing test. They also invest significantly into studies that they hope will lead to direct neural interface.[6]
The term neurobiotics has been used with 'magical' overtones, referring to areas such as mind reading and animating inanimate objects. There are also connection concerning the idea that time is relative (in the non-Einsteinian meaning) and that life (and nerves) can control time to an extent. These uses are nonstandard and probably have no connection to the scientific uses.
</wiki></doc>