<doc><id>no-cloning_theorem</id><concept_name>no-cloning theorem</concept_name><wiki>In physics, the no-cloning theorem states that it is impossible to create an identical copy of an arbitrary unknown quantum state. This no-go theorem of quantum mechanics was articulated by James Park in proving the impossibility of a simple perfect non-disturbing measurement scheme,[1] in 1970 and rediscovered by Wootters and Zurek[2] and by Dieks[3] in 1982. It has profound implications in quantum computing and related fields.  The state of one system can be entangled with the state of another system. For instance, one can use the controlled NOT gate and the Walsh&#8211;Hadamard gate to entangle two qubits. This is not cloning. No well-defined state can be attributed to a subsystem of an entangled state.  Cloning is a process, the result of which is a separable state with identical factors.
The no-cloning theorem is normally stated and proven for pure states; the no-broadcast theorem generalizes this result to mixed states.
The no-cloning theorem has a time-reversed dual, the no-deleting theorem.  Together, these underpin the interpretation of quantum mechanics in terms of category theory, and, in particular, as a dagger compact category.[4][5] This formulation, known as categorical quantum mechanics, allows, in turn, a connection to be made from quantum mechanics to linear logic as the logic of quantum information theory (in the same sense that classical logic arises from Cartesian closed categories).
According to Asher Peres[6] and David Kaiser,[7] the publication of the 1982 proof of the no-cloning theorem by
Wootters and Zurek[2] and by Dieks[3] was prompted by a proposal of Nick Herbert[8] for a superluminal communication device using quantum entanglement. However, Ortigoso[9] pointed out in 2018 that a complete proof along with an interpretation in terms of the lack of simple nondisturbing measurements in quantum mechanics was already delivered by Park in 1970.[1]
</wiki></doc>