<doc><id>number</id><concept_name>number</concept_name><wiki>
A number is a mathematical object used to count, measure, and label. The original examples are the natural numbers 1, 2, 3, 4, and so forth.[1] For being manipulated, individual numbers need to be represented by symbols, called numerals; for example, "5" is a numeral that represents the number five. As only a small number of symbols can be memorized, basic numerals are commonly organized in a numeral system, which is an organized way to represent any number. The most common numeral system is the Hindu&#8211;Arabic numeral system, which allows representing any number by a combination of ten basic numerals called digits.[2][3] In addition to their use in counting and measuring, numerals are often used for labels (as with telephone numbers), for ordering (as with serial numbers), and for codes (as with ISBNs). In common usage, a numeral is not clearly distinguished from the number that it represents.
In mathematics, the notion of number has been extended over the centuries to include 0,[4] negative numbers,[5] rational numbers such as 1/2 and &#8722;2/3, real numbers[6] such as &#8730;2 and &#960;, and complex numbers,[7] which extend the real numbers with a square root of &#8722;1 (and its combinations with real numbers by addition and multiplication).[5] Calculations with numbers are done with arithmetical operations, the most familiar being addition, subtraction, multiplication, division, and exponentiation. Their study or usage is called arithmetic. The same term may also refer to number theory, the study of the properties of numbers.
Besides their practical uses, numbers have cultural significance throughout the world.[8][9] For example, in Western society, the number 13 is regarded as unlucky, and "a million" may signify "a lot."[8] Though it is now regarded as pseudoscience, belief in a mystical significance of numbers, known as numerology, permeated ancient and medieval thought.[10] Numerology heavily influenced the development of Greek mathematics, stimulating the investigation of many problems in number theory which are still of interest today.[10]
</wiki></doc>