<doc><id>nursing_informatics</id><concept_name>nursing informatics</concept_name><wiki>Health informatics (also called health care informatics, healthcare informatics, medical informatics, nursing informatics,  clinical informatics, or biomedical informatics) is information engineering applied to the field of health care, essentially the management and use of patient health care information. It is a multidisciplinary field[1] that uses health information technology (HIT) to improve health care via any combination of higher quality, higher efficiency (spurring lower cost and thus greater availability), and new opportunities. The disciplines involved include information science, computer science, social science, behavioral science, management science, and others. The United States National Library of Medicine (NLM) defines health informatics as "the interdisciplinary study of the design, development, adoption and application of IT-based innovations in health care services delivery, management and planning".[2] It deals with the resources, devices, and methods required to optimize the acquisition, storage, retrieval, and use of information in health and bio-medicine. Health informatics tools include computers, clinical guidelines, formal medical terminologies, and information and communication systems, among others.[3][4] It is applied to the areas of nursing, clinical medicine, dentistry, pharmacy, public health, occupational therapy, physical therapy, biomedical research, and alternative medicine,[5][unreliable medical source?] all of which are designed to improve the overall of effectiveness of patient care delivery by ensuring that the data generated is of a high quality.[6]
The international standards on the subject are covered by ICS 35.240.80[7] in which ISO 27799:2008 is one of the core components.[8]
Health care informatics includes sub-fields of clinical informatics, such as pathology informatics, clinical research informatics (see section below), imaging informatics, public health informatics, community health informatics, home health informatics, nursing informatics, medical informatics, consumer health informatics, clinical bioinformatics, and informatics for education and research in health and medicine, pharmacy informatics.[9][10][11][12][13][14][excessive citations]
Clinical informatics is concerned with the use of information in health care by and for clinicians.[15][16]
</wiki></doc>