<doc><id>perspective_projection</id><concept_name>perspective projection</concept_name><wiki>
Perspective (from Latin: perspicere 'to see through') Linear or Point projection perspective is one of two types of Graphical projection perspective in the graphic arts (The other type is Parallel projection). Linear perspective is an approximate representation, generally on a flat surface (such as paper), of an image as it is seen by the eye. The most characteristic features of Linear perspective are that objects appear smaller as their distance from the observer increases; and that they are subject to foreshortening, meaning that an object's dimensions along the line of sight appear shorter than its dimensions across the line of sight. Also all objects will recede to points in the distance, usually along the horizon line, but also above and below the horizon line depending on view used.
Italian Renaissance painters and architects including Filippo Brunelleschi, Masaccio, Paolo Uccello, Piero della Francesca and Luca Pacioli studied linear perspective, wrote treatises on it, and incorporated it into their artworks, thus contributing to the mathematics of art.
Perspective works by representing the light that passes from a scene through an imaginary rectangle (realized as the plane of the painting), to the viewer's eye, as if a viewer were looking through a window and painting what is seen directly onto the windowpane. If viewed from the same spot as the windowpane was painted, the painted image would be identical to what was seen through the unpainted window. Each painted object in the scene is thus a flat, scaled down version of the object on the other side of the window.[4] Because each portion of the painted object lies on the straight line from the viewer's eye to the equivalent portion of the real object it represents, the viewer sees no difference (sans depth perception) between the painted scene on the windowpane and the view of the real scene.
All perspective drawings assume the viewer is a certain distance away from the drawing. Objects are scaled relative to that viewer. An object is often not scaled evenly: a circle often appears as an ellipse and a square can appear as a trapezoid.  This distortion is referred to as foreshortening.
</wiki></doc>