<doc><id>phatic_communion</id><concept_name>phatic communion</concept_name><wiki>In linguistics, a phatic expression /&#712;f&#230;t&#618;k/ is communication which serves a social function, such as social pleasantries that don't seek or offer information of intrinsic value but can signal willingness to observe conventional local expectations for politeness.[1] Phatic expressions are a socio-pragmatic function and are used in everyday conversational exchange typically expressed in situational instances that call for social cues.[2] In speech communication the term means "small talk" (conversation for its own sake) and has also been called "grooming talking."[3]
For example, greetings such as "hello", "how are you?" (in many contexts), and "good afternoon" are all phatic expressions.[4] In phatic expressions, speech acts are not communicative, since no content is communicated.  According to anthropologist Bronis&#322;aw Malinowski, apparently "purposeless" speech acts&#8212;polite small talk, like "how are you?" or "have a nice day"&#8212;even though their content may be trivial or irrelevant to the situation, perform the important function of establishing, maintaining, and managing bonds of sociality between participants.[5]
In Roman Jakobson's work, the 'phatic' function of language concerns the channel of communication; for instance, when one says "I can't hear you, you're breaking up" in the middle of a cell-phone conversation. This usage appears in research on online communities and micro-blogging.[6][7]
The term phatic communion ('bonding by language') was coined by anthropologist Bronis&#322;aw Malinowski in his essay "The Problem of Meaning in Primitive Languages", which appeared in 1923 as a supplementary contribution to The Meaning of Meaning by C. K. Ogden and I. A. Richards. The term "phatic" means "linguistic" (i.e. "by language") and comes from the Greek &#966;&#945;&#964;&#972;&#962; phat&#243;s ("spoken, that may be spoken"), from &#966;&#951;&#956;&#943; ph&#275;m&#237; ("I speak, say").[8]
</wiki></doc>