<doc><id>phrap</id><concept_name>phrap</concept_name><wiki>Phrap is a widely used program for DNA sequence assembly. It is part of the Phred-Phrap-Consed package.
Phrap was originally developed by Prof. Phil Green for the assembly of cosmids in large-scale cosmid shotgun sequencing within the Human Genome Project. Phrap has been widely used for many different sequence assembly projects, including bacterial genome assemblies and EST assemblies.
Phrap was written as a command line program for easy integration into automated data workflows in genome sequencing centers. For users who want to use Phrap from a graphical interface, the commercial programs MacVector (for Mac OS X only) and  CodonCode Aligner (for Mac OS X and Microsoft Windows) are available.
A detailed (albeit partially outdated) description of the Phrap algorithms can be found in the Phrap documentation. A recurring thread within the Phrap algorithms is the use of Phred quality scores. Phrap used quality scores to mitigate a problem that other assembly programs had struggled with at the beginning of the Human Genome Project: correctly assembling frequent imperfect repeats, in particular Alu sequences. Phrap uses quality scores to tell if any observed differences in repeated regions are likely to be due to random ambiguities in the sequencing process, or more likely to be due to the sequences being from different copies of the Alu repeat. Typically, Phrap had no problems differentiating between the different Alu copies in a cosmid, and to correctly assemble the cosmids (or, later, BACs). The logic is simple: a base call with a high probability of being correct should never be aligned with another high quality but different base. However, Phrap does not rule out such alignments entirely, and the cross_match alignment gap and alignment penalties used while looking for local alignments are not always optimal for typical sequencing errors and a search for overlapping (contiguous) sequences. (Affine gaps are helpful for homology searches but not usually for sequencing error alignment). Phrap attempts to classify chimeras, vector sequences and low quality end regions all in a single alignment and will sometimes make mistakes. Furthermore, Phrap has more than one round of assembly building internally and later rounds are less stringent - Greedy algorithm. 
</wiki></doc>