<doc><id>post_quantum_cryptography</id><concept_name>post quantum cryptography</concept_name><wiki>Post-quantum cryptography (sometimes referred to as quantum-proof, quantum-safe or quantum-resistant) refers to cryptographic algorithms (usually public-key algorithms) that are thought to be secure against an attack by a quantum computer. As of 2019[update], this is not true for the most popular public-key algorithms, which can be efficiently broken by a sufficiently strong quantum computer. The problem with currently popular algorithms is that their security relies on one of three hard mathematical problems:  the integer factorization problem, the discrete logarithm problem or the elliptic-curve discrete logarithm problem. All of these problems can be easily solved on a sufficiently powerful quantum computer running Shor's algorithm.[1][2] Even though current, publicly known, experimental quantum computers lack processing power to break any real cryptographic algorithm,[3] many cryptographers are designing new algorithms to prepare for a time when quantum computing becomes a threat. This work has gained greater attention from academics and industry through the PQCrypto conference series since 2006 and more recently by several workshops on Quantum Safe Cryptography hosted by the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI) and the Institute for Quantum Computing.[4][5][6]
In contrast to the threat quantum computing poses to current public-key algorithms, most current symmetric cryptographic algorithms and hash functions are considered to be relatively secure against attacks by quantum computers.[2][7] While the quantum Grover's algorithm does speed up attacks against symmetric ciphers, doubling the key size can effectively block these attacks.[8] Thus post-quantum symmetric cryptography does not need to differ significantly from current symmetric cryptography. See section on symmetric-key approach below.
Currently post-quantum cryptography research is mostly focused on six different approaches:[2][5]
This approach includes cryptographic systems such as learning with errors, ring learning with errors (ring-LWE),[9][10][11] the ring learning with errors key exchange and the ring learning with errors signature, the older NTRU or GGH encryption schemes, and the newer NTRU signature and BLISS signatures.[12] Some of these schemes like NTRU encryption have been studied for many years without anyone finding a feasible attack. Others like the ring-LWE algorithms have proofs that their security reduces to a worst-case problem.[13] The Post Quantum Cryptography Study Group sponsored by the European Commission suggested that the Stehle&#8211;Steinfeld variant of NTRU be studied for standardization rather than the NTRU algorithm.[14][15] At that time, NTRU was still patented. Studies have indicated that NTRU may have more secure properties than other lattice based algorithms [16].
</wiki></doc>