<doc><id>powered_exoskeleton</id><concept_name>powered exoskeleton</concept_name><wiki>A powered exoskeleton (also known as power armor, powered armor, powered suit, exoframe, hardsuit or exosuit)[1] is a wearable mobile machine that is powered by a system of electric motors, pneumatics, levers, hydraulics, or a combination of technologies that allow for limb movement with increased strength and endurance.[2] Its design aims to provide back support, sense the user's motion, and send a signal to motors which manage the gears. The exoskeleton supports the shoulder, waist and thigh, and assists movement for lifting and holding heavy items, while lowering back stress.[3]
A powered exoskeleton differs from a passive exoskeleton in the fact that a passive exoskeleton is not powered by a system of electric motors, pneumatics, levers, hydraulics, or a combination of technologies. However, similar to a powered exoskeleton, it does give mechanical benefits to the user.[4][5]
The earliest-known exoskeleton-like device was a set of walking, jumping and running assisted apparatus developed in 1890 by Russian engineer[relevant?  &#8211; discuss] Nicholas Yagin. It used energy stored in compressed gas bags to assist in movement, although it was passive and required human power.[6] In 1917, United States inventor Leslie C. Kelley developed what he called a pedometer, which operated on steam power with artificial ligaments acting in parallel to the wearer's movements.[7] This system was able to supplement human power with external power.

In the 1960s, the first true 'mobile machines' integrated with human movements began to appear. A suit called Hardiman was co-developed by General Electric and the US Armed Forces. The suit was powered by hydraulics and electricity and amplified the wearer's strength by a factor of 25, so that lifting 110 kilograms (240&#160;lb) would feel like lifting 4.5 kilograms (10&#160;lb). A feature called force feedback enabled the wearer to feel the forces and objects being manipulated.</wiki></doc>