<doc><id>preconditioner</id><concept_name>preconditioner</concept_name><wiki>In mathematics, preconditioning is the application of a transformation, called the preconditioner,  that conditions a given problem into a form that is more suitable for numerical solving methods. Preconditioning is typically related to reducing a condition number of the problem. The preconditioned problem is then usually solved by an iterative method.
In linear algebra and numerical analysis, a preconditioner 



P


{\displaystyle P}

 of a matrix 



A


{\displaystyle A}

 is a matrix such that 




P

&#8722;
1


A


{\displaystyle P^{-1}A}

 has a smaller condition number than 



A


{\displaystyle A}

. It is also common to call 



T
=

P

&#8722;
1




{\displaystyle T=P^{-1}}

 the preconditioner, rather than 



P


{\displaystyle P}

, since 



P


{\displaystyle P}

 itself is rarely explicitly available. In modern preconditioning, the application of  



T
=

P

&#8722;
1




{\displaystyle T=P^{-1}}

, i.e., multiplication of a column vector, or a block of column vectors, by 



T
=

P

&#8722;
1




{\displaystyle T=P^{-1}}

, is commonly performed by rather sophisticated computer software packages in a matrix-free fashion, i.e., where neither 



P


{\displaystyle P}

, nor  



T
=

P

&#8722;
1




{\displaystyle T=P^{-1}}

 (and often not even 



A


{\displaystyle A}

) are explicitly available in a matrix form. 
Preconditioners are useful in iterative methods to solve a linear system  



A
x
=
b


{\displaystyle Ax=b}

 for 



x


{\displaystyle x}

 since the rate of convergence for most iterative linear solvers increases because the condition number of a matrix decreases as a result of preconditioning. Preconditioned iterative solvers typically outperform direct solvers, e.g., Gaussian elimination, for large, especially for sparse, matrices. Iterative solvers can be used as matrix-free methods, i.e. become the only choice if the coefficient matrix 



A


{\displaystyle A}

 is not stored explicitly, but is accessed by evaluating matrix-vector products.
Instead of solving the original linear system above, one may solve the right preconditioned system:
</wiki></doc>