<doc><id>product_line</id><concept_name>product line</concept_name><wiki>In marketing jargon, product lining is offering several related products for sale individually.  Unlike product bundling, where several products are combined into one group, which is then offered for sale as a units, product lining involves offering the products for sale separately. A line can comprise related products of various sizes, types, colors, qualities, or prices. Line depth refers to the number of subcategories a category has. Line consistency refers to how closely related the products that make up the line are. Line vulnerability refers to the percentage of sales or profits that are derived from only a few products in the line.
In comparison to product bundling, which is a strategy of offering more than one product for promotion as one combined item to create differentiation and greater value, product lining consists of selling different related products individually.[1] The products in the product line can come in various sizes, colours, qualities, or prices.[2] For instance, the variety of coffees that are offered at a caf&#233; is one of its product lines and it could consist of flat white, cappuccinos, short black, lattes, mochas, etc. Alternatively, product line of juices and pastries can also be found at a caf&#233;. The benefits from having a successful product line is the brand identification from customers which result in customer loyalty and multiple purchases.[3] It increases the likelihood of customers purchasing new products from the company that have just been added into the product line due to the previous satisfying purchases.[4]
In marketing, the number of product lines offered is referred as the width of product mix. Product mix, also known as product assortment, is the total number of variety of products that a firm sells to their customers.[5] It measures the total number of product lines. Some companies will focus solely and sell only one type of product that they specialise in.  Having said that, some would offer numerous types of products for diversified markets, depending on the size and objectives of the entities. Each approaches' results vary based on many factors including location, market, trends, etc., therefore business should carefully consider their product mix. The width of product mix is one of the four dimensions of product mix along with the length, depth and consistency of product mix.[6]
As mentioned above, the width of product mix is referred to as the total number of product lines that the company offers. A diversified product mix can target the maximum number of customers, however, such numbers of product lines requires much attention and focus as each product line targets different groups of consumers and involves individual strategy and management. Although specialisation of products (narrow product mix) might be easier for businesses to operate and manage, it reduces the ability to reach out to diverse markets as they fail to offer sufficient options for consumers to cater to their &#8220;needs and wants&#8221;.[7]
</wiki></doc>