<doc><id>quantum_logic</id><concept_name>quantum logic</concept_name><wiki>In quantum mechanics,  quantum logic is a set of rules for reasoning about propositions that takes the principles of quantum theory into account.  This research area and its name originated in a 1936 paper[1] by Garrett Birkhoff and John von Neumann, who were attempting to reconcile the apparent inconsistency of classical logic with the facts concerning the measurement of complementary variables in quantum mechanics, such as position and momentum.
Quantum logic can be formulated either as a modified version of propositional logic or as a noncommutative and non-associative many-valued (MV) logic.[2][3][4][5][6]
Quantum logic has been proposed as the correct logic for propositional inference generally, most notably by the philosopher Hilary Putnam, at least at one point in his career.  This thesis was an important ingredient in Putnam's 1968 paper "Is Logic Empirical?" in which he analysed the epistemological status of the rules of propositional logic. Putnam attributes the idea that anomalies associated to quantum measurements originate with anomalies in the logic of physics itself to the physicist David Finkelstein. However, this idea had been around for some time and had been revived several years earlier by George Mackey's work on group representations and symmetry.
The more common view regarding quantum logic, however, is that it provides a formalism for relating observables, system preparation filters and states.[citation needed]  In this view, the quantum logic approach resembles more closely the C*-algebraic approach to quantum mechanics.  The similarities of the quantum logic formalism to a system of deductive logic may then be regarded more as a curiosity than as a fact of fundamental philosophical importance. A more modern approach to the structure of quantum logic is to assume that it is a diagram&#8212;in the sense of category theory&#8212;of classical logics (see David Edwards).
</wiki></doc>