<doc><id>quantum_cryptography</id><concept_name>quantum cryptography</concept_name><wiki>Quantum cryptography is the science of exploiting quantum mechanical properties to perform cryptographic tasks. The best known example of quantum cryptography is quantum key distribution which offers an information-theoretically secure solution to the key exchange problem. The advantage of quantum cryptography lies in the fact that it allows the completion of various cryptographic tasks that are proven or conjectured to be impossible using only classical (i.e. non-quantum) communication. For example, it is impossible to copy data encoded in a quantum state. If one attempts to read the encoded data, the quantum state will be changed (no-cloning theorem). This could be used to detect eavesdropping in quantum key distribution.
Quantum cryptography attributes its beginning by the work of Stephen Wiesner and Gilles Brassard. Wiesner, then at Columbia University in New York, who, in the early 1970s, introduced the concept of quantum conjugate coding. His seminal paper titled "Conjugate Coding" was rejected by the IEEE Information Theory Society, but was eventually published in 1983 in SIGACT News.[1] In this paper he showed how to store or transmit two messages by encoding them in two "conjugate observables", such as linear and circular polarization of photons,[2] so that either, but not both, of which may be received and decoded. It was not until Charles H. Bennett, of the IBM's Thomas J. Watson Research Center and Gilles Brassard met at the 20th IEEE Symposium held in Puerto Rico that they discovered how to incorporate the findings of Weisner. "The main breakthrough came when we realized that photons were never meant to store information, but rather to transmit it"[1] In 1984, building upon this work Bennett and Brassard proposed a method for secure communication, which is now called BB84.[3] Following a proposal by David Deutsch for using quantum non-locality and Bell's inequalities to achieve secure key distribution [4]
Artur Ekert analysed entanglement-based quantum key distribution in more detail in his 1991 paper.[5]
Random rotations of the polarization by both parties have been proposed in Kak's three-stage protocol.[6] In principle, this method can be used for continuous, unbreakable encryption of data if single photons are used.[7] The basic polarization rotation scheme has been implemented.[8] This represents a method of purely quantum-based cryptography as against quantum key distribution where the actual encryption is classical.[9]
The BB84 method is at the basis of quantum key distribution methods. Companies that manufacture quantum cryptography systems include MagiQ Technologies, Inc. (Boston, Massachusetts, United States), ID Quantique (Geneva, Switzerland), QuintessenceLabs (Canberra, Australia), Toshiba (Tokyo, Japan), and SeQureNet (Paris, France).
</wiki></doc>