<doc><id>rationalism</id><concept_name>rationalism</concept_name><wiki>In philosophy, rationalism is the epistemological view that "regards reason as the chief source and test of knowledge"[1] or "any view appealing to reason as a source of knowledge or justification".[2] More formally, rationalism is defined as a methodology or a theory "in which the criterion of the truth is not sensory but intellectual and deductive".[3]
In an old controversy, rationalism was opposed to empiricism, where the rationalists believed that reality has an intrinsically logical structure. Because of this, the rationalists argued that certain truths exist and that the intellect can directly grasp these truths. That is to say, rationalists asserted that certain rational principles exist in logic, mathematics, ethics, and metaphysics that are so fundamentally true that denying them causes one to fall into contradiction. The rationalists had such a high confidence in reason that empirical proof and physical evidence were regarded as unnecessary to ascertain certain truths &#8211; in other words, "there are significant ways in which our concepts and knowledge are gained independently of sense experience".[4]
Different degrees of emphasis on this method or theory lead to a range of rationalist standpoints, from the moderate position "that reason has precedence over other ways of acquiring knowledge" to the more extreme position that reason is "the unique path to knowledge".[5] Given a pre-modern understanding of reason, rationalism is identical to philosophy, the Socratic life of inquiry, or the zetetic (skeptical) clear interpretation of authority (open to the underlying or essential cause of things as they appear to our sense of certainty). In recent decades, Leo Strauss sought to revive "Classical Political Rationalism" as a discipline that understands the task of reasoning, not as foundational, but as maieutic.
In the 17th-century Dutch Republic, the rise of early modern-period rationalism&#8212;as a highly systematic school of philosophy in its own right for the first time in history&#8212;exerted an immense and profound influence on modern Western thought in general,[6][7] with the birth of two influential rationalistic philosophical systems of Descartes[8][9] (who spent most of his adult life in the Dutch Republic in the period 1628&#8211;1649 and despite frequent moves, he wrote all his major work during his 20-plus years in the United Provinces)[10][11][12][13] and Spinoza[14][15]&#8212;namely Cartesianism[16][17][18] and Spinozism.[19][20][21][22][23][24][25] It was the 17th-century arch-rationalists[26][27][28][29] like Descartes, Spinoza and Leibniz who have given the "Age of Reason" its name and place in history.[30]
</wiki></doc>