<doc><id>resource_dependence_theory</id><concept_name>resource dependence theory</concept_name><wiki>Resource dependence theory (RDT) is the study of how the external resources of organizations affect the behavior of the organization. The procurement of external resources is an important tenet of both the strategic and tactical management of any company. Nevertheless, a theory of the consequences of this importance was not formalized until the 1970s, with the publication of The External Control of Organizations:  A Resource Dependence Perspective (Pfeffer and Salancik 1978). Resource dependence theory has implications regarding the optimal divisional structure of organizations, recruitment of board members and employees, production strategies, contract structure, external organizational links, and many other aspects of organizational strategy.
The basic argument of resource dependence theory can be summarized as follows:
Organizations depend on multidimensional resources: labor, capital, raw material, etc. Organizations may not be able to come out with countervailing initiatives for all these multiple resources. Hence organization should move through the principle of criticality and principle of scarcity. Critical resources are those the organization must have to function. For example, a burger outlet can't function without bread. An organization may adopt various countervailing strategies&#8212;it may associate with more suppliers, or integrate vertically or horizontally.
Resource dependence concerns more than the external organizations that provide, distribute, finance, and compete with a firm.  Although executive decisions have more individual weight than non-executive decisions, in aggregate the latter have greater organizational impact.  Managers throughout the organization understand their success is tied to customer demand.  Managers'
careers thrive when customer demand expands.  Thus customers are the ultimate resource on which companies depend.  Although this seems obvious in terms of revenue, it is actually organizational incentives that make management see customers as a resource.
</wiki></doc>