<doc><id>rhyme_dictionary</id><concept_name>rhyme dictionary</concept_name><wiki>A rime dictionary, rhyme dictionary, or rime book (simplified Chinese: &#38901;&#20070;; traditional Chinese: &#38907;&#26360;; pinyin: y&#249;nsh&#363;) is an ancient type of Chinese dictionary that collates characters by tone and rhyme, instead of by radical.  The most important rime dictionary tradition began with the Qieyun (601), which codified correct pronunciations for reading the classics and writing poetry by combining the reading traditions of north and south China.  This work became very popular during the Tang dynasty, and went through a series of revisions and expansions, of which the most famous is the Guangyun (1007&#8211;1008).
These dictionaries specify the pronunciations of characters using the f&#462;nqi&#232; method, giving a pair of characters indicating the onset and remainder of the syllable respectively.
The later rime tables gave a significantly more precise and systematic account of the sounds of these dictionaries by tabulating syllables by their onsets, rhyme groups, tones and other properties.  The phonological system inferred from these books, often interpreted using the rime tables, is known as Middle Chinese, and has been the key datum for efforts to recover the sounds of early forms of Chinese.  It incorporates most of the distinctions found in modern varieties of Chinese, as well as some that are no longer distinguished.  It has also been used together with other evidence in the reconstruction of the Old Chinese language (1st millennium BC).
Some scholars use the French spelling "rime", as used by the Swedish linguist Bernard Karlgren, for the categories described in these works, to distinguish them from the concept of poetic rhyme.[1]
Chinese scholars produced dictionaries to codify reading pronunciations for the correct recitation of the classics and the associated rhyme conventions of regulated verse.[3]  The earliest rime dictionary was the Shenglei (lit. "sound types") by Li Deng (&#26446;&#30331;) of the Three Kingdoms period, containing more than 11,000 characters grouped under the five notes of the ancient Chinese musical scale.[4]  The book did not survive, and is known only from descriptions in later works.[5]
</wiki></doc>