<doc><id>rhyme</id><concept_name>rhyme</concept_name><wiki>A rhyme is a repetition of similar sounds (usually, exactly the same sound) in the final stressed syllables and any following syllables of two or more words. Most often, this kind of "perfect" rhyming is consciously used for effect in the final positions of lines of poems and songs.[1] More broadly, a rhyme may also variously refer to other types of similar sounds near the ends of two or more words. Furthermore, the word rhyme has come to be sometimes used as a shorthand term for any brief poem, such as a rhyming couplet or nursery rhyme.  
The word derives from Old French rime or ryme, which may be derived from Old Frankish *r&#299;m, a Germanic term meaning "series, sequence" attested in Old English (Old English r&#299;m meaning "enumeration, series, numeral") and Old High German r&#299;m, ultimately cognate to Old Irish r&#237;m, Greek &#7936;&#961;&#953;&#952;&#956;&#972;&#962; arithmos "number". Alternatively, the Old French words may derive from Latin rhythmus, from Greek &#8165;&#965;&#952;&#956;&#972;&#962; (rhythmos, rhythm).[2][3]
The spelling rhyme (from original rime) was introduced at the beginning of the Modern English period from a learned (but perhaps etymologically incorrect) association with Latin rhythmus.[2] The older spelling rime survives in Modern English as a rare alternative spelling; cf. The Rime of the Ancient Mariner. A distinction between the spellings is also sometimes made in the study of linguistics and phonology for which rime/rhyme is used to refer to the nucleus and coda of a syllable. Some prefer to spell it rime to separate it from the poetic rhyme covered by this article (see syllable rime).
Rhyme partly seems to be enjoyed simply as a repeating pattern that is pleasant to hear. It also serves as a powerful mnemonic device, facilitating memorization. The regular use of tail rhyme helps to mark off the ends of lines, thus clarifying the metrical structure for the listener. As with other poetic techniques, poets use it to suit their own purposes; for example William Shakespeare often used a rhyming couplet to mark off the end of a scene in a play.
</wiki></doc>