<doc><id>science_2.0</id><concept_name>science 2.0</concept_name><wiki>Science 2.0 is a suggested new approach to science that uses information-sharing and collaboration made possible by network technologies.[1][2][3] It is similar to the open research and open science movements and is inspired by Web 2.0 technologies.[3][4] Science 2.0 stresses the benefits of increased collaboration between scientists.[2][3][5][6] Science 2.0 uses collaborative tools like wikis, blogs and video journals to share findings, raw data and "nascent theories" online.[2][4][5][7] Science 2.0 benefits from openness and sharing, regarding papers and research ideas and partial solutions.[3]
A general view is that Science 2.0 is gaining traction[3] with websites beginning to proliferate,[7] yet at the same time there is considerable resistance within the scientific community about aspects of the transition as well as discussion about what, exactly, the term means. There are several views that there is a "sea change" happening in the status quo of scientific publishing,[3] and substantive change regarding how scientists share research data.[8] There is considerable discussion in the scientific community about whether scientists should embrace the model and exactly how Science 2.0 might work, as well as several reports that many scientists are slow to embrace collaborative methods[2] and are somewhat "inhibited and slow to adopt a lot of online tools."[3]
The term has many meanings and continues to evolve in scientific parlance. It not only describes what is currently happening in science, but describes a direction in which proponents believe science should move towards, as well as a growing number of websites which promote free scientific collaboration.
The term Science 2.0 suggests a contrast between traditional ways of doing science, often denoted Science 1.0, with more collaborative approaches, and suggests that the new forms of science will work with Web 2.0 technologies.[5] One description from Science is that Science 2.0 uses the "networking power of the internet to tackle problems with multiple interacting variables - the problems, in other words, of everyday life."[6] A different and somewhat controversial view is that of Ben Shneiderman, who suggested that Science 2.0 combines hypothesis-based inquiries with social science methods, partially for the purpose of improving those new networks.[9]
</wiki></doc>