<doc><id>secondary_articulation</id><concept_name>secondary articulation</concept_name><wiki>In phonetics, secondary articulation occurs when the articulation of a consonant is equivalent to the combined articulations of two or three simpler consonants, at least one of which is an approximant. The secondary articulation of such co-articulated consonants is the approximant-like articulation. It "colors" the primary articulation rather than obscuring it. Maledo (2011) defines secondary articulation as the superimposition of lesser stricture upon a primary articulation. 
There are several kinds of secondary articulation supported by the International Phonetic Alphabet.
It can sometimes be difficult to distinguish primary and secondary articulation. For example, the alveolo-palatal consonants [&#597; &#657;] are sometimes characterized as a primary articulation of their own and sometimes as palatalization of postalveolar fricatives, [&#643;&#690; &#658;&#690;] or [s&#800;&#690; z&#800;&#690;].
The most common method of transcription in the IPA is to turn the letter corresponding to the secondary articulation into a superscript written after the letter for the primary articulation. For example, the w in &#10216;k&#695;&#10217; is written after the k. This can be misleading, as it iconically suggests that the [k] is released into a [w] sound, analogous to &#10216;k&#737; k&#8319;&#10217; ([k] with a lateral and nasal release), when actually the two articulations of [k&#695;] are generally pronounced more-or-less simultaneously. Secondary articulation often has a strong effect on surrounding vowels, and may have an audible realization that precedes the primary consonant, or both precedes and follows it. For example, /ak&#695;a/ will not generally sound simply like [akwa], but may be closer to [awkwa] or even [awka]. For this reason, the IPA symbols for labialization and palatalization were for a time placed under the primary letter (e.g. &#10216;k&#811;&#10217; for [k&#695;] and &#10216;&#427;&#10217; for [t&#690;]), and a number of phoneticians still prefer such unambiguous usage, with &#10216;k&#695;&#10217; and &#10216;t&#690;&#10217; used specifically for off-glides, despite the official policy of the IPA. In the official IPA there remains only an alternative symbol for velarization/pharyngealizaton that is superposed over the primary (e.g. &#10216;&#619;&#10217; for dark L), but it has font support for a limited number of consonants and is inadvisable for others, where it can be illegible. 
</wiki></doc>