<doc><id>secret_sharing</id><concept_name>secret sharing</concept_name><wiki>Secret sharing (also called secret splitting) refers to methods for distributing a secret amongst a group of participants, each of whom is allocated a share of the secret. The secret can be reconstructed only when a sufficient number, of possibly different types, of shares are combined together; individual shares are of no use on their own.
In one type of secret sharing scheme there is one dealer and n players. The dealer gives a share of the secret to the players, but only when specific conditions are fulfilled will the players be able to reconstruct the secret from their shares. The dealer accomplishes this by giving each player a share in such a way that any group of t (for threshold) or more players can together reconstruct the secret but no group of fewer than t players can. Such a system is called a (t, n)-threshold scheme (sometimes it is written as an (n, t)-threshold scheme).
Secret sharing was invented independently by Adi Shamir[1] and George Blakley[2] in 1979.
Secret sharing schemes are ideal for storing information that is highly sensitive and highly important.  Examples include:  encryption keys, missile launch codes, and numbered bank accounts.  Each of these pieces of information must be kept highly confidential, as their exposure could be disastrous, however, it is also critical that they should not be lost.  Traditional methods for encryption are ill-suited for simultaneously achieving high levels of confidentiality and reliability.  This is because when storing the encryption key, one must choose between keeping a single copy of the key in one location for maximum secrecy, or keeping multiple copies of the key in different locations for greater reliability.  Increasing reliability of the key by storing multiple copies lowers confidentiality by creating additional attack vectors; there are more opportunities for a copy to fall into the wrong hands.  Secret sharing schemes address this problem, and allow arbitrarily high levels of confidentiality and reliability to be achieved.
</wiki></doc>