<doc><id>service_set_identifier</id><concept_name>service set identifier</concept_name><wiki>In IEEE 802.11 wireless local area networking standards (including Wi-Fi), a service set (also known as extended service set or ESS) is a group of wireless network devices which are identified by the same SSID (service set identifier). SSIDs serve as "network names" and are typically natural language labels. A service set forms a logical network - that is operating with the same level 2 networking parameters- they are on the same logical network segment (e.g., IP subnet or VLAN).
Basic service sets (BSS) are a subgroup of devices within a service set which are additionally also operating with the same physical layer medium access characteristics (i.e. radio frequency, modulation scheme, security settings etc.) such that they are wirelessly networked. Devices within basic service sets are identified by BSSIDs (basic service set identifiers), which are 48-bit labels that conform to MAC-48 conventions. While devices may have multiple BSSIDs, usually each BSSID is associated with at most one basic service set at a time.[1] There are two classes of basic service sets: those that are formed by an infrastructure mode redistribution point (access points or mesh nodes), and those that are formed by independent stations in a peer-to-peer ad hoc topology (an Independent Basic Service Set- or  IBSS.)
A basic service set should not to be confused with the coverage area of an access point, known as the 'basic service area' (BSA).[2]
An infrastructure mode wireless network basic service set (BSS) consists of one redistribution point &#8212; typically an access point (WAP or AP) &#8212; together with one or more "client" stations that are associated with (i.e. connected to) that redistribution point.[3] The operating parameters of the infrastructure-BSS are defined by the redistribution point. Stations communicate only with the redistribution point that they are associated with, and all traffic within the infrastructure-BSS is routed through/bridged by that redistribution point.
</wiki></doc>