<doc><id>thin_plate_spline</id><concept_name>thin plate spline</concept_name><wiki>Thin plate splines (TPS) are a spline-based technique for data interpolation and smoothing. They were introduced to geometric design by Duchon.[1] They are an important special case of a polyharmonic spline. Robust Point Matching (RPM) is a common extension and shortly known as the TPS-RPM algorithm.[2]
The name thin plate spline refers to a physical analogy involving the bending of a thin sheet of metal. Just as the metal has rigidity, the TPS fit resists bending also, implying a penalty involving the smoothness of the fitted surface. In the physical setting, the deflection is in the 



z


{\displaystyle z}

 direction, orthogonal to the plane. In order to apply this idea to the problem of coordinate transformation, one interprets the lifting of the plate as a displacement of the 



x


{\displaystyle x}

 or 



y


{\displaystyle y}

 coordinates within the plane. In 2D cases, given a set of 



K


{\displaystyle K}

 corresponding points, the TPS warp is described by 



2
(
K
+
3
)


{\displaystyle 2(K+3)}

 parameters which include 6 global affine motion parameters and 



2
K


{\displaystyle 2K}

 coefficients for correspondences of the control points. These parameters are computed by solving a linear system, in other words, TPS has a closed-form solution.
The TPS arises from consideration of the integral of the square of the second derivative&#8212;this forms its smoothness measure. In the case where 



x


{\displaystyle x}

 is two dimensional, for interpolation, the TPS fits a mapping function 



f
(
x
)


{\displaystyle f(x)}

 between corresponding point-sets 



{

y

i


}


{\displaystyle \{y_{i}\}}

 and 



{

x

i


}


{\displaystyle \{x_{i}\}}

 that minimizes the following energy function: 
The smoothing variant, correspondingly, uses a tuning parameter 



&#955;


{\displaystyle \lambda }

 to control the rigidity of the deformation, balancing the aforementioned criterion with the measure of goodness of fit, thus minimizing:
</wiki></doc>