<doc><id>transistor_count</id><concept_name>transistor count</concept_name><wiki>
The transistor count is the number of transistors on an integrated circuit (IC). It typically refers to the number of MOSFETs (metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect transistors, or MOS transistors) on an IC chip, as all modern ICs use MOSFETs. It is the most common measure of IC complexity (although the majority of transistors in modern microprocessors are contained in the cache memories, which consist mostly of the same memory cell circuits replicated many times). The rate at which MOS transistor counts have increased generally follows Moore's law, which observed that the transistor count doubles approximately every two years.
As of 2019[update], the largest transistor count in a commercially available microprocessor is 39.54&#160;billion MOSFETs, in AMD's Zen 2 based Epyc Rome, which is a 3D integrated circuit (with eight dies in a single package) fabricated using TSMC's 7&#160;nm FinFET semiconductor manufacturing process.[1][2] As of 2018[update], the highest transistor count in a graphics processing unit (GPU) is Nvidia's GV100 Volta with 21.1&#160;billion MOSFETs, manufactured using TSMC's 12&#160;nm FinFET process.[3] As of 2019[update], the highest transistor count in any IC chip is Samsung's 1&#160;TB eUFS (3D-stacked) V-NAND flash memory chip, with 2&#160;trillion floating-gate MOSFETs (4&#160;bits per transistor).[4] As of 2019, the highest transistor count in a non-memory chip is a deep learning engine called the Wafer Scale Engine by Cerebras, using a special design to route around any non-functional core on the device; it has 1.2&#160;trillion MOSFETs, manufactured using TSMC's 16&#160;nm FinFET process.[5][6][7][8]
In terms of computer systems that consist of numerous integrated circuits, the supercomputer with the highest transistor count as of 2016[update] is the Chinese-designed Sunway TaihuLight, which has for all CPUs/nodes (1012 for the 10 million cores and for RAM 1015 for the 1.3 million GB) combined "about 400 trillion transistors in the processing part of the hardware" and "the DRAM includes about 12 quadrillion transistors, and that&#8217;s about 97 percent of all the transistors."[9] To compare, the smallest computer, as of 2018[update] dwarfed by a grain of sand, has on the order of 100,000 transistors, and the one, fully programmable, with the fewest transistors ever has 130 transistors or fewer.
</wiki></doc>