<doc><id>user_experience_design</id><concept_name>user experience design</concept_name><wiki>User experience design (UXD, UED, or XD) is the process of manipulating user behavior[1] through usability, usefulness, and desirability provided in the interaction with a product.[2] User experience design encompasses traditional human&#8211;computer interaction (HCI) design and extends it by addressing all aspects of a product or service as perceived by users.  Experience design (XD) is the practice of designing products, processes, services, events, omnichannel journeys, and environments with a focus placed on the quality of the user experience and culturally relevant solutions.[3]  Experience design is not driven by a single design discipline. Instead, it requires a cross-discipline perspective that considers multiple aspects of the brand/ business/ environment/ experience from product, packaging, and retail environment to the clothing and attitude of employees. Experience design seeks to develop the experience of a product, service, or event along any or all of the following dimensions:[4]
The field of user experience design is a conceptual design discipline and has its roots in human factors and ergonomics, a field that, since the late 1940s, has focused on the interaction between human users, machines, and the contextual environments to design systems that address the user's experience.[5][6] With the proliferation of workplace computers in the early 1990s, user experience started to become a positive insight for designers. Donald Norman, a professor and researcher in design, usability, and cognitive science, continued the term "user experience," and brought it to a wider audience.[7][8]
I invented the term because I thought human interface and usability were extremely good. I wanted to cover all aspects of the person's experience with the system including industrial design graphics, the interface, the physical interaction and the manual. Since then the term has spread widely, so much so that it is starting to gain its meaning.There is an enable all access occurring in the experience design community regarding its business view all access in part by design scholar and practitioner, Don Norman. Norman claims that when designers describe people only as customers, consumers, and users, designers allowing their ability to do good design.[10]
</wiki></doc>