<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_293</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-analytics-executive-overview</course_url><course_name>Business Analytics Executive Overview</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Douglas B. Laney</course_instructor><course_introduction>Businesses run on data, and data offers little value without analytics. The ability to process data to make predictions about the behavior of individuals or markets, to diagnose systems or situations, or to prescribe actions for people or processes drives business today. Increasingly many businesses are striving to become “data-driven”, proactively relying more on cold hard information and sophisticated algorithms than upon the gut instinct or slow reactions of humans. 

This course will focus on understanding key analytics concepts and the breadth of analytic possibilities. Together, the class will explore dozens of real-world analytics problems and solutions across most major industries and business functions. The course will also touch on analytic technologies, architectures, and roles from business intelligence to data science, and from data warehouses to data lakes. And the course will wrap up with a discussion of analytics trends and futures.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Leadership and Management</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview &amp; Module 1 Analytics Beyond the Spreadsheet//Module 2 Industry and Business Function Analytics //Module 3 Staffing and Organizing for Analytics //Module 4 Analytics Success Today and Tomorrow</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Meet Instructor Doug Laney', 'Lesson 1-1 Overview of Analytics', 'Lesson 1-2 Beyond Basic Business Intelligence', 'Lesson 1-3-1 The Analytics Continuum', 'Lesson 1-3-2 Analytic Output', 'Lecture 1-3-3 Basic Analytic Techniques', 'Lecture 1-4 Analytic Graphical Representation (Visualization)', 'Interview with Kevin Hartman', 'Lecture 1-5-1 Key Analytics Concepts to Know (Data Literacy)', 'Lecture 1-5-2 Data, What Data? (Sources of Data)', 'Lecture 1-5-3 Where to Put the Data and How to Get it There?', 'Lecture 1-5-4 Analytic Methods, Techniques and Concepts', 'Lecture 1-5-5 Other Data Concepts', 'Lecture 1-6-1 Purpose-Built Analytic Solutions', 'Lecture 1-6-2 Data-specific Analytic Solutions', 'Lecture 1-6-3 Business Function-Specific Analytics'], ['Module 2 Overview', 'Lecture 2-1 Banking and Financial Institution Examples', 'Lecture 2-2 Insurance Examples', 'Lecture 2-3 Retail Examples', 'Lecture 2-4 Manufacturing, Consumer Package Goods Examples', 'Lecture 2-5 Energy Sector Examples', 'Lecture 2-6 Telecommunications Examples', 'Lecture 2-7 Government and the Public Sector Examples', 'Lecture 2-8 Healthcare Examples', 'Lecture 2-9 Sports and Entertainment Examples', 'Lecture 2-10 Other Examples'], ['Module 3 Overview', 'Lecture 3-1 The Chief Information Officer (CIO)', 'Lecture 3-2 The Chief Data Officer  (CDO)', 'Lecture 3-3 Chief Digital Officer', 'Lecture 3-4 The Chief Analytics Officer (CAO)', 'Lecture 3-5 The Data Scientist', 'Lecture 3-6 Data Scientist Soft Skills', 'Lecture 3-7 Other Analytics Related Roles', 'Lecture 3-8 The Analytics Center of Excellence', 'Lecture 3-9 Analytics Consulting and Crowdsourcing', 'Interview with Graham Waller'], ['Lecture 4-1-1 Analytics Maturity', 'Lecture 4-1-2 Analytics Maturity Levels', 'Lecture 4-1-3 Key Maturity Disciplines', 'Lecture 4-2 Analytics Success Factors', 'Lecture 4-3-0 Analytics Trends and Futures', 'Lecture 4-3-1 Analytics as a Corporate Strategy', 'Lecture 4-3-2 Data Literacy', 'Lecture 4-3-3 Valuing Information Assets', 'Lecture 4-3-4 A Data Science and AI Ethical Code of Conduct', 'Lecture 4-3-5 Continuous Intelligence', 'Lecture 4-3-6 Reinventing, Digitalizing and Eliminating Business Offerings', 'Lecture 4-3-7 AI will Struggle to Scale in the Organization', 'Lecture 4-3-8 Most Analytic Insights Will Fail to Deliver Business Value', 'Lecture 4-3-9 Quantum Computing Will Start to Outperform Traditional Analytics Computing']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great introduction course for Business Analytics for any level of experienced professionals or students.', 'Great Course and Professor, You are the best!', 'Challenging and packed with good information!  ', 'Definetly a source for present day information and upcoming trends in analytics. This professor definetly can offer a new comers guide to data analytics. ', 'over all is great, but i personal like the experience sharing part, thank you.', 'A very helpful overview of business analytics; the past, the present and what could be expected in the future.', 'Very interesting intro course!!', 'Excellent course, very practical and gives students new ideas by highlighting what other companies are doing.', 'Great learning opportunity', 'T', 'Thanks! You have made a great job on this course. ', 'Good course. This is not a course about technical skills but as a manager or part of senior management team, it will help to understand the foundation, objective, implementation and challenges of business analytics in organisations.', 'A lot of useful data in this course. Especially for someone interesting in understanding the potential of analytics for their organization and interested in designing a roadmap for implementing analytics.', 'The course provides interesting information and insights about the future of Business and Data Analytics, but for me, it was more into theory or general knowledge than something I can apply and use in my practical life experience and career development  ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Jay K', 'By Suman D', 'By Kristen S', 'By Erik M', 'By Raymond Y', 'By Darren T', 'By Jenny B', 'By Interna K', 'By Lata P', 'By Andre M N', 'By Victoria ', 'By Amit K', 'By José T', 'By Asem A']</reviewers><review_date>['May 02, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'Jun 20, 2019', 'May 27, 2019', 'May 28, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'Aug 09, 2019', 'May 08, 2019', 'Aug 22, 2019', 'Apr 25, 2019', 'May 28, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'May 07, 2019']</review_date></doc>