<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_45</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-introduction</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Big Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ilkay Altintas</course_instructor><course_introduction>Interested in increasing your knowledge of the Big Data landscape?  This course is for those new to data science and interested in understanding why the Big Data Era has come to be.  It is for those who want to become conversant with the terminology and the core concepts behind big data problems, applications, and systems.  It is for those who want to start thinking about how Big Data might be useful in their business or career.  It provides an introduction to one of the most common frameworks, Hadoop, that has made big data analysis easier and more accessible -- increasing the potential for data to transform our world!

At the end of this course, you will be able to:

* Describe the Big Data landscape including examples of real world big data problems including the three key sources of Big Data: people, organizations, and sensors. 

* Explain the V’s of Big Data (volume, velocity, variety, veracity, valence, and value) and why each impacts data collection, monitoring, storage, analysis and reporting.

* Get value out of Big Data by using a 5-step process to structure your analysis. 

* Identify what are and what are not big data problems and be able to recast big data problems as data science questions.

* Provide an explanation of the architectural components and programming models used for scalable big data analysis.

* Summarize the features and value of core Hadoop stack components including the YARN resource and job management system, the HDFS file system and the MapReduce programming model.

* Install and run a program using Hadoop!

This course is for those new to data science.  No prior programming experience is needed, although the ability to install applications and utilize a virtual machine is necessary to complete the hands-on assignments.  

Hardware Requirements:
(A) Quad Core Processor (VT-x or AMD-V support recommended), 64-bit; (B) 8 GB RAM; (C) 20 GB disk free. How to find your hardware information: (Windows): Open System by clicking the Start button, right-clicking Computer, and then clicking Properties; (Mac): Open Overview by clicking on the Apple menu and clicking “About This Mac.” Most computers with 8 GB RAM purchased in the last 3 years will meet the minimum requirements.You will need a high speed internet connection because you will be downloading files up to 4 Gb in size.  

Software Requirements:
This course relies on several open-source software tools, including Apache Hadoop. All required software can be downloaded and installed free of charge. Software requirements include: Windows 7+, Mac OS X 10.10+, Ubuntu 14.04+ or CentOS 6+ VirtualBox 5+.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Big Data//Apache Hadoop//Mapreduce//Cloudera</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome //Big Data: Why and Where//Characteristics of Big Data and Dimensions of Scalability//Data Science: Getting Value out of Big Data//Foundations for Big Data Systems and Programming//Systems: Getting Started with Hadoop</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Big Data Specialization', 'Tell us about yourself and learn about your classmates'], ['What launched the Big Data era?', 'Applications: What makes big data valuable', 'Example: Saving lives with Big Data', 'Example: Using Big Data to Help Patients', 'A Sentiment Analysis Success Story: Meltwater helping Danone', 'Getting Started: Where Does Big Data Come From?', "Machine-Generated Data: It's Everywhere and There's a Lot!", 'Machine-Generated Data: Advantages', 'Big Data Generated By People: The Unstructured Challenge', 'Big Data Generated By People: How Is It Being Used?', 'Organization-Generated Data: Structured but often siloed', 'Organization-Generated Data: Benefits Come From Combining With Other Data Types', 'The Key: Integrating Diverse Data'], ['Getting Started: Characteristics Of Big Data', 'Characteristics of Big Data - Volume', 'Characteristics of Big Data - Variety', 'Characteristics of Big Data - Velocity', 'Characteristics of Big Data - Veracity', 'Characteristics of Big Data - Valence', 'The Sixth V: Value'], ['Data Science: Getting Value out of Big Data', 'Building a Big Data Strategy', 'How does big data science happen?:  Five Components of Data Science', 'Asking the Right Questions', 'Steps in the Data Science Process', 'Step 1: Acquiring Data', 'Step 2-A: Exploring Data', 'Step 2-B: Pre-Processing Data', 'Step 3: Analyzing Data', 'Step 4: Communicating Results', 'Step 5: Turning Insights into Action'], ['Getting Started: Why worry about foundations?', 'What is a Distributed File System?', 'Scalable Computing over the Internet', 'Programming Models for Big Data'], ['Hadoop: Why, Where and Who?', 'The Hadoop Ecosystem: Welcome to the zoo!', 'The Hadoop Distributed File System: A Storage System for Big Data', 'YARN: A Resource Manager for Hadoop', 'MapReduce: Simple Programming for Big Results', 'When to Reconsider Hadoop?', 'Cloud Computing: An Important Big Data Enabler', 'Cloud Service Models: An Exploration of Choices', 'Value From Hadoop and Pre-built Hadoop Images', 'Copy your data into the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS)', 'Run the WordCount program']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Very interesting course.  Explained concepts I'd heard of but didn't really know about.  It is a foundation course for a specialization, it's not enough by itself but very good as a foundation course. ", 'I think the course could be shorten by half. The instructors extended the course into 3 weeks, but I think the real meat can fit into just 2 weeks. They use too many examples and several similar case studies to make the same points about why big data is important and beneficial -- repeatedly.', "The course provided almost no value , and there was almost nothing covered that you couldn't find online for free. The presentation was probably the worst part of the course: It was extremely boring and made it hard to get through the videos. ", 'Good intro that also helped me understand some of my previous assumptions', None, 'Perfect for starters!', "I have participated in better courses on Coursera. I think the power point presentations are very very ugly. The colors really don't match well. This could be a lot more visually appealing. Also, for self learners, a bit more text would be cool, even though I know that not having too much text, but rather pictures, is beneficial. The presenter could speak a bit more natural. At the moment, it is very obvious that she reads text aloud. Also, there need to be some more FAQs in the practical parts, because there can be quite a few problems when trying to run mapreduce. I was only able to do it using Google, because I also had to install another hadoop version (5.12.) because my Intel Chipset was not compatible with the version you wanted me to download. There, the file path to map reduce was different from the example you proviided. To be honest, I did not check the Discussion Forums because I was not aware there were any. Maybe I could have gotten help there.", 'The general concepts of big data (week 1 and week 2) seemed a bit drawn out, much of the same was repeated over and over again. This was not necessary. The peer-graded assignment needs more detailed instructions -  like mentioning that it is ok to resize the fields, and that shapes need to be copy/pasted as much as needed. ', 'The intro part is too long. You will not start with the practice till the end of next week and I find that the lectures and videos by then are a lot less complete even when the content is harder. I would have prefer is the theoretical part was shorter and there was more support when we start learning about hadoop', 'This was absolutely useless. Lots of definitions with no motivation. The one saving grace is that the slides are comprehensive.', 'Very information and knowledgeable', 'It is a fantastic platform to upgrade our skills and the way of teaching is every nice to hear and understandable really impressive.Thanks for this beautiful course ', 'I like to course work with interactive questions and guidelines.', 'Everything  was explained in brief manner with day to day examples . Thanks to Ilkay Altintas and Amarnath Gupta for their clear cut explanations and also my reviewers for my assignments . Such an awesome course for beginners.  Ample amount of time was given to finish this course successfully   ', 'this was a great short course for starters in big data analytics and hadoop. the teachers had an excellent in depth knowledge of their field and they communicated it a very learner and professional manner. ', 'This is a great introduction to Big data as well as introduction to tools related to big data.', 'Superb introduction to the concepts of Big data for total newcomers with a simple hands on exercise at the end. Well done team!', 'Excellent introduction to the world of Big Data', 'course is well designed and structured.', 'Great course! Detailed explanations in the basics of Big Data! Keep it up!!! ', 'This is an excellent course! The teachers are wonderful and the course design is very good! Highly recommended if you are new to Big Data!', 'Very good introduction course! Well rounded and well explained', 'awesome!!', 'Concise and Informative course! Excellent course material and teachers.', 'Great intro, nicely updated from the 2015 edition.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Catherine B', 'By Isara A', 'By Abdul K', 'By Matthew L M', 'By Jeffery T', 'By Rongon C', 'By Hendrik B', 'By Raivis J', 'By Patricia P', 'By Pranav V', 'By DHANRAJ N', 'By karra k k', 'By Bob J S', 'By MATHUMITHA .', 'By Ali S', 'By Nishit P', 'By Kosala W', 'By Shesh S', 'By Tejprakash U', 'By Siddhant Y', 'By Mic T', 'By LIU X', 'By keihan k', 'By Vikas G', 'By Bradley T D']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 08, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Sep 27, 2016', 'May 11, 2019', 'Aug 31, 2016', 'May 14, 2019', 'Dec 01, 2017', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019']</review_date></doc>