<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_168</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-driven-astronomy</course_url><course_name>Data-driven Astronomy</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Tara Murphy</course_instructor><course_introduction>Science is undergoing a data explosion, and astronomy is leading the way. Modern telescopes produce terabytes of data per observation, and the simulations required to model our observable Universe push supercomputers to their limits. To analyse this data scientists need to be able to think computationally to solve problems. In this course you will investigate the challenges of working with large datasets: how to implement algorithms that work; how to use databases to manage your data; and how to learn from your data with machine learning tools. The focus is on practical skills - all the activities will be done in Python 3, a modern programming language used throughout astronomy.

Regardless of whether you’re already a scientist, studying to become one, or just interested in how modern astronomy works ‘under the bonnet’, this course will help you explore astronomy: from planets, to pulsars to black holes.

Course outline:
Week 1: Thinking about data
- Principles of computational thinking
- Discovering pulsars in radio images

Week 2: Big data makes things slow
- How to work out the time complexity of algorithms
- Exploring the black holes at the centres of massive galaxies

Week 3: Querying data using SQL
- How to use databases to analyse your data
- Investigating exoplanets in other solar systems

Week 4: Managing your data
- How to set up databases to manage your data
- Exploring the lifecycle of stars in our Galaxy

Week 5: Learning from data: regression
- Using machine learning tools to investigate your data
- Calculating the redshifts of distant galaxies

Week 6: Learning from data: classification
- Using machine learning tools to classify your data
- Investigating different types of galaxies

Each week will also have an interview with a data-driven astronomy expert.

Note that some knowledge of Python is assumed, including variables, control structures, data structures, functions, and working with files.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Physics and Astronomy</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Machine Learning//Applied Machine Learning//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>The University of Sydney</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Thinking about data//Big data makes things slow//Querying your data//Managing your data//Learning from data: regression//Learning from data: classification</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Thinking about data', 'Course overview', 'Pulsars', 'Diving in: imaging stacking', "Challenge: the median doesn't scale", 'The solution: improving your method', 'Module summary', 'Interview with Aris Karastergiou'], ['Big data makes things slow', 'Supermassive black holes', 'What is cross-matching?', 'Evaluating time complexity', 'A (much) faster algorithm', 'Module summary', 'Interview with Brendon Brewer'], ['Organising your data', 'Exoplanets', 'Querying database with SQL', 'More advanced SQL', 'Joining tables in SQL', 'Module summary', 'Interview with Jon Jenkins'], ['Managing your big datasets', 'The lifecycle of stars', 'Setting up your own database', 'Exploring a star cluster', 'Module summary', 'Interview with Emily Petroff'], ['Learning from data', 'The cosmological distance scale', 'What is machine learning?', 'Decision tree classifiers', 'Estimating redshifts using regression', 'Summary', 'Interview with Ashish Mahabal'], ['Classifying your data', 'Types of galaxies', 'Morphological classification of galaxies', 'Limitations of decision tree classifiers', 'Improving our results with ensemble classifiers', 'Module summary', 'Interview with Karen Masters']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I finished this course today. If you want to learn advanced concepts like machine learning, decision tree classification, SQL, and more; then this is the course for you! I'm a senior in high school, and I'm going to major in Astrophysics. If you love Computer Science this will be an interesting course, as it will show the applications of CS to Astronomy.", 'This is a well set course. I have completed one week and I loved blend of maths, astronomy and tools!Course content is not outdated, which is really important for a field like this.', None, 'Starting from the basics and going into ml - nice content :) iIloved the idea to solve more interresting problems, not only house-price-predict. I would like to see more of such courses in the future. Thank you :)', 'Muy recomendable', 'The course was just epic. Anyone who wants to learn about the application of Machine Learning in the field of Astronomy , this course is a must. The activities will be like the instructor is sitting just by your side, and guiding you, which is what any beginner wants to start their journey. The course is just awesome.  ', 'This class is incredible and inspirational. I learned so many highly applicable skills and I am very glad to have taken this class in its entirety. Thank you! ', 'I enjoyed this fusion of programming with Astronomy topics.  Note that the exercises use the Python programming language (no substitutes permitted), fairly generic Structured Query Language (SQL) for databases, numpy (science math tools) Python library, scikit-learn (machine learning) Python library, and matplotlib (math &amp; plotting) Python library. ', 'Excellent presentation and delivery method by the instructors and very good course content. Highly recommend it anyone curious about Universe and to understand it better!', 'Besides being a Senior Developer, and Junior Data Scientist, I also am a Self Taught astronomer, and this course has given me a lot of knowledge and insights about astronomy, andways in which I can practice my self learning carrear in astronomy (and maybe astrophysics?) Awesome course! Highly recommended!', 'very good course, with clear technical explination and interesting', 'What I liked about the course was the graded programming assignments, which help to introduce a person to machine learning techniques and other problems in astronomy data processing.  Being a physics student by formal education and a star gazer too, I am familiar with the theory but was always curious about how to they measure distances, how do they measure red-shifts etc when the distant galaxies are themselves so faint. This course helped me understand these stuff....', 'Very professional, very productive', 'Fantastic! I learned a lot. The exercises were really interesting!', 'Perfect to brush up my Python skills while studying a fascinating subject!', 'This is a very well organized, interesting, and, quite frankly, fun class. I especially liked being able to do hands-on exercises in Python. ', 'Fue un excelente curso , me ayuda mucho para poder intentar el procesado de unos catalogos de galaxias en especial la parte del machine learning aplicado ', 'Interesting, engaging and informative!', 'Ultimate Course,A proper mixture of Data Science,Statistics,Machine learning and Astronomy.Loved it', 'Although, I gave a five star, but I have following notes:', 'Very good intraductional course to modern astronomy that is nowadys more and more science about data. Not so much astronomy theory but good programing tasks, sometimes challenging, especially in the starting weeks. As addition some introduction in machine learning is provided. I would recommend it to everyone interested in data analysis in modern science.', 'The course is fantastic for those who want to work in the field of high-energy astrophysics. Many useful skills are taught during the course and many interesting activities are proposed. I highly recommend it.', 'Unique course, very much excited to learn new things', 'Most of all courses in astronomy and astrophysics are just introduction to subject or provides little advanced theoretical perspective but this is one of the courses which teach us practical astronomy and let us have insights of how astronomers really use physics as well as computers to to get something good out of it.', 'I have a profound admiration for this course and its professors.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ayush N', 'By avinash', 'By João P M', 'By Maciej K', 'By Diego J M G', 'By Samrat M', 'By Josh C', 'By Richard E', 'By Abdul A', 'By Juan M H', 'By Daniel N', 'By Atul N', 'By Behzad B A', 'By Sara D', 'By Richard O', 'By Michael W', 'By miguel a', 'By Mark M', 'By SOURABH S', 'By Alan M', 'By Nazarov A P', 'By Maksym M', 'By Anurag A', 'By Akash M P', 'By Cooper P']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 21, 2018', 'Jun 21, 2018', 'Jul 15, 2017', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Mar 08, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Oct 12, 2017', 'Jul 17, 2017', 'Jun 28, 2017', 'Sep 14, 2017', 'Sep 10, 2017', 'Sep 28, 2017']</review_date></doc>