<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_58</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-statistics-financial-analysis</course_url><course_name>Python and Statistics for Financial Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Xuhu Wan</course_instructor><course_introduction>Course Overview: https://youtu.be/JgFV5qzAYno

Python is now becoming the number 1 programming language for data science. Due to python’s simplicity and high readability, it is gaining its importance in the financial industry.  The course combines both python coding and statistical concepts and applies into analyzing financial data, such as stock data.

By the end of the course, you can achieve the following using python:

- Import, pre-process, save and visualize financial data into pandas Dataframe

- Manipulate the existing financial data by generating new variables using multiple columns

- Recall and apply the important statistical concepts (random variable, frequency, distribution, population and sample, confidence interval, linear regression, etc. ) into financial contexts

- Build a trading model using multiple linear regression model 

- Evaluate the performance of the trading model using different investment indicators

Jupyter Notebook environment is configured in the course platform for practicing python coding without installing any client applications.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Finance</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Visualizing and Munging Stock Data//Random variables and distribution//Sampling and Inference //Linear Regression Models for Financial Analysis</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course overview', '1.0 Module Introduction', '1.1 Packages for Data Analysis', '1.2 Importing data', '1.3 Basics of Dataframe', '1.4 Generate new variables in Dataframe', '1.5 Trading Strategy'], ['2.0 Module Introduction', '2.1 Outcomes and Random Variables', '2.2 Frequency and Distributions', '2.3 Models of Distribution'], ['3.0 Introduction', '3.1 Population and Sample', '3.2 Variation of Sample', '3.3 Confidence Interval', '3.4 Hypothesis Testing'], ['4.0 Introduction', '4.1 Association of random variables', '4.2 Simple linear regression model', '4.3 Diagnostic of linear regression model', '4.4 Multiple linear regression model', '4.5 Evaluate the strategy']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It is a good course overall, combining the basics of statistics, Python and finance.  I've learned a lot from it.  I think the students can benefit more if additional suggested reading materials can be provided, so that if one lacks a strong background in a particular discipline, one can find out more outside the course.  Also will be helpful if slides can be downloaded.", 'this course is very practical! it explains how statistic concepts can be applied into financial-related examples using python. ', 'I had only basic knowledge of python and very basic knowledge of statistic - most of which I had not put to use, since leaving school.  This course was a helped me to get more confidence with using python in a practical way.  In the process I also brushed up my statistical skills - there is no better way to understand statistics then to apply in real-life scenarios as explained in this course.  And python packages makes learning fun, by taking off the difficult computation tasks.  Overall I would recommend this course to anyone who has interest in learning how to apply statistics and python to analysing data.', 'V', 'This gives a application of all the three famous sectors viz, finance, python and statistics. Actually speaking i am searching for these kind of courses and did not get one. Atlast got this one for my solace.  This suited my need.  This course cannot be easily designed as other courses . This really needs one time . Thanks to the person who devised the course and also to the instructor Mr. Xuhu Wan for his meticulous time to provide the information in a precise way. ', "The lecture videos were very helpful to my studies. The teacher was able to explain the materials very clearly. However, I this course doesn't fit my expectations. The reason why is because I wanted to learn how to code in Python. This course emphasizes more on the business side and it doesn't provide an opportunity for us to actually learning the basics of coding in Python. I only learned a few useful terms in Python.", '【Now you know Prof. Xuhu Wan, please avoid his course in HKUST】', 'Good and very practical course! Looking forward to next parts considering more complex models.', 'Overall, the course was good, but I felt that the course was a bit abrupt in its ending, as I would have wanted to learn about nonlinear regression models, making more trading strategies, and automatic the process using Python.', 'A short course that shows how to handle time series data, run a multiple linear regression on it, and evaluate the results. This is only an introductory course, and as such it is clear and concise and thus deserving of 5 stars. However it only touches the surface of Python, statistics or trading. As for trading - before risking Real Money - it is strongly advised to learn much more on the subject of stock markets.', 'very', 'I enjoy very much', 'this is a wonderful course with well-prepared videos to illustrate and well-organised Notebook for practice. the final score you will get is only depended on four quizzes, but it is always useful for you to watch videos carefully and try very best to type codes on Notebook provided for you, which can also benefit your quizzes. you can some basic sentence structure of Python and grasp the practical tool to build a model to make financial inference. with light workload, you can get a lot. ', 'I great and easy-to-understand course to learn python for basic statistics!', None, "\nIt is a very good course to learn the basics in python to analyze \nfinancial stock market data. However, if you don't have prior knowledge \nto statistics and financial data (variance, histograms, regressions, \nvalue at risk, hypothesis testing, ...), the course might be to fast to \nunderstand the background, because you cannot explain all these things \nproperly in 2-3 hours of video. But I guess most people who want to \nanalyze stock data in python have this knowledge.\n        \n\n", 'friendly to beginners', 'Great course by a great instructor.', 'Great course that makes your basics very clear. to top it all the course is taught by an excellent tutor.', 'Hard subject to grasp for a novice, but material and professor was superb!', 'Nice Introduction!', None, 'Clear instruction and very useful python code for applied case study.', 'This course was really enjoyable : well structured, a likeable professor and very useful and illustrative exercises. the use of Jupyter notebooks was also a very good idea.', 'I learned a lot about how to implement financial statistics in Python and some added knowledge on statistics. Great Course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Cheuk W K', 'By Helena K', 'By Satish N', 'By carlo', 'By sabarinathan r', 'By Ezekiel J T', 'By Zeyu H', 'By Egor S', 'By Giancarlo G', 'By Yaron K', 'By Ruikun D', 'By Santiago L C', 'By Shuhong L', 'By Yau T H', 'By Donovan A', 'By Tobias T', 'By DING G', 'By Adrian B W', 'By SHIVAM B', 'By RS', 'By Feiting X', 'By Gary C', 'By Jing H', 'By Boudokhane M', 'By Steven D']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 01, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Apr 16, 2019', 'May 01, 2019', 'May 01, 2019']</review_date></doc>