<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_2</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/what-is-datascience</course_url><course_name>What is Data Science?</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Aklson</course_instructor><course_introduction>The art of uncovering the insights and trends in data has been around since ancient times. The ancient Egyptians used census data to increase efficiency in tax collection and they accurately predicted the flooding of the Nile river every year. Since then, people working in data science have carved out a unique and distinct field for the work they do. This field is data science. In this course, we will meet some data science practitioners and we will get an overview of what data science is today.

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Defining Data Science and What Data Scientists Do//Data Science Topics//Data Science in Business</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What is Data Science?', 'The Many Paths to Data Science', 'Advice for New Data Scientists', 'A day in the Life of a Data Scientist', 'Data Science Topics and Algorithms', 'What is the cloud?'], ['Data Science Skills &amp; Big Data', 'Data Scientists at New York University', 'What is Hadoop?', 'Neural Networks and Deep Learning', 'How Can Someone Become a Data Scientist?', 'High School Students and Data Science Careers', 'Applications of Machine Learning'], ['How Should Companies Get Started in Data Science?', 'Recruiting for Data Science', 'Applications of Data Science']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 6 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very basic course, to be honest.  The grading seemed to be dependent on memorizing exact quotes from videos.  Looking forward to some of the more advanced courses in this series.', 'Videos often have disjointed or unrelated elements. Final week quizzes and mid-video questions often have useless or otherwise unhelpful reading questions. An example from week three\'s final quiz, "True or False: The Untied States Economic Forecast is a publication by McKinsey University Press." The answer is false and is covered in the reading, but the question has absolutely nothing to do with data science. ', 'Too much introduction. There is no need to spend so much time on it. People that take this course usually understand what is data science. they need to learn real knowledge, not spend the whole week on introduction. ', 'Too basic. ', 'This was a good introductory course, especially as someone with basically zero experience in the field. I\'ve been struggling with where to begin (should I take a course on Python? R? What languages are even useful? WTF is cloud computing?) And this course gave me a good starting off point. That said, it wasn\'t technical AT ALL. It\'s really just a bunch of "fireside chats" with data scientists, talking about the languages they use, what concepts they\'re used for, what knowledge is necessary and what isn\'t, etc. If you\'re looking for a "roadmap" to continue learning on Coursera, this is it. ', 'Good overview of data science, its history, and uses of data science.', 'Very nice course and it has a piece of very nice information taught by professionals. The content is related to the practical application of concepts which increase interest in you to proceed further', 'I liked this course very much. The way it is organised to collect different data scientists opinions about the same topic, make it very valuable to the ones who are starting the road to Data Science.', 'Very, very basic... completely useless and a waste of time. I feel like the only purpose of this course is to drag out the certification process so that it costs you more money...', 'Good for fundamental knowledge of data science and data scientists.', 'useless, wasting time', 'This course is not consistent with someone who would sign up for an entire certificate. This course is more suitable as a recruitment tool for a certificate program. Watching these videos was an absolute waste of my time.', 'This is a great course for anyone willing to start exploring the field of Data Science. It starts with basic definitions with proper examples that helps one understand this field with a greater ease!', 'It was a good introduction for everyone even novice.', 'This was a nice and easy course, but the material was quite obvious and not new and could be included in one week lessons of another course.', 'Good contents and brief understanding about Data Science', 'It encompasses fine details to introduce data science and explore data scientists as a career.', 'This is a very good introduction to what actually is data science! Lot of people gets really confused with the definitions and area! ', "Friendly and gentle introduction to data science! Can't wait to go further...", 'Great introduction to Data Science!', "Direct to the point. Increases one's passion to study Data Science by summarizing the main topics. Simple and brilliant", "I have learnt about what the data science is and it's basic knowledge. I am glad I took the course. I will continue finishing the rest of the courses. ", "Excellent quality content! It's a great introductory course that really gets you interested in Data Science. I would highly recommend it to anyone curious in learning about what Data Science is about.", 'Great for introduction!', 'It does in fact answer a basic, fundamental question;  what is Data Science?']</reviews><reviewers>['By Kevin M', 'By Aman J', 'By Jianfei Z', 'By Pooja S', 'By Lauren J', 'By Robert C', 'By Govardhana', 'By Xhuljana M', 'By Julian L G', 'By CHIN-HUNG, Y', 'By lianghui t', 'By Mark L', 'By Akshay B', 'By souro', 'By Nathan S', 'By Huyen P', 'By Mahesh K', 'By Kanchan P', 'By Erik M', 'By Andrew F', 'By Sergi', 'By longmen', 'By Bradly', 'By Ferry T', 'By Dwight F']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 25, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Apr 19, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'Jun 02, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'May 06, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Aug 20, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019']</review_date></doc>