<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_56</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-quantitative-modeling</course_url><course_name>Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Richard Waterman</course_instructor><course_introduction>How can you put data to work for you? Specifically, how can numbers in a spreadsheet tell us about present and past business activities, and how can we use them to forecast the future? The answer is in building quantitative models, and this course is designed to help you understand the fundamentals of this critical, foundational, business skill. Through a series of short lectures, demonstrations, and assignments, you’ll learn the key ideas and process of quantitative modeling so that you can begin to create your own models for your own business or enterprise. By the end of this course, you will have seen a variety of practical commonly used quantitative models as well as the building blocks that will allow you to start structuring your own models. These building blocks will be put to use in the other courses in this Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Modeling//Linear Regression//Probabilistic Models//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Introduction to Models //Module 2: Linear Models and Optimization//Module 3: Probabilistic Models//Module 4: Regression Models</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.1 Course Introduction', '1.2 Definition and Uses of Models, Common Functions', '1.3 How Models Are Used in Practice', '1.4 Key Steps in the Modeling Process', '1.5 A Vocabulary for Modeling', '1.6 Mathematical Functions', '1.7 Summary'], ['2.1 Introduction to Linear Models and Optimization', '2.2 Growth in Discrete Time', '2.3 Constant Proportionate Growth', '2.4 Present and Future Value', '2.5 Optimization', '2.6 Summary'], ['3.1 Introduction to Probabilistic Models', '3.2 Examples of Probabilistic Models', '3.3 Regression Models', '3.4 Probability Trees', '3.5 Monte Carlo Simulations', '3.6 Markov Chain Models', '3.7 Building Blocks of Probability Models', '3.8 The Bernoulli Distribution', '3.9 The Binomial Distribution', '3.10 The Normal Distribution', '3.11 The Empirical Rule', '3.12 Summary'], ['4.1 Introduction to Regression Model', '4.2 Use of Regression Models', '4.3 Interpretation of Regression Coefficients', '4.4 R-squared and Root Mean Squared Error (RMSE)', '4.5 Fitting Curves to Data', '4.6 Multiple Regression', '4.7 Logistic Regression', '4.8 Summary of Regression Models']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I really enjoyed this course. Although I have had exposure to these topics in the past I really enjoyed the teaching style, the clarity with which the topics were presented, and the practical applications. Additionally I found the Coursera platform useful as I could pause, 'rewind', and review concepts as needed.", "Richard Waterman is good at explaining. The level is basic but he advances some useful interpretations of common expressions. For someone like myself with experience in modeling in a different field (biological processes) the examples from the business world are very much appreciated. Learning modeling and statistics is not hard. The hard part is becoming wise at using them. Modeling won't spare you from being creative.", 'this course was a very basic and very useful course to start with any quant related career .', 'This is a good course for all of them who wish to work in this field and are unable to do so because of lack of core knowledge. The course helps to build this fundamental conceptual knowledge.', 'Very good background to quantitative modelling. It gets a bit heavy on the mathematical formulas in places, but if you follow through, it helps cement understanding. Good speed/pace of material.', 'It’s a fantastic experience   i have ever earned.    ', 'The professor is very humble and excellent in teaching. Every aspect is covered in the course. ', 'This course has the right approach to the beginner. I thoroughly enjoyed the course. I learned the basics of how can we relate a quantitative models in real world business. ', 'AMAGING COURSE', 'Fantastic course. Easy to pick and a great teacher.', 'The materials are explained clearly, although they might be considered a little too easy.', 'Very nice course for beginner, the mathematic level is not high (around french baccalaureat) so available to everyone. I enjoyed a lot this course that show how simple math can be used in real life.', 'Great course to refresh basics of modeling and econometrics. Very well structured for both beginners and those who want to refresh their knowledge. Do not expect to be fully capable to create models after only this part of the specialization. ', 'Very engaging class. Thanks', "Very clear and articulate explanation of the concepts.  He doesn't skip a step in the sequencing ideas, drawing comparisons and differences, and illustrating both visually and story-telling.  Excellent. ", "The course curriculum covers all the major topics that I needed. With a little bit of extra effort and googling the concepts of probability that I didn't know, I was able to grasp the course. The quiz helped a lot to assess my progress. The only downside of the course is that there aren't many questions on the discussion forum.", 'excellent course', 'Very easy to follow, and a very suitable introductory class. ', 'Very informative, insightful, and useful for those interested in developing a foundation in quantitative modeling. ', 'The teacher has clear logic in class and can explain quantitative modeling systematically', 'This is a very well structured course focused right at building a solid base for modelling. Many new ideas were discussed and some good examples were used along the way and in the end of module questions as well to test the understanding. I would highly recommend this course to beginners. ', "It's very easy to understand.", 'easy to learn ', 'Good fundamental lessons!', 'Fairly straightforward and provided good content, but intros and summaries were often unnecessary and it seemed that a low percentage of the content was new material being learned. Still enjoyed it and learned useful terminology']</reviews><reviewers>['By Greg A', 'By Omar G A', 'By Shubham s', 'By Jaydeep C', 'By Nash M', 'By Armin S', 'By Jay B M', 'By Bimarsh G', 'By Sumanyu M', 'By Stephane F', 'By Junqing S', 'By Nathan L c', 'By Maria C', 'By Francis D', 'By Arona P', 'By Abhinav C', 'By Vaibhav N', 'By Arvin M', 'By Sumukh S', 'By 许坤荣', 'By Varun P', 'By Palash D', 'By Sandeep C', 'By 刘雨心怡', 'By Farouk G']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 27, 2018', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2018', 'Jul 23, 2017', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Nov 01, 2018', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Jun 16, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2019', 'Jul 12, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019']</review_date></doc>