<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_387</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/statistics-project</course_url><course_name>Statistics with R Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Merlise A Clyde</course_instructor><course_introduction>The capstone project will be an analysis using R that answers a specific scientific/business question provided by the course team. A large and complex dataset will be provided to learners and the analysis will require the application of a variety of methods and techniques introduced in the previous courses, including exploratory data analysis through data visualization and numerical summaries, statistical inference, and modeling as well as interpretations of these results in the context of the data and the research question. The analysis will implement both frequentist and Bayesian techniques and discuss in context of the data how these two approaches are similar and different, and what these differences mean for conclusions that can be drawn from the data.
 
A sampling of the final projects will be featured on the Duke Statistical Science department website.

Note: Only learners who have passed the four previous courses in the specialization are eligible to take the Capstone.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Model Selection//Bayesian Statistics//Statistical Analysis//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About the Capstone Project//Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA)//EDA and Basic Model Selection - Submission//EDA and Basic Model Selection - Evaluation//Model Selection and Diagnostics//Out of Sample Prediction//Final Data Analysis - Submission//Final Data Analysis - Evaluation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Statistics with R Capstone course'], ['What to Do This Week', 'EDA Quiz - Assignment Guide'], ['What to Do This Week'], ['What to Do This Week'], ['What to Do This Week', 'Model Selection and Diagnostics Quiz - Assignment Guide'], ['What do Do This Week', 'Out of Sample Prediction Quiz - Assignment Guide'], ['What to Do This Week'], ['What to Do This Week']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This section guides you through performing a complete analysis. Some of the grading criteria are inconsistent with the tasks stated in the project. However, in my experience giving the kind of report that you'd generate from R markdown to a non-technical, non-statistically minded stakeholder will result in bewilderment. While Rmd is a good format for documenting your approach and creating a reproducible data analysis, the report presented to stakeholders should take a much different form. In writing an Rmd, you are necessarily constrained by the need to write code in a particular order -- that order may not be the most beneficial one to present. Furthermore, having long summary output of various models and other such code is generally not helpful to non-technical stakeholders. I understand that not using Rmd would make grading more difficult, so I'm ok with Rmd being used here. But I think that it would be good to explain this all to students.", "This Capstone has giving me a good understanding of statistic's, and the role this discipline plays in the real world. A special thanks to Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel I feel that she does an amazing job communicating the concepts.", 'Thank you very much for teaching me all the statistics courses in the specialization. Although it is an online study, I think I benefit a lot from the course contents, quizzes and problem sets and the training from final projects one by one. Also, I appreciate a lot the feedback from other students in the courses, which gives me more confidence on my study. As a matter of fact, I know I still have a lot of room to improve on my final project, such as consistency of EDA with the later part of my project, assessment on residual plots, real understanding on the trade off between model interpretation and prediction accuracy, etc., which I will improve in my future study and analysis.  No matter where and what I will study in the future, I always bring the statistics knowledge and R skills that I learned from my first specialization from professors at Duke University. Thank you.', 'Loved this course', "Great course, learned a lot and got me started on another project that I've turned into a really nice portfolio item. I feel much more comfortable with R and statistics principles. ", 'Great! Enjoyed it!', 'Very good ! ', 'The capstone project is an excellent way to utilise the skills and knowledge learnt from the previous 4 courses in the specialisation. I learnt a lot about conducting a data science project from start to finish and it allows for ample time to experiment with different approaches to accomplish the project goals. This capstone project, and the 5-course specialisation, is highly recommended.', 'I think this is a very advisable course as a whole, The capstone offers a good occasion to put into practice what has been learned during the four previous courses and also works as a sort of review. ', 'The Capstone project really helped tie the program together', "This was a highly challenging sequence of four courses and capstone, but worth the considerable investment in time and effort.  Overall, with just a few glitches here and there, the specialization was superbly taught and well-designed.  I thank Mine and the rest of the Stats team at Duke for offering it.  I would also like to see Bayesian Stats made perhaps into two courses.  Or even a follow-up Bayesian course perhaps not required for the specialization.  Professor M. Clyde  is one of the world's leading experts on Bayes, and the creator of the BAS package.  All respect!  I would like to have more of her teaching, but at a  slightly less steeper learning curve. To my fellow students and the Duke team, thanks again.", None, 'Excellent course', 'Sometimes capstone courses are focused just on a final project. In this case, the capstone also includes quizzes which force you to review material that will be helpful in doing the final project. Overall, I would say that I felt a little behind compared to my peers in this specialization, since I started from zero; but on the other hand, I was still able to successfully complete it, so with a lot of hard work it is possible.', 'Great lead up to a final capstone project, in which you test a model for overfitting and validate on out-of-sample data.', 'Strong Capstone Project', 'Very interesting project, a great real-world application example. Highly recommended to anyone that finishes the previous classes.', 'Great', 'A very useful and practical course. The learner had an opportunity to practice the skills he/she learned in the previous course and use it in a real-life situation.', 'V', 'Great, comprehensive way to utilise all of skills obtained during this specialization!', 'Excellent', "This project will reward you for the time you invest. It's a good simulation of a real-world exercise in using concepts from the specialization. The reason I took away one star is because the grading rubrics at every step are relatively superficial, sometimes absurdly superficial. ", 'I will recommend to give the information about the projects even if the proect starts in September 10th so we could advance while enrollment opens up. ', 'We spent several months waiting for this capstone to appear. The instructors dissapeared and nobody knew if this one was going finally to happen or what. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Erik F', 'By Louis S', 'By Dai Q', 'By Jim F', 'By Adam C', 'By Marina Z ', 'By Vinh H', 'By Jian W T', 'By José L E N', 'By andy d', 'By Thomas J H', 'By José M C', 'By Roland', 'By Matthew L', 'By Ryan W', 'By Arjun B', 'By Minas-Marios V', 'By Albert C G', 'By Chin J L', 'By PAUL M', 'By Joanna L', 'By Tom M', 'By Bruce H', 'By Janio A M', 'By Gonzalo C S']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 19, 2017', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Apr 26, 2017', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Jul 13, 2017', 'Aug 01, 2017', 'Oct 13, 2017', 'Dec 04, 2017', 'Mar 24, 2017', 'Apr 04, 2017', 'Aug 24, 2017', 'Mar 22, 2017', 'Feb 02, 2018', 'May 14, 2018', 'Nov 15, 2017', 'Feb 22, 2018', 'Jun 11, 2017', 'Jul 02, 2017', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Aug 19, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2017', 'Dec 06, 2017', 'Aug 15, 2018', 'Apr 04, 2017']</review_date></doc>