<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_359</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-analysis-project-pwc</course_url><course_name>Data Analysis and Presentation Skills: the PwC Approach Final Project</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Mannella</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this Capstone Project, you'll bring together all the new skills and insights you've learned through the four courses. You'll be given a 'mock' client problem and a data set. You'll need to analyze the data to gain business insights, research the client's domain area, and create recommendations. You'll then need to visualize the data in a client-facing presentation. You'll bring it all together in a recorded video presentation.

This course was created by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP with an address at 300 Madison Avenue, New York, New York, 10017.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>PwC</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Understanding the Business Problem //Analyzing the Business Problem//Creating a visual representation of your analysis results //Building a presentation for the client meeting //Presenting your results to the client</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Course 5', 'A Message from our Chief People Officer at PwC', 'Overview of the first assignment'], ['Week 2 - Overview of the second assignment'], ['Week 3 - Overview of the third assignment'], ['Week 4 - Overview of the fourth assignment'], ['Week 5 - Overview of the fifth assignment', 'Course closing - Outcomes from Electric Growers', 'Course closing &amp; Thank you', 'Specialization closing', 'Get Personal with Alex Mannella Podcast - Day in the Life']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This project (more than a course) is very interesting, allows to reuse all the skills acquired during the other 4 courses of the specialization. The learner still have room to conduct his own analysis, build his hypotheses and deliver the presentation ! A great training ! :)', 'Great!!!', 'This course taught me a lot of best practices and many Excel skills.  I am thankful to have had the opportunity to complete the course, and it has already proven helpful at work.', None, 'Excellent specialization! Perfect for beginners!', 'Great Course!', 'Great ', 'Great course! ', 'Awesome course', 'ok', 'Final and fifth course of the PWC specialisation. You will work 5 weeks : on excel for 3 weeks, powerpoint for 1 week and do a final presentation of your work in video.', 'Excellent', 'It was a very motivating course as I had to take together all the concepts that I had learned in previous courses to solve a challenging business project and present the solution to a real client.', 'I think it is a great course t', 'This project was very interesting.', 'Amazing experience!! i Enjoyed every minute spent on this course. ', 'Thanks a lot for this valuable Course Pwc', 'Great learning experience  REAAAAAALLLLLY :)', 'great assignments, great quizzes! You actually are applying your skills.', 'Great course!', 'Good source of practical materials! Thank you for the insights.', "There is no proper guidelines for students who don't have any marketing research or data analysis background as such. The previous courses are not helpful in solving this project either!", '.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Pierre S', 'By Cristiano S', 'By Jason S', 'By David P I', 'By Nicolas S', 'By Sagi S', 'By Pawel S', 'By Manoel L C N', 'By Dickson P', 'By Paula C F', 'By Bernard D V ', 'By Jaspreet k', 'By Jose P B', 'By Felix B', 'By Oleksandr T', 'By Filippos A', 'By Bilal A M S', 'By Dina R', 'By sutan a m', 'By Humberto J', 'By Anastasiia M', 'By Muaaz H H', 'By Diego B F']</reviewers><review_date>['May 30, 2018', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Aug 04, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2017', 'Feb 20, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2018', 'Jun 25, 2017', 'May 16, 2018', 'Jun 26, 2017', 'Nov 15, 2017', 'Aug 28, 2017', 'Jul 03, 2017', 'Sep 18, 2017', 'Sep 01, 2017', 'Jun 27, 2017', 'May 05, 2018', 'May 06, 2019', 'Sep 08, 2019', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'Dec 01, 2017', 'Sep 12, 2017']</review_date></doc>