<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_245</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-management</course_url><course_name>Research Data Management and Sharing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Helen Tibbo</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will provide learners with an introduction to research data management and sharing. After completing this course, learners will understand the diversity of data and their management needs across the research data lifecycle, be able to identify the components of good data management plans, and be familiar with best practices for working with data including the organization, documentation, and storage and security of data. Learners will also understand the impetus and importance of archiving and sharing data as well as how to assess the trustworthiness of repositories. 

Today, an increasing number of funding agencies, journals, and other stakeholders are requiring data producers to share, archive, and plan for the management of their data. In order to respond to these requirements, researchers and information professionals will need the data management and curation knowledge and skills that support the long-term preservation, access, and reuse of data. Effectively managing data can also help optimize research outputs, increase the impact of research, and support open scientific inquiry. After completing this course, learners will be better equipped to manage data throughout the entire research data lifecycle from project planning to the end of the project when data ideally are shared and made available within a trustworthy repository.

This course was developed by the Curating Research Assets and Data Using Lifecycle Education (CRADLE) Project in collaboration with EDINA at the University of Edinburgh. 

This course was made possible in part by the Institute of Museum and Library Services under award #RE-06-13-0052-13. The views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in this Research Data Management and Sharing MOOC do not necessarily represent those of the Institute of Museum and Library Services.

Hashtag: #RDMSmooc</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Management Plan//Research Data Archiving//Metadata//Data Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Understanding Research Data//Data Management Planning//Working with Data//Sharing Data//Archiving Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Research Data Defined', 'Types of Data and Metadata', 'Research Data Lifecycle', 'Why Manage Data?', 'Data Management Stakeholders', 'Data Management Across the Research Lifecycle', '"What Are Data?"', '"Why is Data Management Important?"'], ['Introduction to Data Management Plans', 'Funding Agency Requirements', 'Data Management Plan Content', 'Data Management Planning Tools'], ['Good File Management in Research', 'File Naming', 'Versioning', 'File Formats', 'Data Transformations', 'Documentation', 'Data Citation', 'Storage', 'Backup', 'Data Security', 'Encryption', 'Interview - Natalia Calanzani', 'Interview - Shaun Bevan', '"How does good data management add value to research?"', '"Do you think data sharing helps to reduce waste and increase transparency of research?"'], ['Benefits of Sharing', 'Challenges to Sharing', 'Data Citations', 'Protecting Confidentiality (Part 1)', 'Protecting Confidentiality (Part 2)', 'Intellectual Property and Data Ownership', 'Access', '"What Are the Benefits of Sharing Data?"', '"What Are the Drawbacks of Sharing Data?"'], ['Why Archive Data?', 'Authenticity and Integrity', 'Metadata', 'Demonstrating Trustworthiness', 'Data Curation Standards and Best Practices (Part 1)', 'Data Curation Standards and Best Practices (Part 2)', '"Why is Archiving Data Important?"', '"Why is Digital Preservation Important?"', 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I manage data for researchers who have not been practicing good research data for more than a decade. This course has helped me fill in things that I missed in my education and has also helped me form an arsenal of information to help make the case for better creation of research data.', 'I would recommend the course for everyone who is either beginner or an intermediate researcher like me', 'This is a very uptodate course for interested learner in this modern age for any branch of  student.', 'Great overview of the field.  There was perhaps a bit too much emphases on archiving.  I would have personally benefited from more time on metadata standards.  However, I thought it was a good introduction and it made me want to do a deeper dive into a few key aspects of data management.', "I probably should wait to finish this course before reviewing, but I'm halfway through and have found my motivation gone--I'm finishing it just to finish it. The delivery adds nothing to the content, especially as much of it is simply the presenters reading lists also shown on screen. Class content would better serve the students as a searchable PDF. And why are there super-specific questions on quizzes about things like what specific funders require in a grant proposal? That's information that you look up when you need it, not that you quiz people on. This class is a let down.", 'T', 'It was a pleasure to be in this course and I got a huge benefit from it', 'Good Course', 'Good', 'Great course, the instructors were clear and concise. I had zero knowledge of DM before this course and this course show the basics and essential at least to start to talk about data management. Absolutely indispensable to anyone doing research of any type. Kudos to the teachers!', 'Excellent course!', "Un cours très bien construit. Des vidéo claires, et des petits exercices plein de sens qui permettent d'appliquer les principes vus dans les autres documents", 'I took this course having no prior knowledge of the subject area. The course was informative, and well done. I have gained a good introduction, and consider the time well spent. The content presentation and instructor engagement are a plus. ', None, 'Great foundation course', 'very good content and suplementary reading materials !!!', None, 'Thank you so much coursera. I am so delighted. ', 'I will use this!!!', 'I found this to be an excellent course. I have been teaching myself about data management for about the last two years as part of my work. I have read many documents, taken one course and have been to a couple of workshops. But I still felt that I was missing a lot of information - especially if I am to help researchers with their DMPs. Finally, thanks to this course, I have the more in depth information that I need. The topics covered, and the way they were covered  also helped me to paint a better picture in my mind of the "whole process of data management" - an not just disjointed information which I felt I had.  ', None, 'very interesting course', 'The course offers very good introduction to research data management and sharing. Not only useful for researchers, information professional that are assisting researchers but also  professionals managing the research projects and related data on behalf of funder to maximise the use of research data.  ', 'great job', 'Great course!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Jessica n', 'By Gulam M A K', 'By MD. R A', 'By Alexis K', 'By Johanna G', 'By Obileye O', 'By Mohamad K A', 'By Erick A M C', 'By ESTALYN A S M', 'By Sergio  U', 'By Nicolas C T', 'By Alain M', 'By Mina P', 'By Josiline C', 'By Leila T A', 'By priyanka', 'By Amy', 'By Ehtasham R', 'By Sergio G', 'By Jitka E V', 'By Michalis T', 'By Matthew R', 'By Hoo L V', 'By Claudios H', 'By Majid A']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 06, 2018', 'Apr 23, 2017', 'Sep 15, 2018', 'Sep 08, 2018', 'Sep 07, 2016', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2018', 'Aug 19, 2018', 'Apr 02, 2017', 'Sep 26, 2016', 'Feb 07, 2017', 'Sep 16, 2017', 'Apr 14, 2016', 'Sep 16, 2017', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Mar 01, 2017', 'Apr 08, 2017', 'Nov 01, 2017', 'Mar 28, 2016', 'Oct 08, 2016', 'Apr 13, 2018', 'Oct 29, 2017', 'Jan 08, 2018', 'Mar 01, 2016']</review_date></doc>