<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_215</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/predictive-modeling-analytics</course_url><course_name>Predictive Modeling and Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dan Zhang</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to the second course in the Data Analytics for Business specialization! 

This course will introduce you to some of the most widely used predictive modeling techniques and their core principles. By taking this course, you will form a solid foundation of predictive analytics, which refers to tools and techniques for building statistical or machine learning models to make predictions based on data. You will learn how to carry out exploratory data analysis to gain insights and prepare data for predictive modeling, an essential skill valued in the business. 

You’ll also learn how to summarize and visualize datasets using plots so that you can present your results in a compelling and meaningful way. We will use a practical predictive modeling software, XLMiner, which is a popular Excel plug-in. This course is designed for anyone who is interested in using data to gain insights and make better business decisions. The techniques discussed are applied in all functional areas within business organizations including accounting, finance, human resource management, marketing, operations, and strategic planning. 

The expected prerequisites for this course include a prior working knowledge of Excel, introductory level algebra, and basic statistics.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Regression Analysis//Data Cleansing//Predictive Modelling//Exploratory Data Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>3.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado Boulder</course_orgnization><course_chapter> Exploratory Data Analysis and Visualizations//Predicting a Continuous Variable//Predicting a Binary Outcome//Trees and Other Predictive Models</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the Course', '0. Introduction to the Module. Why Exploratory Data Analysis is Important', '1. Data Cleanup and Transformation', '2. Dealing With Missing Values', '3. Dealing with Outliers', '4. Adding and Removing Variables', '5. Common Graphs', '6. What is Good Data Visualization?'], ['0. Introduction to Predictive Modeling', '1. Introduction to Linear Regression', '2. Assessing Predictive Accuracy Using Cross-Validation', '3. Multiple Regression', '4. Improving Model Fit', '5. Model Selection', '6. Challenges of Predictive Modeling', '7. How to Build a Model using XLMiner'], ['0. Introduction to classification', '1. Introduction to Logistic Regression', '2. Building Logistic Regression Model', '3. Multiple Logistic Regression', '4. Cross Validation and Confusion Matrix', '5. Cost Sensitive Classification', '6. Comparing Models Independent of Costs and Cutoffs', '7. Building Logistic Regression Models using XLMiner'], ['0.Introduction to Advanced Predictive Modeling Techniques', '1. Introduction to Trees', '2.\xa0Classification Trees', '3. Regression Trees', '4. Bagging, Boosting, Random Forest', '5. Building Trees with XLMiner', '6. Neural Networks', '7. Building Neural Networks using XLMiner']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I was very disappointed by this course. The professor was knowledgeable, but was difficult to understand and spoke quickly. Even the transcript had the words [INAUDIBLE] listed multiple times because he was so difficult to understand. There were no slides, so note taking was difficult. The course also requires paying $25 for an Excel Add-In, which was not mentioned before enrolling in the course. The Excel Add-In is a different version from the version used in the video, so it was very difficult to follow along because the screens and outputs were different. I also had an issue with the Excel Add-In that made some of my work late because the issue could not be resolved quickly. The Analytic Solver (the Add-Inrepresentative said the problem was on their end, and had to fix the issue himself. Overall I was extremely disappointed and would not recommend this course to anyone. If this had been the first course in the specialization, I would not have continued. In my opinion UC-B needs to rethink if they should even offer this course.', "This class doesn't even deserve that one star.", "This module is badly organised and taught. The lecturer goes through the concepts with no explanation or illustration. As a result, it was hard to understand the significance and applicability of the concepts taught. It was also very hard to catch what he was saying as his voice was not clear and no slides were provided. Further, no answer key was provided for the assignments and quizzes - we wont even know why we got the question(s) wrong and what should be the correct step(s). The final assignment/quiz was kind of a repeat of the first four quizzes/assignments using a different set of data. While I appreciate that this is to give us more practice, it wasn't very useful as the lack of answer key for the first four assignments/quizzes meant that we couldn't quite know the reason for getting certain question(s) wrong earlier on. ", "Lots of info in 4 short weeks... the instructor did a good job of getting through it. I had issues with neural networks in XLMiner -- particularly, boosting and bagging; my in-Excel XLMiner wouldn't run models without terminating with an error. Using the in-the-cloud version of XLMiner was better because the menus matched what the instructor was showing in the videos (my desktop version did not).  However, I never was able to get the right answer on any neural network boosting or bagging questions on any quiz, though I got all the other questions right - creating decision trees or logistic regression models through XLMiner, even boosting/bagging decision tree models, both Classify and Predict.  There was zero traffic in the discussion forums (people were begging people to grade their peer assignments so they could get a grade) so there was zero response to my pleas for assistance. It was pretty frustrating.  I finally got through the class because getting everything right except neural network boosting/bagging questions enabled me to squeak through with a passing score. I hate not knowing what I was doing wrong though.  Perhaps the instructor's version had different default values than the version I was using. Oh well.  It's in the past :)", "The instructor's accent is difficultto understand. The subtitles are also not helpful as sometimes it also misintreprets what the instructor is saying or writes(incoherent). The instructor is too fast and has explained concept too briefly. Many times I had to google to understand the concept and pass the quiz.", "I liked the course information but it moves too fast. Week 4 module is too complicated to be covered in a 5 minute video. Many concepts should be explained in detail with examples. The teacher doesn't have a very easy accent to understand and there are many occasions when some really difficult concepts are covered in less than a minute. ", 'Its my individual perception about this course, reason of poor review', "Week 3 application assignment is buggy. If you input correct answers they will be marked as incorrect. You must use trial and error to find the wrong answers the quiz is looking for. It's a badly designed assignment that wastes students' time and creates a lot of frustration. Would not recommend the course because of it.", "This course gave me a good understanding of the typical analytic tools used when doing predictive study. It has helped set the direction for my future business analytics study (don't expect to master all the topics in one short course!). If you don't already have a background in basic statistics you will probably struggle to understand much of the material. By basic I'm speaking of things such as basic hypothesis testing, error types, z scores, measures of variation and central tendency, confidence intervals, basic probability, basic understanding of logarithms and exponents. ", "The instructor speaks too quickly and I think this will make it difficult for non-native English speakers to understand the material.  This material will also be more understandable to individuals with a statistical analysis background, not enough time is spent on explanation and it will be necessary to supplement the class if you don't have the proper background.  Passing the class by rote following of the examples will not give you the proper proficiency.   ", 'This course has great content and I believe the professor is very knowledgeable about this subject matter.  However, at times, it can be very difficult to understand what he is saying.  I believe he knows the English language very well but, between his deep accent and speaking very quickly, there are a number of times I cannot understand what he is saying.  This is reflected at times when reading the transcript below each video.  I found it better to slow the video down to 0.75X the regular speed to hear him but that did not remove all of the difficulty.', 'There are a lot better courses for the time. This course mostly teaches you how to use XLMiner which is a paid Excel add on that I am 99% certain I will never use again.', "I don't mean to criticize and I believe the content your courses offer is always great but I had difficulty with the instructor's speech delivery and his accent.", None, '  Dan Zhang is a very good teacher.', 'Well explained', 'its really good', 'this course teach you about the technical of using tools for predictive modeling. very useful for you who want to learn the fundamental of analytics.', 'awsome ', 'Very nice course', 'Its an excellent course and thanks to Professor for making this course so practice oriented.', 'It was an amazing learning experience with a very high reputed university.', "it's really good, but this course is very fast and hard", 'Great Course !', 'I only wished that the teacher would speak slower.']</reviews><reviewers>['By William C', 'By Rohan G L', 'By Yvonne G Q T', 'By Jennifer Z', 'By Pooja', 'By Abhishek U', 'By Chinmaya M', 'By Yihan W', 'By Lance R', 'By Mark S', 'By John T', 'By Rachel S', 'By roshni r', 'By Amol K', 'By Ivan Z', 'By sandhya k', 'By Tanay C', 'By Harliano A', 'By Ameerah R A S', 'By Avinash T', 'By Sankepalli S K', 'By Aqil K', 'By Shiyu D', 'By PRALAY P', 'By Isaura D V']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 03, 2018', 'Jan 29, 2018', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2018', 'Aug 03, 2017', 'Nov 20, 2017', 'Mar 10, 2017', 'Jan 02, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2017', 'Mar 30, 2017', 'May 16, 2019', 'Jul 09, 2018', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2018', 'Jan 03, 2017', 'Nov 27, 2017', 'Nov 20, 2017', 'Sep 09, 2017', 'Aug 28, 2017', 'Feb 16, 2017', 'May 10, 2017', 'May 19, 2018', 'Apr 29, 2018', 'Oct 06, 2018']</review_date></doc>