<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_52</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/analytics-business-metrics</course_url><course_name>Business Metrics for Data-Driven Companies</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Egger</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, you will learn best practices for how to use data analytics to make any company more competitive and more profitable. You will be able to recognize the most critical business metrics and distinguish them from mere data.
 
You’ll get a clear picture of the vital but different roles business analysts, business data analysts, and data scientists each play in various types of companies. And you’ll know exactly what skills are required to be hired for, and succeed at, these high-demand jobs.
 
Finally, you will be able to use a checklist provided in the course to score any company on how effectively it is embracing big data culture. Digital companies like Amazon, Uber and Airbnb are transforming entire industries through their creative use of big data. You’ll understand why these companies are so disruptive and how they use data-analytics techniques to out-compete traditional companies.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Business Analysis//Business Analytics//Business Process</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About This Specialization and Course //Introducing Business Metrics//Working in the Business Data Analytics Marketplace//Going Deeper into Business Metrics //Applying Business Metrics to a Business Case Study</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About This Specialization', 'Introduction'], ['Metrics Help Us Ask the Right Questions', 'Distinguishing Revenue, Profitability, and Risk Metrics', 'Distinguishing Traditional and Dynamic Metrics', 'Egger’s Roast Coffee Case Study Part 1 – Definitions', 'Egger’s Roast Coffee Case Study Part 2 – How a Profitable, Growing Company can go Bankrupt', 'Revenue Metrics – Traditional Enterprise Sales Funnel', 'Revenue Metrics - Amazon.com as a Leading Example of Use of Dynamic Metrics - Part 1', 'Revenue Metrics - Amazon.com as a Leading Example of Use of Dynamic Metrics - Part 2', 'Profitability/Efficiency Metrics: Inventory Management', 'Profitability/Efficiency Metrics: Hotel Room Occupancy Optimization', 'Risk Metrics: Leverage and Reputational Risk'], ['Roles and Companies as They Relate to Big Data', 'The Business Analyst', 'An Interview with Business Analyst Shambhavi Vashishtha', 'Distinguishing the Business Data Analyst and Business Analyst Roles', 'An Interview with Business Data Analyst Tiffany Yu', 'The Data Scientist', 'An Interview with Data Scientist Dai Li', 'The Senior Software Engineer', 'Overview of 5 Types of Companies as They Relate to Big Data', 'Traditional Strategic Business Consulting', 'Bricks-and-Mortar Companies', 'Barnes and Noble Case Study', 'Strategic Business Consulting - Focus on Software/IT Systems Integration', 'Hardware and Software Companies', 'Digital Companies'], ['Web Marketing - Metrics', 'Web Marketing - AdWord Metrics', 'Web Marketing - Segmentation', 'Financial Services Metrics - Money Management and Investing', 'The Equivalence of Different Returns –The Sharpe Ratio', 'Four Types of Money Managers and Their Performance Metrics', 'Venture Capital and Private Equity Investors'], ['A Look Ahead']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I do not think that students should need to pay for a course in order to watch interviews with previous graduates. Half of this course should have been condensed or excluded. There is not much to learn in these modules. It was decent, but it was not a five star course. I think the ratings on this are misleading. ', 'This was a great introductory course. I took this up to get a better perspective of business analysis and i can say with surety that it served a lot of purpose. Thanks Coursera and Duke Professor. ', 'a very interesting course on business metrics, talks about business metrics itself, jobs and companies in this field, also some examples of the application of business metrics like Amazon, Costco.', 'The use of actual business makes it much easier for professionals who are in the business world to pick up the concepts. A lot of courses are much heavier in theory and are a little more difficult to pick up if you have been out of school of some time. ', 'Pretty basic stuff. Even though I was familiar with everything given my background, I struggle to understand how this will add any value to people who are interested in Data Analytics. ', 'I found the course very practical and provide a lot of useful knowledge on the business world and how to evaluate the performances of businesses using metrics. Highly recommend it. ', 'Great Course. Thank you!', 'I cant wait for peer reviewing ', 'thank you!', 'Good introductory course of Business metrics to people with no business background.', 'Very nice class! Pretty useful for beginners:)', 'Excellent course\n  with practical examples and useful theory.         ', 'Great course with good balance of theory content and real world application', 'I liked it', 'Excellent course, even better teacher. Greetings from Uruguay!', 'Super insightful!', 'Great course!', 'Excelente introductorio a las metrics', '很好的一门课,对于没有专业基础的同学来说难度也合适!而且学到了很多实用的知识!', 'Great explanation! Simple examples make it easier for me to understand the content', 'interesting', None, "I really enjoyed this course. It was a good course for someone just starting out in this field (like me) and I didn't feel overwhelmed. The material is useful and they include real world examples that you'd see in a Business Analyst or Data Analyst position. ", 'The course is great (but please consider amending information ratio calculation mistake, the rest is perfect) ', "It's good!"]</reviews><reviewers>['By James B', 'By Dhruv G', 'By Yuntao W', 'By Alex P', 'By Santiago H', 'By ctvv3010', 'By Roshan K B', 'By Thanapich T', 'By Alessandra T', 'By Helena S', 'By Chunxiao C', 'By Vardges Z', 'By Tom S', 'By Edgar M A F', 'By Rodrigo P', 'By William D', 'By Bishwaraj B', 'By Alan D B G', 'By 邱荟璇', 'By Guangyu Z', 'By ShirleyL', 'By okeke n a', 'By Amy H', 'By Mariia A', 'By Mike']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 18, 2016', 'Aug 20, 2017', 'Oct 03, 2016', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Nov 29, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019']</review_date></doc>