<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_103</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/ds</course_url><course_name>Fundamentals of Scalable Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Romeo Kienzler</course_instructor><course_introduction>Apache Spark is the de-facto standard for large scale data processing. This is the first course of a series of courses towards the IBM Advanced Data Science Specialization. We strongly believe that is is crucial for success to start learning a scalable data science platform since memory and CPU constraints are to most limiting factors when it comes to building advanced machine learning models.

In this course we teach you the fundamentals of Apache Spark using python and pyspark. We'll introduce Apache Spark in the first two weeks and learn how to apply it to compute basic exploratory and data pre-processing tasks in the last two weeks. Through this exercise you'll also be introduced to the most fundamental statistical measures and data visualization technologies.

This gives you enough knowledge to take over the role of a data engineer in any modern environment. But it gives you also the basis for advancing your career towards data science. 

Please have a look at the full specialization curriculum:
https://www.coursera.org/specializations/advanced-data-science-ibm

If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you will also earn an IBM digital badge.  To find out more about IBM digital badges follow the link ibm.biz/badging.


After completing this course, you will be able to:
•	Describe how basic statistical measures, are used to reveal  patterns within the data 
•	Recognize data characteristics, patterns, trends, deviations or inconsistencies, and potential outliers.
•	Identify useful techniques for working with big data such as dimension reduction and feature selection methods 
•	Use advanced tools and charting libraries to:
      o	improve efficiency of analysis of big-data with partitioning and parallel analysis 
      o	Visualize the data in an number of 2D and 3D formats (Box Plot, Run Chart, Scatter Plot, Pareto Chart, and Multidimensional Scaling)

For successful completion of the course, the following prerequisites are recommended: 
•	Basic programming skills in python
•	Basic math
•	Basic SQL (you can get it easily from https://www.coursera.org/learn/sql-data-science if needed)

In order to complete this course, the following technologies will be used:
(These technologies are introduced in the course as necessary so no previous knowledge is required.)
•	Jupyter notebooks (brought to you by IBM Watson Studio for free)
•	ApacheSpark (brought to you by IBM Watson Studio for free)
•	Python

This course takes four weeks, 4-6h per week</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Data Science//Internet Of Things (IOT)//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to exploratory analysis//Tools that support BigData solutions//Scaling Math for Statistics on Apache Spark//Data Visualization of Big Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Overview and a warm welcome', 'Overview of technology used within the course'], ['Data storage solutions', 'Parallel data processing strategies of Apache Spark', 'Programming language options on ApacheSpark', 'Functional programming basics', 'Introduction of Cloudant', 'Resilient Distributed Dataset and DataFrames - ApacheSparkSQL', 'Overview of how the test data has been generated (optional)', 'IBM Watson Studio (formerly Data Science Experience)'], ['Overview of the week...', 'Averages', 'Standard deviation', 'Skewness', 'Kurtosis', 'Covariance, Covariance matrices, correlation', 'Multidimensional vector spaces'], ['Overview of the week', "Plotting with ApacheSpark and python's matplotlib", 'Dimensionality reduction', 'PCA']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Currently, it is not advisable to take this course.', 'IBM cloud environment is buggy and inconsistent with lectures.', ' I\'m really disapointed with the "Fundamentals of Scalable Data Science" course from IBM. The videos are referring to an outdated software releases, with really different screenshots from the ones existing on IBM platform. The discussions refers to code samples different from the ones available for download (flow2.js) and to applications present on the IBM Bluemix platform, without explaining where to found or how to create them. All these discrepancies make really difficult to follow the course. LBNL, the speaker is one of the most boring ever encountered in a webinar, barely able to read in english language. Being a course organized by IBM for such an important topic as Watson, I expected a much higher level of quality. I hope that the IBM staff will be able to perform a deep review of this series of course.   ', 'not enough additional materials', 'Very steep learning curve! Getting everything set up correctly is not very user friendly at this stage. Once everything is setup the material presented is very interesting. However, I prefer the tests (assignments) to actually test what was being taught and not something quite distinct (teach python; test spark SQL). The many comments in the forum attest to the issues for this course. Good start but needs improvement. Thank you. ', 'Training Videos are pretty good for a beginner but to consider this an advanced course is incorrect. Intermediate at most. In addition the application of lessons to assignments were minimal as the answers needed for the assignment were not related to the content that was discussed, just very simple fill in the blank.', 'Setup process is tedious', 'This course does cover the needed fundamentals but needs a serious audit and edit of content, transcription, testing and grading for accuracy, conflicting instruction, and actual relevant instructional feedback.', 'Good:', "I couldn't find most relevant IBM web pages only with the instructions; I spotted typos and bugs in exercises; the most disappointing part is the autograder which malfunctions OFTEN on unclear grounds, I had to submit my assignment multiple times and to test the autograder.", 'I will un-enroll after 7 days in the course as the basic cloud environment setup did not work as written in the course handouts and videos. Which could be okay, however noone replied to my questions for 4 days on that, and the reply tips did not work either. Updating with screenshots, explanations no answer till today so what would have been a 15 minute job takes 7+ days here. At other coursera and competition platforms all my questions got answered in hours vs weeks as in this course. ', "If there was negative score, I wouldn't even hesitate to give that to this course. I understand coursera is actually trying to do good to the society and change the way education works in the past. But bad UI won't  get you any further. About this course, I don't know why this Romeo guy is allowed to teach here. Extremely unusable tutorials, extremely bad organization of the the materials, extremely bad accent, extremely unusable IBM cloud service, extremely outdated tutorial for environment setup, and you name it. This guy can't even articulate himself. Please stop doing this to the user since now coursera started charging subscription fees. If there is even no quality control and this kinda of bad actor is allowed here, what is the difference between coursera and traditional college? Just go to the forum and discussion session of this course and look at the complaints over there. You don't even need to search for complaints since they are there on the surface. Shame on you.", 'Fuzzy, outdated, low quality course, according to the instructor; he is very busy "TRAVELLING" so that he cannot improve the quality of this course.', 'A Great Course to get an understanding regarding some basics concepts of data analytics through implementation', 'A perfect course to pace off with exploration towards sensor-data analytics using Apache Spark and python libraries.', 'Great way to understand and learn open source tools and latest IBM data science offerings.', 'This course is teaching how to work with data in a distributed environment. While getting used to IBM Cloud takes time, it is definitely a friendlier environment for data scientists and it removes the burden of setting up the infrastructure.', 'Too many issues with lab material', "the content is really good but I don't understand the Indian accent well although this guy really did his best  ", "Good course, but some of the later videos and assignments refer to data generation on Cloudant and NodeRed that made the videos confusing since the Cloudant videos were removed. This caused me to jump between the course and youtube videos to learn about data generation, only to find out it wasn't necessary.", "Eeverything related with the graded assesment in this course fails, it's outdated and the practicla exercises are not well explain, if you are looking for a hard struggle to get very simple things done, this is your course", 'Nice but details are not discussed properly only taking names wasnt enough', "Need more exercises related to wrangling data and manipulating SQL's with apache spark", 'Not so worth learning compare to the predecessor of this course. Should have included more assignment would have made the course very interesting.', "It was difficult to follow the IBM cloud setup since it was constantly changing, I couldn't understand the reason for using python2.7 since its only 10 months before it wont be supported by the community. Sometime instructors' pronunciations were not clear and and thus added extra confusion. However, instructor do actively participate in helping with discussions. Audio and video quality were also not very good. This course is a very basic introduction to IBM cloud and general stats. Prior knowledge of spark is useful. Overall the course is nice introduction to IBM cloud if one is interested."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Mike D', 'By David-Leigh B', 'By Vincenzo M', 'By Marcin S', 'By Denys v K', 'By Robert M', 'By Vuong B A', 'By Marius J', 'By Ryan S', 'By Zhihao Z', 'By Gabor K', 'By Qian L', 'By Mohanad Q A A', 'By Chirag S', 'By Harshit S', 'By Jose L R', 'By Dmitry B', 'By Karthik D C', 'By Ahmed E A T E', 'By Igor E', 'By Miguel A B G', 'By shubham k g', 'By Mario E R T', 'By Ramkumar K', 'By Nikhil P P']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 29, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Apr 13, 2018', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jun 12, 2019', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Jul 06, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Nov 10, 2018', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Jul 09, 2018', 'Sep 10, 2017', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Apr 10, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Jul 04, 2019', 'Jul 14, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2019']</review_date></doc>