<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_113</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/forensic-accounting</course_url><course_name>Forensic Accounting and Fraud Examination</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr. Richard Riley, Ph.D</course_instructor><course_introduction>Everyday across the world, thousands of businesses are victimized by fraud.  Who commits these bad acts?  Why? And, how? In this course we are going to help you answer the questions: who commits fraud, why and how.  We’ll also help you develop skills for catching them.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Finance</course_category><course_tag>Fraud Detection//Internal Control//Fraud Investigation//Forensic Accounting</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>West Virginia University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Accidental Fraudster//The Predator Fraudster// Big Data, Benford's Law and Financial Analytics//Cyber-Crime and Money Laundering: Contemporary Tools and Techniques.//Whistleblowing</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['The Elements of Fraud', 'Why People Commit Fraud', 'Fraudster Demographics', 'Randy Pierce - The Accidental Fraudster'], ['The Predator Fraudster', 'Attributes of a Predator', 'Internal Control Concepts', 'How to Detect and Prevent Financial Statement Fraud - Crazy Eddie'], ['Using Data and Technology for Fraud Detection and Investigation', 'Data Analysis Tools', 'Benford Analysis', 'Availability of Data and Text Analysis', 'Making Crime Pay: How to Locate Hidden Assets - Steve Comisar'], ['Money Laundering', 'Money Laundering Basics', 'Money Laundering Schemes', 'Making Crime Pay: How to Locate Hidden Assets - Money Laundering'], ['Whistleblowing', 'WorldCom Fraud', 'The Choice to be a Whistleblower', 'ZZZZ Best and Barry Minkow', 'Final Thoughts']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Final quiz has 60 questions but there is no possibilities to " save" answers and proceed later, all questions must be answered in one  access. ', "Positive: It was refreshing to see this offering in Coursera. It is an important topic and there is limited amount of offerings (the Wharton course in accounting analytics crosses in the benfords law topic). The discussions in Madoff, Snowden, etc are positive to stimulate critical thinking. The approach was solid. The videos with real fraudsters were very good allowing to connect the theory to practice. The final exam with 60 questions is also very positive to force/stimulate the student to 'cement' the knowledge gained.", 'I really like this online course because we can study from the comfort of our home as per our convenience. We can also study this anytime. Lecturers from west Virginia university explain everything properly. Also the transcript helps us. It would have been better if transcript were organized into paragraphs for our ease. Additional reading materials also should have been provided so we can further clear our concepts. Other than that this was great!', 'An intriguing course that delves inside the various aspects of Forensic Accounting and Fraud Examination in a awe-inspiring manner with relevant examples, engaging content and learned professors.', 'This course is a better learning than general auditing course that was taken in university by me. Awesome knowledge provided. Very easy and slow english speaking letting us to understand each word.', 'Great course, essential for all auditors and fraud\nfighter personals.', 'Fantastic course for beginner. Thanks professor and Coursera for providing the opportunity,', 'A great course put in a highly interactive mode.', None, 'Very interesting and easy to follow. ', 'The course is very effective since content has been derived from ACFE Official books and quizes are very challenging to pass, they require extensive study', 'This was a basic course, but a good introduction in forensic accounting and fraud examination. I would recommend it to anybody who wishes to determine whether this could be a viable career option for them. I wish there were more interactive material, but nonetheless for the price it delivers value.', None, None, 'I loved this course!! Being at a very early stage in my career, I found this extremely helpful in understanding the dynamics of this filed. I hope there are more courses related to forensic investigation like frauds of stock markets, insurance companies, etc. .', 'Informative and easy to learn. I like this course very much.', 'E', 'Whoa! Life changing experience.', 'Awesome Course!', 'I LOVE DOING THIS COURSE AND HAVE LEARNT LOT ABOUT TOPICS WHICH WERE UNTOUCHED BY ME.', 'excellent course', 'awesome learning experience and a true feeling of learning &amp; clearing the exam.', 'EXCELLENT COURSE AND WELL DESIGNED CONTENT. ', None, 'Really helpful.  Got the opportunity  to go through some  / few real life examples and the got the updates.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Dragana Đ', 'By Ricardo J O', 'By Mohammad S N', 'By Jaiveer S S ', 'By Muhammad U M', 'By Abdullah S M', 'By Sanjay K', 'By Manisankar  K ', 'By HUBERVIC M', 'By premlatha b', 'By Ravi K', 'By Victor P', 'By Tatiane d O M', 'By Adaramola O ', 'By Tanisha M', 'By Yap W C', 'By Natarajan K ', 'By Adekola O A', 'By Siddhartha S', 'By SHINKY S', 'By G S', 'By K S K S', 'By SUJIT K S', 'By Hamraj N', 'By MadhuSudan R']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 06, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2016', 'Nov 03, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2017', 'May 03, 2016', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Nov 23, 2018', 'Nov 09, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019']</review_date></doc>