<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_23</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/probability-intro</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Probability and Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course introduces you to sampling and exploring data, as well as basic probability theory and Bayes' rule. You will examine various types of sampling methods, and discuss how such methods can impact the scope of inference. A variety of exploratory data analysis techniques will be covered, including numeric summary statistics and basic data visualization. You will be guided through installing and using R and RStudio (free statistical software), and will use this software for lab exercises and a final project. The concepts and techniques in this course will serve as building blocks for the inference and modeling courses in the Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//R Programming//Rstudio//Exploratory Data Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About Introduction to Probability and Data//Introduction to Data//Introduction to Data Project//Exploratory Data Analysis and Introduction to Inference//Exploratory Data Analysis and Introduction to Inference Project//Introduction to Probability//Introduction to Probability Project//Probability Distributions//Data Analysis Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Statistics with R'], ['Introduction', 'Data Basics', 'Observational Studies &amp; Experiments', 'Sampling and sources of bias', 'Experimental Design', '(Spotlight) Random Sample Assignment'], ['About Lab Choices (Read Before Selection)', 'Week 1 Lab Instructions (RStudio)'], ['Visualizing Numerical Data', 'Measures of Center', 'Measures of Spread', 'Robust Statistics', 'Transforming Data', 'Exploring Categorical Variables', 'Introduction to Inference'], ['Week 2 Lab Instructions (RStudio)', 'Week 2 Lab Instructions (RStudio Cloud)'], ['Introduction', 'Disjoint Events + General Addition Rule', 'Independence', 'Probability Examples', '(Spotlight) Disjoint vs. Independent', 'Conditional Probability', 'Probability Trees', 'Bayesian Inference', 'Examples of Bayesian Inference'], ['Week 3 Lab Instructions (RStudio)', 'Week 3 Lab Instructions (RStudio Cloud)'], ['Normal Distribution', 'Evaluating the Normal Distribution', 'Working with the Normal Distribution', 'Binomial Distribution', 'Normal Approximation to Binomial', 'Working with the Binomial Distribution'], ['Project Information']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I have a major in mathematics and this is by far one of the best courses I have ever taken on introductory statistics. Instructor explains all the concepts clearly with tons of examples. The labs are very well formed you will never be lost with them. The final project turns out to be fun and informative! Overall, it was a great experience. I recommend it to anyone wanting to get into data science field and/or improve their basic knowledge of statistics and R programming. ', 'This is not a course in how to learn R.  It is a basic statistics course.  The statistical content, including the lectures and book, are very good.  The structure of the first four weeks of the course is very good.  I recommend students follow the syllabus (videos, etc.) in the order shown--one week I tried the homework without viewing the videos first and it made it more difficult than if I had seen them.', "Lecture videos were fantastic! Instructor was amazing. I have a big problem with the final project in Week 5. The entire courses was focused on statistics, yet the final project was focused on R. I wish I had prior R knowledge before starting this course, yet on the front page it says it's a beginner specialization. I would recommend learning R and ggplot before this course. It will make the course a lot less frustrating!", "It's so so bad. Idk if this is old or what. ", 'This course will teach you a little bit of statistics and leave you confused with R. The first four weeks are very straightforward. They give R code for everything. However, this is not good because it does not prepare you well for the last project in which you have to do the whole project using R. This is almost like learning how to cook without knowing how to use a knife. ', 'I took this course primarily for the purposes of learning R and reviewing statistics. While the course content was well organised and succinctly presented in the videos, questions on quizzes and labs could at times be phrased in a confusing manner (even for a native English speaker), and the labs did not prepare one for the finesse with R required for the peer-graded final project. For the final project, I would recommend establishing more specific conditions (e.g., the number of visualisations expected, suggestions as to variables to explore in the dataset, and the points to consider in narrative sections), especially for an entry-level course. As a university professor myself, I have found that it is more pedagogically effective to offer precise guidelines for lower-level courses, and reserve open-ended projects for higher-level courses/seminars.', "I've not studied at this level for a while so the first couple of weeks were intense. The pace didn't let up but the quality of the presentation material was excellent. I didn't feel quite prepared enough for the project and it took much longer than the estimate to complete but well worth it as an exercise. ", 'Really good content and the teacher is one of the best in Coursera. This is for many people a difficult subject that is made easy to digest. Looking forward to more courses from the same Teacher', 'Great course! Explained the concepts so clear and crisp and the exercises with R are great. The project reinforces all the concepts. All in all, a great course for beginners in statistics and R.', "I would give it 5 stars if it was truly for zero beginners. I myself didn't have much problem understanding the content, but I can imagine that people with no background in statistics would have a very hard time. Some very important concepts are just glossed over. Another problem is that much more attention is given to the mathematics behind the stats, as opposed to how to conduct the tests themselves. I'm finishing the 2nd course two (inferential statistics) and I have the same feeling there. We spend video after video learning the nuts and bolts of the math behind, but at times we are only given the code in R. Sometimes the code is not even given!! The same with ggplots. The real-life applicability of the knowledge here is to make sure you are able to use the software to run the analysis. It's important to understand the logic behind, surely, but no one will, professionally, do the calculations by hand. I left this and will leave the second course (Inferential statistics) with the feeling that I've learnt much more the maths than how to actually use R.", 'I liked:', "Be sure you want to learn R before you embark on this course. As a beginner, it was a challenge, but after a few rounds of revisiting the content, it all started to make sense. I would recommend you do the exercises on R Studio. I did mine on Datacamp and had to refamiliarise myself with the RStudio platform for the final assignment, which was slightly painful as more things had to be set up (and time may not be on your side by then). You can use the commands learnt in the course for the final assessment but many classmates seemed to go above and beyond. Online resources are truly indispensable and I'm amazed that I can make decent educated guesses as to what certain lines of code do, in order to improve the chart!", 'The lecturer is very nice and teaching well, the basic knowledge is easy to learn. Examples are vivid and easy to understand as well. The biggest problem is the final project. The things we learn can not support the ability to finish the project. One way to improve it is to give more tips or teach more usage of R. Overall I learnt many useful stuffs and I recommend it!', 'I wish they went over how to use R for beginners in the beginning of the course. I feel like the final project was stressful and piecemealed  together from google searches on the web.  I think they should give us a list of all the codes in the beginning of the course that we will use throughout the entire course. ', "It is an excellent introduction to probability and data, but I think it would be improved by adding one week to the course dedicated to solely data analysis in R, as a precursor to the final project. There was too big of a gap in terms of R practice (for those new to R) between what was explained during the course and the final project. I would have found it super useful to have one more week in which to discuss how to treat missing data, how to clean data in R (even if just a simple cleaning, like getting rid of the NAs), followed by steps/do's and don'ts when analyzing data, different types of graphs in R appropriate for numerical and ordinal data, that sort of thing. That would have made it almost perfect.", 'I regret I have not actively participated in the course. The failure is mainly due to my ignorance, however, the course did not really teach "R". The theory of statistics is great but it is not properly linked with "R". I was misled by the title and teaser film. Sorry.', 'Not suitable for beginners', 'Very well organized.', 'Thanks to this course, I was able to develop my knowledge of statistics and get basic skills in R programming.', 'Dr. Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel is an amazing teacher! I have never learnt and enjoyed so much statistics!', 'Very Nice', "It's a great course, I had acquired new abilities like using R language programming for applied statistics, as well as knowledge about probability and statistics in topics like: sampling,  measures of center and spread, data visualization, inference, probability distribution and much more.  ", 'One of the best course in Statistics.', 'This course was a good introduction to basic probability, experimental design, and data structure. The labs and final assignments made great use of R Studio and markdown. This course is best suited for someone who is proficient in R already. ', 'It was a highly interesting course in which we learnt topics at an easy and understandable pace. The understanding of the project was consolidated further using examples. Lastly, the peer reviewed project had us apply all our understanding on real world data set which is greatly important in the long run.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Akshay J', 'By Alan S', 'By Anastasia', 'By Susan M', 'By Korawat T', 'By Alexander S', 'By Guy T', 'By Rafael A S R', 'By Sonal S', 'By Breno B S', 'By David K', 'By Cheryl L X', 'By 舒穎 鄭', 'By katie v', 'By Raluca B', 'By Hyeon-Jeong S', 'By Syed S R', 'By Grant P', 'By EthanKwon', 'By Lien C', 'By Gopi K D', 'By Samuel O T A', 'By YASHKUMAR R T', 'By Lindsay C', 'By Akash R']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 06, 2019', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Feb 05, 2017', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Dec 26, 2016', 'Jun 23, 2018', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Sep 18, 2016', 'Jul 27, 2017', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Mar 08, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Jun 13, 2019', 'Jul 23, 2018', 'Sep 13, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018']</review_date></doc>