<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_278</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-data-processing</course_url><course_name>Data Processing Using Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>ZHANG Li</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course (The English copy of "用Python玩转数据" &lt;https://www.coursera.org/learn/hipython/home/welcome&gt;)  is mainly for non-computer majors. It starts with the basic syntax of Python, to how to acquire data in Python locally and from network, to how to present data, then to how to conduct basic and advanced statistic analysis and visualization of data, and finally to how to design a simple GUI to present and process data, advancing level by level. 

This course, as a whole, based on Finance data and through the establishment of popular cases one after another, enables learners to more vividly feel the simplicity, elegance, and robustness of Python. Also, it discusses the fast, convenient and efficient data processing capacity of Python in humanities and social sciences fields like literature, sociology and journalism and science and engineering fields like mathematics and biology, in addition to business fields. Similarly, it may also be flexibly applied into other fields.

The course has been updated. Updates in the new version are : 

1) the whole course has moved from Python 2.x to Python 3.x 
2) Added manual webpage fetching and parsing. Web API is also added. 
3) Improve the content order and enrich details of some content especially for some practice projects.

Note: videos are in Chinese (Simplified) with English subtitles. All other materials are in English.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Numpy//Pandas//Wxpython</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Nanjing University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to learn Data Processing Using Python!//Basics of Python//Data Acquisition and Presentation//Powerful Data Structures and Python Extension Libraries//Python Data Statistics and Visualization//Object Orientation and Graphical User Interface</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Promotion Video'], ['1 Introduction to Python', '2 The First Python Program', '3 Basics of Python Syntax', '4 Data Types of Python', '5 Basic Operations of Python', '6 Functions, Modules and Packages of Python', '1 Conditions', '2 range', '3 Loops', '4 break, continue and else in Loops', '5 Self-defined Functions', '6 Recursion', '7 Scope of Variable', 'A1: Standard Library Functions', 'A2: Exceptions'], ['1 Local Data Acquisition', '2 Network Data Retrieval', '1 Sequence', '2 String', '3 List', '4 Tuple'], ['1 Why Are Dictionaries Needed', '2  Dictionary Use', '3  Set', '1 Extension Library SciPy', '2 ndarray', '3 Series', '4 DataFrame'], ['1 Convenient and Fast Data Acquisition', '2 Data Preparations', '3 Data Display', '4 Data Selection', '5 Simple Statistics and Processing', '6 Grouping', '7 Merge', '1 Cluster', '2 Basics of Matplotlib Plotting', '3 Control of Matplotlib Image Attributes', '4 Plotting with pandas', '5 Data Access', '6 Applications of Python into Science and Engineering Fields', '7 Applications into Humanities and Social Sciences Fields'], ['1 GUI and Object Orientation', '2 Abstraction', '3 Inheritance', '1 Basic Framework of GUI', '2 Common Components of GUI', '3 Layout Management', '4 Other GUI Libraries', '5 Comprehensive Applications']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 27 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very nice course. Could be extended to 12 weeks with more detailed coverage of packages. Please upload English audio tracks.', '课程深入浅出，学到了很多东西！非常值得！然后由于做了笔记，也一边操作，所以以后会经常翻过来查看笔记。', 'Really helpful and covers a lot of real stuff.', 'Good course ', 'Very good course. Learnt a lot about data processing using python. The teacher is intresting. I like her.', '我觉得是一门很有意思的python基础课。推荐所有想要学习基础的同学参加这门课程', 'The course provides an insight into the basic structure of Python. It will help you in navigating the areas where Python is robust and effective.', "It's a basic Python lesson, but providing some data analysis and GUI concepts, which needs you to explore after this class or in the future. ", '学习了基本Python语句的写法，很多东西还需要自己下来多实践！', 'Nice course.', 'Very good. Keep it up ', '讲的比鬼佬好多了.', 'It does not cover the details in some aspects, but overall it is a quite helpful course for Python Beginner.', 'Good Course', '简洁但知识丰富，老师很有趣', '从基本语法知识到数据结构，再应用到数据处理，讲解非常好', '老师讲的生动', '讲的很好，入门课程，重要的是老师很可爱，哈哈哈哈。', '课程比较短小精悍，覆盖面相对较广，只是我英文不好，有些题目实在时琢磨不透意思。', 'Very helpful and useful course. ', 'An excellent course covering many aspects applications using Python. It introduces many libraries in a way that raise your interest to want to find out more, which is an essential discipline to cultivate because libraries are always changing and new libraries come into being all the time. The lecturer do a great job to motivate her students.', "It's actually too simple for me, but I think it's good for the beginners.", 'English audio might be good to followup easily', "In sum I liked the course, because the material was  presented  in detail. The professor mentioned many  little things, which are often overlooked or simply not mentioned in similar courses. Furthermore, I liked the stocks examples. Unfortunately, a large part of the presented stock  code is broken, because of a recent breaking change of Yahoo Finance's  API. Some questions in the quizzes are, in my opinion, not easy to understand, I guess because of an errorneous translation from the Chinese language.  ", None]</reviews><reviewers>['By SOURAV M', 'By YE Q', 'By Jingxiong L', 'By Justin J', 'By Zhilin Z', 'By 薛皛', 'By Sandeep R', 'By Jianping L', 'By 刘芸芸', 'By Nikhil K S', 'By Tommy L', 'By Jack 买', 'By Chen L', 'By Mike C', 'By hexinlin', 'By 代江海', 'By pangxie0501', 'By 陈文军', 'By sunmo', 'By SHAH A S', 'By PC', 'By Jacory G', 'By Ravikumar P', 'By Rene W', 'By Thomas B']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 06, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2017', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Aug 20, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Oct 22, 2018', 'Sep 12, 2017', 'Oct 31, 2017', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Jun 05, 2017', 'Jan 03, 2018', 'Feb 10, 2017', 'May 26, 2017', 'May 30, 2018', 'Oct 27, 2017', 'May 03, 2017', 'Feb 08, 2018', 'Oct 22, 2017', 'Jun 06, 2019', 'May 09, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Jul 01, 2017', 'Apr 21, 2017']</review_date></doc>