<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_274</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/mri-fundamentals</course_url><course_name>MRI Fundamentals</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sunghong Park </course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome! In this course learners will develop expertise in basic magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) physics and principles and gain knowledge of many different data acquisition strategies in MRI. In particular, learners will get to know what is magnetic resonance phenomenon, how magnetic resonance signals are generated, how an image can be formulated using MRI, how soft tissue contrast can change with imaging parameters. Also introduced will be MR imaging sequences of spin echo, gradient echo, fast spin echo, echo planar imaging, inversion recovery, etc.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Research</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology(KAIST)</course_orgnization><course_chapter>1 Overview of MRI //2 Mag Reson Phenomenon//3 Signal Processing Theory//4 MR IMAGE FORMATION//5 IMAGE CONTRAST, FIELD OF VIEW, AND RESOLUTION//6 MRI DATA ACQUISITION STRATEGIES</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Lecture 1-1 MRI as one of the Biomedical Imaging Modalites', 'Lecture 1-2 Magnet, RF Coils, and Gradient Coils for MRI'], ['Lecture 2-1 Signal Source of MRI', 'Lecture 2-2 Protons in the strong magnetic field', 'Lecture 2-3  Application of RF to Cause Magnetic Resonance', 'Lecture 2-4 Relaxation. Summary of the 2nd Week'], ['Lecture 3-1 Fourier Transform and MR images', 'Lecture 3-2 Properties of Fourier Transform', 'Lecture 3-3 Basic Signal Functions', 'Lecture 3-4 Sampling', 'Lecture 3-5 Nyquist Sampling Theorem'], ['Lecture 4-1 How to sequence gradient pulses to get an image', 'Lecture 4-2 Slice Selection', 'Lecture 4-3 K-space', 'Lecture 4-4 Frequency Encoding', 'Lecture 4-5 Phase Encoding'], ['Lecture 5-1 Gradient Echo and Spin Echo Imaging', 'Lecture 5-2 Contrast Mechanism in Spin Echo Imaging', 'Lecture 5-3 Contrast Mechanism in Gradient Echo Imaging', 'Lecture 5-4 Field of View', 'Lecture 5-5 Resolution'], ['Lecture 6-1 2D and 3D Imaging', 'Lecture 6-2 Gradient Echo Imaging', 'Lecture 6-3 Spin Echo Imaging and Fast Spin Echo Imaging', 'Lecture 6-4 Echo Planar Imaging', 'Lecture 6-5 Non-Cartesian Imaging']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['It is very useful to start with MRI, and I am really happy that it exists. However, it is a pity that a lot of questions have typos, and sometimes it is completely impossible to answer the question using just information from the lectures.', "Great Course that covers quite a lot on the ins-and-outs of MRI technology, though it doesn't cover fMRI. Despite that fact, it's a definite course to try out if you were curious of how MRIs work.  ", 'thank you for the great information you have gifted ', 'Excellent course, clear explanation and in details on MRI Fundamentals. ', 'It was a great opportunity for me.', 'Very interesting course! Thank you very much! I’m a doctor. I understand MRI! Recommended)', 'fantastic', 'This course is fantastic and helps me a lot in MRI principled. It makes me understand MRI much better than before and solve my weakness in the knowledge in MRI utilization! Thanks the Professor very much!', 'good class', 'Very difficult to understand Mr. Park. Subtitles not helpful. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Karyna I', 'By Al-Rashid J', 'By ABDULRAHMAN A A', 'By Venkateshwaran  S', 'By Farnaz S', 'By Grygoriy K', 'By Muhammad Y M', 'By Raphael', 'By jiangfan', 'By Rosa M K']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 04, 2019', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Oct 28, 2018', 'Apr 22, 2019', 'Jun 03, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'Sep 16, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019']</review_date></doc>