<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_240</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/gcp-advanced-insights-bigquery</course_url><course_name>Achieving Advanced Insights with BigQuery</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>The third course in this specialization is Achieving Advanced Insights with BigQuery. Here we will build on your growing knowledge of SQL as we dive into advanced functions and how to break apart a complex query into manageable steps. 

We will cover the internal architecture of BigQuery (column-based sharded storage) and advanced SQL topics like nested and repeated fields through the use of Arrays and Structs. Lastly we will dive into optimizing your queries for performance and how you can secure your data through authorized views.

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this specialization you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Information Technology.Data Management</course_category><course_tag>Bigquery//Google Cloud Platform//Cloud Computing//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Advanced Functions and Clauses//Schema Design and Nested Data Structures//More Visualization with Google Data Studio//Optimizing for Performance//Advanced Insights with Cloud Datalab//Data Access//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Intro', 'Qwiklabs Introduction'], ['Advanced Functions - Statistical and Approximations', 'Analytic Functions, WITH clause, and RANK()', 'BigQuery User-Defined Functions (UDFs)', 'Sub-query and CTE design', 'Lab Overview', 'Lab Solution'], ['Background: Traditional Relational Database Architecture', 'Denormalized, Column-Based Storage', 'Table Sharding', 'Introducing Nested and Repeated Fields', 'Working with Arrays and Structs in BigQuery', 'BigQuery Standard SQL vs Legacy SQL', 'Practicing SQL on Repeated Fields in BigQuery', 'Lab Solution Walkthrough'], ['Advanced Data Studio: Case Statements and Filters', 'Sharing Dashboards and Data Access Pitfalls'], ['Avoid BigQuery Performance Pitfalls', 'Data Skew in your Datasets', 'Diagnose Performance Issues with the Query Explanation map', 'Lab Overview', 'Lab Solution Walkthrough'], ['Introducing Cloud Datalab', 'Demo: Cloud Datalab Notebook Cells', 'Benefits of Cloud Datalab'], ['Data Access Roles, Creating Authorized Views, and Common Pitfalls'], ['Course Recap']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Really helpful with enough theory background and practical exercises', 'nice course', 'Good but lack of sql example and sql questions', 'I learned lots about the structs and arrays and how it could be used to improve performance by creating parent child relationships instead of doing expensive joins', 'Lots of in-depth material covered in this course, including nesting of data structures. Also provides high-level introductions to Google Data Studio and Cloud DataLab.', "Very helpful to know advanced SQL querying even if I don't really have to do it myself.", 'Course provides a high level understanding of what can be achieved through GCP.', 'Greath', "Excellent course on BigQuery, Dataprep, DataStudio and Dataset Secure Access topics. Hoped to have more on Datalab and Bigquery, and also more difficult labs, but it's ok. ", 'Great course in understanding more advanced topics in BQ', 'Very informative and valuable learning. Enjoyed both the Google specific content as well as the general data analyst content.', 'Fantastic course with great focus on advanced subjects.', 'Thanks for the course, the lab practices are very useful, would be great if there are any project assignments', 'Excellent course, material and labs. Congrats for Google professionals and Coursera staff. Keep rockking, cheers!', 'Great insights!', 'Awesome. This part of specialization is worth time and money spent.', 'This course is very helpful.', 'Excellent course; I only wish there were a much longer and more robust lab on optimizing query performance, after all the tips we learned in the corresponding lessons.', "Super GREAT job Evan! This is the most valuable BigQuery courses I've ever learned!", 'good', 'Muy buen curso', 'Some useful insights here that I can immediately apply to my work in BigQuery. ', 'Superb!!!', 'Useful practical course, especially about performance optimization. Window functions have many options, it would be nice to add window size description with practical examples or links to them.', 'A lab on notebook would have been nice.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Fernando E', 'By Oleg Z', 'By Nguyen V T H', 'By Michael T', 'By Timothy W', 'By Christopher C', 'By Kaushik D', 'By José R P', 'By Harold L M M', 'By Scott M', 'By Kristina F', 'By Izzy L', 'By Rian P', 'By Lorenço G A', 'By Yaakov M', 'By michal.krasowski@gmail.com', 'By Vinh H T', 'By Lawrence M', 'By LIJUN L', 'By Ekta M', 'By Jose L C V', 'By Rommel J P', 'By Aditya S', 'By Konstantin F', 'By Akshaya']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 04, 2018', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Dec 01, 2017', 'Feb 13, 2018', 'May 27, 2018', 'Feb 02, 2018', 'Feb 17, 2018', 'Mar 11, 2018', 'Jan 22, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2017', 'Mar 07, 2018', 'Jun 03, 2018', 'Jan 25, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2018', 'Aug 21, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Oct 11, 2018', 'Oct 15, 2018', 'Sep 18, 2018', 'Oct 02, 2018']</review_date></doc>