<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_220</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-visualization</course_url><course_name>Data Management and Visualization</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Lisa Dierker</course_instructor><course_introduction>Whether being used to customize advertising to millions of website visitors or streamline inventory ordering at a small restaurant, data is becoming more integral to success. Too often, we’re not sure how use data to find answers to the questions that will make us more successful in what we do. In this course, you will discover what data is and think about what questions you have that can be answered by the data – even if you’ve never thought about data before. Based on existing data, you will learn to develop a research question, describe the variables and their relationships, calculate basic statistics, and present your results clearly. By the end of the course, you will be able to use powerful data analysis tools – either SAS or Python – to manage and visualize your data, including how to deal with missing data, variable groups, and graphs. Throughout the course, you will share your progress with others to gain valuable feedback, while also learning how your peers use data to answer their own questions.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>SAS Language//Data Analysis//Python Programming//Data Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Wesleyan University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Selecting a research question//Writing your first program - SAS or Python//Managing Data//Visualizing Data//Supplemental Materials (All Weeks)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome Video', 'Video Lesson - Steps in data analysis', 'Video Lesson - What do we mean by data?', 'Video Lesson - Datasets and codebooks', 'Video Lesson - Developing a research question'], ['SAS Lesson 1 - Defining exploratory data analysis', 'SAS Lesson 2 - SAS coding conventions', 'SAS Lesson 3 - Running your program and examining frequency distribution', 'SAS Lesson 4 - Refining your research question by selecting rows', 'Python Lesson 1 - Defining Exploratory Data Analysis', 'Python Lesson 2 - Python Coding Conventions', 'Python Lesson 3 - Running your program and examining frequency distributions', 'Python Lesson 4 - Refining your research question by selecting rows'], ['SAS Lesson 1 - Setting aside missing data', 'SAS Lesson 2 - Coding in valid data and recoding values', 'SAS Lesson 3  - Creating secondary variables', 'SAS Lesson 4 - Grouping variables within individual variables', 'Python Lesson 1 - Setting aside missing data', 'Python Lesson 2  - Coding valid data and recoding values', 'Python Lesson 3 - Creating secondary variables', 'Python Lesson 4 - Grouping values within individual variables'], ['SAS Lesson 1 - Graphing individual variables', 'SAS Lesson 2 - Describing distributions visually', 'SAS Lesson 3 - Measures of center and spread', 'SAS Lesson 4 - Designing the role each of your variables will play', 'SAS Lesson 5 - Graphing decisions: categorical response variables', 'SAS Lesson 6 - Graphing decisions: quantitative response variable', 'Python Lesson 1 - Graphing individual variables', 'Python Lesson 2 - Describing distributions visually', 'Python Lesson 3 - Measures of Center and Spread', 'Python Lesson 4 - Designing the role each of your variables will play', 'Python Lesson 5 - Graphing Decisions: Categorical response variables', 'Python Lesson 6 - Graphing decisions: quantitative response variable'], ['How to Write a Literature Review', 'Translation Code', 'Acknowledgments']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The course doesn't really develop an understanding of Data Management and Visualization outside of the context of SAS or Python syntax. Also there are a number of points throughout the course that would benefit from an update most particularly the initial documentation to get started with SAS. The LIBNAME in the downloadable PDF is incorrect and it took me a significant amount of effort to identify and resolve the error since I was unfamiliar with the process.", 'This course states that it is for people with no knowledge in SAS. I had to go online elsewhere to learn SAS before completing this course. There are free SAS tutorials on the SAS webpage - I highly recommend completing them before trying this course. ', 'I came into this course after getting a rough idea about data analysis (from the IBM introduction courses), and this definitely adds on to the experience. The instructors make sure that the student is conceptually sound by the end of the course. Highly recommended.', "I wanted to do the whole specialization this course is a part of, but the forums are inactive and questions go unanswered... You're also at the mercy of peer reviewers, who may grade unfairly if there are technical difficulties, and who may not grade you in a timely manner. (Or they don't submit their assignments so you can grade them in a timely manner.) The videos have WAY too much B-roll and not enough visual aids. ", 'great course, excellent course material', 'I enjoyed every bit of ot', 'Very helpful for beginners ', 'Excellent introduction to SAS no matter what your field of research. Videos are clear and easy to follow. Looking forward to doing the next course.', "It's very clear and innovative!", 'Nice introductory course to learning both SAS and Python in data analysis!  I look forward to taking the next course!', 'Very nice course with introduction to Data analysis!', 'Good Learning experience and loved the way of teaching.', 'My name is Jose Antonio. I am looking for a new Data Scientist career (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseantonio11)', "This is not a course for learning Python, and the coding is straightforward as you are given examples for everything. What this course does do is to give really well-presented, high quality lecture materials and (possibly uniquely) allow you to choose a research topic and matching data of your choice to use throughout the specialisation. For me, this is much more motivating than doing analysis on data you really don't care about, just for the sake of it.It's fun to read your fellow student's research blogs, also. Really looks like students on this course are from all over the world.", 'got to grips with SAS', 'wonderful study experience！', 'Very helpful videos and clear explanations. Easy to follow up.', 'Beautifully designed course. Really helps me understand basic data analysis and improve reporting skills. ', 'I thought this course was great.  It helped me get interested in python and think about data in a new way.', 'Good Course simplistic way in explaining core concepts', 'Well done. Thank you.', None, 'excellent course especially for those interested into playing with data', 'Excellent!', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Adam K', 'By Rebekah C', 'By Mukkesh G', 'By JMF', 'By Berend B', 'By uzoamaka', 'By Shubham S', 'By Karen B', 'By Rodrigo B', 'By Shaun M', 'By Ziwen W', 'By Shakoor A', 'By Jose A R N', 'By Rusmat A', 'By Renier S', 'By Taoson', 'By Miguel R', 'By Alexander N', 'By John C V', 'By bijith k', 'By Massimo Z', 'By Mina E ', 'By Bakr G', 'By EKONG, E', 'By MANOJ K']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 07, 2019', 'May 21, 2016', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Oct 19, 2016', 'Jul 25, 2016', 'Jul 05, 2016', 'May 15, 2017', 'Nov 05, 2015', 'Aug 26, 2017', 'Jun 23, 2018', 'Feb 14, 2017', 'Aug 22, 2016', 'Feb 11, 2017', 'Nov 07, 2015', 'Aug 29, 2017', 'Oct 22, 2016', 'Feb 27, 2016', 'Mar 02, 2016', 'Oct 20, 2015', 'Feb 10, 2016', 'Feb 22, 2016']</review_date></doc>