<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_376</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/entrepreneurs-blockchain-technology</course_url><course_name>How Entrepreneurs in Emerging Markets can master the Blockchain Technology</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Co-Pierre Georg</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, you will gain a thorough understanding of the blockchain and distributed ledger technologies, including an introduction to the necessary foundations in cryptography. The course will discuss blockchain as a distributed ledger and introduce distributed consensus as a mechanism to maintain the integrity of the blockchain. The other revolutionary technologies that are changing the world as we speak are artificial intelligence and machine learning. You will learn about the three major types of AI algorithms: supervised and unsupervised machine learning, as well as reinforcement learning. 

You will learn about the application of blockchain outside of finance. In particular, how blockchain fundamentally changes the way we deal with our personal data. You will see how the web 2.0 model--where big companies like facebook and google collect as much of your personal data as possible to sell it to third parties--is coming to an end. The new web 3.0 is decentralized and uses the power of the blockchain to put users in full control over their own data. Finally, we will look at the benefits and considerations of blockchain and whether blockchain is the right solution for your problem.

#UCTFintech</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Finance</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Cape Town</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Cryptographic foundations of the blockchain//Mastering the blockchain technology//How Artificial Intelligence Changes Data Analytics//Preparing your company for the fintech revolution</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['How Entrepreneurs in Emerging Markets can master the Blockchain Technology', 'What Excites You About Blockchain?', 'Introduction to week 1', 'Financial Markets Today: Financial Intermediation', 'Financial Market Infrastructures', 'How blockchain can change the financial system', 'A blockchain-based startup: Proof of Steak', 'Public Key Cryptography', 'Hash Functions - Five Properties', 'Merkle Trees'], ['Introduction to Week 2', 'Single- and double-entry bookkeeping', 'In conversation: How will blockchain disrupt banks?', 'What is a blockchain?', 'From blocks to blockchain', 'Distributed consensus', 'Consensus Mechanisms overview', 'Consensus Mechanism: Proof Of Work', 'Consensus Mechanism: Proof of Stake'], ['Introduction to Week 3', "What is artificial intelligence? - A bird's eye view", 'Artificial Intelligence in Banks', 'Unsupervised learning - Agglomerative clustering', 'Unsupervised learning - Partitional clustering', 'Supervised learning', 'Supervised learning - Classification and Regression', 'Reinforcement learning', 'Aunnie Patton Power: Artificial Intelligence in Impacting Investing', 'Benji Meltzer: Aerobotics - Using Artificial Intelligence for tree crop protection'], ['Introduction to Week 4', 'Web 3.0 - from client-server architecture to distributed applications', 'Blockchain benefits', 'Blockchain considerations', 'Blockchain outside finance: supply chain solutions', 'Custos Media Technologies - Fighting piracy using blockchain', 'Do you need blockchain?', 'Custos Media Technologies - Do you need blockchain?']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Best course I have ever done in Coursera, very useful, insightful, straight-forward, most important, necessary course for those who don't know much about Financial Technology. The course allows you to understand the meaning of blockchain, the need for blockchain and the future blockchain can provide. If you'd like to be prepared to what is coming next in the Technology world, then do yourself a favor and do this course; its a life changer!", 'Really very thought of course. Strongly recommended. Thank you so much...', 'Excellent introduction to Blockchain and AI and their applications in business. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Hélda M', 'By Kolaiel A ', 'By Louise']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 06, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019']</review_date></doc>