<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_368</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/functional-mri-2</course_url><course_name>Principles of fMRI 2</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Martin Lindquist, PhD, MSc</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course covers the analysis of Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) data. It is a continuation of the course “Principles of fMRI, Part 1”</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Module 1A: Crises in neuroscience and psychology: Problems and solutions', 'Module 1B: Crises in neuroscience and psychology: Problems and solutions', 'Module 2A: Pitfalls and Biases in Interpretation: Circularity, Reverse inference, Voodoo, and Beyond', 'Module 2B: Pitfalls and Biases in Interpretation: Circularity, Reverse inference, Voodoo, and Beyond', 'Module 3: Meta Analysis', 'Module 4: Using meta-analysis to improve inference', 'Module 5: Optimizing acquisition for your study goals', 'Module 6: Resting-state fMRI'], ['Module 7A: Advanced Experimental Design I - Fundamentals of design efficiency', 'Module 7B: Advanced Experimental Design I - Fundamentals of design efficiency', 'Module 8: Advanced Experimental Design II – Efficiency in fMRI', 'Module 9: Advanced Experimental Design III – Optimizing experimental designs with genetic algorithms', 'Module 10: Model building: Parametric modulators', 'Module 11: Basis Sets II: Smooth FIR, HTW, Basis sets at 2nd level', 'Module 12A: Multicolinearity and diagnostics', 'Module 12B: Multicolinearity and diagnostics', 'Module 13: Robust regression', 'Module 14A: Practical group analysis: Procedures and checks', 'Module 14B: Practical group analysis: Procedures and checks'], ['Module 15: Brain Connectivity – different types', 'Module 16: Functional Connectivity', 'Module 17: Multivariate Decomposition Methods', 'Module 18: Dynamic Connectivity', 'Module 19: Network Analysis I – Graph theory', 'Module 20: Effective Connectivity', 'Module 21: Mediation, moderation, and structural models', 'Module 21B: Mediation, moderation, and structural models'], ['Module 22: Directed graphs: DCM', 'Module 23: Directed graphs: Granger causality', 'Module 24: Principles of causal inference', 'Module 25: Multi-voxel Pattern Analysis: A neuroscientific perspective', 'Module 25B: Multi-voxel Pattern Analysis: A neuroscientific perspective', 'Module 26: MVPA Intro', 'Module 27: Performing MVPA I', 'Module 28: Performing MVPA II', 'Module 29: MVPA-PM Example – NPS - Expand: Social and physical pain', 'Module 29B: MVPA-PM Example – NPS - Expand: Social and physical pain']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent courses, very useful. Worth enrolling and purchasing.', 'Great course and demonstration with real research examples.', 'Very useful and interesting', 'Very interesting. I liked very much the last bit on MVPA.', 'Excellent!', 'Just amazing! It helps me a lot. I will recommend it to everyone working with me in the college. And these two teachers are lovely! Thanks!', 'Thanks a lot, both curses were very interesting and will help a lot in future research!', 'Comprehensive, Informative &amp; exciting course... highly recommended for Psychiatrists, or any mental health professionals interested in neuropsychiatry and neuroscience !', 'بسیار خوب', 'Superb!', 'You guys are amazing!! Excellent course!!', 'Similar to the first installment of the series. I found this course enlightening and easily digestible, especially considering the advance material it discusses. Overall enjoyable experience. ', 'Thank you again guys for your work!', 'Very good course. Best week is the last week. Its does a good overview of fMRI Statistical analysis and design of experiments.', 'Excellent, thorough explanation of the computations and theory underlying fMRI analysis. I particularly enjoyed the emphasis on MVPA. Thanks!', 'pretty great', 'The course was ery good, I wish it also included working with sample fmri data.', 'Still very good course with a lot to offer especially parts covering new methods. The only downside for me were the mathematical parts by Martin which got complex, messy and seemed to be explained not as clear as in previous course. Some ecological, more experiment related examples could be useful to help understand mathematical operations and formulas.', "Pretty good lectures that touch on many aspects of fmri but doesn't really get into enough details to really learn about the difficulties with this methodology.   Would be nice if they had some real data processing exercises to demonstrate someof the concepts.", "Disappointed that it's all theory and no application. I know there are a ton of differeint fMRI processing pipelines, but even just to walk through one would be much more useful.", 'Sometimes hard to follow. ', 'Lot of information. Almost no useful instruction. I saw that the instructors knew about lots of cool things. I did not learn how to do any of those cool things.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Peter M', 'By Jinyi K', 'By Yanlei W', 'By Francesco C', 'By Yacila I D A', 'By 田云', 'By Pablo A', 'By Feras A A H A S', 'By farzaneh d d', 'By Hironaka I', 'By Cibele E B', 'By Al-Rashid J', 'By Theodor R', 'By Janzaib M', 'By Ian F', 'By Siyuan G', 'By chekuri o s s v', 'By Jan S', 'By Richard K', 'By Brandy R', 'By seyed s m z', 'By Jordan M']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 16, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Jul 23, 2017', 'Jun 09, 2017', 'Jan 04, 2017', 'Jun 11, 2018', 'Sep 29, 2016', 'May 10, 2018', 'Jul 30, 2016', 'Aug 09, 2016', 'Feb 01, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'May 24, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2016', 'Jan 20, 2017', 'Jan 03, 2017', 'Feb 19, 2017', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'May 03, 2018']</review_date></doc>