<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_401</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/cyber-security-manufacturing</course_url><course_name>Cyber Security in Manufacturing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Shambhu Upadhyaya</course_instructor><course_introduction>The nature of digital manufacturing and design (DM&amp;D), and its heavy reliance on creating a digital thread of product and process data and information, makes it a prime target for hackers and counterfeiters. This course will introduce students to why creating a strong and secure infrastructure should be of paramount concern for anyone operating in the DM&amp;D domain, and measures that can be employed to protect operational technologies, systems and resources. 

Acquire knowledge about security needs and the application of information security systems. Build the foundational skills needed in performing a risk assessment of operational and information technology assets. Gain valuable insights of implementing controls to mitigate identified risks.

Main concepts of this course will be delivered through lectures, readings, discussions and various videos. 

This is the seventh course in the Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design Technology specialization that explores the many facets of manufacturing’s “Fourth Revolution,”  aka Industry 4.0, and features a culminating project involving creation of a roadmap to achieve a self-established DMD-related professional goal.

To learn more about the Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology specialization, please watch the overview video by copying and pasting the following link into your web browser: https://youtu.be/wETK1O9c-CA</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Mechanical Engineering</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Digital Manufacturing Security//Guidance on Securing Digital Manufacturing Operations//Protecting Operational Technologies and Intellectual Property//Breach Response</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Digital Manufacturing Security Part 1', 'Digital Manufacturing Security - Part 2', 'Information Security Framework - Part 1', 'Information Security Framework - Part 2', 'Operational Technology and Informational Technology', 'Risk Management', 'Application of Information Security - Part 1', 'Application of Information Security - Part 2'], ['Securing all Aspects of a Digital Manufacturing Operation', 'Human-Machine and M2M Interactions', 'Securing End to End Process via Security Development Life Cycle', 'Software Security Flaws and Threats', 'Network Security and Authentication - Part 1', 'Network Security and Authentication - Part 2'], ['Protecting Operational Technologies and Intellectual Property - Part 1', 'Protecting Operational Technologies and Intellectual Property - Part 2', 'Supply Chain Security', 'Shipping, RFID tags, Mobile Device Security and Wireless Communication - Part 1', 'Shipping, RFID tags, Mobile Device Security and Wireless Communication - Part 2', 'Data/Applications and Cloud Security', 'Intellectual Property Protection from Threats'], ['Breach Response', 'Reliability versus Security', 'Intrusion Prevention Techniques and Data Leak Prevention Tools - Part 1', 'Intrusion Prevention Techniques and Data Leak Prevention Tools - Part 2', 'Monitoring, Intrusion Detection, and Network Hardening', 'Intrusion Response, Recovery, and Forensics', 'Your 4.0 Roadmap to Success', 'Your 4.0 Roadmap to Success']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['thank you for the course', 'Good', 'E', 'This course addresses an issue that not to be overlooked in Industry 4.0: Cybersecurity! System security is a key strategy for an Advanced Manufacturing project.', 'Very Good Course...', 'A very educational course .', 'great material and course as part of the DMD specialization!', 'Excellent course with a ton of great information and resources.  Learned a lot about cybersecurity and its role in digital manufacturing systems.', 'I liked the course.', 'Unexpectly so good and a lot of detail to learn.', 'good course', 'too lengthy', 'I really appreciate ', 'Overall a good course- the final section (which applies to the DMD specialization) should have had a gate where folks who were only interested in the Cyber security portion could escape.', 'The course is informative but not properly  organized. The most important things missing is not having presentation available for the students to use']</reviews><reviewers>['By Tejash y T G', 'By Atichat P', 'By David H', 'By Wesley T', 'By Tejo R B', 'By Guy G', 'By Vancho D', 'By David C', 'By yashar k s', 'By wittaya s', 'By YASHVANTH', 'By Sanket P', 'By Jachin C', 'By Kevin K', 'By Alireza Z']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 13, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Feb 21, 2018', 'May 02, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2017', 'Jun 13, 2017', 'Jan 24, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2018', 'Jun 01, 2018', 'Aug 02, 2017', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2017', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Jul 25, 2018']</review_date></doc>