<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_0</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning</course_url><course_name>Machine Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Andrew Ng</course_instructor><course_introduction>Machine learning is the science of getting computers to act without being explicitly programmed. In the past decade, machine learning has given us self-driving cars, practical speech recognition, effective web search, and a vastly improved understanding of the human genome. Machine learning is so pervasive today that you probably use it dozens of times a day without knowing it. Many researchers also think it is the best way to make progress towards human-level AI. In this class, you will learn about the most effective machine learning techniques, and gain practice implementing them and getting them to work for yourself. More importantly, you'll learn about not only the theoretical underpinnings of learning, but also gain the practical know-how needed to quickly and powerfully apply these techniques to new problems. Finally, you'll learn about some of Silicon Valley's best practices in innovation as it pertains to machine learning and AI.

This course provides a broad introduction to machine learning, datamining, and statistical pattern recognition. Topics include: (i) Supervised learning (parametric/non-parametric algorithms, support vector machines, kernels, neural networks). (ii) Unsupervised learning (clustering, dimensionality reduction, recommender systems, deep learning). (iii) Best practices in machine learning (bias/variance theory; innovation process in machine learning and AI). The course will also draw from numerous case studies and applications, so that you'll also learn how to apply learning algorithms to building smart robots (perception, control), text understanding (web search, anti-spam), computer vision, medical informatics, audio, database mining, and other areas.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Logistic Regression//Artificial Neural Network//Machine Learning (ML) Algorithms//Machine Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>Stanford University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Linear Regression with One Variable//Linear Algebra Review//Linear Regression with Multiple Variables//Octave/Matlab Tutorial//Logistic Regression//Regularization//Neural Networks: Representation//Neural Networks: Learning//Advice for Applying Machine Learning//Machine Learning System Design//Support Vector Machines//Unsupervised Learning//Dimensionality Reduction//Anomaly Detection//Recommender Systems//Large Scale Machine Learning//Application Example: Photo OCR</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Machine Learning!', 'Welcome', 'What is Machine Learning?', 'Supervised Learning', 'Unsupervised Learning'], ['Model Representation', 'Cost Function', 'Cost Function - Intuition I', 'Cost Function - Intuition II', 'Gradient Descent', 'Gradient Descent Intuition', 'Gradient Descent For Linear Regression'], ['Matrices and Vectors', 'Addition and Scalar Multiplication', 'Matrix Vector Multiplication', 'Matrix Matrix Multiplication', 'Matrix Multiplication Properties', 'Inverse and Transpose'], ['Multiple Features', 'Gradient Descent for Multiple Variables', 'Gradient Descent in Practice I - Feature Scaling', 'Gradient Descent in Practice II - Learning Rate', 'Features and Polynomial Regression', 'Normal Equation', 'Normal Equation Noninvertibility', 'Working on and Submitting Programming Assignments'], ['Basic Operations', 'Moving Data Around', 'Computing on Data', 'Plotting Data', 'Control Statements: for, while, if statement', 'Vectorization'], ['Classification', 'Hypothesis Representation', 'Decision Boundary', 'Cost Function', 'Simplified Cost Function and Gradient Descent', 'Advanced Optimization', 'Multiclass Classification: One-vs-all'], ['The Problem of Overfitting', 'Cost Function', 'Regularized Linear Regression', 'Regularized Logistic Regression'], ['Non-linear Hypotheses', 'Neurons and the Brain', 'Model Representation I', 'Model Representation II', 'Examples and Intuitions I', 'Examples and Intuitions II', 'Multiclass Classification'], ['Cost Function', 'Backpropagation Algorithm', 'Backpropagation Intuition', 'Implementation Note: Unrolling Parameters', 'Gradient Checking', 'Random Initialization', 'Putting It Together', 'Autonomous Driving'], ['Deciding What to Try Next', 'Evaluating a Hypothesis', 'Model Selection and Train/Validation/Test Sets', 'Diagnosing Bias vs. Variance', 'Regularization and Bias/Variance', 'Learning Curves', 'Deciding What to Do Next Revisited'], ['Prioritizing What to Work On', 'Error Analysis', 'Error Metrics for Skewed Classes', 'Trading Off Precision and Recall', 'Data For Machine Learning'], ['Optimization Objective', 'Large Margin Intuition', 'Mathematics Behind Large Margin Classification', 'Kernels I', 'Kernels II', 'Using An SVM'], ['Unsupervised Learning: Introduction', 'K-Means Algorithm', 'Optimization Objective', 'Random Initialization', 'Choosing the Number of Clusters'], ['Motivation I: Data Compression', 'Motivation II: Visualization', 'Principal Component Analysis Problem Formulation', 'Principal Component Analysis Algorithm', 'Reconstruction from Compressed Representation', 'Choosing the Number of Principal Components', 'Advice for Applying PCA'], ['Problem Motivation', 'Gaussian Distribution', 'Algorithm', 'Developing and Evaluating an Anomaly Detection System', 'Anomaly Detection vs. Supervised Learning', 'Choosing What Features to Use', 'Multivariate Gaussian Distribution', 'Anomaly Detection using the Multivariate Gaussian Distribution'], ['Problem Formulation', 'Content Based Recommendations', 'Collaborative Filtering', 'Collaborative Filtering Algorithm', 'Vectorization: Low Rank Matrix Factorization', 'Implementational Detail: Mean Normalization'], ['Learning With Large Datasets', 'Stochastic Gradient Descent', 'Mini-Batch Gradient Descent', 'Stochastic Gradient Descent Convergence', 'Online Learning', 'Map Reduce and Data Parallelism'], ['Problem Description and Pipeline', 'Sliding Windows', 'Getting Lots of Data and Artificial Data', 'Ceiling Analysis: What Part of the Pipeline to Work on Next', 'Summary and Thank You']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 56 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Overall the course is great and the instructor is awesome. Machine learning is fascinating and I now feel like I have a good foundation.  A few minor comments: some of the projects had too much helper code where the student only needed to fill in a portion of the algorithm.  I would have preferred to have worked through more of the code. Also, there were a few times when the slides didn't contain the complete equations so it was difficult to piece it all together when writing the code.  Lastly, I wish that there was more coverage on vectorized solutions for the algorithms.", 'It would be better if it would have been done in Python', 'Excellent starting course on machine learning. Beats any of the so called programming books on ML. Highly recommend this as a starting point for anyone wishing to be a ML programmer or data scientist.', "I've never expected much from an online course, but this one is  just Great!", 'This is an extremely basic course. Machine learning is built on mathematics, yet this course treats mathematics as a mysterious monster to be avoided at all costs, which unfortunately left this student feeling frustrated and patronized. So much time is wasted in the videos with arduous explanations of trivialities, and so little taken up with the imparting of meaningful knowledge, that in the end I abandoned the videos altogether. The quizes were basic (largely based on recall of, rather than application of knowledge), as were the programming assignments (nearly all of which were spoon-fed, with the tasks sometimes being simple as multiplying two matrices together).', "Sub title should be corrected. Since I'm not that good in English but I know when there're mis-traslated or wrong sub title. If you fix this problems , I thin it helps many students a lot. Thanks!!!!!", 'I am Vietnamese who weak in English. To learn this course I have to choose playback rate 0.75.', 'This course has of course (pun intended) built a formidable reputation for itself since it was laucnhed. I took the course in 2019 when it had been around for a few years and so what I am saying here may resonate with a lot of people who have taken the course before me. "Concretely"(!), Prof Ng takes the student on a very well structured journey that covers the vast canvas of ML, explaining not just the theoretical aspects but also laying equal empahsis on the pratical aspets like debugging or choosing the right approach to solving a ML problem or deciding what to do first / next. At that level this course is highly recomended by me as the first course in ML that anyone should take. I do have a suggestion to make regarding how some of the portions could have been explained more lucidly. These are portions that pertain entirely to the mathematics and programming problems, where I struggled for days and (for back propogation) for months before realising that maybe the explanation given in the slide wasn\'t clear enough and at times i just needed to try really random ideas to get out of the programmin rut that I was stuck in. An advise for anyone doing the course would be to write down the matrices in full detail and do the transformations of cost fucntion and gradient descent or back prop using pen and paper and attempt to write the code for it only after once one is clear about the exact mathematical operation happening. Thank you, Prof Ng for gifting this course to the online learners community and I would also like to thank the mentors who have replied to the queries patiently while stadfastly enforcing the honour code.', 'It would be ideal course if instead of octave pyhon or r is used', 'You need to know, what do you want to get out of this course. It gives you a lot of information, but be prepared to work hard with linear algeabra and make efforts to compute things in Mathlab/Octave. ', 'Very helpful and easy to learn. The quiz and programming assignments are well designed and very useful. Thank Prof. Andrew Ng and coursera and the ones who share their problems and ideas in the forum.', 'Everything is taught from basics, which makes this course very accessible- still requires effort, however will leave you with real confidence and understanding of subjects covered. Great teacher too..', 'I just started week 3 , I have to admit that It is a good course explaining the ideas and hypnosis of machine learning . The instructor takes your hand step by step and explain the idea very very well.', 'The course is ok but the certification procedure is a mess!', "I‘m a Chinese post-graduate student of Computer Sciense. This class is very useful to me because of it's amazing course videos and the well-designed programming exercises. It is really lucky to have this opportunity to find the course and to finish it. This class will be a footstone for further studying in AI field for anyone who just get started.", "Overall, this is a great course and I learned an enormous amount of information.  The biggest issue I had was the disconnect between the course and the assignments/quizzes.  Although they had help sections, because you couldn't ask direct questions about the algorithms/quizzes, if you had a problem, you were basically on your own. (At least that is what it felt like.)  For example, if you missed a quiz question and couldn't figure out the answer, there seemed little recourse to find the actual answer.  In a couple cases, I decided to just take the 80% on a quiz simply because I had no idea what the answer was.", 'Explained well but I was not able to implement  it on exercise.', 'It was a great learning experience. All the lectures were in details.  ', 'Very good instruction for machine learning, and also very very good for new comers!!!', 'It was a very helpful course.', 'Course content was awesome, gave me lot of insights. If assignments were in Python, it would have helped a lot to improve my skills. Anyways I would recommend this course to a beginner who wants to understand the logic behind the machine learning process. Thank You AndrewNg Sir!!!', 'Good Course', 'Excellent Machine Learning Lessons which need little advanced knowledge of mathematics.', 'Explanation was very good and assignment helps us to understand the real picture. The way course is planned along with octave exercise, Graphs and visualization of data (X,Y) is very good. Very good course who is starting the Machine learning from scratch.    ', 'Exceptional. Best course to start learning Machine Learning! Only one grouse though, the exercises are in Matlab and not in python.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Robert G C J', 'By Rishav S', 'By Murali N', 'By Vasily', 'By Deleted A', 'By Pooritat T', 'By anhhuy', 'By rajeev a', 'By Имильбаев Р Р', 'By Olga K', 'By Mike L', 'By Jason S', 'By Fadi', 'By Bruno C', 'By JImmy C', 'By Anton D', 'By OMKAR K D', 'By Nikhil J', 'By Hou Z', 'By Aditya K', 'By Prabhu N', 'By Mohan K', 'By Akyuu F', 'By vinod', 'By Prateek J']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 11, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2016', 'Apr 07, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2017', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'May 08, 2019', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Apr 18, 2018', 'Aug 19, 2017', 'Jun 17, 2017', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'Nov 09, 2015', 'May 19, 2019', 'Apr 24, 2019', 'Mar 30, 2019', 'May 18, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'May 18, 2019', 'May 28, 2019', 'May 18, 2019', 'May 08, 2019', 'May 18, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019']</review_date></doc>