<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_123</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/linear-regression-model</course_url><course_name>Linear Regression and Modeling</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course introduces simple and multiple linear regression models. These models allow you to assess the relationship between variables in a data set and a continuous response variable. Is there a relationship between the physical attractiveness of a professor and their student evaluation scores? Can we predict the test score for a child based on certain characteristics of his or her mother? In this course, you will learn the fundamental theory behind linear regression and, through data examples, learn to fit, examine, and utilize regression models to examine relationships between multiple variables, using the free statistical software R and RStudio.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Linear Regression//R Programming//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About Linear Regression and Modeling//Linear Regression//More about Linear Regression//Multiple Regression//Final Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Statistics with R'], ['Introduction', 'Correlation', 'Residuals', 'Least Squares Line', 'Prediction and Extrapolation', 'Conditions for Linear Regression', 'R Squared', 'Regression with Categorical Explanatory Variables'], ['Outliers in Regression', 'Inference for Linear Regression', 'Variability Partitioning'], ['Introduction', 'Multiple Predictors', 'Adjusted R Squared', 'Collinearity and Parsimony', 'Inference for MLR', 'Model Selection', 'Diagnostics for MLR'], ['Project Files and Rubric']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course is good regarding concepts and theoretical exercises, but poor regarding applying new knowledge in R. Since the course is introductory, an instruction how to install R and a list of R functions without clear explanation how they should be applied in general regression situations makes me explore other sources to learn how to apply those concepts (e.g. DataCamp, CRAN-RProject, etc) and then get back to learn theory? Sorry for expectations but course should provide a full and integrated package of knowledge and skills, especially for beginners. ', 'Really great course, clear and easy to follow. Highlight recommended. ', "I feel I'm running out of complement words for this course series. In conclusion, clear teaching, helpful project, and knowledgeable classmates that I can learn from through final project. ", "It's a very good course for starting to learn about linear regression. Just be aware that the quality of this course is a bit lower than the previous two. There are fewer videos, the book material is shorter (less suggested exercises and the chapters cover fewer things about linear regression) and some quiz exercises of week 2, which should only cover simple linear regression, have some questions about multiple linear regression which is the 3rd week's topic. ", 'Great instruction on stats, however the R portion a weekly project that is largely self directed, very little instruction.', 'it provides a superficial knowledge. A deep understanding of subject can not be gain from this course', 'She just started with wk 2. There should have been more explanation and videos in week 1...not very interesting.  I think statistics you need to take in person.', 'Not suitable for beginners', 'Amazing content!', 'The flow of information is clear and understandable. ', 'Great course, just like the rest of the specialization.', 'Simple syllabus, but excellent explanation. ', '10/10', 'The applications of linear regression models are vast. This is a useful course.', 'Great contents and great teacher. I enjoyed it very much.', 'Very good, and most important of all, very well explained!', 'Excellent. A well designed course and the explanation are very easy to understand', 'Great course!', 'Nice module! It is very clear.', 'The course provides good insights for linear regression. Also, I think the professors are intended to statistics and its application in real life.', 'A great intro to linear regression, both from theoretical and practical point of view.  Really enjoyed the course! ', 'Exceptionally helpful for beginners due to perfect combination of theoretical and practical sessions.', 'Instructor  teaches the concept well , a new to statistics can learn easy', 'Best course in the series so far. Highly recommended! Seriously.', 'Very good course. while it does not cover everything. the teacher does a great job explaining things in a simple manner. My feed back would be to move ANOVA into this module. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mindaugas Z', 'By Richard M', 'By Rui Z', 'By Diego R G', 'By Mark N', 'By Anukul', 'By M. I F', 'By Syed S R', 'By Tulio R C', 'By Abdullatif A', 'By Dario B', 'By YASHKUMAR R T', 'By Gencay I', 'By Sergio E T', 'By Henri M', 'By Aleix D', 'By Alfredo J N', 'By Olga', 'By GUO S', 'By Charles C', 'By Daniel C J', 'By PRIYANKA D', 'By Sylas J', 'By Emmanouil K', 'By Omar K']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 07, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'May 25, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Jun 09, 2016', 'Sep 13, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jun 08, 2017', 'Mar 19, 2017', 'Sep 22, 2016']</review_date></doc>