<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_30</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/excel-intermediate-1</course_url><course_name>Excel Skills for Business: Intermediate I</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr Yvonne Breyer</course_instructor><course_introduction>Spreadsheet software remains one of the most ubiquitous pieces of software used in workplaces across the world. Learning to confidently operate this software means adding a highly valuable asset to your employability portfolio. In the United States alone, millions of job advertisements requiring Excel skills are posted every day. Research by Burning Glass Technologies and Capital One shows that digitals skills lead to higher income and better employment opportunities at a time when digital skills job are growing much faster than non-digital jobs.

In this second course of our Excel specialization Excel Skills for Business you will build on the strong foundations of the Essentials course. Intermediate Skills I will expand your Excel knowledge to new horizons. You are going to discover a whole range of skills and techniques that will become a standard component of your everyday use of Excel. In this course, you will build a solid layer of more advanced skills so you can manage large datasets and create meaningful reports. These key techniques and tools will allow you to add a sophisticated layer of automation and efficiency to your everyday tasks in Excel.

Once again, we have brought together a great teaching team that will be with you every step of the way. Prashan and Nicky will guide you through each week (and I am even going to make a guest appearance in Week 5 to help you learn about my favourite tool in Excel - shh, no spoilers!). Work through each new challenge step-by-step and in no time you will surprise yourself by how far you have come. This time around, we are going to follow Uma's trials and tribulations as she is trying to find her feet in a new position in the fictitious company PushPin. For those of you who have done the Essentials course, you will already be familiar with the company. Working through her challenges which are all too common ones that we encounter everyday, will help you to more easily relate to the skills and techniques learned in each week and apply them to familiar and new contexts.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Concatenation//Microsoft Excel//Consolization//Pivot Table//Pivot Chart</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>Macquarie University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Working with Multiple Worksheets &amp; Workbooks//Text and Date Functions//Named Ranges//Summarising Data//Tables//Pivot Tables, Charts and Slicers//Final Assessment</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Week 1 Introduction', 'Week 1 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Multiple Worksheets', 'Practice Video: 3D Formulas', 'Practice Video: Linking Workbooks', 'Practice Video: Consolidating by Position', 'Practice Video: Consolidating by Category (Reference)', 'Week 1 Wrap-Up'], ['Week 2 Introduction', 'Week 2 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Combining Text (CONCAT, &amp;)', 'Practice Video: Changing Text Case (UPPER, LOWER, PROPER)', 'Practice Video: Extracting Text (LEFT, MID, RIGHT)', 'Practice Video: Finding Text (FIND)', 'Practice Video: Date Calculations (NOW, TODAY, YEARFRAC)', 'Week 2 Wrap-Up'], ['Week 3 Introduction', 'Week 3 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Introducing Named Ranges', 'Practice Video: Creating Named Ranges', 'Practice Video: Managing Named Ranges', 'Practice Video: Named Ranges in Formulas', 'Practice Video: Apply Names', 'Week 3 Wrap-Up'], ['Week 4 Introduction', 'Week 4 Discussion', 'Practice Video: COUNT functions', 'Practice Video: Counting with Criteria (COUNTIFS)', 'Practice Video: Adding with Criteria (SUMIFS)', 'Practice Video: Sparklines', 'Practice Video: Advanced Charting', 'Practice Video: Trendlines', 'Week 4 Wrap-Up'], ['Week 5 Introduction', 'Week 5 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Creating and Formatting Tables', 'Practice Video: Working with Tables', 'Practice Video: Sorting and Filtering in Tables', 'Practice Video: Automation with Tables', 'Practice Video: Converting to Range and Subtotaling', 'Week 5 Wrap-Up'], ['Week 6 Introduction', 'Week 6 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Creating and Modifying a Pivot Table', 'Practice Video: Value Field Settings', 'Practice Video: Sorting and Filtering a Pivot Table', 'Practice Video: Reporting Filter Pages', 'Practice Video: Pivoting Charts', 'Practice Video: Pivoting Slicers', 'Week 6 Wrap-Up'], ['Final Assessment']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I found the following areas to be particularly useful to learn about:', 'I would like to extend my thanks without exception to everyone who has participated in the creation of this amazing course. Seriously WOW!! Now I just feel very proud of being Macquarie University student knowing that my university has one of the best Excel training courses on all online training platforms.', 'Greetings to all of you', 'It was great experience ', "I learned a lot from this course. Before starting this course I even can't plot a simple graph for my reports but then this course helped me learning mind blowing skills. Thanks Macquarie University.", 'It was a good experience. I have learned many new tools and how to work smartly. i recommend every Student and employee to go through this course because excel makes work easier. Thanks Coursera.', "Best Coursera course I've taken, with the following reasons: 1/ easy to digest, 2/ great demo, 3/ thoughtful practice (application of knowledge), 4/ clear narration with great visual support (the videos aren't only showing you a screenshot of the instructor's screen but actually zooming in here and there, student's can see clearly where they should click on).  Just great!", 'Truly educative', 'It was great to learn through this course..thanks very much..much appreciated', 'really helpful', '-', 'Well Structured, crisp, and insightful. Well done!', "Excellent Class. I learned a great number of things in this class. I can't wait until the next class. I am enjoying them and learning new things.", "I had Started this course from scratch Excel Business Essential, I felt the urge to dig deeper and got my self enrolled into Intermediate Level 1 Where I got to know about Absolute and reference Cell which seems to be daunting and i did not know why my excel records behave in weird manner. More Importantly i used to refer the columns by their reference which was not easy to remember but by the help of ranges It was very easy to link different columns from different worksheets. Nested used of formulas gave me control over my desired results. and i did not know much about pivot table and it's filter and hidden feature. If any body who wants to learn excel i will strongly recommend to give it a shot", 'The course is excellent in that it gives you spreadsheet samples to practice on. ', 'Very good course! I learned so many skills that are a + for my carrer', 'Excellent and so easy to learn and comprehend', 'Fantastic course, lots of great new tools and very pos', 'Great course in the Excel material and lectures. ', 'well taught!', 'Cours très bien mené du point de vue pédagogique', 'Great', 'Nice course! I learn a lot from it, and i feel more confident about my routine work', 'Excellent course!', 'Great course to enhance our Excel skills!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Joakim E E', 'By Harry G', 'By Musharaf K', 'By Hari K M', 'By Haris J', 'By HAMZA F', 'By Candice S', 'By Olamiji S', 'By Muhammad A', 'By Marina J', 'By Tejasvi H', 'By Utsav P', 'By David M', 'By Inam H', 'By Shaun W', 'By Lisanet G U', 'By ROLLAND E O', 'By Elena S', 'By Emily N', 'By waseela a k', 'By Françoise V', 'By Juan A', 'By Julian L', 'By Łukasz M', 'By Duc T N']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 09, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Nov 16, 2018', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Jan 03, 2019']</review_date></doc>