<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_40</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-visualization-tableau</course_url><course_name>Fundamentals of Visualization with Tableau</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Suk S. Brar, M.B.A.</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this first course of the specialization, you will discover just what data visualization is, and how we can use it to better see and understand data. Using Tableau, we’ll examine the fundamental concepts of data visualization and explore the Tableau interface, identifying and applying the various tools Tableau has to offer. By the end of the course you will be able to prepare and import data into Tableau and explain the relationship between data analytics and data visualization. This course is designed for the learner who has never used Tableau before, or who may need a refresher or want to explore Tableau in more depth.  No prior technical or analytical background is required.  The course will guide you through the steps necessary to create your first visualization story from the beginning based on data context,  setting the stage for you to advance to the next course in the Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Tableau Software//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Visualization (Computer Graphics)</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started &amp; Introduction to Data Visualization//Exploring and Navigating Tableau//Making Data Connections//Context of Data Visualization &amp; Course Wrap-Up</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction and Specialization', 'Introduction to Data Visualization', 'What is Data Visualization and Why Do We Do It?', 'Tools for Data Visualization', 'Installing Tableau', 'Creating Your First Visualization'], ['Exploring and Navigating Tableau Overview', 'Importing Visualizations', "Navigating the Tableau Public's Software - Part 1", "Navigating the Tableau Public's Software - Part 2", "Navigating the Tableau Public's Software - Part 3"], ['Making Data Connections Overview', 'Preparing Your Data For Import', 'Primary Types of Connections', 'Preparing Your Data', 'Connecting and Merging Multiple Data Sources'], ['Context of Data Visualization Overview', 'The "Who, What, and How" of Data Visualization', 'Illustration of the "Who, What, and How"', 'Context of Data Visualization', 'Course Wrap-Up']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is terrible for many reasons. Firstly, the amount of content is ridiculously small - only about 20 minutes of video lectures per week. Moreover, more than 50% of content is just non-relevant. ', "The content might be ok but the support on this course is ridiculous. Mentors/teachers don't respond in the discussions which means assignments are poorly understood. Then 'peer graded assignments' are a joke - how can a peer grade you when they don't even understand the assignment cause its so poorly written. I got completely opposite grading from two different people, meaning one is clearly wrong but both count as my 'grade' - don't bother with this course, save up a few months and go to a real course where you can speak to the teacher and don't have depend on morons scoring your assignments. ", 'I\'m sorry but this course is just bad. The fact that the assignments are peer reviewed put you in a dead lock. You are at the mercy of "peers" that doesn\'t even check the answers you provide and are just plainly rude. Disappointing. ', 'This course is very good intro to anyone that has never done Data Visualization. You get clear understanding of the objectives and the  Fundamentals of what Data Visualization is all about.', 'course was great no doubt , except the 2nd week assignment which was difficult to interpret.  ', 'Great start. Excellent videos and the introduction of material was done very well', 'Good for beginners', 'This was very helpful in learning the basics to using Tableau. I learned how to effectively import and analyze data. ', 'super easy', None, "I am so happy I took this course.  It provided me with the Fundamentals, encouragement, and ability to practice viz's by watching how they did their own.  The book that was assigned was inspirational.  Our assignments were challenging and then I challenged myself in creating about  eight visualizations.", 'really good', 'Great Course! Wonderful delivery of the fundamentals of the software as well as the Data Visualization framework.', 'It was a well scripted and thought out course and of course helped me learn lots of new stuff', "It's a good course. I am currently in the second course in this specialization and it has already captivated me in the world of Tableau.", 'Nice introduction. You will definetly find the foundation of Visualization on this course and start thinking Vizzes.. Good content', 'This was a great class to understand the beginnings of visualizations by understanding the data and the questions that you need answered and think about.', 'It was fun to learn!! ', None, 'A very good course for new comer. E', 'A very nice course to begin Tableau!', 'Good insight on visualization', 'Extremely satisfied by this course! looking forward to more such courses', 'very good course for beginners to learn the tableau visualization and basic fundamentals about the visualization concepts', 'The course gives a great introduction to the concepts of Data Visualization ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mykola S', 'By Katrina', 'By Juan P H G', 'By Tumelo M', 'By Nitin K', 'By Sarena L M', 'By Vignesh', 'By Jolito R', 'By Curt W', 'By Taruna S', 'By Barbara S', 'By BIJINI C', 'By Kevin R P', 'By Abey', 'By Kashyap M', 'By Jamiil T A', 'By JULIE D', 'By Parul J G', 'By Abhijeet N', 'By Yanlin P', 'By Meghana R', 'By Farin M', 'By Sebin K T', 'By Vinoth', 'By Arnab G']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 24, 2016', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Apr 18, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2017', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>