<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_246</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/intro-practical-deep-learning</course_url><course_name>An Introduction to Practical Deep Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Andres Rodriguez</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course provides an introduction to Deep Learning, a field that aims to harness the enormous amounts of data that we are surrounded by with artificial neural networks, allowing for the development of self-driving cars, speech interfaces, genomic sequence analysis and algorithmic trading. 

You will explore important concepts in Deep Learning, train deep networks using Intel Nervana Neon, apply Deep Learning to various applications and explore new and emerging Deep Learning topics.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>Intel</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Deep Learning and Deep Learning Basics//Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), Fine-Tuning and Detection//Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN)//Training Tips and Multinode Distributed Training//Hot Research and Intel's Roadmap//Final Quiz</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Deep Learning', 'Exercise 1: Introduction to Deep Learning', 'Deep Learning Basics', 'Exercise 2: Deep Learning Basics'], ['Convolutional Neural Networks', 'Exercise 3: Convolutional Neural Networks', 'Fine-Tuning and Detection', 'Exercise 4: Fine-Tuning and Detection'], ['Recurrent Neural Networks', 'Exercise 5: Recurrent Neural Networks'], ['Training Tips', 'Exercise 6: Training Tips', 'Multinode Distributed Training'], ['Hot Research', 'Exercise 8: Reinforcement Learning', "Intel's Roadmap"], ['Final Quiz']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Thank you Intel and Coursera', 'Excellent learning experience. Thank you...', 'A very dense and informative course.', 'Love this course!! Thanks. ', 'Awesome experience', 'well it has been a good course for me to get an overall view on Deep learning , but there was so much information in every video that was hard to grasp from the first time', 'very good', 'Great course', 'No projects! The knowledge level is good though.', 'Tough Enough To Remove Dust Of Time From Your Brain. Quizes Were Good Brain Exercise', 'Good for theory knowledge , but very low in practical knowledge', 'The theoretical aspect is good for those aiming at basics but the neon exercises are average. The data sets should be readily imported or there should at least be one standard method to import any kind of data set. Except for this part, the exercises complemented the videos.', "This course is not worth the time and money. I would suggest doing  any of courses in the Andrew Ng's deeplearning.ai specialization instead. No programming assignments that's evaluated here. No instructor or TA are active in the forums. No questions are answered in the discussion forums.  Many courses in deep learning are available online where you can actually learn something by getting hands-on. "]</reviews><reviewers>['By RAMA R R', 'By Ehtesham H', 'By Emil L', 'By Brad C', 'By Anirban L', 'By Mohammed S E', 'By Ambar R', 'By Dongliang Y', 'By Praveen k', 'By Gunjan B', 'By Shubham r', 'By Raveesh G', 'By Ramakrishna B C']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 01, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Sep 25, 2018', 'May 13, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Apr 28, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Jul 07, 2019', 'Apr 05, 2019']</review_date></doc>