<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_287</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/stereovision-motion-tracking</course_url><course_name>Stereo Vision, Dense Motion &amp; Tracking</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Radhakrishna Dasari</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course enables learners to develop 3D vision applications using a stereo imaging system. They are introduced to stereo vision theory, dense motion and visual tracking. They are able to discuss techniques used to obtain the 3D structure of objects. Topics include epipolar geometry, optical flow, structure from motion, multi-object tracking, 3D vision and visual odometry.    

This course is ideal for anyone curious about or interested in exploring the concepts of computer vision. It is also useful for those who desire a refresher course in mathematical concepts of computer vision. Learners should have basic programming skills and experience (understanding of for loops, if/else statements), specifically in MATLAB (Mathworks provides the basics here: https://www.mathworks.com/learn/tutorials/matlab-onramp.html).  Learners should also be familiar with the following: basic linear algebra (matrix vector operations and notation), 3D co-ordinate systems and transformations, basic calculus (derivatives and integration) and basic probability (random variables).   
  
Material includes online lectures, videos, demos, hands-on exercises, project work, readings and discussions. Learners gain experience writing computer vision programs through online labs using MATLAB* and supporting toolboxes.

This is the third course in the Computer Vision specialization that lays the groundwork necessary for designing sophisticated vision applications. To learn more about the specialization, check out a video overview at https://youtu.be/OfxVUSCPXd0. 

 * A free license to install MATLAB for the duration of the course is available from MathWorks.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Algorithms</course_category><course_tag>Computer Programming//Stereopsis//Matlab//3D Vision</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Stereo Vision//Dense Motion &amp; SFM//Visual Tracking//3D Vision</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Stereo Vision', 'Stereo Vision Fundamentals', 'Epipolar Geometry', 'Fundamental &amp; Essential Matrices', 'Multiple View Geometry'], ['Introduction to Visual Motion', 'Optical Flow', 'Dense Motion Applications', 'Structure from Motion (SFM)'], ['Introduction to Visual Tracking', 'Motion Models &amp; Tracking', 'Tracking as Inference', 'Multi-Object Tracking', 'Is Multi-Object Tracking Difficult?'], ['Introduction to 3D Vision', 'Why is 3D Vision Important?', 'Shape from X', 'Depth from Active Sensing', 'Model-Based Reconstruction', 'Visual Odometry &amp; SLAM']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['When some one takes a course he/she expects a little detail behind each explanation, when ever the instructor said lets go in details, probably the explanation was more sparse than before. One should write, compute and explain the math behind any algorithm not just an abstract verbal explanation. The course was not up to mark. I Cancelled it in the middle.', "Assignment in week 1 don't  have any information.", "This class is awful, don't do it because you will lose your time and your money! "]</reviews><reviewers>['By Manish S', 'By Jangsoo P', 'By Brice L']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 31, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>