<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_181</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/basic-data-processing-visualization-python</course_url><course_name>Basic Data Processing and Visualization</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Julian McAuley</course_instructor><course_introduction>This is the first course in the four-course specialization Python Data Products for Predictive Analytics, introducing the basics of reading and manipulating datasets in Python. In this course, you will learn what a data product is and go through several Python libraries to perform data retrieval, processing, and visualization. 

This course will introduce you to the field of data science and prepare you for the next three courses in the Specialization: Design Thinking and Predictive Analytics for Data Products, Meaningful Predictive Modeling, and Deploying Machine Learning Models. At each step in the specialization, you will gain hands-on experience in data manipulation and building your skills, eventually culminating in a capstone project encompassing all the concepts taught in the specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Libraries//Data Pre-Processing//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Web Scraping</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1:  Introduction to Data Products//Week 2: Reading Data in Python//Week 3: Data Processing in Python//Week 4: Python Libraries and Toolkits//Final Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What is a Data Product?', 'Data Product Examples in Enterprise', 'Developing a Data Product Strategy', 'Python and Jupyter Basics', 'Python Recap', 'Livecoding: Getting Started With Jupyter'], ['CSV &amp; JSON Files', 'Reading CSV &amp; JSON Files', 'Processing Structured Data in Python', 'Live-Coding: JSON', 'Extracting Simple Statistics From Datasets', 'Simple Statistics: Live-Coding'], ['Data Filtering and Cleaning', 'Processing Text and Strings in Python', 'Processing Times and Dates in Python', 'Livecoding: Time and Date Data'], ['Matrix Processing and Numpy', 'Introduction to Data Visualization', 'Introduction to Matplotlib', 'Live-coding: MatPlotLib', 'urllib and BeautifulSoup'], ['Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course is easy to follow, well organized, and assumes very little background.  It effectively demonstrates the power of Python in large data applications and provides insights and guidance on which tools are best used.', 'Over all a great course for beginner', 'Excellent to start your career in machine learning!!!', 'Excellent and interesting course', 'Great first class in this series. ', 'This course enables students to learn intermediate level skills in data wrangling, data exploration,  and visualization. The final project requires selecting a topic of personal interest and constructing a complete project work flow. By doing this, areas of weakness in data wrangling, cleaning/QA, data exploration, and visualization may to uncovered and addressed. The result is to build greater skills and confidence. ', 'Great course for an absolute beginner!', "The positives: I liked the design of the final project, and how users were encouraged to 'get out there' and find some interesting open source data sets. The lectures were well structured with good narratives and good examples. ", 'Quick intro to data processing. More material on numpy and pandas would have been nice. Im still trying to figure out why the specialization mentions "Design Thinking". At least in this course...not a single design thinking concept was mentioned.', 'The test scripts make no sense.', "This is not a Python introduction, but the authors approach it as if it were.  Even the most basic data scientist will not calculate averages in the way described here. We'd use pandas or similar to get not just means, but other summary stats as well.  For a Python course, I could understand doing it the way shown here.  But not for data science."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Carl W', 'By Zakir U S', 'By Mohd Z A', 'By Oriol P M', 'By Cambron T D', 'By Clarence E Y ', 'By umair', 'By Sebastian S', 'By Jonas J T', 'By Davide C', 'By Paul E J']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 27, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Aug 12, 2019', 'May 22, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019']</review_date></doc>