<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_196</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-decision-making-scenarios</course_url><course_name>Decision-Making and Scenarios</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Richard Lambert</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is designed to show you how use quantitative models to transform data into better business decisions. You’ll learn both how to use models to facilitate decision-making and also how to structure decision-making for optimum results. Two of Wharton’s most acclaimed professors will show you the step-by-step processes of modeling common business and financial scenarios, so you can significantly improve your ability to structure complex problems and derive useful insights about alternatives. Once you’ve created models of existing realities, possible risks, and alternative scenarios, you can determine the best solution for your business or enterprise, using the decision-making tools and techniques you’ve learned in this course.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Cash Flow//Financial Statement//Balance Sheet//Investment</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Evaluation Criteria: Net Present Value//Evaluating Projects//Expressing Business Strategies in Financial Terms//New Product Value</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction &amp; Overview', '1.1 Introduction: Criteria for Evaluating Projects', '1.2 Time Value of Money', '1.3 NPV Analysis of Projects', '1.4 Other Evaluation Techniques', '1.5 The Cost of Capital'], ['2.1 Introduction and Analyzing Incremental After-Tax Cash Flows - Initial Investment Phase', '2.2 Analyzing Incremental After-Tax Flows - Operating Phase', '2.3 Analyzing Incremental After-Tax Flows - Terminal Phase', '2.4 Example: New Production Machine', '2.5 Key Considerations in Evaluations'], ['3.1 Introduction to Financial Statements', '3.2 Balance Sheets and Income Statements', '3.3 Cash Flow Statements'], ['4.1 Introduction and Speadsheet Setup', '4.2 Forecasting Future Cash Flows', '4.3 NPV and IRR Calculations', '4.4 Formulation and Evaluation of Alternative Scenarios', '4.5 Expanding Beyond the Time Horizon', 'Course Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Tries to cram a huge amount of financial accounting into less than 4 hours of lecture.  There's no way anyone could assimilate all the information if they don't already have a finance background.", "Class was too simple, especially with regards to scenario analysis. Professors should've covered scenario manager tool, data tables and other scenario analysis techniques. Also, the methods used were academic, e.g. week 3; professors should've taught NPV/IRR via DCF analysis.", 'Fantastic course. Great depth and and breadth within the scope of the subjects covered and explained quite complex concepts very clearly and systematically', 'EXCELLENT. BUT ONE COULD ALSO ADD SOLUTIONS TO THE GIVEN QUIZES FOR BETTER UNDERSTANDING', 'the lecturers were very friendly while explaining every bit of study material, and throughout the course I was mesmerized by the way they teach. overall this course is must to do for those who want o take important decisions for their business firms. so 5 star', "Hi, I'm a spanish spoken student. ", 'This is a solid course on financial decision making. Highly recommended for those who work in operations management and on strategic initiatives and projects.', 'Great professors, dood use of spreadsheets, step by step explanation', 'Great course!', 'The teachers were very knowledgeable, and taught this information well. My ONLY concern is that Module 3 contained a lot of information that would have made Module 2 easier to understand, and as such the content in Module 3 should have been presented before the content in Module 2.', 'If anyone is interested to get a head start with excel and valuation, this is a great course. The best part is you can re-visit the videos for references.', "Excellent design, optimum amount of information to cover both the foundation, but also practical application of each of the items in the financial statements and their inter-connections. Pace of 3rd and 4th modules a little fast. Hard to keep up with that pace if the learner has a tired mind. Don't recommend to take those lessons after working hours, or when otherwise tired :). Dedicate solid 2 hours with fresh mind, and you will benefit greatly from this course.", 'This week was not all that difficult.', 'Best course to understand the project valuation and the concept of IRR and NPV. Awesome way of explanation with real examples.', 'very good course. could be a bit longer on week 4 to explore the spreadsheet model', 'An excellent course, helps improve understanding on how to assess a projects feasibility. ', ' Although I have taken financial accounting and financial management courses before, it was due to this course that I am now able to combine knowledge from both to successfully evaluate projects. The depth of knowledge was really enlightening.', 'I liked the class and it gave good information. The professors ordered the materials well, and I would recommend anyone to take this MOOC.', 'Very good online decision-making and scenarios course!\n', None, 'A little bit too much of a shift towards accounting during the latter half, but still an excellent short course.  Learned a lot in a short amount of time.', 'I had a great experience with this course. The course content was short and concise. ', 'Very good knowledge to understand the value of projects through of a period of time.', 'The course material and examples are very useful. I really like the CF spreadsheet at the end of week 4 as this is very organized CF model and I can use this as reference to build my own. Thank you!', 'Excelent course']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ephraim B', 'By Morgan S', 'By Fahad A', 'By Prateek S', 'By maanas s', 'By Ivan D A G', 'By Andrew J', 'By Adrian J M S', 'By Zhongyuan Z', 'By Emem M', 'By Evangelina F X', 'By Karen V', 'By Surendra K', 'By Shivam c', 'By André I', 'By Kartik S', 'By Zacharias L', 'By Dorothy L M', 'By Ooi T K', 'By Aidan B', 'By Justin F', 'By himanshu s', 'By Paulo D F', 'By Shisa R', 'By Jose J E F']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 29, 2017', 'Apr 30, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'Sep 04, 2018', 'Sep 12, 2018', 'Oct 02, 2018', 'Oct 07, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2018', 'Jul 14, 2017', 'May 27, 2016', 'Jul 23, 2016', 'May 13, 2017', 'Jun 07, 2017', 'Apr 02, 2017', 'Nov 15, 2017', 'Apr 23, 2017', 'Jan 22, 2017']</review_date></doc>