<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_6</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-for-applied-data-science-ai</course_url><course_name>Python for Data Science and AI</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Joseph Santarcangelo</course_instructor><course_introduction>This introduction to Python will kickstart your learning of Python for data science, as well as programming in general. This beginner-friendly Python course will take you from zero to programming in Python in a matter of hours.

Module 1 - Python Basics
o	Your first program
o	Types
o	Expressions and Variables
o	String Operations

Module 2 - Python Data Structures
o	Lists and Tuples
o	Sets
o	Dictionaries

Module 3 - Python Programming Fundamentals
o	Conditions and Branching
o	Loops
o	Functions
o	Objects and Classes

Module 4 - Working with Data in Python
o	Reading files with open
o	Writing files with open
o	Loading data with Pandas
o	Numpy 

Finally, you will create a project to test your skills.

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Python Programming//Numpy//Pandas</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Python Basics //Python Data Structures //Python Programming Fundamentals //Working with Data in Python //Analyzing US Economic Data and Building a Dashboard </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Types', 'Expressions and Variables', 'String Operations'], ['List and Tuples', 'Dictionaries', 'Sets'], ['Conditions and Branching', 'Loops', 'Functions', 'Objects and Classes'], ['Reading Files with Open', 'Writing Files with Open', 'Loading Data with Pandas', 'Pandas: Working with and Saving Data', 'One Dimensional Numpy', 'Two Dimensional Numpy', 'Simple APIs (Part 1)', 'Simple APIs (Part 2)'], ['Overview', 'IBM Digital Badge']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Course focuses more on forcing you to sign up for various IBM cloud tools than learning python.  The final assignment has a 300+ reply thread in the discussion forum because you are graded on the ability to integrate your IBM Watson Notebook with IBM cloud storage, but the instructions have multiple errors, such as not working if you provision your storage in the wrong region.', "The worst course I took. I couldn't believe the course is provided by IBM. The slide is completely unclear and there are some small mistakes in that. And the final project is aimless, I don't know why you come up with such a project for the beginner. Anyway, I'm so disappointed with IBM and this course. ", "Still I don't understand the relation of the course' content and the final assignment. ", "  As in the other parts of the certificate, the tasks are simply too easy. The content in the videos (many typos!!!!) are really valuable but the tasks man... Only the surface of the surface will be discussed, no deeping down into the wild. In this course the libraries numpy and pandas are presented but in the final assignment we actually don't needed the libs... When I read the description of the final assignment, I was excited because I assumed we will need to code EVERYTHING ourselves. So really do the thinking of how to solve the requirements, testing it in a notebook out, reading the docs, discovering new cool stuff... But unfortunately my dream did not come true. The most exciting function was already provided and some of the answers were little bit of copy and paste instead of really recalling newly learned knowledge. Before this review I really wanted to give 4 out of 5 stars but after writing this review I will now give only 2 stars. Actually, 2 stars are in my opinion unfair, since the creators have put a lot of time and love in the course content. Unfortunately, so much potential is thrown away  ", 'The IBM cloud "service" leaves much to be desired. Multiple times I\'ve experienced outages while I was in the middle of lab assignments. It\'s a paid course where they give you "free" credits to do the course work in their cloud "service." But the credits are inadequate for the labs and they constantly ask for your credit card to buy more "service." While the class is okay I wouldn\'t recommend it to anyone because of the poor IBM cloud support.', 'I had a lot of problems with the Peer Assignment, which had nothing to do with Python Programming. The Watson environment has changed a lot compared to the learning materials.', "The course content is good. However, the instructions for the final peer graded assignment are unclear. It appears to me that we were graded on our ability to interact with IBM cloud and Watson service not so much python skills also. Although I completed, I would not recommend to other until changes are made. It seems I'm not the only one that is unhappy or who had difficulties, just look at the week 5 discussion forum!", "It is amazing how bad this is considering that it is marketed as an IBM product. This is not the level of quality people expect when they hear the name IBM! You'd be better off paying 9.99 for a Udemy course than taking this course. It is not in depth at all and does a stunningly poor job at building real understanding and competency. The videos and labs are full of sloppiness and errors... again, not living up to the IBM name. I don't know about y'all, but I'm probably never going to pay money for a coursera course again... not really worth it.", 'The final assignment changed during the course from fake album cover to economic data analysis and dashboarding.', "Time waster, doesn't go in depth, the total video content is of less then 2 hours. The quizzes and assignments are too easy.", 'Need detailed explanation for the topics, course need to be rephrased accordingly.', 'No support from moderators, plenty of typos.', '\n(5 stars):  Course was great!!  ', 'Final test needs to be actually tested by instructors. Has a few bugs in it. You would learn more about python reading a book. ', 'The final project at week 5 needs to be completely revamped.  Poor learning experience...absolutely ridiculous and is creating tremendous frustration amongst all students.', 'This class was supposed to be for beginners and most of the information in the videos was easy to digest, however, the final project had elements and questions that were never covered. Also, there were many, many spelling and context errors in the videos and quizzes. This lead to a tremendous amount of confusion and I am not happy with this course or my grade. Please consider reviewing the lessons and final project to cater this course more to beginners.', 'Every course has offered something interesting, challenging, and surprising.  I am glad I have spent the time with this class.  I would strongly recommend it to others with an interest in data science.', 'The lessons are very concise, the most fundamental concepts are taught appropriately, and beginners can learn quick. The exercises are not too hard to make you lose interest, and not too easy that they become boring. I was totally immersed in the course so I found this greater than any physical classroom lessons. 6 STARS! ', "the final assingment is somewhat tricky, but it's ok", 'Excellent outline. This course performs fabulous way for beginner can achieve the python language effortlessly.', 'From zero knowledge to a good knowledge on Python. ', 'Good course but final assignment is very poorly designed in terms of instructions.', 'The videos are quick, had to keep rewinding to grasp at the details. A slower pace would help beginners.', 'Very high level overview of Python. To gain skills, you will need lots of practice outside of this class. Good overview. Lots of typos - could use a good proofreading.']</reviews><reviewers>['By David J', 'By Jiayang Z', 'By Ruben F S', 'By Aykut Ö', 'By Steve O', 'By Robert', 'By Declan H M G', 'By Julian L G', 'By Jason A C', 'By Het P', 'By Vigneshwaran P', 'By Michael R', 'By Asim I', 'By Simon O', 'By Jason U', 'By Jennifer P', 'By William B L', 'By Troy L Y X', 'By Juan P D', 'By Nhan T N', 'By Julio E L C', 'By Sukanto M', 'By Mahmood H', 'By James C']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 20, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'May 10, 2019', 'May 22, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'May 09, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'May 21, 2019', 'Apr 20, 2019', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019']</review_date></doc>