<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_16</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/open-source-tools-for-data-science</course_url><course_name>Open Source tools for Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Polong Lin</course_instructor><course_introduction>What are some of the most popular data science tools, how do you use them, and what are their features? In this course, you'll learn about Jupyter Notebooks, RStudio IDE, Apache Zeppelin and Data Science Experience. You will learn about what each tool is used for, what programming languages they can execute, their features and limitations. With the tools hosted in the cloud on Cognitive Class Labs, you will be able to test each tool and follow instructions to run simple code in Python, R or Scala. To end the course, you will create a final project with a Jupyter Notebook on IBM Data Science Experience and demonstrate your proficiency preparing a notebook, writing Markdown, and sharing your work with your peers.

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introducing Skills Network Labs//Jupyter Notebooks//Apache Zeppelin Notebooks//RStudio IDE//IBM Watson Studio//Project: Create and share a Jupyter Notebook</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What is Skills Network Labs?', 'Account Features', 'Creating an account.'], ['What are Jupyter Notebooks?', 'Getting started with Jupyter Notebooks'], ['What are Zeppelin Notebooks?', 'Zeppelin for Scala', 'Getting started with Zeppelin'], ['What is RStudio IDE?', 'Uploading files, Installing packages and loading libraries in RStudio IDE', 'Getting started with RStudio IDE', 'RStudio Environment and History'], ['What is IBM Watson Studio (Data Science Experience)?', 'Creating an account on IBM Watson Studio (Data Science Experience)', 'Jupyter notebooks on Watson Studio (Data Science Experience) - Part 1/2', 'Jupyter Notebooks on IBM Watson Studio (Data Science Experience) - Part 2/2'], ['IBM Digital Badge']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I am amazed that IBM even put this course out on Coursera. It is the worst course I have come across. It is a humongous waste of time. It supposedly introduces the IBM Watson Studio but ALL the videos are outdated and do not reflect the platform currently on IBM's website. It is impossible to follow the instructions. You just have to sign up to the platform and hobble along trying to make sense of it. The quizzes were a utter waste of time. They don't even reflect the content in the videos. Many of the questions had topics that were not even covered. I was unable to do the final assignment because it's impossible to get to the Jupyter notebooks page when you sign in. It was an incredibly frustrating experience. I wasn't alone - the discussion forums are filled with hundreds of comments on the same issue - not being able to find the webpage where they need to create a notebook and do the assignment. I did not see any of the moderators even bothering to reply. Why have you put this course out here if you have no interest in providing quality content or help when your content is utterly outdated. I question IBM's reputation. This is a shambles of a course that I actually paid for (still paying since they changed it to a monthly debit!). I am in two minds whether to even continue with this certificate - seems ", "The experience of using IBM Watson really sucks! Tons of problems just kept poping out all the way from creating accounts to using notebook. And these problems have been existing for months, which is really shameful. Hope there's somebody can fix these problems right away.", 'Links are out of date', 'Very informative... But the instructor could have given a proper link in the description as it was very difficult to navigate through and have lost a lot of time figuring the way out', "The entire section is without any introductions, any explanations. The services described in the video and actual (revised) versions don't line up. Instructor is just a useless, read-it-on guy that doesn't add anything to the learning experience. Overall, useless crap.", 'Videos are bit out of date so could be sometimes tricky to find the needed instructions!', 'the videos are outdated.', "Course videos are outdated as of 1/14/2019. This lead to a lot of time wasted checking the discussion boards for answers. Otherwise it's a great course.", "This course is useless. I spent several days watching videos and reading the materials only to get stuck in the end with no help in sight. Dozens of students are in the forums asking for help but even the instructor couldn't help us with the watson studio software. ", 'Please make this lesson easier to understand. The tutorials regarding how to use the open source tools are also out of date which makes the lesson very confusing. I had to do additional research on youtube, which I honestly found more valuable than this course. ', "\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\n\nYOU\nLEARN ABSOLUTELY NOTHING! One star it's even too much. You learn how to make\naccounts on the IBM's proprietary platform so that you can pay one day (there\nis a monthly limit about the stuff you can do and if you don’t pay you are\nscrewed). Giving away all your private data, of course. A platform that for\nfree gives you the computing power of a 15 years old machine (with many other\ndrawbacks). Jupyter Notebooks, R, Scala, it's all out there without Watson\nStudio, you could have installed Anaconda for example with all the beauty and\nspeed of your personal machine (who doesn't have at least a dual core\nnowadays?). Without considering that would have been a lot more useful. So, you\nwill learn only which open source tools you could use, but they send you on a\nproprietary platform to do that, without teaching you anything about those\ntools. Wait, they ask you to write 1 + 1 on python when you take the exam, you\nare all set with data science. This is a shame!\n\n\n\n", 'Its a good courser : but the instructor is boring ', 'Brief overview of the open source tools such as Jupyter and RStudio.', 'Excellent course', 'This course provided a concise overview of data science tools and sufficient exposure to scenarios that show how to use them. The  Watson Studio needs to be updated to reflect the current sign up process, however. I took of one star for this reason.', 'Good course!!!', 'The exercises could have been a bit more challenging.', 'Please update the videos, with new IBM Watson Studio interface examples.', "Some of the Watson Studio videos are confusing because they are recorded on the previous version and they don't match anymore.", "The course in watson studios contains videos the were too outdated and didn't really help understand how to use the platform as it is nowadays. ", "While the content was informative, the tutorials are not well matched to the work required and there is zero support available, other than the discussion Forum where many others have been waiting weeks for helpful responses.  I have learned from this course to look outside Coursera for support when trying to accomplish the course objectives.  This is not what I expected.  You will see, if you search the internet, many other tutorials exist which actually provide feedback in real time..especially for working in R.  I come to this course with no prior computer programming experience which is likely the reason I have struggled and been so lost. This was promoted as a beginner course but you will see, if you go through the lessons yourself, as if you were a new learner, that suppositions have made about the learner possessing prior knowledge to succeed in this course.  If you read the discussion Forum you will see several people expressing surprise that IBM is associated with a course this poorly organized and supported. I was excited to learn about the many Open Source Tools available for Data Science, and did appreciate the exposure to Watson Studio. I plan to revisit IBM's videos on youtube to gain more experience. For the problematic disconnect between the instructions given and the assignments expected I would not recommend this course to anyone. ", 'useless and non-up-dated', 'great!!!', 'Course content was good. May want to consider updating some of the videos as some of them do not match with what the IBM UI looks like now.', 'Exceptional on hands training']</reviews><reviewers>['By Shaili P', 'By 宋文傑', 'By John H', 'By karthickeyan k', 'By Egemen C', 'By Mikhael R', 'By Amir H', 'By Nicholas J', 'By Gas', 'By Sparkle W', 'By DD', 'By Mansoor A K', 'By Чернова И Р', 'By Gowtham ', 'By Clarence E Y ', 'By Akhil K', 'By Alexander P', 'By Vinit K S', 'By Diana T', 'By Daniela P', 'By julie c', 'By Daniel G F', 'By DARWIN G V', 'By Petko V', 'By Angel  J C V']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 26, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'May 14, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Jun 01, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'May 15, 2019', 'Jun 01, 2019', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2019', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018']</review_date></doc>