<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_120</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/guided-tour-machine-learning-finance</course_url><course_name>Guided Tour of Machine Learning in Finance</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Igor Halperin</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course aims at providing an introductory and broad overview of the field of ML with the focus on applications on Finance. Supervised Machine Learning methods are used in the capstone project to predict bank closures. Simultaneously, while this course can be taken as a separate course, it serves as a preview of topics that are covered in more details in subsequent modules of the specialization Machine Learning and Reinforcement Learning in Finance.
The goal  of Guided Tour of Machine Learning in Finance is to get a sense of what Machine Learning is, what it is for and in how many different financial problems it can be applied to.

The course is designed for three categories of students:
Practitioners working at financial institutions such as banks, asset management firms or hedge funds
Individuals interested in applications of ML for personal day trading
Current full-time students pursuing a degree in Finance, Statistics, Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics, Engineering or other related disciplines who want to learn about practical applications of ML in Finance  

Experience with Python (including numpy, pandas, and IPython/Jupyter notebooks), linear algebra, basic probability theory and basic calculus is necessary to complete assignments in this course.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>New York University Tandon School of Engineering</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Artificial Intelligence &amp; Machine Learning//Mathematical Foundations of Machine Learning//Introduction to Supervised Learning//Supervised Learning in Finance</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome Note', 'Specialization Objectives', 'Specialization Prerequisites', 'Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Part I', 'Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Part II', 'Machine Learning as a Foundation of Artificial Intelligence, Part I', 'Machine Learning as a Foundation of Artificial Intelligence, Part II', 'Machine Learning as a Foundation of Artificial Intelligence, Part III', 'Machine Learning in Finance vs Machine Learning in Tech, Part I', 'Machine Learning in Finance vs Machine Learning in Tech, Part II', 'Machine Learning in Finance vs Machine Learning in Tech, Part III'], ['Generalization and a Bias-Variance Tradeoff', 'The No Free Lunch Theorem', 'Overfitting and Model Capacity', 'Linear Regression', 'Regularization, Validation Set, and Hyper-parameters', 'Overview of the Supervised Machine Learning in Finance'], ['DataFlow and TensorFlow', 'A First Demo of TensorFlow', 'Linear Regression in TensorFlow', 'Neural Networks', 'Gradient Descent Optimization', 'Gradient Descent for Neural Networks', 'Stochastic Gradient Descent'], ['Regression and Equity Analysis', 'Fundamental Analysis', 'Machine Learning as Model Estimation', 'Maximum Likelihood Estimation', 'Probabilistic Classification Models', 'Logistic Regression for Modeling Bank Failures, Part I', 'Logistic Regression for Modeling Bank Failures, Part II', 'Logistic Regression for Modeling Bank Failures, Part III', 'Supervised Learning: Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The lecture is actually good. The positive experience is totally ruined by the quality of programming assignments though. As someone put it on course forum - they seem as if someone built a poor implementation with odd design choices in rush, then deleted a couple of random lines and asked students to read his/her mind. Not sure if I'll continue the specialization now.", 'Do not take this course before you review week 2,3 and 4 coding assignments which are wholly disconnected and arbitrary guesswork assignments where your task is to fill in missing pieces of code without any guidance or support. In its current stage the course is inaccessible to all but most tenacious learners with significant python and scikit experience. ', "One of the worst courses I've taken on Coursera. These courses really need to be tested before put out for public consumption. ", "Terrible. For the first time in long time I felt such abandoned. No support. Notebooks written sloppy with plenty of copy-paste and no fixing. Thought more of the lecturer as well but videos feel like he's just coming up with the material. Having strong mathematical background I felt that the lecturer is intentionally making simple things sound hard. I'm left with deep sense of wasted time. Leaving Coursera and never coming back.", "Not an introductory level course. If you are new to machine learning, I would suggest taking Andrew Ng's course.....However some materials in this course are somewhat deep and rewarding if you have already got the basis..", 'interesting but big gap between lectures and coding assignments', 'Excellent course with some tech glitches that are being cleared up.', "I rate the lectures and the lecture material a 5; however, the exercises are poorly documented and prepared and there is zero presence on the Forums from any of the TA's.  The exercises, Forum and lack of TA's I rate a 1.  Thus the 3 rating.", 'So many technical issues in the grading system. Also, Assignments are not clearly explained', "1) I don't really understand who is the target audience for this course. ", "I would give this class zero stars if I could. It is a great topic and I had high expectations.  The assignments are poorly worded, instructions are vague and that is putting it mildly.  The material required to complete the assignments is mostly not covered in the lectures.  I can't believe NYU gives its name to this jumbled mess.  Buyer Beware!", 'The assignments are very bad. Some content are hard to understand what it wants me to do. So little instructions about the formula and model, on the contrary, it needs the EXACT SAME answer with the EXACT SAME process of the assignment wants to pass it.', "More or less this course is good and interesting. However, homework assignments were awful. It's unclear and it's very hard to understand what is asked and how it would be graded.", 'Very Difficult - Impossible to succeed without very strong prior experience. Would deserve more guidelines', 'I learned much and got good practice in Python and Tensorflow as well as good exposure to the literature.  I was able to download the course materials from the course system and work out homework on my own system for which I was pleased.  The automatic grading system worked without incident once I figured it out and did not crash on me.  On the other hand, some of the homeworks were less than fully explained and/or motivated by the course material and did contain errors and omissions in the supplied code that I had to track down in order to get them correct.  The feedback from the grader was of no use beyond stating whether the answer was correct, but this is pretty standard.  The course was frustrating at times and I would recommend it only for students who are highly motivated, but for those who are, it is definitely worth the effort.', 'The course is not mature enough. If someone wants to learn machine learning in finance with efficiency and practicality, he or she should consider other options instead of this specialization/course.', 'Good lectures', 'The assignments of the last week were poorly planned, almost impossible to understand.', 'Thank you, for this very useful course!', 'good content', "At first I was irritated that some of the material wasn't covered in class but when I read all of the recommended reading then it became more clear what to do. This course takes time and attention. Its not an introduction course, its more an an intermediate course.  I was impressed with this course as it directly relates to applications in finance and helped me to see how to apply algorithms I already know to finance. It also gave me a bit more mathematical rigor. ", 'A very informative and well paced intro to ML / DL', 'Excellent Course, Professor clases are good complement for other ML courses.', "I liked this course. It extends your knowledge regarding such basic algorithms as linear/logistic regression, gives some useful practice with TensorFlow. But, I would definitely recommend everyone, who didn't understand the material go through it again and read recommended materials after each week. Otherwise, such lack of understanding will be like a snowball.", 'This course is a perfect introduction to machine learning applied to finance, which covers the essentialtopics that students must know to deepen their knowledge in this fascinating field.']</reviews><reviewers>['By maciej.osinski', 'By Teemu P', 'By Leo M', 'By Dawid L', 'By lcy9086', 'By George D', 'By B S C', 'By John G S', 'By Bilal E', 'By Denis K', 'By Steven O', 'By Minglu Z', 'By Vladimir B', 'By Christophe O', 'By Walter O A', 'By Yi B', 'By Kiran', 'By Ronald B', 'By Yergali B', 'By Vinay P K', 'By Jacques J', 'By Pavel K', 'By GUILLERMO R J', 'By Dima S', 'By Juan A S']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 06, 2018', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'Apr 23, 2019', 'Jul 11, 2018', 'Aug 21, 2018', 'Aug 12, 2018', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Apr 19, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'Jun 03, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 29, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2019']</review_date></doc>