<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_180</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/art-science-ml</course_url><course_name>Art and Science of Machine Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to the art and science of machine learning. In this data science course you will learn the essential skills of ML intuition, good judgment and experimentation to finely tune and optimize your ML models for the best performance.  

In this course you will learn the many knobs and levers involved in training a model. You will first manually adjust them to see their effects on model performance. Once familiar with the knobs and levers, otherwise known as hyperparameters, you will learn how to tune them in an automatic way using Cloud Machine Learning Engine on Google Cloud Platform.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Tensorflow//Machine Learning//Cloud Computing//Estimator</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//The Art of ML//Hyperparameter Tuning//A pinch of science//The science of neural networks//Embeddings//Custom Estimator//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction'], ['Introduction', 'Regularization', 'L1 &amp; L2 Regularizations', 'Lab Intro: Regularization', 'Lab: Regularization', 'Learning rate and batch size', 'Optimization', 'Practicing with Tensorflow code', 'Lab Intro: Hand-Tuning ML Models', 'Lab Solution: Hand-Tuning ML Models'], ['Introduction', 'Parameters vs Hyperparameters', 'Think Beyond Grid Search', 'Lab Intro: Improve model accuracy by Hyperparameter Tuning with Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab Solution: Improve model accuracy by Hyperparameter Tuning with Cloud AI Platform'], ['Introduction', 'Regularization for sparsity', 'Lab: L1 Regularization', 'Lab Solution: L1 Regularization', 'Logistic Regression'], ['Introduction', 'Neural Networks', 'Lab: Neural Networks Playground', 'Training Neural Networks', 'Lab: Using Neural Networks to build a ML model', 'Multi-class Neural Networks'], ['Intro to Embeddings', 'Review of Embeddings', 'Recommendations', 'Data-driven Embeddings', 'Sparse Tensors', 'Train an Embedding', 'Similarity Property'], ['Custom Estimator', 'Model Function', 'Lab: Implementing a Custom Estimator', 'Keras Models', 'Demo: Keras Models + Estimator'], ['Summary', 'Specialization Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It has a lot fo great content, but the way it's laid out confused me greatly.", 'This final course is also very good. Embedding is my favorite part and Lak is my favorite instructor.', 'The best course ever to give you the glimpse of the whole ML land - what is ML? Why ML? and most importantly How to do ML for real life business problems - from developing models to model evaluation, serving in production with all scaling tips and techniques with essence of Cloud. The best course for ML practitioners out there. Learnt a lot and what other place to learn from apart from the people who are actually doing it for the most popular products used across the web and mobile world.', 'Labs were had less quality than in previous weeks.', "Too shallow to truly be useful. I think if anything it gives you an idea of what's possible and roughly the areas you should explore and learn about but you won't learn too much following this through.", 'Some lab contents are distracting from the core subject, deviate from the video contents.', 'The quality of the lesson material is great but the quantity is nowhere sufficient to get the hands-on experience', 'Labs vms are to slow.  Speaker is difficult to understand.  Mic varies and speech pattern is not clear.  The presentations need some graphics rather than a guy talking.  Sketch out the ideas on a white board rather than  talking 5 minutes to a single slide.', 'Very very informative for learning....had good time to gothrough this course...', 'Thank you for such wonderful classes, it helps me a lot on tensorflow  learning.', 'Great inside about the core topics with real word problems which make learning easier and practical. Thanks a lot for this great course', 'thanks for the great work. There is so much to learn and I appreciate the effort you made to break things down and providing lab while making the hard decisions on what to commit. ', 'This was the most useful course in the specialisation.', 'GREAT MENTORS with GREAT LEARNING EXPERIENCE', 'Excelente curso, muchas gracias!!', 'Amazing way to keep the audience interested. Throughout the specialization, I was always interested to learn what was about to come, next up. I completely recommend this specialization. It is a fun way to learn!!', 'nice', 'Loved the breadth and depth of machine learning topics in this course.', 'Excelente', 'finest', 'Its one of the best course for machine learning ', 'Very interesting course! Specifically the last modules with custom estimators and the ability to create estimators straight from Keras! ', "\nThank you for this course and specialization, it really good. There were some small bumps in the labs, but those were minor. Appreciate the work you've done to put out this course and the specialization!", 'Wow, really enjoyed parts of this one. Thanks', 'Great course! You get some basics on how to fine tune your model (and why those methods are effective). Nice introduction to NN and what I think was the most relevant: building estimators from scratch and how Keras can offer a simpler way to work.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Eric', 'By Jun W', 'By Soham M', 'By Luciano M', 'By Laimonas S', 'By Yakup K Y', 'By Dmitry B', 'By john f d', 'By Raja R G', 'By Morris C', 'By Pawan K T', 'By Mark B', 'By Richard K', 'By Aman K S', 'By Alan I S R', 'By Putcha L N R', 'By Bielushkin M', 'By Zezhou J', 'By Jordan K R M', 'By Somaiya J G', 'By Muyide I', 'By Chingiz K', 'By Gennady L', 'By Harm t M', 'By Mario R']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 01, 2019', 'May 30, 2018', 'Oct 12, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'May 20, 2019', 'May 06, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Nov 23, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019']</review_date></doc>