<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_395</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/analytics-capstone</course_url><course_name>Increasing Real Estate Management Profits: Harnessing Data Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Egger</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this final course you will complete a Capstone Project using data analysis to recommend a method for improving profits for your company, Watershed Property Management, Inc. Watershed is responsible for managing thousands of residential rental properties throughout the United States. Your job is to persuade Watershed’s management team to pursue a new strategy for managing its properties that will increase their profits. To do this, you will: (1) Elicit information about important variables relevant to your analysis; (2) Draw upon your new MySQL database skills to extract relevant data from a real estate database; (3) Implement data analysis in Excel to identify the best opportunities for Watershed to increase revenue and maximize profits, while managing any new risks; (4) Create a Tableau dashboard to show Watershed executives the results of a sensitivity analysis; and (5) Articulate a significant and innovative business process change for Watershed based on your data analysis, that you will recommend to company executives. 

Airbnb, our Capstone’s official Sponsor, provided input on the project design. The top 10 Capstone completers each year will have the opportunity to present their work directly to senior data scientists at Airbnb live for feedback and discussion.

"Note: Only learners who have passed the four previous courses in the specialization are eligible to take the Capstone."</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Tableau Software//MySQL//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Data Extraction and Visualization//Modeling//Cash Flow and Profits//Data Dashboard//Dashboard for Decision-makers//Final Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the Capstone Project', 'What Watershed Owners Care About', 'Elicitation Interview with Your Project Manager', "Elicitation Interview with Watershed's Marketing Director", "Elicitation Interview with Watershed's Financial Director"], ['Meet Your Data'], ['Creating a Predictive Model for Short-term Rental Rates', 'Normalizing Rents to Improve Occupancy Forecasting', 'Using the Dollars to Percentile Conversion Guide Spreadsheet', 'Optimizing Rents to Maximize Revenues', 'Using the Solver Revenue Maximization Guide Spreadsheet'], ['Estimating Watershed Cash Flow and Profits', 'Distinguishing Cash Flow from Profits and Losses', 'Using the Annual Cash Flows and Profits Spreadsheet'], ['Using Tableau to Perform Sensitivity Analysis', 'Dashboard for Analyst Use', 'Dashboard Modification for a Financial Audience', 'Bar in Bar Graphs in Tableau', 'Histograms in Tableau', 'Tables in Tableau'], ['Preparing Your Dashboard for Decision-makers', 'Jittered Maps in Tableau'], ['Persuading Decision-makers to Follow Your Recommendations', 'Congratulations on Joining the Exciting Field of Data Analytics!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 27 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great project to show the skills you learned!', 'I highly recommend this as a data analysis course. Other MOOCs in data analysis satisfy themselves with teaching you to swim with wings in the paddle pool. Here you graduate with stormy seas swimming skills that will help you in the real world. Very challenging but very worthwhile. ', "The capstone project and corresponding course work is amazing. The project is framed as a business analysis problem with you acting as the analyst. You are tasked with exploring the company's database to extract the relevant information, construct a predictive model in Excel, visualize the results in Tableau, and deliver a persuasive presentation for your expert recommendation. This project actually utilizes skills learned throughout the specialization with an actual application of knowledge. Duke doesn't leave you stranded though. The course offers quizzes along the way to ensure that you have the correct values to arrive at the correct assumptions at each step so you know you can accomplish this task. I highly recommend this project and thank the University for this learning opportunity.", 'This course would help you consolidate all the learnings from the previous modules and apply them in a realistic situation.', 'It was great and I learned a lot. This is making me want to go back to grad school to get my MBA in Finance and a Masters in Business Analytics. :) The only thing I think could be improved is to be more clear on the instructions in certain areas and let students do the analysis part. ', 'The workload of this course is not very high. This course also expands slightly on Tableau skills from the previous course on Tableau. One of the first few weeks also involve extracting data using SQL, so this was new experience. My overall opinion is that this course really spoon-feed quite a bit, so that during the peer review you can see almost everyone comes with almost identical proposal. As of now it seems there is still a healthy number of students who take this module (which is really important for any peer-reviewed course). Finally kudos to the team and Coursera for making this course free for anyone who have completed the other courses in this specialization.', 'This was a good Capstone, learned so much.', 'A great way to put the learning into practice. Strongly encourage anyone who started this specialisation course to complete the Capstone project.', None, 'Awesome course, the business case, realy cool', 'Good', 'Amazing!!!', 'It really help me summarise the critical point I learned through out the course.', 'Simply awesome, it did not only helped me to develop the required skills, but gave me the security to try greater. Astounding method, totally recommended specialization', "It's very worth taking.", 'This was a great course. Enabled you to apply what you have learned from previous courses in order to complete your project. Highly recommended if you would like to deepen your skills in data analytics. ', 'Excellent course :)', 'Fantastic course, very well prepared. Thank you !!!', 'Great capstone course that successfully integrates all the concepts learning in the previous courses.', 'You will be proud of yourself when you complete this Capstone !', 'A great learning experience', 'Absolutely fantastic course and specialization. It was hard work with some very late nights but the best things don\'t come easily. I wish to thank Dr Egger and Dr Schaich Borg for their energy, enthusiasm and time to make this course so good - and to making it accessible at such a reasonable cost to us in Africa.  The dancing videos were a scream and I finally "get" the unicorn thing. One of the most profound learning experiences I\'ve ever had.', 'Excellent!', 'Wonderful course! The final project is so interesting! I could also communicate with my peers and learn from their work. ', 'Excelente curso para aplicar as ferramentas vistas nos cursos anteriores.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mikhail P', 'By Michael N', 'By Michael D', 'By Seshadri G', 'By Nicholas A P', 'By Wong L L', 'By Virgil B', 'By Megan C', 'By Sabrina R', 'By David A R B', 'By Kuljeet K', 'By Majid A', 'By Ge W', 'By Javier C', 'By Yunyun G', 'By Chua E', 'By Kathryn M L', 'By Grzegorz K', 'By Ken W', 'By D. C', 'By Rochelle A', 'By Paul J H L', 'By Hongyi Y', 'By Lingwei H', 'By Francisco D']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 11, 2018', 'Aug 31, 2017', 'Jul 25, 2016', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'Sep 17, 2017', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Nov 01, 2018', 'Aug 23, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2017', 'Mar 01, 2017', 'Mar 19, 2016', 'Aug 06, 2017', 'Oct 19, 2016', 'Oct 12, 2016', 'Jan 23, 2018', 'Mar 19, 2016', 'Jul 25, 2016', 'Mar 28, 2017', 'Jul 30, 2017', 'Jun 28, 2017', 'Oct 20, 2016', 'Apr 13, 2018', 'Mar 27, 2017', 'Aug 08, 2016']</review_date></doc>