<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_202</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/experimentation</course_url><course_name>Experimentation for Improvement</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Kevin Dunn</course_instructor><course_introduction>We are always using experiments to improve our lives, our community, and our work. Are you doing it efficiently? Or are you (incorrectly) changing one thing at a time and hoping for the best? 

In this course, you will learn how to plan efficient experiments - testing with many variables. Our goal is to find the best results using only a few experiments. A key part of the course is how to optimize a system.

We use simple tools: starting with fast calculations by hand, then we show how to use FREE software. 

The course comes with slides, transcripts of all lectures, subtitles (English, Spanish and Portuguese; some Chinese and French), videos, audio files, source code, and a free textbook. You get to keep all of it, all freely downloadable.

This course is for anyone working in a company, or wanting to make changes to their life, their community, their neighbourhood. You don't need to be a statistician or scientist! There's something for everyone in here. 
⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯
Over 1000 people have completed this online course. What have prior students said about this course?

"This definitely is one of the most fruitful courses I have participated at Coursera, considering the takeaways and implementations! And so far I finished 12 [courses]."

"Excelente curso, flexible y con suficiente material didáctico fácilmente digerible y cómodo. No importa si se tiene pocas bases matemáticas o estadísticas, el curso proporciona casi toda explicación necesaria para un entendimiento alto."

"I wish I had enrolled in your course years ago -- it would have saved us a lot of time in optimizing experimental conditions." Jason Eriksen, 3 Jan 2017

"Interesting and developing both analytical and creative thinking. The lecturer took care to bring lots of real live examples which are fun to analyze." 20 February 2016.

"... love your style of presentation, and the examples you took from everyday life to explain things. It is very difficult to make such a mathematical course accessible and comprehensible to this wide a variety of people!"
⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯⎯</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Process Optimization//R Programming//Experimental Design//Experiment</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>McMaster University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Analysis of experiments by hand//Using computer software to analyze experiments//Getting more information, with fewer experiments//Response surface methods (RSM) to optimize any system//Wrap-up and future directions</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Promotional video for this course', '1A: Why experiments are so important', '1B: Some basic terminology', '1C: Analysis of your first experiment', '1D: How NOT to run an experiment'], ['2A: Analysis of experiments in two factors by hand', '2B: Numeric predictions from two-factor experiments', '2C: Two-factor experiments with interactions', '2D: In-depth case study: analyzing a system with 3 factors by hand', 'Enrichment: Made for you by Madeleine: an interview with Joy'], ['3A: Setting up the least squares model for a 2 factor experiment', '3B: Solving the mathematical model for a 2 factor experiment using software', '3C: Using computer software for a 3 factor experiment', '3D: Case study: a 4-factor system using computer software', 'Enrichment: Dr. Soo Chan Carusone talks about experiments in a medical context'], ['4A: The trade-offs when doing half-fraction factorials', '4B: The technical details behind half-fractions - math warning!', '4C: A case study with aliasing in a fractional factorial', '4D: All about disturbances, why we randomize, and what covariates are', '4E: All about blocking', '4F: Introducing aliasing notation', '4G: Using aliasing notation to plan experiments', '4H: An example of an analyzing an experiment with aliasing', 'Enrichment: My colleague, David, and his student Jeff, talk about water treatment experiments'], ['5A: Response surface methods (RSM): an introduction', '5B: Response surface methods (RSM): one variable', '5C: Why changing one factor at a time (OFAT) will mislead you', '5D: The concept of contour plots and which objectives should we maximize', '5E: RSM in 2 factors: introducing the case study', '5F: RSM case study continues: constraints and mistakes', '5G: RSM case study continues: approaching the optimum', 'Enrichment: An interview with Dr. Joe Kim (McMaster University)'], ['6: The big picture (wrapping it up, and other topics)']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The absolute best starting point if you need to learn DOE at an urgency.  It is up to par and even beyond professional options that charge thousands of dollars for a 40 hour, 1 week course. Professor Dunn even offers a free coursebook to complement his excelent lectures, which goes well beyond the intensive 5-6 weeks period. Uses R for programming and gives just the necessary snippets of code needed to complete every exercise and quiz. Plenty of real-life examples and a succinct style makes this course your only stop to understand DOE and then go on your own. Statistics are not needed, but having a previous background will help you appreciate even more the quality and effort put in every lecture. Two words of advice: 1 ) Take notes, as every video is full of little details. 2 ) It is the entry-level DOE course, seasoned experimenters will finish all units in 1 or 2 weeks.', 'A very good introduction to the concept of Design of Experiments. The course gives you a good overview and leaves you with a manual for your own work. Furthermore the course has several extras, e.g. an own online textbook.', 'This is a great course to learn how to perform efficient experiments by varying multiple factors at a time. For scientists who do R&amp;D research, this is an invaluable tool that will set you apart from your colleagues. In this course you learn "Experimental Design" with a bit of R code to get you started. The lessons progress at an even and steady pace that helps you retain information taught in previous sections. This was a very well executed course.', 'Highly recommended introductory course for anyone getting into experimentation. I found the starting point appropriate for total novices (though for someone with some background, the pacing felt very slow and repetitive at times), but there was a well-defined progression from the simplest to more advanced concepts.', 'very clear and well explained', 'This is a very insightful and useful course for experiment design.', 'Great Course ', 'Excellent course!', "Amazing course! I really enjoyed myself during learning. The instructor is amazing and very professional. I really appreciate the fact that it contains examples from many different fields. It's really for everyone who wants to improve any adopted process. Thank you :)", 'Perfect!', 'Satisfying course content  and structure.  Reasonable course speed.  Nice,  practical reference.   Good introduction to design of experiments and response surface methods. ', 'Excellent. Well structured with a lot of practical example. Strongly suggested to increase your DoE skills. ', 'Aprendí las bases del diseño experimental', 'É um curso muito bom que te ensina a conduzir experimentos de maneira sistemática a fim de obter melhores resultados.', "Kevin was superb! It was so obvious that he had deep knowledge and experience on Experimental Design because he was able to explain the concepts in layman's terms without making it overly simple. I also appreciated how he used diverse examples in terms of the kinds of experiments used, despite his background in engineering. Thank you, Kevin! I am excited to apply what I have learned here in my work.", 'Great course! Very helpful in visualizing my data and discussing optimization.', 'Great! In this course you will have a comprehensive introduction to the methods of Design of Experiments, using several real world illustrations and well driven software applications. ', 'Best', 'This is one of the best organized course on the subject. It is vast and complicated area , however thanks to  Kevin for making it so simple , most beautiful part is, the way Fractional Factorial has been introduced and integrated into course.  ', 'an excelent course to learn the basics of process improvement ', 'It was a awesome course to learn more about everything!', "Perfect !!! The best course on experiment I've ever take. ", 'Very good course,and an excellent instructor. Thank you very much Professor Kevin Dunn.', "Excellent start in Design of Experiments!  I've pointed others to this course.", 'Make complex field accessible for all.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Francisco G H R', 'By Bettina S', 'By Patrick B', 'By Pablo C M', 'By María C B', 'By Qiong Z', 'By Jessica L', 'By Jean-Philippe G', 'By Marwa A E K M A Z', 'By Suyanne C S', 'By Steven Z', 'By MATTIA R', 'By Helen R M P', 'By Felipe A F', 'By West K D P', 'By kailyn c', 'By Aureliano A B', 'By yashar k s', 'By Deleted A', 'By Noel B', 'By Thiago N', 'By 廖文杰', 'By Eitan B', 'By Hunter E', 'By Charles G']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 02, 2017', 'Aug 16, 2017', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2017', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'May 29, 2017', 'Mar 17, 2018', 'Oct 04, 2016', 'Oct 28, 2015', 'Oct 28, 2017', 'Jun 04, 2017', 'Mar 10, 2016', 'Feb 19, 2018', 'Oct 27, 2017', 'Nov 03, 2017']</review_date></doc>