<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_462</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/datasci-capstone</course_url><course_name>Data Science at Scale - Capstone Project</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Bill Howe</course_instructor><course_introduction>In the capstone, students will engage on a real world project requiring them to apply skills from the entire data science pipeline: preparing, organizing, and transforming data, constructing a model, and evaluating results.    Through a collaboration with Coursolve, each Capstone project is associated with partner stakeholders who have a vested interest in your results and are eager to deploy them in practice.  These projects will not be straightforward and the outcome is not prescribed -- you will need to tolerate ambiguity and negative results!  But we believe the experience will be rewarding and will better prepare you for data science projects in practice.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//R Programming//Data Analysis//Data Wrangling//Statistics</course_tag><course_rating>4.1</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Washington</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Project A: Blight Fight//Week 2: Derive a list of buildings//Week 3: Construct a training dataset//Week 4: Train and evaluate a simple model//Week 5: Feature Engineering//Week 6: Final Report</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Get the Data', 'Understand the Domain'], ['Milestone: Create a list of "buildings" from a list of geo-located incidents'], ['Milestone: Derive labels for each building'], ['Milestone: Train a Simple Model'], ['Milestone: Adding more features'], ['$null$']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[None, 'The topic and milestone-based schedule are great; you are free to take many decisions but still get enough guidance to avoid straying away from the project goal. Instructor and student commitment is a bit low; there is very little feedback in the forums and submissions are sometimes so shallow that add little value to the reviewer.', 'An interesting problem to tackle. I really liked that you started with very raw data and needed to work on many cleaning methods. Good practice for real data science. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Kenneth P', 'By Roberto S', 'By Wesley E']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 10, 2016', 'Sep 06, 2017', 'Jan 02, 2017']</review_date></doc>