<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_189</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/reinforcement-learning-in-finance</course_url><course_name>Reinforcement Learning in Finance</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Igor Halperin</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course aims at introducing the fundamental concepts of Reinforcement Learning (RL), and develop use cases for applications of RL for option valuation, trading, and asset management. 

By the end of this course, students will be able to
- Use reinforcement learning to solve classical problems of Finance such as portfolio optimization, optimal trading, and option pricing and risk management.
- Practice on valuable examples such as famous Q-learning using financial problems.
- Apply their knowledge acquired in the course to a simple model for market dynamics that is obtained using reinforcement learning as the course project.

Prerequisites are the courses "Guided Tour of Machine Learning in Finance" and "Fundamentals of Machine Learning in Finance". Students are expected to know the lognormal process and how it can be simulated. Knowledge of option pricing is not assumed but desirable.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>option pricing and risk management//simple model for market dynamics//Q-learning using financial problems//optimal trading//Portfolio Optimization</course_tag><course_rating>3.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>New York University Tandon School of Engineering</course_orgnization><course_chapter>MDP and Reinforcement Learning//MDP model for option pricing: Dynamic Programming Approach//MDP model for option pricing - Reinforcement Learning approach//RL and INVERSE RL for Portfolio Stock Trading</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the Specialization', 'Prerequisites', 'Welcome to the Course', 'Introduction to Markov Decision Processes and Reinforcement Learning in Finance', 'MDP and RL: Decision Policies', 'MDP &amp; RL: Value Function and Bellman Equation', 'MDP &amp; RL: Value Iteration and Policy Iteration', 'MDP &amp; RL: Action Value Function', 'Options and Option pricing', 'Black-Scholes-Merton (BSM) Model', 'BSM Model and Risk', 'Discrete Time BSM Model', 'Discrete Time BSM Hedging and Pricing', 'Discrete Time BSM BS Limit'], ['MDP Formulation', 'Action-Value Function', 'Optimal Action From Q Function', 'Backward Recursion for Q Star', 'Basis Functions', 'Optimal Hedge With Monte-Carlo', 'Optimal Q Function With Monte-Carlo'], ['Week Introduction', 'Batch Reinforcement Learning', 'Stochastic Approximations', 'Q-Learning', 'Fitted Q-Iteration', 'Fitted Q-Iteration: the  Ψ-basis', 'Fitted Q-Iteration at Work', 'RL Solution: Discussion and Examples'], ['Week Welcome Video', 'Introduction to RL for Trading', 'Portfolio Model', 'One Period Rewards', 'Forward and Inverse Optimisation', 'Reinforcement Learning for Portfolios', 'Entropy Regularized RL', 'RL Equations', 'RL and Inverse Reinforcement Learning Solutions', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I leave this review after I have completed the specialization of all 4 courses.', 'Course content is okay but the coding exercices are not on point at all.', 'assignments are very frustrating, unclear instructions, no help from staff/moderator/instructor, technical issues that are not resolved, etc. it just feels like the course was rushed to production and they let the students debug it. the final assignment cannot be submitted, everyone is stranded here and unable to complete the course.', "The lectures are interesting and the exercises are challenging, yet engaging. However, the technical support for assignment submissions is abysmal. Course staff are unhelpful, if they respond, which they often don't. I was unable to complete the course due to technical problems, don't pay for this scam. ", 'Do not undertake this course unless you are i. proficient in python and the subject matter already and ii. have 3 friends to take the course at the same time because otherwise your final assignment will not get graded. ', 'The content of the courses in this specialization is astonishing, very nice.', 'Tests at the end of the videos cut what Igor is saying and they are often about the following video.', "Final assignment was too vague and doesn't seem that useful.", 'This course is excellent!', 'Great delivery', 'Excellent course. The peer reviewed evaluation is very interisting and it is definitely  worth the time to do it in detail but does not take two hours with luck a week.', 'It is a good course to leave the comfort zone of filling model and start creating your own models from research papers. However, I have to say that the last assignment is quite impossible to do without help . It seems that they have some notation problems in the reference paper.', 'Excellent overview of reinforcement learning with applications to option pricing and stock trading..To benefit fully from this course, a good command of python and various libraries for machine learning/data science is essential...']</reviews><reviewers>['By Yi B', 'By Bozanian K', 'By cyril c', 'By Alexander E', 'By Teemu P', 'By Omar E O F', 'By Matthieu B', 'By Tom B', 'By 刘晶', 'By Oleg M P', 'By Luis A A C', 'By santiago r z', 'By Hilmi E']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 15, 2019', 'Sep 05, 2018', 'Oct 11, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2018', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Jul 17, 2018', 'Jun 06, 2019', 'Sep 04, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2018']</review_date></doc>