<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_370</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/biostatistics-2</course_url><course_name>Mathematical Biostatistics Boot Camp 2</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian Caffo, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn fundamental concepts in data analysis and statistical inference, focusing on one and two independent samples.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Statistical Hypothesis Testing//Biostatistics</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Hypothesis Testing//Two Binomials//Discrete Data Settings//Techniques</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Hypothesis Testing', 'More Hypothesis Testing', 'General Rules of Hypothesis Testing', 'Two-sided Tests', 'Confidence Intervals &amp; P Values', 'Power', 'Calculating Power', 'T Tests &amp; Monte Carlo', 'Two Sample Tests - Matched Data I', 'Two Sample Tests - Matched Data II', 'Two Sample Tests - Regression to the Mean', 'Two Sample Tests - Two Independent Groups'], ['Two Sample Binomial Tests - Score Statistic', 'Two Sample Binomial Tests - Exact Tests', 'Two Sample Binomial Tests - Comparing 2 Binomial Proportions', 'Relative Risks &amp; Odds Ratios - Relative Measures', 'Relative Risks &amp; Odds Ratios - The Relative Risk', 'Relative Risks &amp; Odds Ratios - The Odds Ratio', 'Delta Method', 'Delta Method &amp; Derivation'], ["Fisher's Exact Test", 'Hyper-Geometric Distribution', "Fisher's Exact Text in Practice &amp; Monte Carlo", 'Chi Squared Testing', 'Testing Independence', 'Generalization', 'Goodness of Fit Testing'], ["Simpson's Paradox", "Simpson's Paradox, more examples", 'Weighting', 'CMH test', 'Case Control Sampling', 'Exact inference for The Odds Ratio', 'Matched 2x2 Tables', 'Dependence and Marginal Homogeneity', 'Estimation of the Marginal Difference in Proportions', 'Odds and Ends for Matched 2x2 Tables', 'the sign test', 'the sign rank test', 'the rank sum test', 'Poisson distribution', 'Poisson likelihood', 'Poisson P-value calculation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course should be part of the Data Science specialization. Actually, you can supplement the Statistical Inference course with these two Boot camp courses really well! ', 'Please, make a reboot of this course with some improvements in the material.', 'Outstanding professor -- more rigorous than other similar classes. Just the right degree of challenge in the quizzes.', 'Excellent! A great  leading course to build up one with clear background to explore the data science. ', 'Thank you Dr Brian for the in-depth teaching from fundamental to application in real-world healthcare research', "Thankful that a course like this exists, as most MOOCs are quite basic.  And thanks to Coursera for running the courses even though attendance seems to be low (darn, that pesky calculus pre-requisite).  Lecture quality is varied--some quite good (such as the lectures in Boot Camp I) and others seem like he hadn't looked at his notes for a long time.  It's great to hear a stats professor talk about the strengths and weaknesses of many approaches.  It complements a mathematical statistics book quite well.  It would have been nice to have had some problems that were more challenging.  Overall, while the Johns Hopkins Data Science MOOCs are pretty good, they are a bit more basic than what's available through MIT and Stanford.", 'Goode videos and teacher. The videos are old and it will be perfect to refresh them and make it more interactive.', None, 'The last week was a bit rushed and unclear. ', 'It was very challenging. It would be better if a couple of practice exercises were put after the relevant lecture videos and not just after the weekly lecture videos. ', '"much better than the data science with R concentration provided also by John Hopkins. This course has concrete examples, and the lecturer doesn\'t treat his audience like the first-grade kids." I take this back. The lecturer doesn\'t know what he\'s taking about and what he is gonna talk about for at least half of the time. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Do H L', 'By Andre T d C', 'By Vivek', 'By Joseph L', 'By Chen-wei O', 'By Michael K', 'By Luis G G E', 'By Paulina J', 'By Burak H', 'By Edit T', 'By Gu F']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 02, 2016', 'Jul 28, 2018', 'Sep 08, 2018', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2019', 'Oct 01, 2016', 'Oct 01, 2018', 'Apr 16, 2017', 'Jun 20, 2017', 'Sep 25, 2016', 'Mar 05, 2017']</review_date></doc>