<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_101</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/unix</course_url><course_name>The Unix Workbench</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sean Kross</course_instructor><course_introduction>Unix forms a foundation that is often very helpful for accomplishing other goals you might have for you and your computer, whether that goal is running a business, writing a book, curing disease, or creating the next great app. The means to these goals are sometimes carried out by writing software. Software can’t be mined out of the ground, nor can software seeds be planted in spring to harvest by autumn. Software isn’t produced in factories on an assembly line. Software is a hand-made, often bespoke good. If a software developer is an artisan, then Unix is their workbench. Unix provides an essential and simple set of tools in a distraction-free environment. Even if you’re not a software developer learning Unix can open you up to new methods of thinking and novel ways to scale your ideas. 

This course is intended for folks who are new to programming and new to Unix-like operating systems like macOS and Linux distributions like Ubuntu. Most of the technologies discussed in this course will be accessed via a command line interface. Command line interfaces can seem alien at first, so this course attempts to draw parallels between using the command line and actions that you would normally take while using your mouse and keyboard. You’ll also learn how to write little pieces of software in a programming language called Bash, which allows you to connect together the tools we’ll discuss. My hope is that by the end of this course you be able to use different Unix tools as if they’re interconnecting Lego bricks.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Shell Script//Github//Bash (Unix Shell)//Cloud Computing</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Unix and Command Line Basics//Working with Unix//Bash Programming//Git and GitHub//Nephology</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Week 1'], ['Welcome to Week 2'], ['Welcome to Week 3'], ['Welcome to Week 4'], ['Introduction to Cloud Computing', 'Setting Up DigitalOcean', 'Connecting to the Cloud', 'Moving Files In and Out of the Cloud', 'Talking to Other Servers', 'Automating Tasks', 'Cloud Computing Exercises', 'Shutting Down a Server', 'Next Steps', 'Giving Feedback', 'Using This Book']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Generally mediocre introduction to a few bits and pieces of unix. Useful, but has some misconceptions (e.g., what a regular expression is) and will teach you some unsafe habits (e.g., using $* instead of $@ to expand to the positional parameters starting from 1). It would be nice if there was some discussion about what shell scripts were actually used for out in the world. The cloud computing section seems tacked on and wholly unhelpful. Don't make your students give their credit card numbers to some external business unless you're going to do something of at least some lasting value. Even then, you probably should find another way to do this. Set something up on a coursera or JHU server if all you're going to do is literally have them copy and paste (and not learn) 6 lines of code.  ", 'Lazy, Sloppy, Unfocused', 'Really a Great course for learning unix . Learn a lot in the unix enviroment . Thanks Johns Hopkins University for this course , student like me who can not afford  and pay for education   in the top reputed university . Thanks coursera for providing such a platform for the needy students. thanks for the financial aid for the course. ', 'This course is well structured, useful in learning experience, work enverionment experience, and personally who ever start this course are going to really enjoy script programming.', 'learnt a lot about Unix, GitHub. great and helpful content.', 'Excellent introduction to the command line and github. Great as it goes past superificial introductions and teaches programming and manipulation of the command line.', 'This is a very good course. The contents are very organised and understandable. It would have been great some more videos and a little less text; the course is mostly based on reading materials. However, the quality of the text is quite good so I could not complaint. ', 'This is a grate course', 'Very informative and thought provoking course.', 'I really liked the course', 'es un curso hecho bien, en el cual llegas a aprender con grande facilidad.', 'Great course!', 'It was great because it allowed me to go at my own pace rather than watching and listening to someone talk', "This is my first course taken on Coursera. This platform is absolutely tremendous in it's way. Had a great experience and want to continue my learning here. ", 'A very helpful course :)', 'superb course   ', 'Well presented short course easy read content', 'excellent topic for beginer', 'Very nice course for linux beginner.', 'Very good exercises and very good explanations. Thanks a lot!', 'Good stuff.', "I've been searching for good introductory courses into Unix for over a year now - and finally, I found something with the right amount of challenge and pace that could be achieved within a month's time. Thank you to Sean Kross and the team that developed this course! I'll be paying attention to this space and I now feel I have a better foundational understanding of the ethos behind Unix workflows...", 'Best course for basic unix knowledge', "The course literature was fairly easy to understand and was structured in a logical way to build up skills. The videos introducing the lecture were a little bit off-putting, I think Sean should try to read from the side of the camera less as otherwise you can't concentrate on what he is saying. The exercises were challenging.", 'Great introduction to the shell world to start swimming on your own!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Daniel H', 'By Peter B', 'By Ajay S', 'By joaodavidcoelholuis', 'By Yagya D S', 'By Haseeb Q', 'By Miguel M G', 'By Juan M R', 'By Wiktor W', 'By Sergio A C V', 'By fabian87', 'By Daniel K', 'By Kacy C', 'By NAGARAJ G S', 'By Velashini V', 'By ABDUL M F P S', 'By Franco F P', 'By atul k s', 'By Dinesh K P', 'By Héctor E G', 'By David H', 'By Adam E', 'By Nimit S', 'By Mitchell E', 'By justina']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 04, 2019', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Apr 07, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Apr 13, 2019']</review_date></doc>