<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_276</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/bioconductor</course_url><course_name>Bioconductor for Genomic Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Kasper Daniel Hansen, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn to use tools from the Bioconductor project to perform analysis of genomic data. This is the fifth course in the Genomic Big Data Specialization from Johns Hopkins University.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Bioinformatics//Bioconductor//Genomics//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week One//Week Two//Week Three//Week Four</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Installing R on Windows ', 'Installing R on A Mac ', 'Installing R Studio on a Mac ', 'What is Bioconductor', 'Installing Bioconductor', 'The Bioconductor Website', 'Useful Online Resources', 'R Base Types', 'GRanges - Overview', 'IRanges - Basic Usage', 'GenomicRanges - GRanges', 'GenomicRanges - Basic GRanges Usage', 'GenomicRanges - seqinfo', 'AnnotationHub', 'Usecase: AnnotationHub and GRanges, part 1', 'Usecase: AnnotationHub and GRanges, part 2'], ['Biostrings', 'BSgenome', 'Biostrings - Matching', 'BSgenome - Views', 'GenomicRanges - Rle', 'GenomicRanges - Lists', 'GenomicFeatures', 'rtracklayer - Data Import'], ['Basic Data Types', 'Annotation Overview', 'ExpressionSet Overview', 'ExpressionSet', 'SummarizedExperiment', 'GEOquery', 'biomaRt', 'R S4 Classes', 'R S4 Methods'], ['Getting data into Bioconductor', 'Short Read', 'Rsamtools', 'oligo', 'limma', 'minfi', 'Count-based RNA-seq analysis']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Lots of good data.  Really a walk through of coding without too much theory.  Would prefer a little more theory.  Would have helped in completing the course and capstone.  Ended up having to take Eric Lander Intro to Bio course on edx to really understand what I had done.  In particular, a better explanation of what is going on at a basic with methylation marks and how the Epigenome Map was constructed.', 'Amazing course, motivated me to use bio conductor for descriptive seq studies of DNA.', 'Excellent introduction to Bioconductor. Thanks to the team. However, absence of inputs from TA or Instructor was felt in the discussion.', 'So practical! I learned a lot about specific and useful cases. It is true that I have to learn a lot yet but with this background, I will get used to any code soon.', 'Great Introductory course for sequence analyses using Bioconductor. However, the quizzes badly require more explanation. An update to the course to introduce currently more relevant packages and analysis methods would add more value.', 'The course is hard and needs previous knowledge of R. The time for for doing the "quizes" are not long. On the other hand, the questions resemble real world bioinformatics problems. The real inconvenience with this course is that the Forum does not work. Because not all that is questioned in the "quizes" are thought in the classes. So a help from the Forum is a real need for this course to work smoothly. ', "The content is relevant and presented well, though slightly out of date. It would be very helpful to update this course. Note that the discussion forums haven't been tended for years so they are not at all helpful and some code is deprecated without warning.", 'Extremely complicated, not for beginners!', "Great subject, yet a very difficult field to teach, and unfortunately, this course doesn't do it well enough.", 'Lectures are poorly understandable and the code examples are not explained in their meaning. Also some questions of the final quizes are difficult to understand. All the lectures and the quizes should have be constructed on a simpler use case', 'Very frustrating and disappointing experience. The lectures were hard to follow on many levels:', 'It is a good start for people who study epigenomics!', 'I learned a lot from this class and the instructor is good.', 'Before you can run, you must learn to walk.', 'I think it is a good class overall but the pace is fast and the resources that can help you is lacking. This will be good for someone who already kind of understands bioconductor.', 'pretty good', 'Good course, although some previous experience with R is required and that was not clearly stated beforehand. Moreover it would be better to have a more introductory course to R.', 'Four stars because the content is good. Not five stars because the english is not so good and for a non-english expert it can be difficult to understand, and the subtitle contains quite often errors.', "I'm going to take this again! hard one.", 'The course is tough and needs lots of practice and time to handle the stuff explained in this course. In my opinion the stuff should be split into 2 courses (partA and partB) with detailed explanation of every covered topic.', 'A great introduction to Bioconductor! The course is very hands-on, so be ready to use R extensively.', "It's very helpful in learning genomic data science. I think it's a little difficult in the beginning. The instructor have some accent, which made me even harder to get into it. ", 'A nice course to introduce Bioconductor to students ', 'good', 'The lessons are fairly easy to follow - although the transcript needs re-writing so that the correct words are identified to the speech.  I spent a lot of time trying to decipher one or two key words.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Michael R D', 'By Arpan K B', 'By Mohammad Z A', 'By Enrique E S C', 'By Ramesh G', 'By MAURICIO D A M', 'By Amy G', 'By Kanvar K', 'By Kasper T K', 'By Graziano P', 'By Miglė P', 'By 王灿', 'By Chunyu Z', 'By Geoffrey K', 'By Ji-Young K', 'By Alex Z', 'By Thodoris S', 'By Alberto T', 'By Shivani S D N K S', 'By sandeep s', 'By Essi K', 'By Qiyao Z', 'By Sourav S', 'By Ming L', 'By Oliver S']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 25, 2017', 'Apr 12, 2018', 'Mar 12, 2016', 'Jun 13, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Dec 13, 2016', 'Mar 30, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2018', 'May 13, 2018', 'Mar 13, 2016', 'Dec 16, 2016', 'Feb 10, 2016', 'Aug 28, 2019', 'Aug 31, 2016', 'Jul 14, 2017', 'May 02, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2016', 'Aug 02, 2017', 'Dec 05, 2016', 'Apr 16, 2018', 'May 21, 2018', 'Sep 04, 2016', 'Dec 05, 2017', 'Aug 26, 2018']</review_date></doc>