<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_191</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/fundamentals-machine-learning-in-finance</course_url><course_name>Fundamentals of Machine Learning in Finance</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Igor Halperin</course_instructor><course_introduction>The course aims at helping students to be able to solve practical ML-amenable problems that they may encounter in real life that include: (1) understanding where the problem one faces lands on a general landscape of available ML methods, (2) understanding which particular ML approach(es) would be most appropriate for resolving the problem, and (3) ability to successfully implement a solution, and assess its performance.  
A learner with some or no previous knowledge of Machine Learning (ML)  will get to know main algorithms of Supervised and Unsupervised Learning, and Reinforcement Learning, and will be able to use ML open source Python packages to design, test, and implement ML algorithms in Finance.
Fundamentals of Machine Learning in Finance will provide more at-depth view of supervised, unsupervised, and reinforcement learning, and end up in a project on using unsupervised learning for implementing a simple portfolio trading strategy.

The course is designed for three categories of students:
Practitioners working at financial institutions such as banks, asset management firms or hedge funds
Individuals interested in applications of ML for personal day trading
Current full-time students pursuing a degree in Finance, Statistics, Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics, Engineering or other related disciplines who want to learn about practical applications of ML in Finance  

Experience with Python (including numpy, pandas, and IPython/Jupyter notebooks), linear algebra, basic probability theory and basic calculus is necessary to complete assignments in this course.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>New York University Tandon School of Engineering</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Fundamentals of Supervised Learning in Finance//Core Concepts of Unsupervised Learning, PCA &amp; Dimensionality Reduction//Data Visualization &amp; Clustering//Sequence Modeling and Reinforcement Learning</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What is Machine Learning in Finance?', 'Introduction to Fundamentals of Machine Learning in Finance', 'Support Vector Machines, Part 1', 'Support Vector Machines, Part 2', 'SVM. The Kernel Trick', 'Example: SVM for Prediction of Credit Spreads', 'Tree Methods. CART Trees', 'Tree Methods: Random Forests', 'Tree Methods: Boosting'], ['Core Concepts of UL', 'PCA for Stock Returns, Part 1', 'PCA for Stock Returns, Part 2', 'Dimension Reduction with PCA', 'Dimension Reduction with tSNE', 'Dimension Reduction with Autoencoders'], ['UL. Clustering Algorithms', 'UL. K-clustering', 'UL. K-means Neural Algorithm', 'UL. Hierarchical Clustering Algorithms', 'UL.  Clustering and Estimation of Equity Correlation Matrix', 'UL. Minimum Spanning Trees, Kruskal Algorithm', 'UL. Probabilistic Clustering'], ['SM. Latent Variables', 'Sequence Modeling', 'SM. Latent Variables for Sequences', 'SM. State-Space Models', 'SM. Hidden Markov Models', 'Neural Architecture for Sequential Data', 'RL. Introduction', 'RL. Core Ideas', 'Markov Decision Process and RL', 'RL. Bellman Equation', 'RL and Inverse Reinforcement Learning']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This Prof. really have the talent of complicating even the most simplest of the ideas.  His teaching method is really bad. Plus some assignments have nothing to do with that week's lectures.", "The material is promising, but the staff running the course do not give a lot of direction on how to pursue learning the content. On the other hand, there is a lot of repeated material from the previous course. I do not know if they expect students to jump in at different parts of the specialization, but it seemed unnecessary. The rest of this review is a repeat of my review for the previous course, but still holds true in this course. The programming assignments are left almost completely to the students guessing what they're suppose to do with little direction. There is almost no feedback on how your code has performed, except to say that your code was wrong, which you already understand from not getting the points. While I was able to achieve a passing grade in this course, it was only because of the community of students that figured things out together, but with no other reliable way of figuring the material out. The code was also rife with bugs that weren't fixed for weeks while students tried and failed over and over again to pass assignments that they simply could not pass. It ended up wasting many hours of my time and, no doubt, other students' time. Simply check the forums to see the frustration from the Coursera community, that normally expects and receives high quality educational content.", "It's excellent and incomparable course!", 'Very informative', 'Excellent course. ', 'The lectures were truly outstanding,  the best overview on different methods in machine learning I have seen so far. The problem sets were also interesting, informative and  introduced several useful api from sklearn, tensorflow.   With a little  work  these problem sets could (and probably should)  be improved to match the quality of the lectures.   For example adding more clarifications in the homework notebooks  would be very helpful.  Having said this, I think this is an excellent course, and highly recommend it.', 'A great course with deep insight.', 'Furthered my understanding of how probabilistic models are connected to Machine Learning models. Very happy with the content in this course.', 'Great course which covers both theories as well as practical skills in the real implementations in the financial world.', "So far so good. The lecturer refers to projects of which some weren't covered in this course. So a little confusing. Takes lots of googling to finish this course. ", 'Good material..The course would improve a lot if there were clear explanations for the goals  of the assignments  and the plan for the assignment.. The  codes for the assignment should be fully debugged..', 'Add some hints in the notebooks, it was very hard to understand some parts', 'Good course with relevant topics, but assignments are not clear sometimes, lack of support with them.', 'This could have been the real deal with so many fascinating topics to learn here, but unfortunately, this specialization is setting new low standards in each assignments. The grader does not work, sometime we are asked to produce wrong results (as oppose to the research material). It is very frustrating!', 'Content and programming assignments are not much correlated. Lots of kernel problems while submitting assignments and late reply by staff.', 'the course content is okay. but the coding exam really needs improvement.  ', "content of the lessons is quite good, I would give it 5 stars if the assignments weren't so buggy, contains mistakes, unclear instructions, no help from staff/moderator/instructor, technical issues that are not resolved, etc. a lot of frustration, it just feels like the course was rushed to production and they let the students debug it", 'Many technical issues with assignments. Additionally, assignment instructions are often poor or insufficient.', 'If assignment are clear this course would be a great one. So I would like to suggest that explain more details about assignment and some guide lines', 'good overview of methods but project part was frustrating due to slow Jupyter servers which blocked progress. Overall still positive as course content is unique.', 'Content is good but assignments are buggy.', 'Completely horrible labs.', 'Do not attempt this course unless you are extremely experienced in the topic and python already.', 'The assignment submitting problem is fixed. But the confusing requirements are still in assignments. Always be stuck by concept or formula which irrelevant to the ML.', 'WORST CLASS EVER. Stay away!!!! I want my money back. (and even that is not possible).']</reviews><reviewers>['By wasif.masood', 'By Sean H', 'By 刘晶', 'By Pavel K', 'By Luis A A C', 'By Zoltan S', 'By Yuning C', 'By Angelo J I T', 'By Arditto T', 'By Jacques J', 'By Hilmi E', 'By Bozanian K', 'By Aydar A', 'By Umendra C', 'By Pramanshu R', 'By Lingzi', 'By cyril c', 'By Philip T', 'By Amalka W', 'By Nicolas M', 'By Daniel F', 'By Andreas A', 'By Teemu P', 'By Minglu Z', 'By tze s']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 08, 2018', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Sep 08, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Sep 03, 2019', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Aug 19, 2018', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Oct 11, 2018', 'Oct 25, 2018', 'Nov 01, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018']</review_date></doc>