<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_249</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/cluster-analysis</course_url><course_name>Cluster Analysis in Data Mining</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jiawei Han</course_instructor><course_introduction>Discover the basic concepts of cluster analysis, and then study a set of typical clustering methodologies, algorithms, and applications. This includes partitioning methods such as k-means, hierarchical methods such as BIRCH, and density-based methods such as DBSCAN/OPTICS. Moreover, learn methods for clustering validation and evaluation of clustering quality. Finally, see examples of cluster analysis in applications.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Cluster Analysis//Data Clustering Algorithms//K-Means Clustering//Hierarchical Clustering</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Orientation//Module 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4//Course Conclusion</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction'], ['1.1. What is Cluster Analysis', '1.2. Applications of Cluster Analysis', '1.3 Requirements and Challenges', '1.4 A Multi-Dimensional Categorization', '1.5 An Overview of Typical Clustering Methodologies', '1.6 An Overview of Clustering Different Types of Data', '1.7 An Overview of User Insights and Clustering', '2.1 Basic Concepts: Measuring Similarity between Objects', '2.2 Distance on Numeric Data Minkowski Distance', '2.3 Proximity Measure for Symetric vs Asymmetric Binary Variables', '2.4 Distance between Categorical Attributes Ordinal Attributes and Mixed Types', '2.5 Proximity Measure between Two Vectors Cosine Similarity', '2.6 Correlation Measures between Two variables Covariance and Correlation Coefficient'], ['3.1 Partitioning-Based Clustering Methods', '3.2 K-Means Clustering Method', '3.3 Initialization of K-Means Clustering', '3.4 The K-Medoids Clustering Method', '3.5 The K-Medians and K-Modes Clustering Methods', '3.6 Kernel K-Means Clustering', '4.1 Hierarchical Clustering Methods', '4.2 Agglomerative Clustering Algorithms', '4.3 Divisive Clustering Algorithms', '4.4 Extensions to Hierarchical Clustering', '4.5 BIRCH: A Micro-Clustering-Based Approach', 'ClusterEnG Overview', 'ClusterEnG: K-Means and K-Medoids', 'ClusterEnG Application: AGNES', 'ClusterEnG Application: DBSCAN'], ['4.6 CURE: Clustering Using Well-Scattered Representatives', '4.7 CHAMELEON: Graph Partitioning on the KNN Graph of the Data', '4.8 Probabilistic Hierarchical Clustering', '5.1 Density-Based and Grid-Based Clustering Methods', '5.2 DBSCAN: A Density-Based Clustering Algorithm', '5.3 OPTICS: Ordering Points To Identify Clustering Structure', '5.4 Grid-Based Clustering Methods', '5.5 STING: A Statistical Information Grid Approach', '5.6 CLIQUE: Grid-Based Subspace Clustering'], ['6.1 Methods for Clustering Validation', '6.2 Clustering Evaluation Measuring Clustering Quality', '6.3 Constraint-Based Clustering', '6.4 External Measures 1: Matching-Based Measures', '6.5 External Measure 2: Entropy-Based Measures', '6.6 External Measure 3: Pairwise Measures', '6.7 Internal Measures for Clustering Validation', '6.8 Relative Measures', '6.9 Cluster Stability', '6.10 Clustering Tendency'], ['$null$']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The instructor basically reads the slides line by line, with very few examples.', 'Redundant, poor explanations and a complete lack of examples about the general concepts and the foundations of this discipline. The interaction between the teacher and the slides is limited to a reading exercise that does not provide any add value at all. Very dissapointed and still wondering if this course is worth my attention -and extremely limited time- or not. Plenty of room for improvement.', 'Great course that provides a good overview of different clustering approaches and how to deploy them to various problems. I found the lecture material unclear or vague at times, so that for certain topics understanding heavily depends on one diving through the provided reading material (which I found very helpful). However, the topic of evaluation is very dense in the lectures and the provided book chapters do not provide relevant insights as well, making the programming assignment for this part quite challenging (at least if not already deeply familiar already with the concepts involved). Be ready to invest effort to make the most of this. ', 'Course is very good I learnt about a lot of things related to clustering. Actually it is a very good introductory course in clustering compared to the resources available online in general. Although few things that I think might help improve the course', 'I have sat through 4 of the lessons and I am not very impressed. I fell that the topic is very interesting, but the professor does not do a very good job explaining the algorithms. It may be because I do no have the textbook, but overall a rather poor course. There need to be a little more explanation beyond the slides.', 'This was my favorite course in the whole specialization. Everything is explained very concisely and clearly making the subject matter very easy to understand.', 'Excellent!', 'This course is a great resource to learn about the different clustering algorithms out there. I need to solve a clustering problem in my research and my knowledge about clustering ended at kmeans. The course teaches systematic ways to find out whether you should be clustering your data in the first place, what clustering algorithm should be best for your data, and how to evaluate the goodness of the algorithm and the used parameters. Many unknown unknowns have been illuminated to me by the course.', 'Nice lecture.', 'Clustering demytified', 'A very good course, it gives me a general idea of how clustering algorithm work.', 'Great course!', 'Very useful and well taught', 'Explained with nice examples', 'Very intense and required complex thinking and programming skill', 'E', 'Very good', 'Excellent overview of many clustering algorithms!', "Very informative lectures, wonderful assignments. This course isn't so easy but it gives you real knowledge and useful experience.", 'Awesome!', 'This course along with the Reading material proposed will give you a big picture of how clustering algorithms work, as well as clustering validation methodologies. It is really useful if you are thinking about applying such algorithms and understanding the state-of-the-art.', 'Gave a very good understanding of cluster analysis - explaining all different methods and algorithms, the benefits and drawbacks of each. The tool ClusterEng looks very good and can help in a lot of situations. Thank so much', 'awesome', 'VERY GOOD', 'Nice. Good Course ']</reviews><reviewers>['By zshowing', 'By NACHO', 'By Bernd', 'By ADARSHPANDEY', 'By Daniel B', 'By Eric A S', 'By VIDUSHI M', 'By barbara', 'By Ian W', 'By AJETUNMOBI O', 'By Darren', 'By Christopher D', 'By Leela P', 'By Pavan G', 'By Tanan K', 'By Valerie P', 'By Oren Z', 'By Vasco D S N C D', 'By Glushko O V', 'By Hernan C V', 'By Jose A E H', 'By Srinath R M', 'By vaseem a', 'By KRUPAL J K', 'By PABLO P Q']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 25, 2017', 'Apr 16, 2017', 'Oct 27, 2017', 'Dec 24, 2017', 'Feb 21, 2017', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2018', 'Aug 20, 2018', 'May 01, 2017', 'Sep 25, 2017', 'Nov 08, 2016', 'Jan 16, 2017', 'Oct 02, 2017', 'Oct 10, 2017', 'Jul 11, 2017', 'Jun 07, 2017', 'Nov 22, 2017', 'Sep 19, 2017', 'Jul 01, 2017', 'Jul 12, 2017', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Apr 09, 2019', 'Apr 09, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019']</review_date></doc>