<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_159</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/introductiontoprobability</course_url><course_name>An Intuitive Introduction to Probability</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Karl Schmedders</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will provide you with a basic, intuitive and practical introduction into Probability Theory. You will be able to learn how to apply Probability Theory in different scenarios and you will earn a "toolbox" of methods to deal with uncertainty in your daily life. 

The course is split in 5 modules. In each module you will first have an easy introduction into the topic, which will serve as a basis to further develop your knowledge about the topic and acquire the "tools" to deal with uncertainty. Additionally, you will have the opportunity to complete 5 exercise sessions to reflect about the content learned in each module and start applying your earned knowledge right away. 

The topics covered are: "Probability", "Conditional Probability", "Applications", "Random Variables", and "Normal Distribution".

You will see how the modules are taught in a lively way, focusing on having an entertaining and useful learning experience! We are looking forward to see you online!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Bayes' Theorem//Normal Distribution//Probability//Conditional Probability</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Zurich</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Probability//Conditional Probability//Application//Discrete Random Variables//Normal Distribution</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Introduction', 'Definition and Rules', 'A First Look at Statistical Independence', 'Subjective Probabilities', "Empirical Probabilities: Benford's Law", 'Exercise'], ['Intuition', 'Definition', 'Multiplication Rules', 'Probability Tables', 'Bayes Rule', 'Exercise'], ['The Birthday Problem', 'The Monty Hall Problem', 'Structuring Risks: Part 1', 'Structuring Risks: Part 2', "The Prosecutor's Fallacy", 'The Sad Story of Sally Clark'], ['Discrete Random Variables', 'Expected Value', 'Measures of Dispersion', 'Application: Financial Model', 'Binomial Distribution', 'Application: Airline Overbooking', 'Exercise 1', 'Exercise 2'], ['Continuous Random Variables', 'Normal Distribution', 'Calculating Normal Probabilities', 'Calculations with the Normal Distribution', 'Application of the Normal Distribution', 'Exercise']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent way of teaching. Clear Explanation of the topics with to the point discussion. Diverse applications of probability covered in one course. Definitely helpful in my office / research work. ', 'The course explains probability and normal distribution concepts in a way it is easier to follow. And makes it further easier using usual excel function. Very well taught course! A big thank you!!', 'Engaging, entertaining, taught as if teaching to students and not mindless drones. Great fun!', 'Thank you for this excellent course, I hope you create more advanced courses.', 'The course was just awesome! Both instructors are super charismatic and give extremely clear life examples to illustrate their points. Thank you.', 'A spectacular course to make you start wondering about chances and the way you are taking decisions!', 'The course was great, thank you! The only thing I would change are the exercises, which required to repeat some values presented in the associated videos, somehow I did not find it exciting/teaching me anything... Still, thank you!', "A very very good course for the people who fear probability section. The professor explains well from the basic as if you know nothing about the probability and that's the speciality of this course. Go for it if you are willing to gain some basic and also influential knowledge about probability.  By the time I was taking this course I was a reading a book named 'The Black Swan' by Nassim Nicholas Taleb . And I tell you there were many similarities between the sayings of this professor and the author of the book. Well that might be the another reason I enjoyed this course well.  After all, a very good course for the beginners who are going to take a little step further in the corporate world. Thank you.", "Thoroughly enjoyed the course! After this course I feel confident to learn more about probability as it doesn't seem intimidating as it did before I started . Many Thanks!", 'Prof Karl is fun. I like this course very much and I wish there will be more advanced course taught by him.', "The course lived up to my expectations, providing good intuition for the fundamentals of probability. I would highly recommend it to anyone looking for a brief overview of the subject. The exercises were a bit too easy for my taste, but that didn't detract from the overall quality of the course.", 'That was the great course! I really enjoyed by it.', 'I have learned that "An Intuitive Introduction to Probability" explain basic concepts very clearly. I could learn basic concepts and did small application of theory. Very good for the people searching for an introduction to probability. ', 'The most essential course on the fundamentals of probability theory with an amazing professor whose enthusiasm for teaching the concepts is irresistible and captivating. I literally loved this course so much so that my high-school dream of some-day fully grasping the real intuitive concepts of probability come true. Thank you very much Sir for teaching me this course. I have become a fan of you. Request you to offer some courses on the financial side aspects of the uncertainty and how best it should be managed.', 'Excellent introduction! Really clarifies some key concepts in probability. ', 'Amazing refresher for important probability concepts with intriguing real world applications and examples!', 'Good course and the teaching is at a good pace.', 'Very informative course. Excellent instructors. Supplement materials are also very useful. ', 'Beautiful Course!', "The best place I've found to start getting a good (and Intuitive, as the course's name rightfully states) grasp of Probability concepts that I have been familiar with for many years, without really understanding their meaning. Thanks a bunch for the superb work. ", None, 'Simple course to remind some concepts from the university', 'Nice way to get the knowledge of probability. Beginners must try this if they HATE probability.', 'Thank you so much! All the explanation in the course were clear and intuitive! I have looked for explanation for probability and random variables in many places and still could not grasp the ideas. and Karl is the best teacher!', 'Very interesting. Even with a limited unterstanding of the math behind probability you will get the gist of the course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By rims', 'By Arundhati A A', 'By Ian G A', 'By Anoop', 'By Maksim U', 'By Christos G', 'By Tomasz K', 'By Sushant M S', 'By Nadia S', 'By Yijie X', 'By John T', 'By Заров Е А', 'By Damian S', 'By Lokesh K', 'By Tiago L A', 'By Sarthak K', 'By Henrique M R P', 'By Valentin A', 'By Valerii M', 'By Carlos V', 'By enrique a r', 'By Ishchenko I', 'By Parakh S', 'By Nguyen M', 'By Tobias A']</reviewers><review_date>['May 17, 2019', 'May 25, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Mar 08, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2018', 'Sep 24, 2018', 'Sep 28, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018']</review_date></doc>