<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_97</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/ai-with-ibm-watson</course_url><course_name>Getting Started with AI using IBM Watson</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rav Ahuja</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will learn how to quickly and easily get started with Artificial Intelligence using IBM Watson. You will understand how Watson works, become familiar with its use cases and real life client examples, and be introduced to several of Watson AI services from IBM that enable anyone to easily apply AI and build smart apps. You will also work with several Watson services to demonstrate AI in action.
 
This course does not require any programming or computer science expertise and is designed for anyone whether you have a technical background or not.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Deep Learning//Application Programming Interfaces (API)//Artificial Intelligence (AI)//Machine Learning//watson</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Watson AI Overview//Watson AI Services//More Watson AI Services//Watson in Action</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the course', 'Watson - The AI for Business', 'How Watson Works', 'Enriching Customer Service', 'Intelligent Chatbots, Virtual Assistants, and IBM Watson', 'Assisting in Compliance Oriented Business Processes', 'Making Data and AI Accessible to All', '3 Ways Watson Can Help Your Business', 'What Differentiates Consumer and Business AI Aystems', 'Getting Started on your AI Journey'], ['Introduction to Watson Services', 'A Few Watson Services', 'Intelligent Chatbots, Virtual Assistants and IBM Watson', 'Watson Assistant', 'Watson Discovery', 'Watson Natural Language Understanding', 'Watson Knowledge Studio', 'Watson Speech to Text', 'Watson Text to Speech', 'Watson Language Translator', 'Watson Natural Language Classifier'], ['Watson Studio', 'Watson Machine Learning', 'Watson Knowledge Catalog', 'Watson OpenScale', 'Computer Vision, Its Applications, and IBM Watson', 'Watson Visual Recognition', 'Watson Personality Insights', 'Watson Tone Analyser', 'Watson Compare and Comply'], ['Watson at Work', 'Watson Use Cases', 'Optional: Watson for Oncology, Clinical Trial Matching, and Genomics', 'Watson at ADNOC', 'Watson at LivePerson', 'Watson at Hilton']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The promotional style was not very constructive (many videos were more like advertisements for IBM)', 'This felt more like an IBM Advertisement than a course. This course could be a one pager on the different services that are offered. No one will likely remember what is offered, the names of the offerings are likely to change going forward, and the offerings themselves will change. ', None, 't', 'Great course! Thanks everyone who created this course!', 'This is a great way to get familiar with the Watson suite of APIs and learn more about the real-world applications of AI thought fascinating case studies. There is a little overlap with the previous course Introduction to Artificial Intelligence but it is a good review of important concepts.', 'telling about different programs and their application it is a good starting point to understand what IBM is doing', 'This was a great course!', 'easy and simple to understand', 'Amazing to see what the potential is with Watson by seeing how it is already being used in the world today.', 'A good course, especially good for beginners like me.', 'In this course, you will learn about IBM Watson services and how they are put in to action world wide. You have some interesting tests to pass!', 'Amazing Course. This helped not only learn about what IBM Watson has to offer but its applications and how AI is transforming businesses and making them more effective and efficient.', 'Great course!', 'good', 'very well documented ', 'A very good course to introduce the IBM Watson tools to new Users and Students like us. It is a great step from IBM to improve our Knowledge on AI and to Make a Better World with the Help of IBM Watson.', 'Great class, very clear.', 'Nice course', 'Excellente course and well design content', "It's great course fro anyone who is a beginner for IBM Watson and wants to learn more about about Watson offers, how it can be leveraged and the real-world applications where Watson is helping with it's AI Services.", 'only info about ibm service no exercises', 'A lot of advertising but good', 'Reasonable intro, a bit slow', 'It provides basic knowledge about IBM Watson']</reviews><reviewers>['By Gulnara K', 'By David T', 'By Deepesh A', 'By Fei W', 'By Dilrabo B', 'By Mark M', 'By Heidi P', 'By Bryan J', 'By Fadhel A A R A S', 'By Mike O', 'By James R', 'By MOHAN P', 'By Affan A', 'By Sergio I', 'By PILLA S', 'By Imtiaz A K', 'By ISMAIL M K', 'By Rodrigo S B', 'By Yap C Y', 'By José L P C', 'By Ishan J', 'By Youssef K S M', 'By joaquin c', 'By David B', 'By NGUYEN K V']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 21, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 09, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2019', 'Jul 19, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 22, 2019', 'Aug 25, 2019', 'Aug 25, 2019', 'Aug 25, 2019', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019', 'Sep 01, 2019', 'Sep 03, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Sep 11, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019', 'Sep 04, 2019', 'Sep 05, 2019', 'Sep 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>