<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_87</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/excel-advanced</course_url><course_name>Excel Skills for Business: Advanced</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr Yvonne Breyer</course_instructor><course_introduction>Spreadsheet software remains one of the most ubiquitous pieces of software used in workplaces around the world. Learning to confidently operate this software means adding a highly valuable asset to your employability portfolio. Across the globe, millions of job advertisements requiring Excel skills are posted every day. At a time when digital skills jobs are growing much faster than non-digital jobs, completing this course will position you ahead of others, so keep reading.

In this last course of our Specialization Excel Skills for Business you will build on the strong foundations of the first three courses: Essentials, Intermediate I + II.  In the Advanced course, we will prepare you to become a power user of Excel - this is your last step before specializing at a professional level. The topics we have prepared will challenge you as you learn how to use advanced formula techniques and sophisticated lookups. You will clean and prepare data for analysis, and learn how to work with dates and financial functions. An in-depth look at spreadsheet design and documentation will prepare you for our big finale, where you will learn how to build professional dashboards in Excel.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Dashboard (Business)//Financial Modeling//Microsoft Excel//Data Cleansing</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Macquarie University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Spreadsheet Design and Documentation//Advanced Formula Techniques//Data Cleaning and Preparation//Financial Functions and Working with Dates//Advanced Lookup Functions//Building Professional Dashboards//Final Assessment</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Week 1 Introduction', 'Week 1 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Spreadsheet Design Principles', 'Practice Video: Calculations', 'Practice Video: Formatting', 'Practice Video: Documentation', 'Practice Video: Interface and Navigation'], ['Week 2 Introduction', 'Week 2 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Tables and Structured Referencing', 'Practice Video: Using Functions to Sort Data', 'Practice Video: Introduction to Array Formulas', 'Practice Video: Working with an Array Function (TRANSPOSE)', 'Practice Video: Solving Problems with Array Formulas'], ['Week 3 Introduction', 'Week 3 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Replace blanks with repeating values', 'Practice Video: Fix Dates (DATE, MONTH, YEAR, DAY, TEXT)', 'Practice Video: Remove Unwanted Spaces (TRIM, CLEAN)', 'Practice Video: Diagnostic Tools (ISNUMBER, LEN, CODE)', 'Practice Video: Remove Unwanted Characters (SUBSTITUTE, CHAR, VALUE)'], ['Week 4 Introduction', 'Week 4 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Working with Dates (EOMONTH, EDATE, WORKDAY.INTL)', 'Practice Video: Financial Functions (FV, PV, PMT)', 'Practice Video: Loan Schedule (PMT, EDATE)', 'Practice Video: Net Present Value and Internal Rate of Return (NPV, IRR)', 'Practice Video: Depreciation Functions (SLN, SYD, DDB)'], ['Week 5 Introduction', 'Week 5 Discussion', 'Practice Video: INDIRECT', 'Practice Video: ADDRESS', 'Practice Video: Introduction to OFFSET', 'Practice Video: Solving Problems with OFFSET'], ['Week 6 Introduction', 'Week 6 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Dashboard Design', 'Practice Video: Prepare Data', 'Practice Video: Construct Dashboard', 'Practice Video: Creative Charting', 'Practice Video: Interactive Dashboard'], ['Final Assessment']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 25 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Course &amp; Specialisation completed successfully #EverybodySayWow. I really enjoyed this course and benefited greatly from completing each course in the specialisation. The format really worked for me. I liked the introductory videos and the initial high level overviews provided by Prashan and Nicky. I also loved the tutorial videos and as the specialisation progressed, found it beneficial to revisit some of these where my knowledge was still lacking. As often said, practise makes permanent so the periodic quiz questions and weekly assessments helped ensure that I really had grasped the learning objectives. ', 'Useless. Sure the course teaches some "cool" stuff, that I\'m sure is very useful in the real world.', 'the final for this course is so hard given how unequipped you are off the practice. a lot of the questions I have no idea what to do. Ruined coursera for me', 'This was one of the best courses I have ever taken in my esperience as a student I really appreciate the effort your team had put on this', 'The EXCEL course I should have done years ago!', 'The course is great and the concepts are easy to understand. It added all necessary skills businesses require. However, it would be nicer if there was more practice material, even if not for grade. Just so who really wants to practice more have more materials offering different situations in which you can apply what we just learned. That is the reason for the 4 stars, needs more exercises to help in the process of refining skills and a deeper understanding of the concepts. Thank you for this opportunity. I am very grateful for it. It will sure help me finding a new job and to be very productive and efficient there.', 'Some of the questions of the assesments were not seen during the course. Formulas laike indirect, index and match should have further explanation and more practice exercises.', 'The skills teached are a nice to have, however, the setup of the course is just poor. I also did intermediate 1 and 2. You can see that this one was just made quickly without much effort. The practice files for week 4 and 5 where never uploaded (even though they mentioned in the discussion forums that they were working on it 1 year ago).', 'Abit complicated but very useful in the practical problem solving environment, when grasped!', 'One of the best course for excel I have ever come across!! Final Tests &amp; Weekly Assessments are must to get a great insight and clarity on functions and applications! Quite confident about using excel now!', 'I feel satisfied with contents of this course, all topics are very important and applicable into the daily work with any king of data. ', 'Very helpful lectures. I am more confident in my Excel skills after taking this course. Thanks to the lecturers!', 'This course is very advanced and very helpful to me to stretch my excel capabilities, content and materials are valuable to keep them with me as a reference, although the final assignments are so challenging.', 'спасибо', 'Using excel to create dashboard is amazing thing', 'Excellent course and great instructors. ', 'It greatly has increased my efficiency &amp; makes me feel more professional!', "Great course. It's very well designed. The task are in the same level of dificulty of the classes. It's really benefitial  how the teachers try to make us a certain exercise in many different ways.", 'For me, Advanced felt like going back to Essentials in some weeks, but in a good way. Format and Professional Dashboards are necessary, and the examples really gives you a hint of how you can present it. Array formulas are one of the most interesting things of this course, really useful.', 'it is long and well worth journey so far. thank you!', 'Tough but worth learning', 'Very interesting course !', 'As the final course of the specialization, this course refines the concepts taught in the previous courses (advanced formula techniques &amp; lookup functions) as well as illustrates new useful functions and techniques when dealing with data (spreadsheet design, data cleaning). The cherry on top is how to design and create professional dashboards. As the previous courses, it is well-structured and concepts are explained clearly. Highly recommended.', 'amazed with all the skills this program provide me', 'Awesome course! useful, clear and with a really nice pace. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Tony M', 'By Florian D', 'By Rieki V D H', 'By Felipe C K', 'By Andreas Z', 'By Liviambranco@hotmail.com', 'By Mauricio M T', 'By Thomas', 'By Roy K', 'By Rushabh D D', 'By Nicolás G', 'By Shenkuan Z', 'By Mina J', 'By  Г В  В ', 'By ZUWEI L', 'By Shay K', 'By Ashok S', 'By edson s', 'By Sebastian T R', 'By Ying W', 'By Vaclav F', 'By Yann D', 'By Laura R', 'By Clark C C', 'By Maria d C B E']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 15, 2018', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Jun 12, 2019', 'Nov 10, 2018', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Jun 01, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Nov 29, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>