<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_364</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/executive-data-science-capstone</course_url><course_name>Executive Data Science Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>The Executive Data Science Capstone, the specialization’s culminating project, is an opportunity for people who have completed all four EDS courses to apply what they've learned to a real-world scenario developed in collaboration with Zillow, a data-driven online real estate and rental marketplace, and DataCamp, a web-based platform for data science programming. Your task will be to lead a virtual data science team and make key decisions along the way to demonstrate that you have what it takes to shepherd a complex analysis project from start to finish.  For the final project, you will prepare and submit a presentation, which will be evaluated and graded by your fellow capstone participants.

Course cover image by Luckey_sun. Creative Commons BY-SA https://flic.kr/p/bx1jvU</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Leadership and Management</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Data Analysis//Management//Data Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Executive Data Science Capstone</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['A Welcome Message from Roger Peng']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 1 hour to complete</course_time><reviews>['Nice try to set something interactive up .. but the capstone it is nothing more than that. All 5 courses could have formed a first module of the specialization "Executive Data Science" leaving room for much more project management related issues to be dealt with as well (just a thought). Feels like this specialization was just made to show off to other universities that "everything" was covered by JHU. ', 'It was too easy. :)', "I wasn't as challenged as I thought I would be with the Capstone course.", 'Thanks for creating short course for busy business pearson.', 'Total disappointment. This was only clipping through a tool, not a real capstone project.', 'Disappointing, thought it would be more involved, perhaps with a real presentation graded by other participants in the course. Was interesting to watch the videos, but it was a 10 minute job. The other parts were OK, but after the Capstone I would hesitate to recommend the course.', 'This required nearly no effort and is probably of little value in the real world.', '  Interesting for a Non-Data Science Executive.  ', 'It was very easy to work with. One of the best designed capstone projects I`ve taken.', 'A great addition the the Data Science program for those that want or have to lead a team', 'Very well orga', 'Loved this simulation! Great work for a final experience with this course. ', 'It was fun to do the capstone. Thank you very much.', None, 'The real life scenario been created in this capstone is Awesome!  ', 'The capstone course is different from other courses as it allows the learner to be act like a data manager and applies what he learnt from the courses.', 'Really well developed project, good fun and very useful.', 'Great Project very crisp but was sure to test my knowledge', 'I love working on the capstone project!!', 'excellent', 'Coursera data science very help full, interest in learning.', 'A great course which demonstrate the learning in practical scenario. ', 'Very enjoyable and beneficial course!', 'Well done exercise.  Thank you.', 'Great design, love the capstone project!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Martijn T', 'By Suman C', 'By Brett M', 'By Hajime O', 'By Dirk', 'By Martin K', 'By Thomas N', 'By Elton K', 'By Fatih Y', 'By Isaiah M', 'By Jayanthy A', 'By Kim K R', 'By Marc-André B', 'By Jens M', 'By TARUN C', 'By Danny Y L', 'By Jean-Michel M', 'By Jay P', 'By Synthia', 'By HARI M', 'By Sudhakar M D ', 'By Alzum S M', 'By Kenneth B', 'By Michel G', 'By xun y']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 13, 2017', 'Mar 24, 2018', 'May 18, 2016', 'Mar 29, 2016', 'Sep 04, 2016', 'Mar 29, 2016', 'Jan 17, 2017', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Sep 15, 2018']</review_date></doc>