<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_50</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/datasciencemathskills</course_url><course_name>Data Science Math Skills</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Egger</course_instructor><course_introduction>Data science courses contain math—no avoiding that! This course is designed to teach learners the basic math you will need in order to be successful in almost any data science math course and was created for learners who have basic math skills but may not have taken algebra or pre-calculus. Data Science Math Skills introduces the core math that data science is built upon, with no extra complexity, introducing unfamiliar ideas and math symbols one-at-a-time. 

Learners who complete this course will master the vocabulary, notation, concepts, and algebra rules that all data scientists must know before moving on to more advanced material.

Topics include:
~Set theory, including Venn diagrams
~Properties of the real number line
~Interval notation and algebra with inequalities
~Uses for summation and Sigma notation
~Math on the Cartesian (x,y) plane, slope and distance formulas
~Graphing and describing functions and their inverses on the x-y plane,
~The concept of instantaneous rate of change and tangent lines to a curve
~Exponents, logarithms, and the natural log function.
~Probability theory, including Bayes’ theorem.

While this course is intended as a general introduction to the math skills needed for data science, it can be considered a prerequisite for learners interested in the course, "Mastering Data Analysis in Excel," which is part of the Excel to MySQL Data Science Specialization.  Learners who master Data Science Math Skills will be fully prepared for success with the more advanced math concepts introduced in "Mastering Data Analysis in Excel." 

Good luck and we hope you enjoy the course!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Math and Logic.Math and Logic</course_category><course_tag>Bayes' Theorem//Bayesian Probability//Probability//Probability Theory</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Data Science Math Skills//Building Blocks for Problem Solving//Functions and Graphs//Measuring Rates of Change//Introduction to Probability Theory</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Data Science Math Skills'], ['Sets - Basics and Vocabulary', 'Sets - Medical Testing Example', 'Sets - Venn Diagrams', 'Numbers - The Real Number Line', 'Numbers - Less-than and Greater-than', 'Numbers - Algebra With Inequalities', 'Numbers - Intervals and Interval Notation', 'Sigma Notation - Introduction to Summation', 'Sigma Notation - Simplification Rules', 'Sigma Notation - Mean and Variance'], ['Cartesian Plane - Plotting Points', 'Cartesian Plane - Distance Formula', 'Cartesian Plane - Point-Slope Formula for Lines', 'Cartesian Plane: Slope-Intercept Formula for Lines', 'Functions - Mapping from Sets to Sets', 'Functions - Graphing in the Cartesian Plane', 'Functions - Increasing and Decreasing Functions', 'Functions - Composition and Inverse'], ['Tangent Lines - Slope of a Graph at a Point', 'Tangent Lines - The Derivative Function', 'Using Integer Exponents', 'Simplification Rules for Algebra using Exponents', 'How Logarithms and Exponents are Related', 'The Change of Base Formula', 'The Rate of Growth of Continuous Processes'], ['Probability Definitions and Notation', 'Joint Probabilities', 'Permutations and Combinations', 'Using Factorial and “M choose N”', 'The Sum Rule, Conditional Probability, and the Product Rule', 'Bayes’ Theorem (Part 1)', 'Bayes’ Theorem (Part 2)', 'The Binomial Theorem and Bayes Theorem']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This course is very strong with respect to presenting the concepts you need to know for data science. It is extremely WEAK in terms explaining those concepts. If you are like me and did this kind of math back in the 70's and 80's but have not used it since, be prepared to seek sources outside Coursera in order to understand the material and pass the quizzes. The instructors leave out explanations and skip important points leaving you confused about the concept. \n", 'For newbies, the set theory, real numbers, basic statistics and so on are quite well explained. The intro to probability, however, is shallow and quite confusing. It lacks some real-life examples to offer a better grasp of the theory. Coins and dices examples are a good start, but made up examples without a real base are not clarifying at all.', None, 'Difficult content not explained well by the presenters. ', 'Very good informative, surely has helped me understand probability more intutively.', 'Great Course, really refresh my math skills', 'Good', 'Good!', 'Learned a lot from this course, thanks :)', 'I have got various knowledge from it. We have learn various lesson s of math. I am thankful for the professor who teaches us this things', 'First of all thanks to the data science math skill because i learned many new things,ideas,knowledge and skills from this course and more thankful to professors because of them i am able to give all the answers and it was too much interesting to do .', 'I like  this  course.  it   is  very  intersting.  Thanks  for  course.', 'Really a great place to get a  free education. I already complete a course and am looking forward to complete my second course.', 'I learned many new things, ideas, knowledge,and skills from this course.I am very much thankful to both professors for teaching about all of those interesting lessons,providing many more things. now, I am able to give all of the answers frequently which I learned from this beneficial course.', 'Learning this course I have gain many new and interesting skills. I am very much glad to get the knowledge from two professors and they gives me more knowledge on those interesting courses. I was able to do the answers of the given courses.And I THANKS them to give me such opportunity to do these courses.', 'I have learn many things from this course  such as algebra, equations,and other math problems. It has given me many information .', 'Great course', 'Nice Course, Looking for specialization bundle on this one', "It's very good to learn this course, so amazing.", 'good class', 'Great course!', 'This course from course era has given me  new opportunity to explore and has given me confidence in data science ,', 'Excellent course. Very detailed explanation of concepts.', 'Thanks for sharing the course details and subsequently facilitating the course.', 'I love the way teacher, teach me.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Robyn J', 'By Roberto S', 'By Marcel S', 'By Danuel R', 'By Mukund B G', 'By Ramneek k', 'By Sai K G', 'By Gustavo L R', 'By Kasidis S', 'By Yojana S', 'By Gitashah', 'By Merishka a', 'By Ritima B', 'By srijanapuri', 'By Preeti A', 'By shruti b', 'By Saida S A', 'By Qicheng S', 'By Mai V X', 'By LI M', 'By Valerii M', 'By Joy G', 'By K H S B', 'By Bijan K B', 'By RAJESH K']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 08, 2017', 'Jul 24, 2017', 'Apr 30, 2017', 'Apr 01, 2017', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Nov 09, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>