<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_61</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-text-mining</course_url><course_name>Applied Text Mining in Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>V. G. Vinod Vydiswaran</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce the learner to text mining and text manipulation basics. The course begins with an understanding of how text is handled by python, the structure of text both to the machine and to humans, and an overview of the nltk framework for manipulating text. The second week focuses on common manipulation needs, including regular expressions (searching for text), cleaning text, and preparing text for use by machine learning processes. The third week will apply basic natural language processing methods to text, and demonstrate how text classification is accomplished. The final week will explore more advanced methods for detecting the topics in documents and grouping them by similarity (topic modelling). 

This course should be taken after: Introduction to Data Science in Python, Applied Plotting, Charting &amp; Data Representation in Python, and Applied Machine Learning in Python.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK)//Text Mining//Python Programming//Natural Language Processing</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Working with Text in Python//Module 2: Basic Natural Language Processing//Module 3: Classification of Text//Module 4: Topic Modeling</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Text Mining', 'Handling Text in Python', 'Regular Expressions', 'Demonstration: Regex with Pandas and Named Groups', 'Internationalization and Issues with Non-ASCII Characters'], ['Basic Natural Language Processing', 'Basic NLP tasks with NLTK', 'Advanced NLP tasks with NLTK'], ['Text Classification', 'Identifying Features from Text', 'Naive Bayes Classifiers', 'Naive Bayes Variations', 'Support Vector Machines', 'Learning Text Classifiers in Python', 'Demonstration: Case Study - Sentiment Analysis'], ['Semantic Text Similarity', 'Topic Modeling', 'Generative Models and LDA', 'Information Extraction']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It is no exaggeration to say it took me longer to complete this course than the first 3 courses in the specialty and the time was utterly wasted. I wouldn't object if I felt like I was learning new skills but it is mostly battling a poorly constructed course, with terrible assignments, a broken autograder and a Professor who is utterly disinterested in the education of his students.", 'Very painful going through this course although i have quite well coped with course 1-3. ', 'I would see autograder and unspecific instructions ruin this course.....Sometimes you know how to get the answer and the answer looks just right! but you still cannot get passed! I would not be taking this course if it was not part of this Specialization........ Improvements need to be made!', 'Instructor does not explain concepts, just superficially goes through subjects. ', 'This is almost a waste of my time. The structure can be clearer and the connection to Python is outdated. The assignments are poorly designed. The instruction is not effective. ', 'The instructor provided very low quality material.', 'Instructor was poor.  Inadequate coverage of the material in the lectures, some questions not clear as to what was expected.  You can do better reading a book on this subject on your own.', "Curriculum is valuable but the course quality isn't on par with the other Applied Data Science using Python courses by University of Michigan. Week 4 assignment doesn't do enough to bring all the previous topics together in a realistic application. Week 3 lectures and notebook have teach the use of a scoring function wrongly - an issue addressed in forum threads for months but no edits to the video lectures and notebook have been made as of yet.", 'This course makes you give up on data science and MOOCs. ', 'The most discouraging course in specialization.', 'Unclear assignment instructions, buggy autograder, and no instructor help.', 'I really wanted to like this course, and there were some redeeming features, but overall I\'m unable to recommend it in its current state.  IMO, the lectures were at much too high a level while the programming assignments were very detailed with vague instructions and little guidance.  There was no link between what was discussed in class and how the fine details of the assignments were to be understood.  In addition, the course was published with errors in the auto-grader and no resources in the Resources link (not even slide decks from the lectures, so to review material you were forced to re-visit all the recorded lectures which was very inefficient).   My recommendation to Coursera and the Univ of Michigan is to completely re-do the course, doubling the number of lectures to provide not just the broad overview of the topics, but also some detailed descriptions of recommended ways to implement what was discussed.   I would also recommend using Professor Andrew Ngs Machine Learning course as a guide for how to create great programming assignments, with detailed PDFs (typically 5-6 pages) describing what is to be done AND WHY (linking back to the lectures) and "telling a story" that is cohesive and leads the student to create something end-to-end (in small steps) that does something amazing by the end.  The programming assignments in this course seemed, in contrast, to be a shotgun blast of "do this", "create this", "make this happen" with little context of how the small pieces fit together or what the overall goal of the assignment is to accomplish -- and at the end, a feeling of "I passed the autograder\'s expections, but have no idea what I\'ve really done or why".  There were so many great things that could have been done with the Text Mining topic, and this course touched on just a few in a very haphazard way that simply left me confused and wondering why I spent so much time to learn so little. ', 'Amazing teacher.', 'This instructor was great! His slides and explanations were much easier to follow than the other course instructors in the specialization. ', 'Very clear and nice explanations.', 'contents are good.', 'Really provides practical application and ideas on how to use tools in real world. Thanks so much!', 'nicely taught with all the concepts', 'Excellent course', 'Perfect course for quick guidance ', 'Well structured and quality lectures and content.', 'Great course!', '  This course is great. The knowledge gained in this course is very useful in real world.  ', 'This is a very helpful courses for text mining. It starts with cleaning data and then gradually build up the skills to classify and group texts. I love all the case studies. The assistant walks me through the tasks using the tools and methodologies mentioned in the lectures. It also helps to solve the assignments.  ', 'great teacher!!']</reviews><reviewers>['By David M', 'By Li Q', 'By lcy9086', 'By Aryan P', 'By Jian G', 'By Alejandro C M', 'By Michael T B', 'By Niccolo A H', 'By Eklavya s', 'By Мирзабекян А В', 'By David W', 'By David C', 'By Léa F', 'By Aya', 'By Saichand D', 'By Nithin R', 'By Phillip L C', 'By komal p', 'By AHMED B K', 'By Vrishti j', 'By Dibyendu C', 'By Sreenivasulu B', 'By Agnes H', 'By Yunfeng H', 'By Samuel E G G']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 06, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2018', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'May 15, 2018', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Jul 19, 2018', 'Apr 05, 2018', 'Aug 08, 2017', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Oct 18, 2018', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019']</review_date></doc>