<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_145</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/probability-statistics</course_url><course_name>Probability and Statistics: To p or not to p?</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr James Abdey</course_instructor><course_introduction>We live in an uncertain and complex world, yet we continually have to make decisions in the present with uncertain future outcomes.  Indeed, we should be on the look-out for "black swans" - low-probability high-impact events.

To study, or not to study?  To invest, or not to invest?  To marry, or not to marry?

While uncertainty makes decision-making difficult, it does at least make life exciting!  If the entire future was known in advance, there would never be an element of surprise.  Whether a good future or a bad future, it would be a known future.

In this course we consider many useful tools to deal with uncertainty and help us to make informed (and hence better) decisions - essential skills for a lifetime of good decision-making.

Key topics include quantifying uncertainty with probability, descriptive statistics, point and interval estimation of means and proportions, the basics of hypothesis testing, and a selection of multivariate applications of key terms and concepts seen throughout the course.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Dealing with Uncertainty and Complexity in a Chaotic World//Quantifying Uncertainty With Probability//Describing The World The Statistical Way//On Your Marks, Get Set, Infer!//To p Or Not To p?//Applications</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome!', '1.1 The Monty Hall Problem', '1.2 Decision Making Under Uncertainty', '1.3 Uncertainty in the News', '1.4 Simplicity vs. Complexity - The Need for Models', '1.5 Safe to Assume? Beware, When Model Assumptions Go Wrong!', '1.6 Roadmap of the Course', 'Week One Summary and Key Takeaways'], ['2.1 Probability Principles', '2.2 Simple Probability Distributions', '2.3 Expectation of Random Variables', '2.4 Bayesian Updating', '2.5 Parameters', '2.6 The Distribution Zoo', 'Week Two Summary and Key Takeaways'], ['3.1 Classify Your Variables!', '3.2 Data Visualisation', '3.3 Descriptive Statistics - Measures of Central Tendency', '3.4 Descriptive Statistics - Measures of Spread', '3.5 The Normal Distribution', '3.6 Variance of Random Variables', 'Week Three Summary and Key Takeaways'], ['4.1 Introduction to Sampling', '4.2 Random Sampling', '4.3 Further Random Sampling', '4.4 Sampling Distributions', '4.5 Sampling Distribution of the Sample Mean', '4.6 Confidence Intervals', 'Week Four Summary and Key Takeaways'], ['5.1 Statistical Juries', '5.2 Type I and Type II errors', '5.3 P-values, Effect Size and Sample Size Influences', '5.4 Testing a Population Mean Claim', '5.5 The Central Limit Theorem', '5.6 Proportions: Confidence Intervals and Hypothesis Testing', 'Week Five Summary and Key Takeaways'], ['6.1 Decision Tree Analysis', '6.2 Risk', '6.3 Linear Regression', '6.4 Linear Programming', '6.5 Monte Carlo Simulation', '6.6 Overview of the Course and Next Steps']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 20 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Yes, the scoring system for peer-reviewed work needs work -- poorly formatted and unnecessarily confusing.  That said, I would welcome more courses by Dr James Abdey.  As an introduction and overview/review, this particular course is excellent.  NOT superficial, as one reviewer commented.  If fact, if you download the PDFs which accompany each major video, you will that you can very quickly progress to the deeper end of the pool: much quality information.  I would love to see an option for R, and not just Excel.  But I can highly recommend this course (do suggest the assessment be tweaked), and hope again that Dr James Abdey will offer more.', 'The setup of peer reviewed assignments was a very poor experience due to lack of explanation and incorrect grading rubrics.  Reviewers were presented with a single radio-button list, when they should have been presented with a series of check-boxes.', 'The only reason to vote 4 instead 5 stars stay in the fact that there are not official moderator to fix the quiz bugs. For all the rest, 5 stars! At all! I loved it!', 'This is a fantastic course to refresh probability and statistics. The only reason i have provided four star is due to a bug in the week 5 assignment where the grading does not provide multiple selections. Additionally there is no support for course stuff if you have question. You are really on your own.  I would still encourage to take this one. ', 'Hi, ', 'Great', 'Lecturer is patient and always tries to explain difficult concepts clearly.', 'Very good introduction and overview, gives clear picture of probability and statistics. ', 'Best course on the concepts of Probability and statistics , for the beginners. Dr.James Abdey provides lot of examples from the everyday life .', 'Very good primer!', 'T', 'it was a nice learning experience, with a very step-by-step approach', "It's a great course.", 'Really well done! ', 'Easy to follow to your own time', 'It was a great experience learning from Sir Abdey!', 'Dr James Abdey is a fantastic teacher. He delivered the knowledge with plain languages and vivid examples. Very helpful!', "This course gives brief idea about different probabilistic methods used and their purpose in the real world. It's a very basic course where anyone can take and have a detailed knowledge on probability &amp; Statistics.", 'One of the good starting points to learn the basics of probability and statistics. With less of mathematics and more on theory and interesting examples, this course is just right to start your journey on statistics. It covers some of the detail concepts with ease. Highly recommended', 'wonderful course and the tutor!!', 'This course was very knowledgeable and given a review of my previous study.', "Basic introduction to the world of statistics, well structured and supplied with reading materials. Quite elementary, I'd say at most it's a HS/pre-college level overview of different fields and concepts. The lecturer conveys a strong appreciation for the subject. Recommended for those who want a first approximation to the subject.", "The course material was top notch I learned a lot. It was an excellent crash course, and beautifully explained. I took off a star because the failure of the grading system in Assignment #2 / Week 5 cost me a lot of time, and likely affected many of my peers as well. That type of technical glitch is unacceptable in MOOC, particularly because there doesn't seem to be anyone around to support the students. Thanks for resolving it, though, whoever you are!", 'The concept is well presented with the assumption that further research and dedication needed is required to get to next level.', 'Great Course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Thomas J H', 'By Brett C', 'By Paolo T', 'By Tanmoy C', 'By Abhishek S', 'By ruixi z', 'By Chia K X', 'By yue', 'By fozan t', 'By Georgios P', 'By Yves G', 'By Ravikumar S', 'By Leonardo B', 'By Ivan ', 'By José L', 'By Geeti P M', 'By Guomin R', 'By Duvvuri Y S P', 'By Majnoo G', 'By Madhav C', 'By MALIK I A', 'By Jordi a', 'By david w', 'By Weichi C', 'By Mayur P K']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 14, 2018', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Nov 02, 2018', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'May 25, 2019', 'Jun 06, 2019', 'Jul 19, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2018']</review_date></doc>