<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_130</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/digital-analytics</course_url><course_name>Digital Analytics for Marketing Professionals: Marketing Analytics in Practice</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Kevin Hartman</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course builds on the theory and foundations of marketing analytics and focuses on practical application by demystifying the use of data in marketing and helping you realize the power of visualizing data with artful use of numbers found in the digital space.

This course is part of the iMBA offered by the University of Illinois, a flexible, fully-accredited online MBA at an incredibly competitive price. For more information, please see the Resource page in this course and onlinemba.illinois.edu.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Marketing</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Marketing Analytics//Marketing Performance Measurement And Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview and Marketing Analytics Process//Data Collection//Data Analysis//Data Visualization</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Marketing Analytics in Practice', 'About Prof Kevin Hartman', 'Lesson 1: Following the MAP, Part 1', 'Lesson 1: Following the MAP, Part 2'], ['Lesson 2: Preparing for the Analysis Journey, Part 1', 'Lesson 2: Preparing for the Analysis Journey, Part 2', 'Lesson 3: Data Collection Part I: Unstructured Data', 'Comments by Prof Rhiannon Clifton'], ['Lesson 4: Data Collection Part II: Structured Data', 'Lesson 5: Data Management in Practice, Part 1', 'Lesson 5: Data Management in Practice, Part 2'], ['Lesson 6: Insights from Digital Data Pt.1', 'Lesson 6: Insights from Digital Data Pt.2', 'Lesson 7: Pictures You See with Your Brain and Feel with Your Heart, Part 1', 'Lesson 7: Pictures You See with Your Brain and Feel with Your Heart, Part 2']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I was quite disappointed by this course. There are a lot of repetitions with course 2, it's very theorical and ressources are quite old and it's only articles to read, no video, interviews…. Plus quizz 4 asks a lot of question about a subject not mentionned in the lecture. I think it needs to be revisited.", 'Excellent Course', "Not just great content and teaching, but fantastic resources that I'll be using for years.  Thank you!", 'Very useful information, presented at a fairly digestible pace.', 'In a single word Just Fantabulous!! It is not only good for beginners but also a great refresher for experienced professionals. I am Fan of Kevin Hartman, never seen a instructor explaining such a complex topics in easy to grasp language. I really enjoyed doing peer-graded assignments, quizzes and video lectures.', 'AWESOME', 'Excellent course', 'I loved this course. It was technical and very different for someone who has done none of this before. But how interesting and challenging. Excellent!!', 'Great presenter, slides and info. Learned a whole lot and can already apply everything to my job. Perfect.  ', 'Provides a good overview of the marketing analytics practice and how it can be used for imroving the marketing performance and effectiveness.', 'Excellent course, advise to all business analytics!', 'Thank you for the class. I get to learn about digital analytics in marketing.', 'A very useful and interesting course!', "This professor and this course was brilliant. It's rare to find this quality of teaching where I come from. ", 'L', 'Great Performance', 'Intense course, loved it very well organized.', 'Very impressive course one of my favorites', "It's great , i will suggest for my friends.", 'That was a great introductory course. ', 'Amazing Course!!!', 'This was an extremely interesting class and Professor Hartman was absolutely fantastic!', 'Excellent', 'I love the course, assignment review process was a really a pain. Great course content and perfectly delivered.', 'i have huge knowledge from this course i will use it in my career ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Bénédicte M', 'By Vladimir V', 'By Felicia H', 'By Mario H U B', 'By Asheesh P', 'By NKETIAH E', 'By Magdalena I', 'By Sharlene V', 'By Stefanie P', 'By Krishna R', 'By Hikmat T M', 'By Shridevi J', 'By Joshua J M', 'By Kartik A', 'By Sudeepti P', 'By Kripesh K C', 'By A S C R', 'By Maheep', 'By DEVANAND M', 'By farzin e', 'By Ana C', 'By Joe F', 'By IVIN A A', 'By Nkululeko S M', 'By Israa M R']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 26, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Apr 05, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Apr 12, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Jul 09, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Aug 17, 2018', 'Aug 19, 2018']</review_date></doc>