<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_12</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning-with-python</course_url><course_name>Machine Learning with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>SAEED AGHABOZORGI</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course dives into the basics of machine learning using an approachable, and well-known programming language, Python. 
In this course, we will be reviewing two main components:
First, you will be learning about the purpose of Machine Learning and where it applies to the real world. 
Second, you will get a general overview of Machine Learning topics such as supervised vs unsupervised learning,  model evaluation, and Machine Learning algorithms. 

In this course, you practice with real-life examples of Machine learning and see how it affects society in ways you may not have guessed!

By just putting in a few hours a week for the next few weeks, this is what you’ll get.
1) New skills to add to your resume, such as regression, classification, clustering, sci-kit learn and SciPy 
2) New projects that you can add to your portfolio, including cancer detection, predicting economic trends, predicting customer churn, recommendation engines, and many more.
3) And a certificate in machine learning to prove your competency, and share it anywhere you like online or offline, such as LinkedIn profiles and social media.

If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you will also earn an IBM digital badge upon successful completion of the course.

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Machine Learning//Regression//Classification//Clustering//Recommender Systems//Final Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Introduction to Machine Learning', 'Python for Machine Learning', 'Supervised vs Unsupervised'], ['Introduction to Regression', 'Simple Linear Regression', 'Model Evaluation in Regression Models', 'Evaluation Metrics in Regression Models', 'Multiple Linear Regression', 'Non-Linear Regression'], ['Introduction to Classification', 'K-Nearest Neighbours', 'Evaluation Metrics in Classification', 'Introduction to Decision Trees', 'Building Decision Trees', 'Intro to Logistic Regression', 'Logistic regression vs Linear regression', 'Logistic Regression Training', 'Support Vector Machine'], ['Intro to Clustering', 'Intro to k-Means', 'More on k-Means', 'Intro to Hierarchical Clustering', 'More on Hierarchical Clustering', 'DBSCAN'], ['Intro to Recommender Systems', 'Content-based Recommender Systems', 'Collaborative Filtering'], ['OPTIONAL: Signing-up for a Watson Studio Account', 'OPTIONAL: Sharing Notebooks on Watson Studio']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course concentrates more on Maths rather than explaining how algorithm can be implemented in Python. This is difficult for a someone with less knowledge in Maths. ', 'Good theoretical background on how some machine learning tasks actually work mathematically, but, to be quite frank, much of it is a) not necessary, (i.e. I\'ve used regression as a prime aspect of my job for approaching 3 decades now, and have never known that it used partial derivatives to determine what elements to vary, but, quite frankly, that knowledge has never been required or even vaguely useful for either its use or explanation) b) presented in a way that, as soon as it begins to get interesting from an algorithmic standpoint, stops with a "beyond the scope of this class," (to be fair, I have a -major- pet peeve about that phrase from working with developers for decades) and c) if such depth of knowledge was considered important, it should have been split up amongst more classes - i.e. at the point someone takes this class, they\'ve been through 7 other classes in the IBM Data Science track, and only 3 of them have presented enough and important enough info that I\'ve even bothered to keep notes for future reference.  Instead of 4 classes that effectively wasted all of our time, (including the two whole intro classes) if the background mathematics is important, (again, I would venture that, to a non-expert-level general practitioner, which this class is aimed at, it\'s just not) move some of it out of this class and into some of the others so that we don\'t end up with effectively two important classes out of 9 - the Data Analysis with Python class, for being the most challenging mechanically, (i.e. what -exactly- should I be typing in at the command prompt to get what I want to happen) and this one, for being the most challenging theoretically.  Would very much like to see a re-work of the overall curriculum to better space out the effort vs time invested relationship.', 'Errors in the presentations and in the Jupyter workbooks, plenty of typos. Not professional at all.', 'This was my favorite course in the specialization and hence the only one that gets my 5* rating!', 'The courses are good, but they presume the student knows very good python programming. The lectures are nice and concise but they do not go in too much depth and there is some disparity between the depth of knowledge that is needed in the labs vs the lectures. The labs assume very good programming expertise.', 'The course was highly informative and very well presented. It was very easier to follow. Many complicated concepts were clearly explained. It improved my confidence with respect to programming skills.', 'This was an extremely hard course to understand because of the very dense mathematics. The laboratories were filled with typos which made understanding the concepts much harder. Sometimes code would even be wrong. Please review the labs carefully and try to explain the concepts better. It also helps when you explain what your code is doing so students can understand what is being written.', 'I am thoroughly enjoying the course. The codes written are the shortest possible codes but the narrations are just fabulous to comprehend and remember. I need more practice to write the codes correctly by my own but my fundas are all cleared and I know exactly why am I doing the next step.', 'Really high quality videos and labs.', "Good Start with detailed explanation about each element in the syllabus. I thoroughly enjoyed working with labs and assignments. After the course, You'll have a solid understanding and you can explore almost any algorithm and understand it intuitively.", 'puts a lot of the previous courses all together. challenging, but doable.', 'It was an exited course though some difficulties to acquire the knowledge behind ML algorithms. But this course is worth learning. Definitely, thanks to Mr. SAEED AGHABOZORGI  and all the team.', 'I am happy to have this online education, I drop out my nuclear engineering degree, I am happy to learn practical things with future... I work for IBM also...but I want to become a data scientis', 'I liked this course. Nice to see how math learnt in theory years ago can be used in practice in some of the models.', 'one of the best shot term course in Mechine Learning', 'I love this course, particularly the labs, they are great!  ', 'Very interesting subject, and very well explained. Even if I miss more concrete code examples, I can always look for it, the theory and the logic behind it was explained flawlessly.', 'Thank You Mr. Saeed Aghabozorgi for designing and delivering such a immersive course, I found lot of pointers and specific details associated with many interesting topics in Machine Learning.', 'Probably this is one of the course within the program that will give you the most important background on what Data Science is about. It is relatively easy to understand each algorithm with the support of the labs and the Notebooks provided by the team. The project at the end of the course is really interesting and challenging. ', 'The instructor was awesome. His voice was crisp and to the point. The course is actually well laid out with proper structure. Altogether a great learning experience. Cheers... Keep up the good work.', 'Concise presentation,brief and to-the -point explanations, great course for an intermediate ML developer looking to brush up their skills.Programming exercises should me more detailed.', "The content here is extremely valuable, I'm sure.  But for folks coming into the Applied Data Science specialization with no prior Python coding experience, the code here is mostly incomprehensible.   I got a 94% in the course with peer assessment of the assignments, but I think I understood maybe 30% of the coding, if I'm being generous.  The video explanations of the different statistical models are clear and easy to follow, and  the topics are fascinating.  I look forward to coming back to review and relearn this material once I actually take a course in Python programming.", 'Very complicated subject. Many lines of code in the algorithms are not explained, and the learner is left to either figure out their function themselves or to memorize them.', 'labs are not easy to understand', 'very bad course ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Radhika K', 'By Dylan H', 'By Vincent L', 'By Karim C N', 'By Dr S K', 'By Rama S C', 'By Kevin L K', 'By APARAJITO S', 'By Mike D', 'By RAVIKUMAR M', 'By asher b', 'By Brahim A', 'By Jonathan', 'By Bjørn I A', 'By Arijit G', 'By Rose C', 'By Juan V P', 'By Imran R', 'By Peter H', 'By SIDDHANT K', 'By Rajdeep S', 'By Jess M', 'By Sisir K', 'By Serdar M', 'By Parth R J']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 07, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'Sep 13, 2018', 'Jun 05, 2019', 'Nov 05, 2018', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Apr 07, 2019', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Jun 25, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'May 08, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Mar 03, 2019']</review_date></doc>