<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_209</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/galaxy-project</course_url><course_name>Genomic Data Science with Galaxy</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>James Taylor, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn to use the tools that are available from the Galaxy Project. This is the second course in the Genomic Big Data Science Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Bioinformatics//Data Analysis//Genome//Genomics</course_tag><course_rating>3.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Galaxy 101//Working with sequence data//RNA-seq &amp; Running your own Galaxy</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Challenges of Reproducibility', 'Introduction to the Galaxy Platform'], ['Galaxy 101: Genomic Intervals', 'Galaxy 101: Workflows', 'Annotation, Sharing, and Publishing'], ['Sequence Data Quality Control', 'ChIP-Sequence Analysis with MACS'], ['RNA-seq Analysis: Mapping', 'RNA Sequence Analysis: Assembly Quantitation, and Differential Expression', 'Installing Galaxy Locally', 'Galaxy on the Cloud']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The programs on used in the lecture videos have all been deprecated and there was not enough information provided in the lectures to be able to tackle the final project. ', 'There is far less information provided in the course content to adequately prepare students to carry out the project at the end of week four. The lectures are very low level and introductory but the course project is in-depth and requires a lot of prior knowledge.', 'Seems like Galaxy is far updated after the preparation of the course material. A refreshment on them might be useful. It is not essential but this discrepancy increased the time I had to spend on the course.', 'The course itself is very well taught, although the information is rudimentary relative to the final project. The main reason I am giving the course 2 stars is because the lectures do not prepare the learner for the final project (although it does provide most of the basics for training yourself), and the peer review of the final project lacks direction. For example we are expected to grade our peers based on whether their answers are correct, without having any guidance of what the correct answer actually is.', 'The course content covers the very basics and is unfortunately not technical enough for you to actually apply to real data analysis. In addition the class project at the end is much more demanding than what was covered by the materials. Finally the grading of the class project is peer-based which is fine but no answers or guidance are provided which leads to "blind leading the blind" scenario. In my case my project was correctly done but i received a failing grade because my "peer" marked the assignment incorrectly. I merely resubmitted the exact same result and got lucky with a competent "peer" who gave me the pass i deserved the first time around.', 'Overall, this was one of the worst courses I have ever taken. The course is all about pushing buttons. "Why should I push this button and not that? And what will it do?" you ask – well, this course will certainly not answer that! For example, the instructor stresses the importance of pushing the QC buttons to get a report of the quality of the data, but you are not told how to read the output nor what to do if something is alarming – not even what would be an alarming output. And then, for the rest of the course the QC reports are ignored. ', 'The course was ok until the final project. The videos should cover more the topic that are needed to solve the project or more reading should be provided. ', 'My assignment has not been peer reviewed for a while now. The course is not as explanatory as the other courses in the specializations. Honestly a bit disappointing.', 'Great course! Could divide the learning experience into two parts. Genomics and IT. A lot was demanded from the genomics side that personally, I supplemented with uTube presentations. From the IT side I soon learned that once the sequencing had been performed, it was a big data problem of fuzzy pattern matching for which you had a lot of software primitives (Galaxy) tied together by workflows. Again, uTube helped to solidify this concept. The class approach while teaching a lot, mostly relied on independent research in order to be successful in a directed study endeavor. ', 'It is fast-paced. The teacher is good. The final exam is out of proportion to what was taught in class. There is minimal guidance on the task, which is frustrating for those trying to take the course seriously and thoroughly.', '  I learned a lot through the course, but the final project really makes this course pathetic. The peer-review system is a mess. I do have some molecular biology background but I still feel that understanding the requirements for the project is challenging, I can imagine how confusing it could be for students without biology background.  ', 'Class is incredibly out of date.  Good general information, but needs to be updated to reflect current version of Galaxy.', '1 star is very enough!', 'This course is frustrating, there is not\nnear enough information in the lectures to do the final assignment. There’s\nalso NO support from staff, just a former student volunteering. A total disappointment.  ', 'The course material is introductory. The final exam is confusing with very vague instruction.', 'worst ever course on coursera. This entire specialization on data sciences for genomics is a horribly done effort with no co-ordination, inadequate theory, poorly thought out examples and assignments totally different from what is taught', 'var rating = 3;', '\nYou lacked more details about the environment and the terms used. It was super complicated to draw conclusions in the final project due to lack of information in the course.The\n Galaxy is very powerful, provides fantastic features, I think it would \nbe interesting to extend the duration and create more in-depth \nmaterials.\n\n', 'Very useful!', 'Very good', 'Great course.', 'goodjob', 'Very useful course, do not miss it. It puts a lot of things together. The project will make you work a lot if you really want to learn.', 'Great introductory material, please do suggest more reading material!', "Great instructor with clear and thorough understanding of the material. If you don't have any experience with this technology, this course will walk you through it patiently."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Lauren B', 'By Marc-Michel W', 'By Ummiye V O', 'By Bryan G', 'By Arkan A', 'By Lars L R', 'By Katarzyna M', 'By Haymanti S', 'By Steve S', 'By Felipe B', 'By Ke Z', 'By Robert D', 'By 邵文', 'By Anna A', 'By Yunfei D', 'By Kiran', 'By Jason M', 'By Gilson B d J', 'By Xing Y', 'By Carlos H L d M', 'By Michael N', 'By Nicholas H', 'By Dahis M', 'By Ricardo A C I', 'By Rene C']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 19, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Jul 05, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Aug 03, 2017', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'Mar 27, 2018', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'May 01, 2018', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2017', 'Nov 01, 2017', 'Sep 18, 2017', 'Oct 16, 2018', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Mar 08, 2019', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Aug 30, 2016', 'Jun 12, 2016']</review_date></doc>