<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_289</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/meaningful-marketing-insights</course_url><course_name>Meaningful Marketing Insights</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>David Schweidel</course_instructor><course_introduction>With marketers are poised to be the largest users of data within the organization, there is a need to make sense of the variety of consumer data that the organization collects. Surveys, transaction histories and billing records can all provide insight into consumers’ future behavior, provided that they are interpreted correctly. In Introduction to Marketing Analytics, we introduce the tools that learners will need to convert raw data into marketing insights. The included exercises are conducted using Microsoft Excel, ensuring that learners will have the tools they need to extract information from the data available to them. The course provides learners with exposure to essential tools including exploratory data analysis, as well as regression methods that can be used to investigate the impact of marketing activity on aggregate data (e.g., sales) and on individual-level choice data (e.g., brand choices). 

To successfully complete the assignments in this course, you will require Microsoft Excel. If you do not have Excel, you can download a free 30-day trial here: https://products.office.com/en-us/try</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Marketing</course_category><course_tag>Basic Descriptive Statistics//Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Marketing</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Emory University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Meet Dr. Schweidel &amp; Course Overview//Exploring your Data with Visualization and Descriptive Statistics, Part 1//Exploring your Data with Visualization and Descriptive Statistics, Part 2//Regression Analysis for Marketing Data//From Analysis to Action</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Meet Dr. Schweidel'], ['Course Objectives &amp; Example 1: Political Advertising Expenditures', 'Course Goals &amp; Example 2: Performing Arts Centers', 'Organizing Data', 'The Motion Picture Industry'], ['Excel Analysis of Motion Picture Industry Data', 'Displaying Conditional Distributions', 'Analyzing Qualitative Variables', 'Steps in Constructing Histograms', 'Common Descriptive Statistics for Quantitative Data'], ['Regression-Based Modeling', 'Introduction to Customer Analytics', 'Customer Choices Drive Business Decisions', 'Illustrating Customer Analytics in Excel'], ['Customer Valuation Excel Demonstration', 'Inventory Management Excel Demonstration']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["As someone with a very limited background in statistics, I found the course jumped very quickly from basics to extremely complicated statistical modeling with all the jargon that comes with it. So either the course description didn't provide enough information for a non-statistician to realize it will get very complex, or the language and explanations should have been simplified/more descriptive for the audience. ", "There's barely enough content or involvement, here, to qualify this as a course. The video lessons drill in on incredibly simple concepts while breezing right over complex terms, formulas, and practical knowledge which is then tested. There are very few reference documents. There are no ways to cross-reference our methodology/problem solving in excel.", 'I love this course.', 'love this course', 'This course is a must for anyone who is serious about learning about data driven marketing and gleaning practical insights.', 'The last 2 video lectures: Customer Valuation Excel Demonstration and Inventory Management Excel Demonstrationm were very well explained and taught me something new and useful.', 'Great content. The hands-on approach and the use of actual tools with basic software are just great.', None, 'Excellent course! Very hands on with right level of theory and application. Prof. Schweidel is obviously an expert in this field. ', 'This course provided practical hands-on approach to understanding basics of marketing forecasting. ', 'This course went in depth into some excel functions used for analyzing sales and marketing data, really thought it was useful. ', 'an excellent start to marketing analytics', 'Really enjoyed the class. I like that the examples and data files were on topics that someone in marketing might use in their daily work.', 'Helpful, practical assignments and tutorials.', 'Useful and Insightful', "It is a very good structured entry level course to marketing analytics for professionals who have some Excel skills but don't know where to start. It's the first part of a 6-course pack and I look forward to start the rest asap. I strongly recommend.", 'Excellent lectures and content throughout the course.  ', "One of the best courses on analytics. You will use excel, real data, and your own insights. It's a package.", 'Good learning experience', 'The content is extremely valuable and was delivered in a very good way fully engaging the learners! ', 'Some notions introduced too fast and with little explanations. Overall very interesting and applicable.', 'Great content and examples. Sometimes, the theoretical background could be explained more comprehensively in the lectures.', 'I would have liked more discussion of theory behind what the formulas were and, actually, using slicers for data so that clients couldn\'t "break" the file unintentionally. Otherwise, it was a good basic course, a little too dependent on showing Excel rather than saying why something worked (IF clauses are a good example here, cutting and pasting formulas is not as helpful to my personal learning style as just explaining the rationale behind them.) ', 'It was an amazing course. But i found some of the statistical models difficult to understand so needed to go back and review my statistics a bit to grapple with it. Overall, a brilliant course.', 'I wish solutions for probabilities related questions were very detailed, for people who are still learning statistics, or forgot. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Waseem B', 'By Christian K', 'By Sejan R C', 'By Mahdi T C', 'By Aloka G', 'By Melanie M', 'By Jairo J N P', 'By S. J D I', 'By Harish K', 'By Elena W', 'By Juliana D', 'By Arjun S', 'By David W', 'By Monique S', 'By Jin M', 'By Omer E', 'By William B', 'By JATIN A', 'By John', 'By Darya Y', 'By Isabelle P', 'By Steffen M', 'By Christine M', 'By Asma A', 'By Steve Y']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 28, 2017', 'May 25, 2018', 'Jul 12, 2018', 'Jul 13, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2016', 'Nov 12, 2017', 'Jun 13, 2017', 'May 09, 2017', 'Jan 03, 2017', 'Aug 23, 2017', 'Aug 29, 2017', 'Oct 19, 2018', 'Nov 01, 2018', 'Aug 21, 2018', 'Jul 11, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2019', 'Sep 01, 2019', 'Nov 25, 2016', 'Oct 21, 2016', 'Dec 22, 2016', 'Mar 13, 2017', 'Jun 24, 2017', 'Aug 21, 2019', 'Sep 05, 2017']</review_date></doc>