<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_131</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/bayesian</course_url><course_name>Bayesian Statistics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course describes Bayesian statistics, in which one's inferences about parameters or hypotheses are updated as evidence accumulates. You will learn to use Bayes’ rule to transform prior probabilities into posterior probabilities, and be introduced to the underlying theory and perspective of the Bayesian paradigm. The course will apply Bayesian methods to several practical problems, to show end-to-end Bayesian analyses that move from framing the question to building models to eliciting prior probabilities to implementing in R (free statistical software) the final posterior distribution. Additionally, the course will introduce credible regions, Bayesian comparisons of means and proportions, Bayesian regression and inference using multiple models, and discussion of Bayesian prediction.

We assume learners in this course have background knowledge equivalent to what is covered in the earlier three courses in this specialization: "Introduction to Probability and Data," "Inferential Statistics," and "Linear Regression and Modeling."</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Bayesian Statistics//Bayesian Linear Regression//Bayesian Inference//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>3.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About the Specialization and the Course//The Basics of Bayesian Statistics//Bayesian Inference//Decision Making//Bayesian Regression//Perspectives on Bayesian Applications//Data Analysis Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Statistics with R'], ['The Basics of Bayesian Statistics', "Conditional Probabilities and Bayes' Rule", "Bayes' Rule and Diagnostic Testing", 'Bayes Updating', 'Bayesian vs. frequentist definitions of probability', 'Inference for a Proportion: Frequentist Approach', 'Inference for a Proportion: Bayesian Approach', 'Effect of Sample Size on the Posterior', 'Frequentist vs. Bayesian Inference'], ['Bayesian Inference', 'From the Discrete to the Continuous', 'Elicitation', 'Conjugacy', 'Inference on a Binomial Proportion', 'The Gamma-Poisson Conjugate Families', 'The Normal-Normal Conjugate Families', 'Non-Conjugate Priors', 'Credible Intervals', 'Predictive Inference'], ['Decision making', 'Losses and decision making', 'Working with loss functions', 'Minimizing expected loss for hypothesis testing', 'Posterior probabilities of hypotheses and Bayes factors', 'The Normal-Gamma Conjugate Family', 'Inference via Monte Carlo Sampling', 'Predictive Distributions and Prior Choice', 'Reference Priors', 'Mixtures of Conjugate Priors and MCMC', 'Hypothesis Testing: Normal Mean with Known Variance', "Comparing Two Paired Means Using Bayes' Factors", 'Comparing Two Independent Means: Hypothesis Testing', 'Comparing Two Independent Means: What to Report?'], ['Bayesian regression', 'Bayesian simple linear regression', 'Checking for outliers', 'Bayesian multiple regression', 'Model selection criteria', 'Bayesian model uncertainty', 'Bayesian model averaging', 'Stochastic exploration', 'Priors for Bayesian model uncertainty', 'R demo: crime and punishment', 'Decisions under model uncertainty'], ['Bayesian inference: a talk with Jim Berger', 'Bayesian methods and big data: a talk with David Dunson', 'Bayesian methods in biostatistics and public health: a talk with Amy Herring'], ['Project information']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 30 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['While the other modules so far have been terrific with good levels of support and clear explanations, this module is pretty terrible for a few reasons. ', 'Unfortunately, for me, this course did not live up to my expectations in comparison to the previous 3 courses I took as part of the Statistics with R specialisation. I gave the previous 3 a full 5 stars each.', 'Very large drop in quality from the previous three courses in the specialization. Unlike the previous classes, there is not a quality textbook provided. What passes for a "textbook" is essentially a written re-hashing of the lectures which provides no new examples.  The lectures themselves can be hard to follow and often times skip over important calculations. There are no practice problems. The labs are also less clear and there are major leaps between what is taught and what we are expected to know to solve the problems. The lack of quality resources and poor teaching coupled with the more challenging material made this course very frustrating. ', 'Starts out good in the first week and then ramps up to graduate level statistics without really a lot of notation explanation.  Week 3 with the silver haired lady as the teacher was the WORST. nothing made sense when she taught.', 'Good for reviewing Bayesian Statistic. But not for new learners.', 'The last two weeks are way too hard to follow and could provide more practical examples instead of focusing on mathematical theory and formulas. That would make more sense to this course when compared to the content of the previous ones in this specialization.', 'Worst course in the specialization. Totally killed my interest in statistics and R. Warning to everyone, do not do this course if you have / want to learn statistics. Only do it if you want to re-enforce the view that statistics is not something for you.', "I have been doing the specialization from course 1, giving 5 stars to all of them. This course had the poorest explanations in the videos. I like the content, as it is challenging but many questions come to mind which are not thoroughly discussed in the video. For example, when you do the exercises you get topics that raises questions and there is no way to clear these doubts. Sometimes in the forums, but it shouldn't be the case.", 'much different than the other classes in the series.  They tried to put to much into this short course and consequently its way too hard.  They should drop if from the statistics specialization and produce on new and longer stand alone Bayesian class.  dissappointed because I dont think I can finish this class and now I wont be able to finish the specialization.', "Like many other reviewers, I was caught out by the dramatic shift in approach and presentation style at week 3 of this class.  In one of the in-class forum threads on this topic I found a perhaps sarcastic recommendation from one of the mentors to take a different class (UC Santa Cruz) which I did in the middle of this one.  I learned more from that one.  The in-video demonstrations do not always explain the numbers that show up on the screen, and there is much less direct connection to using R than in the previous classes in the specialization.  In the final programming projects, the Bayesian magic is hidden behind packages so you don't actually work directly with the computations...just a different function call.  This was the least rewarding class of the specialization, and I won't bother to continue to the capstone project because of it.", 'Rushed exposition of extremely complex ideas.  The level of this course is not at all consistent with that of the previous courses in the series. There is really no excuse for this; it\'s possible to provide an intuitive understanding of the Bayesian approach that is on par with the other courses (e.g. along the lines of Stone\'s "Bayes Rule: A Tutorial Introduction". This course has damaged my opinion of Duke\'s online offerings and Coursera more generally.', "A bit of a letdown after I loved the first three courses. It's a useful and interesting course. However, what I loved about the previous courses was that they were self-contained and if sometimes challenging I always managed to do the quizzes with the knowlegde and practice from the lectures and labs. With this one, I literally had to guess my way through some of the quizzes which is both frustrating and not very educational.", "The course has seen a lot of improvement with new study materials and videos. I'd say that this is now much better than what the course was previously.", 'I think it was way too much subject matter to fit into the 5 weeks. In previous courses, I could watch lectures and take notes in a reasonable amount of time. This course, 7-minute lectures would take me 45 minutes to listen and take notes. They just went way too fast through the material, even talking much faster. Splitting this into 2 sections would have been much better.', 'Very good introduction to Bayesian Statistics. Very interactive with Labs in Rmarkdown. Definitely requires thinking and a good math/analytic background is helpful. ', 'In my opinion this is the most difficult course in this specialization. There is a lot of new concepts to master and, although Bayesian reasoning is more natural, most of us has been conditioned to think as a frequentist, not as a Bayesian. However, the course offered a glimpse on how Bayesian approach can deal certain issues where frequentist approaches fail and that is the most important lesson one can take home from this course.', 'Too many formulas... More examples would be nice.', 'Weeks 1 and 2 were perfect. Weeks 3 and 4 felt rushed. The course suddenly became very formula heavy.', 'I would suggest that you split this course in three components, mirroring the frequentist courses of the same specialization: introduction, inference and regression. That would make the material much more digestible, because today, it feels quite compressed and many things are left unexplained (specially the last two weeks of the course, I spent as much time there as with the rest of the specialization altogether!).', 'The material was rushed and did not provide enough examples for a beginner to understand.', 'I  want to give 0 ratings. The worst course I have seen so far in Coursera.  Horrible planning, horrible execution and makes no sense. Totally disappointed by the style of course design and delivery', "Clearly, Professor Clyde doesn't know how to teach.", 'The professors tried to put too much material into very short videos. ', "they didn't tell that this course didn't have a homework, reading, or practice problems to do. Ended up s", 'great course!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Richard M', 'By Tansel T A', 'By Anna P', 'By Sara M', 'By Toan T L', 'By Tulio R C', 'By Ong Y R T', 'By Juan P S', 'By Mark N', 'By Kevin P B', 'By Val', 'By Anna D', 'By Praveen A', 'By Elizabeth C S', 'By Wesley E', 'By Chin J L', 'By Aleix D', 'By Rofi S I', 'By Dario B', 'By Shannon', 'By Syed S R', 'By Chen N', 'By vacous', 'By Daniel R', 'By Pedro G F M']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 24, 2019', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Aug 12, 2018', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Feb 25, 2018', 'Feb 26, 2018', 'May 23, 2017', 'Oct 13, 2018', 'Aug 06, 2018', 'Nov 01, 2016', 'Jun 07, 2018', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Aug 19, 2018', 'Jun 17, 2019', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'Sep 13, 2018', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Jun 06, 2017', 'Jun 14, 2017', 'Dec 20, 2018']</review_date></doc>