<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_217</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/datascimed</course_url><course_name>Data Science in Stratified Healthcare and Precision Medicine</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr Areti Manataki</course_instructor><course_introduction>An increasing volume of data is becoming available in biomedicine and healthcare, from genomic data, to electronic patient records and data collected by wearable devices. Recent advances in data science are transforming the life sciences, leading to precision medicine and stratified healthcare. 

In this course, you will learn about some of the different types of data and computational methods involved in stratified healthcare and precision medicine.  You will have a hands-on experience of working with such data.  And you will learn from leaders in the field about successful case studies. 

Topics include: (i) Sequence Processing, (ii) Image Analysis, (iii) Network Modelling, (iv) Probabilistic Modelling, (v) Machine Learning, (vi) Natural Language Processing, (vii) Process Modelling and (viii) Graph Data.

Watch the course promo video here: http://edin.ac/2pn350P</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Python Programming//Machine Learning//Image Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>The University of Edinburgh</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the Course//WELCOME TO WEEK 2//WELCOME TO WEEK 3//WELCOME TO WEEK 4//WELCOME TO WEEK 5</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course', 'About the Course', 'Demystifying Data Science', 'Python Basics Part 1', 'Python Basics Part 2', 'Professor Andrew Morris', 'Professor Aileen Keel'], ['Introduction', 'DNA and Sequencing', 'Modelling the Data', 'Conclusion', 'Professor Tim Aitman', 'Professor David Porteous', 'Introduction', 'Medical Imaging Data &amp; Modalities', 'Analysing Medical Images'], ['Introduction', 'Representing Networks', 'Biological Networks', 'Conclusion', 'Introduction', 'Statistical Methods in Medical Research', 'Conclusion', 'Introduction', 'Supervised Learning', 'Unsupervised Learning', 'Conclusion'], ['Introduction', 'Tasks', 'Computational Methods', 'Angus McCann from IBM', 'Introduction', 'Modelling Processes', 'Analysing Processes', 'Process Mining', 'Rodrigo Barnes from Aridhia'], ['Introduction', 'Graph Data &amp; RDF', 'Ontologies &amp; Graph Data Conclusion', 'Dr Steve Pavis', 'Professor Mark Parsons', 'Society, Law and Ethics', 'Course Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is really good and it brings together medical concepts and data science. I would like to see more such courses and even a specialisation series of medical research, precision medicine and data science for medical professionals that want to work on data science. ', 'The course "Data Science in Stratified Healthcare and\nPrecision Medicine" was excellent. The course content consisted of lectures,\ntutorials and case studies. The case studies provided fantastic insights into data\nscience and precision medicine. The course was run by Dr Areti Manataki and Dr\nFrances Wong. The lectures were very well presented and very informative. The tutorials\nwere excellent and based around using python for data science tasks such as NLP\nand imaging manipulation. The course was finished off by a peer graded assessment.\n  ', 'Course introduces a varieties of Data Analytics methods and machine learning approaches for working with the stratified Healthcare data. I would recommend this course to those who are thinking about making their carrier in Data Science specially in Healthcare Business!', 'Congratulations for the course, it is very well structured, approaching very interesting topics of Data Science in a very practical way, enabling to learn and to try with interesting examples.', 'One of the great course I have ever done through coursera! Thank you to Dr.Wong and Dr.Areti for their great contribution!', 'A very knowledgeable course that gives insight into the upcoming advances in healthcare with the help of data science.', 'Great Course!', 'Great course. It was so intriguing I had to go through the videos non-stop!', 'Very insight full and packs quite the punch in terms of content', "The course fulfills all my expectations, I'm looking forward to enrolling in a further version of it.", "Great course, really well designed and well produced and I feel like I've learned a lot! The coding was a bit of a shock to the system but it was nice and challenging. Thank you to the team!", 'Compact course in introducing Precision medicine through Data Science ', 'Very Good', 'It is very clear in explanation and easy to understand.', 'Excellent introduction to use of data science in healthcare with hands-on training in machine learning and NLP. Great course.', 'Very less students for peer graded assignment', "It's a great course to get familiar with the key areas that concern Stratified Healthcare, Precision Medicine and biomedicine data management in general. I wish there were a specialised course on these matters!", 'Great course to get a crash course in the basics of coding applied to this field, a great beginning step that will allow you to find what you would like to specialize in.', 'A good insight on healthcare perspective of data sciences.', 'Overall a good introductory course to Data Science in Stratified Healthcare and Precisi', 'If you are starting your career with your first job as a Data Professional in a Health-Care startup/company, I would recommend you to take this course and get to know "what there is to learn" for doing data science in Health-Care.', '  Peer-graded Assignment took so long  ', ' the assignment was totally confusing. The final project had nothing to do with what was being covered in the course. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Dr S K', 'By David B', 'By Sanjog S', 'By Joao C', 'By SIJU J', 'By Khyati D A', 'By Giulio M', 'By Fatai M A', 'By Brook C M', 'By DAVID C', 'By Steph W', 'By Aditya h', 'By Jefferson D R C', 'By Khaing S T', 'By Sandeep R', 'By Surendrabikram T', 'By Carlos V', 'By Spencer H', 'By Rimjhim A', 'By David A', 'By Debayan D', 'By Gaibura A', 'By Jonathan G']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Jun 04, 2018', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'Jun 25, 2018', 'Jun 08, 2018', 'May 30, 2018', 'May 23, 2018', 'Apr 18, 2019', 'Apr 19, 2019', 'Jun 16, 2019', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Aug 17, 2018', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'May 29, 2019', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'May 06, 2018']</review_date></doc>