<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_60</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/search-engine-optimization</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Search Engine Optimization</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rebekah May</course_instructor><course_introduction>Ever wonder how major search engines such as Google, Bing and Yahoo rank your website within their searches? Or how content such as videos or local listings are shown and ranked based on what the search engine considers most relevant to users? Welcome to the world of Search Engine Optimization (SEO). This course is the first within the SEO Specialization and it is intended to give you a taste of SEO. 

You will be introduced to the foundational elements of how search engines work, how the SEO landscape has changed and what you can expect in the future. You discuss core SEO strategies and tactics used to drive more organic search results to a specific website or set of websites, as well as tactics to avoid to prevent penalization from search engines. You will also discover how to position yourself for a successful career in SEO should this subject prove interesting to you. We hope this taste of SEO, will entice you to continue through the Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Marketing</course_category><course_tag>Search Algorithm//Search Engine Optimization (SEO)//Mathematical Optimization//Semantics</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started &amp; Introduction to SEO//Evolution of SEO//Current SEO Best Practices//SEO of Today, Tomorrow and Beyond &amp; Course Wrap-Up</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction and Specialization', 'Introduction', 'Introduction to SEO', 'What You Can Expect from a Career in SEO', 'How I Got Started in SEO', 'My Role as an SEO Manager', 'Key Skills We Look for When Hiring', 'Tips for Finding a Job', 'How I Got Started in SEO', 'A Day in the Life of an SEO Professional', 'Key Skills We Look for When Hiring', 'Specific Skills Managers Want', 'Tips for Finding a Job', 'Tips for Interviewing', 'Building a Marketable Portfolio', 'Overview of In-house SEO'], ['Evolution of SEO', 'How Search Engines Work', 'History of Search Engines (1945 - 1993)', 'Advancement of Search (1993 - 2000)'], ['Current SEO Best Practices', 'Introduction to Search Engine Algorithms', 'SEO Best Practices and Ranking Factors', 'Early Algorithms: Florida, Austin, and Brandy', 'Updates: Personalized, Universal, Vince, and Caffeine', 'Panda: The Game Changer for Content', 'Cleaning Up Links with Penguin', 'Refinements: Hummingbird, Pigeon, and Mobile', 'How You Can Avoid Penalties'], ['SEO of Today, Tomorrow, and Beyond', 'Evolution of Keyword Optimization', 'Strengthening Your Keyword Strategy', 'How Does Branding Influence Website Rank?', 'Course Summary and Wrap-Up']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['An extremely well thought out and structured course. Absolutely loved all the lessons, quiz and reading material. I am motivated to continue through the rest of the courses in this specialization. ', 'I audited the course, so take that as you will, but:', "It is a good intro for somebody like myself with no background. An entire section was dedicated to getting a job in the field which wasn't useful for me. The course is also 4 years old, and while much of the reading is new, I wish it focused more on tactics and less on the history of search (another whole section). ", "I really liked how the course is able to insert someone that doesn't know anything about SEO into the right path, I been searching for a course like this a lot time ago and I'm happy to found it.", 'I think you should focus more in SEO basics and not so much in jobs, history and things like that.', 'Interesting, but too generic. Without proceeding in the following courses, this one is totally unuseful. Conversely, if you want to have a deep learning about SEO, this could be a great introduction to this wide world', 'Some interesting history on SEO. Too much on getting employed as an SEO professional.', 'A lot of unrelated information for an introduction in the 1st 2 modules.', 'Teaching Quality Is Very Low, Information is also lacked, By The Way Tutor words are not understable. ', "It's somewhat harder to learn information and retain it when the speaker is stumbling over their content. Additionally, there are ways to show SEO optimization in a more interactive way. I think this course could be improved with a more thoughtful look at the content. ", "Although informative, this course is dated... SEO courses should be updated with new information every 3 months.  Additionally, this course focuses on history and career information.. but I feel the career information should come in the 4th course for this speciality.  How would someone even know if they're interested in an SEO career before they've delved into it?", 'Lectures are far too short, and for some reason follow the "tell them what you\'re going to say, say it, then tell them what you said" approach. Yeah, not necessary when the "lecture" is only 1 minute long. The course would be 10 minutes shorter if they just did lectures like every other lecturer.', 'Course lacks real example and full of theory.  It lacks steps of what actually needs to be done to achieve SEO.', 'An evaluation is always tied to the value it provides in relation to the paid price. ', 'As a web developer, I found that I already knew about 98% of the information presented. The final 2% I could have found faster via a Google search than by watching the lectures. It was also a little strange to me that the course began with a segment on job opportunities and how to begin a career in SEO. I feel this would have made more sense after an introduction to the material.', 'Please review the transcriptions, there are mistakes.', 'Chapter 1 &amp; 2 are mainly dedicated for SEO careers. ', 'The first course in this specialize should really be called "a history of SEO." Only the week 4 material had the material that you are seeking to learn about. ', 'Outdated links and content. ', 'It provides a broad overview, but materials are not very refined and the course does not provide a good structured approach to the subject. At least it did not for me, leaving me wondering as to what next steps could be if I wanted to explore further.', None, "Unfortunately, this wasn't what I expected from the course. Maybe since I didn't take specialization but I feel that this course was too theoretical. I understand the history of SEO but I'm not confident how useful it'll be in real-life/commercial sense.", 'Great work', 'I was overwhelmed with the detailed introduction to the SEO field, market, job and history. I feel much more comfortable now and even discovered new resources for researching and learning. Awesome!', 'Great to be part of this course.............................................................................................................................']</reviews><reviewers>['By vedika j', 'By Jessa B', 'By Richard B', 'By jose t l', 'By Mónica A', 'By Michele B', 'By Christine K', 'By Ibrahim A K', 'By VIKAS T', 'By Luke G', 'By Christine O', 'By Lee M B', 'By Christine D', 'By Roberto R', 'By Halliday H', 'By Laura  T d M C', 'By Christophe V N T', 'By Elean M', 'By Brooke L', 'By Alessio T', 'By alex g m', 'By Kumar D', 'By Mouad R', 'By Andrei F C', 'By Bhupinder S G']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 18, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2017', 'Oct 29, 2017', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'May 02, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'Oct 21, 2018', 'Sep 06, 2017', 'Jul 10, 2017', 'Apr 06, 2017', 'Mar 29, 2016', 'Feb 17, 2016', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Jun 21, 2019', 'Oct 08, 2018', 'Sep 17, 2017', 'Sep 26, 2016', 'May 19, 2016', 'Feb 13, 2016', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018']</review_date></doc>