<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_247</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/enterprise-systems</course_url><course_name>Enterprise Systems</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jason Chan</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course provides you with an understanding of what Enterprise Systems (also commonly termed as Enterprise Resource Planning Systems, ERPs) are. After learning about what these systems are, we would touch upon why these systems are useful to companies, through which you would get to see the various jobs and positions that are associated with the use and deployment of ERPs. 

In this course, you would also develop an appreciation of the managerial aspects related to the selection and implementation of ERPs. Specifically, we would touch on the important points to consider when shortlisting and purchasing an ERP, the approaches taken in ERP implementation, and change management techniques to utilize when an organization is undergoing ERP implementation. At the end of this class, you will be endowed with practical knowledge that would help you to address real world business problems associated with ERP usage and implementation.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Information Technology.Support and Operations</course_category><course_tag>Management//IT Skills and Knowledge</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Minnesota</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) Fundamentals//Business Processes in ERP//Software Selection &amp; Considerations//Change Management//Course Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.1a Personal Introduction', '1.1b Introduction to Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP)', '1.1c Course Overview', '1.2 Business Process Concept', '1.3a Business Functions Part 1', '1.3b Business Functions Part 2', '1.4 A Brief History of SAP'], ['2.1a Companies and Business Processes', '2.1b Procurement Process', '2.1c Production Process', '2.1d Business Fulfillment Process', '2.2 Sales Organization', '2.3 Master Data', '2.4 Example Fulfillment Process'], ['3.1a ERP Selection Process Part 1', '3.1b ERP Selection Process Part 2', '3.1c ERP Selection Process Part 3', '3.2 Magic Quadrant Tool', '3.3 ERP Module Possibilities'], ['4.1 ERP Implementation Considerations', '4.2 Defending Against Pitfalls', '4.3a ERP Implementation Best Practices Part 1', '4.3b ERP Implementation Best Practices Part 2', '4.4 ERP Implementation Partner Considerations'], ['Project Overview']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course is very interesting and there is lot to learn about this course.', 'I enjoyed this course. Prior to this course, I had not prior knowledge of ERP and it developed my knowledge on Enterprise systems', 'Very good course, come expecting to learn and take good notes. ', 'Good intro course. About 4 hours of video and some quizes.', 'Super', 'very helpful', 'Thank you very much for the guidance. All the lectures were very clear and informative.', 'Very good organized and valued information.', 'Great content with real life and real business examples which help us to see and find out how this works in the professional world', 'Presentation was good and enough as a beginner.', 'good introduction for getting to know and understand ERP systems', "Course was very lightly attended, it took a full 3 weeks to get feedback on my submission, but that wasn't really the problem.", 'The course itself is rather shallow with only superficial info on ERP systems. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nareddy S S ', 'By Inemi E S', 'By Philaundre T', 'By Vladimir T', 'By P S 1', 'By RAHUL J', 'By Bamunusinhage K T S', 'By Basem B S', 'By Juan E R L', 'By Abdullah H S', 'By Lennart P', 'By Kevin G', 'By Marcel H']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 15, 2019', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Oct 22, 2018', 'Apr 07, 2019', 'Jun 09, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jul 12, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Dec 25, 2018']</review_date></doc>