<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_281</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/simple-regression-analysis-public-health</course_url><course_name>Simple Regression Analysis in Public Health</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>John McGready, PhD, MS</course_instructor><course_introduction>Biostatistics is the application of statistical reasoning to the life sciences, and it's the key to unlocking the data gathered by researchers and the evidence presented in the scientific public health literature. In this course, we'll focus on the use of simple regression methods to determine the relationship between an outcome of interest and a single predictor via a linear equation. Along the way, you'll be introduced to a variety of methods, and you'll practice interpreting data and performing calculations on real data from published studies.  Topics include logistic regression, confidence intervals, p-values, Cox regression, confounding, adjustment, and effect modification.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>P-Value//Proportional Hazards Model//Confounding//regression</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Simple Regression Methods//Simple Logistic Regression//Simple Cox Proportional Hazards Regression//Confounding, Adjustment, and Effect Modification//Course Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Simple Regression: An Overview', 'Simple Linear Regression with a Binary (or Nominal Categorical) Predictor', 'Simple Linear Regression with a Categorical Predictor', 'Simple Linear Regression with a Continuous Predictor', 'Simple Linear Regression Model: Estimating the Regression Equation—Accounting for Uncertainty in the Estimates', 'Measuring the Strength of a Linear Association', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'Simple Logistic Regression: An Overview', 'Simple Logistic Regression with a Binary (or Categorical) Predictor', 'Simple Logistic Regression: Accounting for Uncertainty in the Estimates', 'Estimating Risk and Functions of Risk from Logistic Regression Results', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'Simple Cox Regression: An Overview', 'Simple Cox Regression with a Binary (or Categorical) Predictor', 'Simple Cox Regression with a Continuous Predictor', 'Simple Cox Regression: Accounting for Uncertainty in the Estimates', 'Estimating Survival Curves from Cox Regression Results', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'Confounding: A Formal Definition and Some Examples', 'Adjusted Estimates: Presentation, Interpretation, and Utility for Assessing Confounding', 'Adjusted Estimates: The General Idea Behind the Computations', 'Additional Examples', 'Effect modification: Introduction with an analytic example', 'Effect modification: Tree damage and elevation example', 'Effect modification: Examples from the literature', 'Confounding versus effect modification: A review', 'Additional examples'], ['Biostatistical Consulting Project']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent course - ', 'Very practical course. The tutor makes complex concepts seem easy.', 'I would like to thank the instructor. Sir, you have explained everything so well and clearly step by step. It has been very helpful', 'The Question and Answer section needs a few corrections, some incorrect answers are marked as correct. Simple linear regression analysis with continuous predictor is missing and the one for logistic regression in used its place.', 'Great course!  The organization and explanations were a little confusing for this course and the exams compared to the others.  Despite this, I learned a lot of useful information and appreciate the effort and organization dedicated to helping students learn the material.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mohammed S U', 'By Ulrick S K K', 'By Sutopa T', 'By Anurag M', 'By Cassandra N']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 13, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Aug 28, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>