<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_1</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/neural-networks-deep-learning</course_url><course_name>Neural Networks and Deep Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Andrew Ng</course_instructor><course_introduction>If you want to break into cutting-edge AI, this course will help you do so. Deep learning engineers are highly sought after, and mastering deep learning will give you numerous new career opportunities. Deep learning is also a new "superpower" that will let you build AI systems that just weren't possible a few years ago. 

In this course, you will learn the foundations of deep learning. When you finish this class, you will:
- Understand the major technology trends driving Deep Learning
- Be able to build, train and apply fully connected deep neural networks 
- Know how to implement efficient (vectorized) neural networks 
- Understand the key parameters in a neural network's architecture 

This course also teaches you how Deep Learning actually works, rather than presenting only a cursory or surface-level description. So after completing it, you will be able to apply deep learning to a your own applications. If you are looking for a job in AI, after this course you will also be able to answer basic interview questions. 

This is the first course of the Deep Learning Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Artificial Neural Network//Backpropagation//Python Programming//Deep Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>deeplearning.ai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to deep learning//Neural Networks Basics//Shallow neural networks//Deep Neural Networks</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'What is a neural network?', 'Supervised Learning with Neural Networks', 'Why is Deep Learning taking off?', 'About this Course', 'Course Resources', 'Geoffrey Hinton interview'], ['Binary Classification', 'Logistic Regression', 'Logistic Regression Cost Function', 'Gradient Descent', 'Derivatives', 'More Derivative Examples', 'Computation graph', 'Derivatives with a Computation Graph', 'Logistic Regression Gradient Descent', 'Gradient Descent on m Examples', 'Vectorization', 'More Vectorization Examples', 'Vectorizing Logistic Regression', "Vectorizing Logistic Regression's Gradient Output", 'Broadcasting in Python', 'A note on python/numpy vectors', 'Quick tour of Jupyter/iPython Notebooks', 'Explanation of logistic regression cost function (optional)', 'Pieter Abbeel interview'], ['Neural Networks Overview', 'Neural Network Representation', "Computing a Neural Network's Output", 'Vectorizing across multiple examples', 'Explanation for Vectorized Implementation', 'Activation functions', 'Why do you need non-linear activation functions?', 'Derivatives of activation functions', 'Gradient descent for Neural Networks', 'Backpropagation intuition (optional)', 'Random Initialization', 'Ian Goodfellow interview'], ['Deep L-layer neural network', 'Forward Propagation in a Deep Network', 'Getting your matrix dimensions right', 'Why deep representations?', 'Building blocks of deep neural networks', 'Forward and Backward Propagation', 'Parameters vs Hyperparameters', 'What does this have to do with the brain?']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I enjoyed the lectures and a few practice quiz. But I don't think the structure of assignments presented here is the correct way to assess learning. The assignments or exercises should be interspersed between lectures and the problems should be more interactive (pushing the student to think). Moreover, the amount of pre-written code was immense and therefore didn't really make me think a lot on my own. This structure of assignment forces the student to focus on matching the expected output instead of really understanding the concept.  I am pretty sure most students did not really grasp the concepts at an intellectual level but still passed with decent grades. This is exactly the problem with schools today and I hope that Coursera is working towards rectifying that. ", "The course expands on the neural network portion of Andrew Ng's original Machine Learning course, but ported over to Python. Even though it is spread out over 4 weeks, it really doesn't cover any additional material. Instead, Ng repetitively goes over the math and coding with vectors in Python, while stressing how hard the calculus derivation would be. This might all be helpful to you if calculus was not your strong suit, but my guess is that if you have any kind of background in computer science or statistics, the math in this course would be almost elementary. ", 'I felt the assignments are more of a fill in the blanks, than using brain. There was not much of a challenge considering my Scala certification', 'too easy to pass (the code needed for the assignments is even presented during the lecture)', 'Lectures a good. The programming assignments are too simple, with most of the code already written for you, so you only have to add in very similar one-line numpy calculations, or calls of previous helper functions. I would learn more if the programming part was harder. ', "I'm very dissapointed, all what taught here is also on the Andrew Ng's Machine Learning course. The sole difference is that here python is used and that the exercises are extremely easy, you almost have not to think. And even they give an approx of lines of code you have to write which are no more than 4 and if that threshold is surpassed is because you have to copy &amp; paste same thing with different variables names. ", "This is a good course with good explanation but the only problem with this course is that it covers so much information all at once during the entire week and then there is just literally one or two programming assignment at the end. There should be exercise questions after every video to apply those skills taught in theory into programming. I now know general concept of deep learning but I still barely have a clue on how to code those concepts. If I wanted to code all that myself I still wouldn't even know where to start, where to get the data etc etc because the programming assignments were  just, now write this, now write that. Also there should be a help button where mentors should be available because we have tons of questions after learning a new concept. We cant just type all questions in the discussions forum and then then wait till someone replies and then that question gets lost among the pile of other questions. Especially in programming assignments when we get stuck and then dont have a clue what to do now. For $50 a month, the teaching structure is really poor. Even khan academy has a much better educational structure. and its all free too.  I am a college student with a part time job and I am contributing 70% of my earnings towards this course because my future depends on it.", 'Course  targets very slow learners. Professor repeats same stuff again and again and again, basically for 4 weeks we learn how to calculate the same things  (front-back propagations and cost function).  Programmings assignments are incredibly easy, all solutions are made by authors, you just write in code what they described in notes. 1-2 lines here and there.', 'Very good course to start Deep learning. But you need to have the basic idea first. I would suggest to do the Stanford Andrew Ng Machine Learning course first and then take this specialization courses', None, "This course was a hot mess.  Andrew Ng seemed to lose his train of thought in some of the lectures, and he would repeat himself and just say nonsense sometimes. There were a bunch of errors in the quizzes and the assignments were confusing at times.  On the whole, this was not up the the standard of Andrew Ng's old ML class.  I did continue with this series of courses anyway, and I noticed a marked improvement in the quality of the second course, so its possible that they cleaned up the first one in the time since I took it.", 'This is really a very good introductory course for people from various background. The assignments are also nicely designed to give an insight to how things works. ', "If you are already used to Python/numpy and you followed the free Machine Learning course from Ng, you really won't learn anything, apart from a new activation function.", 'Coding Exercise Were quite simple, a full length assignment  would have been better.', 'What a great course. I was expecting this to be more of an introduction to using Tensorflow and high level introduction to neural networks. Instead it is an incredibly well explained introduction to how to build your own neural network (in python) and implement it on some sample data. This really gives you a good grounding in what a neural network is doing (at least implementation wise) and a good foundation to build on. I am sure later courses in the specialization cover use of Tensorflow (maybe keras?) but I can see how this course enables you to understand what is going on under the hood of all these toolsets. He has a great ability to explain what could be very complicated ideas simply and layout what could be convoluted coding sequences in a very well organised and concise manner. I will recommenced this  course to anyone starting out with either the intention to go into data science (using algorithms) or machine learning (building your own algorithms).', "I have learnt a lot of tricks with numpy and I believe I have a better understanding of what a NN does. Now it does not look like a black box anymore. I look forward to see what's in the next courses!", 'Nothing can get better than this course from Professor Andrew Ng. A must for every Data science enthusiast. Gets you up to speed right from the fundamentals. Thanks a lot for Prof Andrew and his team.', 'Dear Andrew! Thank you so very much for making me belive in myself as a machine learning engineer. Your lectures &amp; excercises are like "shoulders of Giants" on which a good student can stand out high.', 'not satisfied', 'Programming assignment is too simple', 'Very basic level', "The lectures and assignments are extremely shallow, unengaging and poorly edited and recorded. Andrew Ng is riding the waves of the popularity of his ML course. I regret every dollar and minute I wasted on this crap. DON'T ENROLL DO YOURSELF A FAVOR GO READ A BOOK!", 'Too easy', 'This is a good review of the concepts. It helped even more once I finished the course and reflected on the material by working out the equations for back propagation by my own hand. Looking forward to the next course in the series.', "A bit easy (python wise) but maybe that's just a reflection of personal experience / practice. The contest is easy to digest (week to week) and the intuitions are well thought of in their explanation."]</reviews><reviewers>['By vatsal m', 'By Jonathan C', 'By Mageswaran D', 'By Martin P', 'By oli c', 'By Nicolás A G', 'By Mohammad S B H', 'By Nikolay B', 'By Md. N H', 'By Johan W', 'By Alan S', 'By Deven P', 'By Antoine C', 'By Parth S', 'By John A', 'By Giovanni D C', 'By Sameer K', 'By Serge G', 'By Niloufar Y', 'By nikcojeanian', 'By Mohammad G H', 'By Jonathan C', 'By Ashkan A e A', 'By Nikhil D K', 'By Leon V']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 14, 2017', 'Aug 20, 2017', 'Nov 09, 2017', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Apr 28, 2019', 'Oct 26, 2017', 'Jun 30, 2018', 'Oct 10, 2017', 'Oct 28, 2017', 'May 14, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2018', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'May 31, 2019', 'Aug 30, 2018', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2017', 'Oct 01, 2018', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'May 12, 2019', 'Apr 07, 2019']</review_date></doc>