<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_223</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/dataviz-project</course_url><course_name>Data Visualization with Tableau Project</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Suk S. Brar, M.B.A.</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this project-based course, you will follow your own interests to create a portfolio worthy single-frame viz or multi-frame data story that will be shared on Tableau Public. You will use all the skills taught in this Specialization to complete this project step-by-step, with guidance from your instructors along the way. You will first create a project proposal to identify your goals for the project, including the question you wish to answer or explore with data. You will then find data that will provide the information you are seeking. You will then import that data into Tableau and  prepare it for analysis. Next you will create a dashboard that will allow you to explore the data in depth and identify meaningful insights. You will then give structure to your data story by writing the story arc in narrative form. Finally, you will consult your design checklist to craft the final viz or data story in Tableau. This is your opportunity to show the world what you’re capable of - so think big, and have confidence in your skills!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Interactive Visualization//Tableau Software//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started and Milestone 1: Develop a Project Proposal//Milestone 2: Importing and Prepping the Data//Milestone 3: Exploratory Analysis//Milestone 3: Exploratory Analysis and Dashboard Submission//Milestone 4: Storytelling and Storyboarding//Milestone 5: Final Presentation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Project Welcome', 'Milestone 1 Assignment Overview'], ['Milestone 2 Assignment Overview'], ['Milestone 3 Assignment Overview'], ['Key Metrics, Indicators, Decision Triggers', 'Dashboard and Storytelling with Data'], ['Milestone 4 Assignment Overview'], ['Milestone 5 Assignment Overview', 'Project Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Love the fact that course loaded with project assignments.  I'm deduct 1 star because it doesn't allow me to proceed ahead of schedule.  This course is only available about 4-5 times per year, I started on 5/20 and completed week 1 assignment on 5/22, but have to wait till 6/11 to ", 'I expected the Capstone Project to be very different. In particular, I expected to have less freedom in choosing the project.', "While I think its great students get more practice with Tableau and storyboarding, no new material is presented in this course, and there's zero instructor involvement (everything is peer reviewed).  ", 'This course was fun and full of helpful tips.', "Great End to a Great Specialization. I couldn't recommend this more to someone wanting to start with Tableau.", 'great content ever had on online. I love this course very much because this course helped me to make how to make story with a data. Thank you coursera. Keep it up!.', 'The final project was a great way to bring all the different concepts of the specialization together. I really enjoyed it. ', 'Excellent Basics and Information', 'Excellent course!', 'Project Base Course', 'Great course on data visualization fundamentals. That we got to apply them in Tableau is even better. Would love to see this team do a similar course for an open source viz software like RShiny or Pentaho.', 'Great capstone project to practise your Tableau skillset on. Definitely worth it!', 'My name is Jose Antonio from Brazil. I am looking for a new Data Scientist career (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseantonio11).', 'Very informative', 'This a chance for  you to practice a visualization project by Tableau with full flow. Because it is a chance, so let do it as good as possible for your mastering.', 'An excellent course yet again from Coursera!', 'Great course and specialization over all, thanks!', 'Excellent!!!!', 'Good learning experience ', 'Good round up for the Specialisation', 'I wish there had been professional feedback on our submissions- even if it was just the final one. However, great course overall.', 'Data Visualization with Tableau Project, excellent course.  ', 'The course in itself is good but the peer review part is not very satisfactory. Some reviewers do not understand the lessons and review questions well and provides incorrect reviews.', 'This is the last of the Data Visualization with Tableau, which summarizes all sections of the course.', "There is almost no instruction in this course. You just prepare a project and review what other people did. I don't like it because there are some technical mistakes, such as in the last milestone they ask you to submit a project proposal but do not provide any space where you can post a link. No involvement from course staff, either. "]</reviews><reviewers>['By Wei W', 'By Luca N', 'By Mark A', 'By Bill H', 'By Maksym M', 'By SAYANTA S R', 'By Jessica R', 'By Garvish', 'By Brian T', 'By Behring B', 'By Amy B', 'By Ananya N', 'By Jose A R N', 'By Manikanta  L', 'By Nhan T N', 'By Avijeet S', 'By Ricardo T V', 'By Cristiano S', 'By Ajith K', 'By Craig S', 'By Lindsey R', 'By Irvin Y D M', 'By Amrita G', 'By Sebastian', 'By Svetlana L']</reviewers><review_date>['May 22, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2017', 'Apr 05, 2018', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2018', 'Sep 13, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Jul 31, 2017', 'Aug 13, 2017', 'Nov 06, 2017', 'Mar 31, 2018', 'May 30, 2017', 'Sep 19, 2018', 'Jul 23, 2018', 'Jun 13, 2019', 'May 27, 2019', 'May 30, 2019', 'May 17, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2018', 'Apr 26, 2018', 'Sep 13, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2018', 'Aug 15, 2017', 'Aug 17, 2017']</review_date></doc>