<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_426</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/genomic-data-science-project</course_url><course_name>Genomic Data Science Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this culminating project, you will deploy the tools and techniques that you've mastered over the course of the specialization. You'll work with a real data set to perform analyses and prepare a report of your findings.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Introduction to the Dataset - Andrew Jaffe//Understand the Problem//Alignment//QC the Alignment//Get Feature Counts //Exploratory Analysis //Statistical Analysis//Gene Set Analysis//Describe Your Analysis </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the Capstone - Kasper Hansen'], ['The Dataset - Andrew Jaffe'], ['The Results - Andrew Jaffe'], ['$null$'], ['$null$'], ['$null$'], ['$null$'], ['$null$'], ['$null$'], ['$null$']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['An excellent challenge.  Previous courses everything was neatly packaged before you start.  This course teaches you how to get there.', "Great course! I can't think of a better way of putting together all we learned during the whole specialisation in one real world research project...", 'Really practical project in the genomics field!', 'Excellent set of assignments to apply multiple tools used in the specialization!', None, 'By conducting the capstone project, I applied essential concepts and tools to analyse genomic data in order to understand interesting biological processes. The tasks were well designed and explained. The peers in this learning community were ver supportive. After taking this specialization, I feel confident in integrating genomic and transcriptomic  data analysis into my plant biological research. THANK YOU!', 'Good application of the learnt techniques.', 'good way of wrapping up everything we learned in the specialization :) ', None, None, 'No clear explain about which is the right dataset to be downloaded, no support from instructors about that on discussion forum.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Paul S', 'By Fabio M R A', 'By Chengran Y', 'By Luis F R C', 'By Shah M T K', 'By Hao X', 'By Thodoris S', 'By Francia V D L R', 'By David N', 'By Jacob S', 'By Alberto T']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 20, 2018', 'Jul 24, 2016', 'Feb 27, 2017', 'Feb 13, 2017', 'Dec 19, 2016', 'Nov 20, 2016', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2018', 'May 11, 2017', 'Jun 06, 2016', 'Jun 24, 2016']</review_date></doc>