<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_187</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/supply-chain-analytics-essentials</course_url><course_name>Supply Chain Analytics Essentials</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Yao Zhao</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Supply Chain Analytics - an exciting and emerging area that is in high demand! 

In this introductory course to Supply Chain Analytics, I will take you on a journey to this fascinating area of Supply chain analytics where supply chain management meets data analytics. You will learn real life stories and examples on how analytics can apply to various domains of a supply chain, from sell, to move, make and source, to generate a significant social and / or economic impact. You will also learn about job market trend, job requirement and preparation. Lastly, you will master a data analysis technique to assess the efficiency of a supply chain. Supply Chain Analytics is a relatively new and fast developing area. Thus this course is by no mean exhaustive nor should you expect to be an expert upon completion. My goal of this course is to open the eyes of the learners to the impact of Supply Chain Analytics, and hopefully this will encourage you to learn more.

Upon completing this course, you will

1. Understand why analytics is critical to today’s supply chains
2. See the pain points of a supply chain and how analytics can be applied to address them
3. Understand the requirement of supply chain analytics jobs, and how to prepare for them
4. Assess a company’s overall supply chain efficiency quantitatively

I hope you enjoy the course!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Supply Chain Analytics//Job Analysis//Supply Chain//Supply Chain Efficiency Assessment</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rutgers the State University of New Jersey</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome!//Supply Chain Analytics Essentials//Cash Cycle to Measure Supply Chain Efficiency//Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Why Supply Chain Analytics?', 'My Journey in Supply Chain Analytics', 'What Is Supply Chain Management?', 'K-Mart vs Wal-Mart; Compaq vs. Dell', 'Wal-Mart vs. Amazon', 'Analytics Is Critical To Supply Chain Management'], ['Supply Chain Domains', 'Demand Planning', 'Product Selection, Pricing &amp; Promotion', 'Fulfillment Diagnostics', 'Distribution &amp; Logistics Planning', 'Transportation Management', 'Production Planning, Workforce Management', 'Inventory Management', 'Strategic Sourcing, Supplier Management', 'Order Management', 'Supply Chain Analytics - Job Opportunities, Requirement &amp; Preparation'], ['The Chain Effect', 'Inventory Measures', "Little's Law Implications", 'Cash Conversion Cycle Calculation &amp; Implications'], ['Wal-Mart vs. Amazon - A Step-by-Step Calculation', 'Cash Conversion Cycle Screencast', 'Project Description: Apple vs. Samsung']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['suggest to have in depth of each sub areas  of supply chain and talk about the problems in those subareas', 'Great course, very useful . The professor`s way of teaching this course is amazingly simple', 'This course is a good overview of supply chain domains and analytics with real-life examples.', 'An inspiring course. This course introduces quantitative models and tools to efficiently manage operations that produce and distribute products and services, with applications in manufacturing, logistics and service industries. The only advice I may give is the assignment could be a bit more complicated than what the video teaches.', 'Hi, my name is Nidhi and I have just entered the industry right out of undergrad. Currently, I am pursuing my Masters in Supply Chain Analytics. I am working in the financial services doing operations. I believe that this course has expanded my knowledge about supply chain analytics. I really liked the real life examples that these videos provided. They gave insight about how different industries relate to supply chain and use real time data to show the concepts.  ', "It's a fascinating journey to learn about this course because it introduces an area of Supply chain analytics where supply chain management meets data analytics! By combing real life stories and examples on how analytics can apply to various domains of a supply chain to generate a significant social and economic impact (the amazon and Walmart case), I got a deep understanding about how analytics works in supply chain industry. I strongly recommend this course to all people who are interested in data analyze and supply chain.", 'It is a very good course to understand the basics of the supply chain analytics.', 'Short, Crisp videos for conceptual understanding of the application and importance of Supply Chain Analytics in businesses. And some great case examples and problems to work upon!', 'Nice overview! This course strengthened my interest in Supply Chain Analytics and I will continue learning within this field!', 'It is a useful and easy understandable course!', 'This a very good course, recommend people with Supply Chain or Data background to take this. A huge boost for your career.', None, 'This course is very helpful for me to understand supply chain analytics and development trend of supply chain work in the future. From learning this course, I could have much more preparation for my career from now.', 'Very Basic and helpful course', 'The course is very helpful. I got a lot from the 4-week course. I really enjoy the videos and the assignments. Also glad that the professor includes the job market of supply chain analytics in the course. It was very interesting.', 'This is the best course that one can afford to learn it to know what is analytics and how it can be applied to the supply chain. Professor was soo good in explaining and every time when he states a real-life example you get in attached to the subject and this will excite you to focus.', 'Excellent Course Content, to the point and very interesting', 'The course was good and gave all the necessary information regarding Supply Chain Analytics', ' A lot of knowledge, from the fundamental to the highest level I can grab from this course about the supply chain analytics.  I really recommended to all the beginners out there. Thank you so much Cousera ', None, 'Quick course on core concepts, clearly explained with good examples. ', 'Was helpful overall.', 'While the course was fruitful, I was expecting some more deep dive into analytics techniques which was lacking. I believe there would be a separate advanced supply chain analytics course which I can pursue.', 'Very basic content about supply chain management. Huge overlapping content with financial statement analysis for accounting students. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By G.S.S. B R', 'By Sami S A', 'By Zhe G', 'By Mingqian Z', 'By Nidhi L', 'By nightoak', 'By Abhinav B', 'By Prabal G', 'By Thomas L', 'By JIAORONG L', 'By Binyu C', 'By Lisa L', 'By Yalin F', 'By Ravin S N S', 'By Yin H C', 'By Chaithanya R', 'By Anmol B K', 'By Deepak G', 'By Siti H H A', 'By akash k', 'By Jim H', 'By SAPTARSHI M', 'By Raenoj I', 'By Yue L']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Oct 25, 2018', 'Oct 25, 2018', 'Oct 28, 2018', 'Nov 05, 2018', 'May 07, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'Jul 16, 2019', 'Jul 28, 2019', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'May 17, 2019', 'May 07, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Sep 04, 2019']</review_date></doc>