<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_313</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/advanced-methods-reinforcement-learning-finance</course_url><course_name>Overview of Advanced Methods of Reinforcement Learning in Finance</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Igor Halperin</course_instructor><course_introduction>In the last course of our specialization, Overview of Advanced Methods of Reinforcement Learning in Finance, we will take a deeper look into topics discussed in our third course, Reinforcement Learning in Finance.

In particular, we will talk about links between Reinforcement Learning, option pricing and physics, implications of Inverse Reinforcement Learning for modeling market impact and price dynamics, and perception-action cycles in Reinforcement Learning. Finally, we will overview trending and potential applications of Reinforcement Learning for high-frequency trading, cryptocurrencies, peer-to-peer lending, and more.

After taking this course, students will be able to 
- explain fundamental concepts of finance such as market equilibrium, no arbitrage, predictability,
- discuss market modeling,
- Apply the methods of Reinforcement Learning to high-frequency trading, credit risk peer-to-peer lending, and cryptocurrencies trading.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Algorithms</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>New York University Tandon School of Engineering</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Black-Scholes-Merton model, Physics and Reinforcement Learning//Reinforcement Learning for Optimal Trading and Market Modeling//Perception - Beyond Reinforcement Learning//Other Applications of Reinforcement Learning: P-2-P Lending, Cryptocurrency, etc.</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Specialization', 'Specialization Prerequisites', 'Interview with Rossen Roussev', "Reinforcement Learning and Ptolemy's Epicycles", 'PDEs in Physics and Finance', 'Competitive Market Equilibrium Models in Finance', 'I Certainly Hope You Are Wrong, Herr Professor!', 'Risk as a Science of Fluctuation', 'Markets and the Heat Death of the Universe', 'Option Trading and RL', 'Liquidity', 'Modeling Market Frictions', 'Modeling Feedback Frictions'], ['From Portfolio Optimization to Market Model', 'Invisible Hand', 'GBM and Its Problems', 'The GBM Model: An Unbounded Growth Without Defaults', 'Dynamics with Saturation: The Verhulst Model', 'The Singularity is Near', 'What are Defaults?', 'Quantum Equilibrium-Disequilibrium'], ['Welcome!!', 'Market Dynamics and IRL', 'Diffusion in a Potential: The Langevin Equation', 'Classical Dynamics', "Potential Minima and Newton's Law", 'Classical Dynamics: the Lagrangian and the Hamiltonian', 'Langevin Equation and Fokker-Planck Equations', 'The Fokker-Planck Equation and Quantum Mechanics'], ['Welcome!!', 'Electronic Markets and LOB', 'Trades, Quotes and Order Flow', 'Limit Order Book', 'LOB Modeling', 'LOB Statistical Modeling', 'LOB Modeling with ML and RL', 'Other Applications of RL', 'The Value of Universatility']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent course!!!', 'Interesting deep dive into a RL application in Finance at forefront of research, however be prepared for challenging project assignments with limited support or guidance. Not for the fainthearted.', 'Assessments are once again out of touch with the materials that have been presented and do not reflect any practical uses you may need to work on in the industry. Skip this certificate until fixed. ', 'No real follow up by the team, and the assignments have nothing to do with the classes.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Rodrigo A d S', 'By Niklas O', 'By Teemu P', 'By Matthieu B']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 01, 2019', 'Oct 15, 2018', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Sep 29, 2018']</review_date></doc>