<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_497</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/complete-reinforcement-learning-system</course_url><course_name>A Complete Reinforcement Learning System (Capstone)</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Martha White</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this final course, you will put together your knowledge from Courses 1, 2 and 3 to implement a complete RL solution to a problem. This capstone will let you see how each component---problem formulation, algorithm selection, parameter selection and representation design---fits together into a complete solution, and how to make appropriate choices when deploying RL in the real world. This project will require you to implement both the environment to stimulate your problem, and a control agent with Neural Network function approximation. In addition, you will conduct a scientific study of your learning system to develop your ability to assess the robustness of RL agents. To use RL in the real world, it is critical to (a) appropriately formalize the problem as an MDP, (b) select appropriate algorithms, (c ) identify what choices in your implementation will have large impacts on performance and (d) validate the expected behaviour of your algorithms. This capstone is valuable for anyone who is planning on using RL to solve real problems.

By the end of this course, you will be able to: 

Complete an RL solution to a problem, starting from problem formulation, appropriate algorithm selection and implementation and empirical study into the effectiveness of the solution.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Artificial Intelligence (AI)//Machine Learning//Reinforcement Learning//Function Approximation//Intelligent Systems</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>University of Alberta</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Milestone 1: Formalize Word Problem as MDP//Milestone 2: Choosing The Right Algorithm//Milestone 3: Identify Key Performance Parameters//Milestone 4: Implement Your Agent //Milestone 5: Submit Your Parameter Study!</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Weekly reading'], ['Weekly Reading'], ['Weekly Reading'], ['Weekly Reading'], ['Weekly reading']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[]</reviews><reviewers>[]</reviewers><review_date>[]</review_date></doc>