<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_331</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/causal-effects</course_url><course_name>Measuring Causal Effects in the Social Sciences</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Anders Holm</course_instructor><course_introduction>How can we know if the differences in wages between men and women are caused by discrimination or differences in background characteristics? In this PhD-level course we look at causal effects as opposed to spurious relationships. We will discuss how they can be identified in the social sciences using quantitative data, and describe how this can help us understand social mechanisms.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Social Sciences.Governance and Society</course_category><course_tag>Difference In Differences//Instrumental Variable//Causal Inference//Causality</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Copenhagen</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Nature of Causal Effects and How to Measure Them//The Multivariate Regression Model and Mediating Factors//Randomized Controlled Trials//Instrumental Variables//Difference in Difference</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Lecture 1 - The Nature of Causal Effects and How to Measure Them '], ['Lecture 2 - The Multivariate Regression Model and Mediating Factors'], ['Lecture 3 - Randomized Controlled Trials '], ['Lecture 4 - Instrumental Variables'], ['Lecture 5 - Difference in Difference']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This course makes clear distinction between different approaches to causality with nice graphics. That's good. But my feeling is that it uses explanation methods which are easy to understand only for those... who are already familiar with IV &amp; DID. It's easy to find on the web more straight forward explanations on the web, yet still statistically rigorous.", 'Lecturer extremely difficult to follow. Quiz questions required remembering numbers (!) from weeks earlier. In general a course based on good ideas, all missed in really bad execution of the course.', "Unfortunately this course consists of the Professor reading his notes very quickly with rapid listing of concepts and very little time spent explaining complex topics. The quizzes emphasize the terms for various elements of the analysis rather than teaching how to work with the tools to analyze data. There does not seem to be anyone monitoring the course forum and mistakes in quiz questions and questions asked on the forum are not answered or replied to by anyone. I was committed to working with the course but by week 4 it was unfortunately impossible to absorb and there was no way to interact with anyone to get help. I'm sure there is room for improvement on this course and I hope the instructor does work to improve with the course, but currently the course is disappointing as a learning experience.", 'Good course with good explanation. But request please use a whiteboard instead of chalkboard in the background as the chalkboard becomes difficult to read on mobile devices. Some explanations can be augmented with additional reading ', 'Great material to review causal inference concepts.', 'Very useful course for people doing measurements in social sciences.', 'This is a great course for people working in evaluating  different social projects. Improved my insights a lot!', 'I found it enlightening. It surely clarifies the concept of causality.', 'Very good short time course, highly recommended.', 'The Professor has interpreted the course very detailed and thoroughly in terms of key methodologies and formulas. He also gave concrete examples and database to help me understand the theoretical knowledge. The quiz after each course are very helpful to understand new concepts and data implications in the examples. The only flaw might be too fast and not clear pronunciation of the instructor. Also, this is the only course about Impact Evaluation (i.e. RCT, IV, Diff-in-Diff) provided in Coursera. I hope there will be other similar courses available in Coursera!', 'This is an useful course for medical researchs even though you can apply to other social science.', 'Very good course!', "Great course! I finally understood the relation between RCT's, Instrumental Variables and DiDs. The prior suggested readings helped a lot, and the classes were very well conducted with intuitive explanations before the formal derivations that were also very helpful. ", 'Very easy and intuitive', 'Отличный, специальный курс. Доступный но требует базовых знаний!', 'The course was well structured and helped to identify different approaches used to measure causality. Overall a well designed course.', 'Quite fundamental and basic stuff for causal inference, but it is a good start.', 'The course covers many important topics with good examples but could have been longer and more detailed about various assumptions and their violations. The accent of the instructor and many algebraic notations are diificult to understand for non-mathematicians or non-statisticians like myself.', 'Good course that takes participants from linear regression to RCT and approaches for causal inference in observational data. Four stars are given as some of the quizes include questions on specific estimates from lectures instead of more general aspects.', None, 'The course is great. Although it is really fast and requires some advanced understanding of algebra and statistics, it is not bad. However, I would reccommend to expand it and to include the advances in non-manipulative causation, as sustained by proff. J. Pearl and F. Squazzoni (specifically talking about sociology).', 'Material is good', 'Very good course! I learned a lot. I missed readings and other complementary material.', 'Throughout this course, I could deepen my understanding on practical use of statistics for social siceinces. Its simple mathematical proof on estimations methods is useful for practitioners', 'Very fast and standard way of sharing knowledge. Easy to understand but diffcicult to digest. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Tomasz J', 'By irene k', 'By Lisa D', 'By Rohit V K', 'By Vidya B R', 'By Sixtus A', 'By niladri s b', 'By Olawoyin G A', 'By Jie F', 'By Sophie W', 'By Eugenio D F', 'By Monika B', 'By Aureliano A B', 'By Lucas B', 'By Кулиев Н С', 'By Aysha R ', 'By Junxiong Y', 'By DR A N', 'By Tarjei W', 'By pureum k', 'By Diego P', 'By Venu R', 'By Carlos A S', 'By ryohasegawa', 'By Dursun D']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 05, 2018', 'Jun 30, 2017', 'Mar 09, 2017', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2017', 'Dec 16, 2016', 'May 16, 2018', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'Jul 16, 2019', 'Sep 11, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2017', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2016', 'Mar 02, 2017', 'Jul 25, 2016', 'Jul 18, 2017', 'Apr 21, 2018', 'Jan 21, 2019']</review_date></doc>