<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_138</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/advanced-machine-learning-signal-processing</course_url><course_name>Advanced Machine Learning and Signal Processing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Romeo Kienzler</course_instructor><course_introduction>&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this course you agree to the End User License Agreement as set out in the FAQ.  Once enrolled you can access the license in the Resources area &lt;&lt;&lt;

This course, Advanced Machine Learning and Signal Processing, is part of the IBM Advanced Data Science Specialization which IBM is currently creating and gives you easy access to the invaluable insights into Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning Models used by experts in many field relevant disciplines. We’ll learn about the fundamentals of Linear Algebra to understand how machine learning modes work. Then we introduce the most popular Machine Learning Frameworks for python Scikit-Learn and SparkML. SparkML is making up the greatest portion of this course since scalability is key to address performance bottlenecks. We learn how to tune the models in parallel by evaluating hundreds of different parameter-combinations in parallel. We’ll continuously use a real-life example from IoT (Internet of Things), for exemplifying the different algorithms. For passing the course you are even required to create your own vibration sensor data using the accelerometer sensors in your smartphone. So you are actually working on a self-created, real dataset throughout the course.

If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you will also earn an IBM digital badge.  To find out more about IBM digital badges follow the link ibm.biz/badging.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Setting the stage//Supervised Machine Learning//Unsupervised Machine Learning//Digital Signal Processing in Machine Learning</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['A warm welcome', 'Linear algebra', 'High Dimensional Vector Spaces', 'Supervised vs. Unsupervised Machine Learning', 'How ML Pipelines work', 'Introduction to SparkML', 'What is SystemML (1/2) ?', 'What is SystemML (2/2) ?', 'How to use Apache SystemML in IBM Watson Studio', 'Extract - Transform - Load'], ['Linear Regression', 'LinearRegression with Apache SparkML', 'Linear Regression using Apache SystemML', 'Batch Gradient Descent using Apache SystemML', 'The importance of validation data to prevent overfitting', 'Important evaluation measures', 'Logistic Regression', 'LogisticRegression with Apache SparkML', 'Probabilities refresher', "Rules of probability and Bayes' theorem", 'The Gaussian distribution', 'Bayesian inference', 'Bayesian inference - example', 'Maximum a posteriori estimation', 'Bayesian inference in Python', 'Why is Naive Bayes "naive"', 'Support Vector Machines', 'Support Vector Machines using Apache SparkML', 'Crossvalidation', 'Hyper-parameter tuning using GridSearch', 'Decision Trees', 'Bootstrap Aggregation (Bagging) and RandomForest', 'Boosting and Gradient Boosted Trees', 'Gradient Boosted Trees with Apache SparkML', 'Hyperparameter-Tuning using GridSeach and CrossValidation in Apache SparkML on Gradient Boosted Trees', 'Regularization'], ['Introduction to Unsupervised Machine Learning', 'Introduction to Clustering: k-Means', 'Hierarchical Clustering', 'Density-based clustering (Guest Lecture Saeed Aghabozorgi)', 'Using K-Means in Apache SparkML', 'Curse of Dimensionality', 'Dimensionality Reduction', 'Principal Component Analysis', 'Principal Component Analysis (demo)', 'Covariance matrix and direction of greatest variance', 'Eigenvectors and eigenvalues', 'Projecting the data', 'PCA in SystemML'], ['Signal decomposition, time and frequency domains', 'Fourier Transform in action', 'Signal generation and phase shift', 'The maths behind Fourier Transform', 'Discrete Fourier Transform', 'Fourier Transform in SystemML', 'Fast Fourier Transform', 'Nonstationary signals', 'Scaleograms', 'Continous Wavelet Transform', 'Scaling and translation', 'Wavelets and Machine Learning', 'Wavelets transform and SVM demo']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I feel bad giving it such a low rating, but I have to be honest. I did not learn much from this course. There was nothing "advanced" about the machine learning, and image processing was only gone over in the final week, and it was mostly just an overview of the important topics/concepts. This course lacked the rigour and depth I was expecting. Maybe my expectations were too high.  The assignments given were very simple. There should have been more interesting projects/assignments. The quality of the lecture videos was mediocre, in terms of both presentation and content. Someone can finish this course within a week, in fact just a few days, without even putting much effort into it. Overall this course lacked a coherent structure and it felt like it was put together in haste without much consideration for students. ', 'In general the course is excellent. However, it had a lot of information contained for a 4 week period especially week 2. I definitely learned a lot. ', 'Programming assignments were not challenging. Good course coverage.', None, 'the best advanced signal course ', "This course introduces some of the most popular methods of supervised and unsupervised machine learning. While it doesn't go deep into details behind the intuition, it gives a good explanation of when and why these algorithms can be applied. ", 'Excellent Material. The lectures and assignments are very good. Lectures sometimes felt a bit theoretical but needed that to understand concepts well.', 'Such great material. I really loved working out the notebooks. I have to go back and redo the IoT starter exercise to get  better accuracy, but this was awesome!', 'Very good, only the english from guest lecture is horrible.', 'good introduction. well choosen chunks of information.', 'Excelente curso, com ótimas explicações, bem detalhadas e sem rodeios. Os exemplos são práticos e abrangentes! Parabéns à equipe do Coursera e à IBM pelo excelente curso! Nota 1000!!!', 'Interesting that they add signal processiong and IoT. Something usually overlooked in other courses', 'Great course. superb instructor Sir Romeo. !! I am big fan of him now. !!', 'The PCA/FT/FFT material is awesome.  The presentation is great.  The assignments while not great, where a sufficient taste of watson studio. ', 'I would like to recommend this course  this is really interesting and most interesting part is the signal processing which builds an proper understanding of the math buzzwords like fourier and wavelet transform.', 'A career changer course, thanks the hand-ons which is second to none, i have gained experience which on other online course can produce, thanks to IBM for this course which timely and excellent.', 'Concise and straight to the point.', 'Very good data science specialization covering many interesting advanced technologies!', 'Very good course for learning, Fourier transformation explanation was the best one', ' I like very much the architecture-based approach of these courses/ specialization.', 'Well structured course.', 'Great course from IBM!', 'Good overview, with interesting practical examples in Python', 'Very well structured, easy to follow/understand. This is a hot topic at the moment and helped me in my job.', 'Outstanding lectors!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Seylan N', 'By Amardeep S', 'By varshaneya v', 'By Arooj A Q', 'By  Y N', 'By Dmitry B', 'By Ravi K', 'By Jozeene', 'By Norman F', 'By Andreas N', 'By Paulo R R', 'By Jorge A V', 'By Khawar A A', 'By Paul B', 'By Shakti s', 'By Akosu A ', 'By Henry U', 'By Sven', 'By Azeezur R', 'By Edoardo B', 'By engin C', 'By mahmut k', 'By Piero A M', 'By Ilario M', 'By Stanislaw K']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Sep 08, 2018', 'Sep 10, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'Jul 04, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2018', 'Jun 26, 2018', 'Jun 26, 2018']</review_date></doc>