<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_355</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/web-data</course_url><course_name>Web of Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Catherine Faron Zucker</course_instructor><course_introduction>This MOOC – a joint initiative between EIT Digital, Université de Nice Sophia-Antipolis / Université Côte d'Azur and INRIA - introduces the Linked Data standards and principles that provide the foundation of the Semantic web. You will learn how to publish, obtain and use structured data directly from the Web. Learning the principles, languages and standards to exchange Data on the Web will enable you to design and produce new applications, products and services that leverage the volume and variety of data the Web holds.

We divided this course into four parts that cover the core technical skills and competencies you need to master to be able to use the Web as a space for giant structure data exchange:
•    in the first part, “Principals of a Web of Linked Data”: you will learn and practice the principles to publish and obtain data directly on the Web instead of Web pages; 
•    in the second part, “The RDF Data Model”: you will learn the standard data model for the Web and its syntaxes to publish and link data on the Web in your applications and services;
•    in the third part, “SPARQL Query Language”: you will learn how to directly query and access data sources on the Web and obtain structured data relevant to your activity and domain;
•    in the fourth and final part, “Integration of other Data Formats and Sources”: you will learn how the Web standards interact and interoperate with other data formats to allow the integration of a variety of data sources.

Each week alternates short videos and quizzes, as well as supplementary resources and forums to gradually progress through the different principles and standards.

After following this course successfully, you will have the skills to obtain focused and structured datasets from the Web that you can then use to augment you own datasets, enrich their dimensions, feed your applications, perform data mining, machine learning and training, data analysis, AI processing and reasoning and other data management.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>search for occurrences of a query graph//publish Linked Open Data on the Web//access remotely data sources on the Web//use and mix together existing data to obtain new data</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>EIT Digital </course_orgnization><course_chapter>PRINCIPLES OF A WEB OF LINKED DATA//The RDF data model//SPARQL Query Language//Integration of other data formats and sources</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Welcome video by Fabien Gandon', 'Historical Introduction to the Web Architecture', 'Separating Presentation and Content', 'From Pages to Resources', 'Linked Data Principles', 'Stack of Standards and Languages', 'The BBC Web site uses linked (open) data', 'DBpedia at the heart of the linked open data cloud', 'Searching the Web of data', 'Open Calais: From natural language to linked data', 'When software agents access the Web of data', 'Linked Data for Exploratory Search', 'Take Away Week 1'], ['Describing Resources', 'Triple Model and Graph Model', 'Serialization Syntaxes', 'Values, Types and Languages', 'Representing groups', 'Naming Graphs', 'RDF Schema', 'Validating and Translating RDF Data', 'Visualization of RDF Graphs', 'Take Away Week 2'], ['RDF Graph Pattern Matching', 'Statements', 'Filter, Constraint and Function', 'Pre and Post Processing', 'Several Query Forms', 'Results and Update', 'Flint SPARQL Editor', 'Corese', 'Gephi and Corese to analyze data on the Web', 'QAKIS.org', 'Take Away Week 3'], ['RDFa: an RDF syntax inside HTML', 'GRDDL: extract RDF from X(HT)ML', 'JSON-LD: JSON syntax for RDF', 'Tabular data and metadata (CSV)', 'R2RML: integration with databases', 'LDP: a REST API to linked data', 'Augmenting Web browser with data in the pages', 'RDFa distiller', 'JSON-LD from Google Knowledge Graph API', 'Licentia: a Web site to choose the license of your data', 'Take away Week 4', 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['A comprehensive overview and hands-on practices allowing to apply these skills into practice. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Manuel X D']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 30, 2019']</review_date></doc>