<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_207</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/dna-sequencing</course_url><course_name>Algorithms for DNA Sequencing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ben Langmead, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>We will learn computational methods -- algorithms and data structures -- for analyzing DNA sequencing data. We will learn a little about DNA, genomics, and how DNA sequencing is used.  We will use Python to implement key algorithms and data structures and to analyze real genomes and DNA sequencing datasets.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Bioinformatics Algorithms//Algorithms//Python Programming//Algorithms On Strings</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>DNA sequencing, strings and matching//Preprocessing, indexing and approximate matching//Edit distance, assembly, overlaps//Algorithms for assembly</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Module 1 Introduction', 'Lecture: Why study this?', 'Lecture: DNA sequencing past and present', 'Lecture: Genomes as strings, reads as substrings', 'Lecture: String definitions and Python examples', 'Practical: String basics ', 'Practical: Manipulating DNA strings ', 'Practical: Downloading and parsing a genome ', 'Lecture: How DNA gets copied', 'Optional lecture: How second-generation sequencers work ', 'Optional lecture: Sequencing errors and base qualities ', 'Lecture: Sequencing reads in FASTQ format', 'Practical: Working with sequencing reads ', 'Practical: Analyzing reads by position ', 'Lecture: Sequencers give pieces to genomic puzzles', "Lecture: Read alignment and why it's hard", 'Lecture: Naive exact matching', 'Practical: Matching artificial reads ', 'Practical: Matching real reads '], ['Week 2 Introduction ', 'Lecture: Boyer-Moore basics', 'Lecture: Boyer-Moore: putting it all together', 'Lecture: Diversion: Repetitive elements', 'Practical: Implementing Boyer-Moore ', 'Lecture: Preprocessing', 'Lecture: Indexing and the k-mer index', 'Lecture: Ordered structures for indexing', 'Lecture: Hash tables for indexing', 'Practical: Implementing a k-mer index ', 'Lecture: Variations on k-mer indexes', 'Lecture: Genome indexes used in research', 'Lecture: Approximate matching, Hamming and edit distance', 'Lecture: Pigeonhole principle', 'Practical: Implementing the pigeonhole principle '], ['Module 3 Introduction ', 'Lecture: Solving the edit distance problem', 'Lecture: Using dynamic programming for edit distance', 'Practical: Implementing dynamic programming for edit distance ', 'Lecture: A new solution to approximate matching', 'Lecture: Meet the family: global and local alignment', 'Practical: Implementing global alignment ', 'Lecture: Read alignment in the field', 'Lecture: Assembly: working from scratch', 'Lecture: First and second laws of assembly', 'Lecture: Overlap graphs', 'Practical: Overlaps between pairs of reads ', 'Practical: Finding and representing all overlaps '], ['Module 4 introduction ', 'Lecture: The shortest common superstring problem', 'Practical: Implementing shortest common superstring ', 'Lecture: Greedy shortest common superstring', 'Practical: Implementing greedy shortest common superstring ', 'Lecture: Third law of assembly: repeats are bad', 'Lecture: De Bruijn graphs and Eulerian walks', 'Practical: Building a De Bruijn graph ', 'Lecture: When Eulerian walks go wrong', 'Lecture: Assemblers in practice', 'Lecture: The future is long?', 'Lecture: Computer science and life science', 'Lecture: Thank yous ']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course is very helpful to me,especially the code that the professor assistants wrote in the class. There are some algorithms have mentioned  and completed ,but I think if the class talked about the software like BWA, BFAST and other DNA sequence or De novo assembly software, it will be more perfect and helpful. Finally ,thank you for your work', 'This course was a really awesome course for anyone that has a light background in Python and wants to look more into bioinformatics. The instructors were very passionate and clear, and there was a good balance between learning about biology and the programming aspect. However, for somebody that only has the programming knowledge from Course 3 of the Genomic Data Science Specialization (Python for Genomic Data Science), that course, I believe, is too light for the new Python concepts taught in this course. I believe that before taking this course, you may need more background knowledge for Python. However, this is still a stellar course that I greatly enjoyed, with the homework and assignments being appropriately challenging.', "This is one of the best courses I've seen so far, that explains and showcases main principles, fundamentals of genomics, algorithms. Lectures are very informative and use metaphors for person to understand complex tasks in simple manner. I loved practicals as you could go along with the lecture in parallel, seeing how such algorithms were made and what steps to take while doing so. 5/5", 'Great material, nicely presented.', "This is more of my area... just starting the first videos and I'm already excited.", 'this is just so good. i did take a lot of courses online and in my university on bioinformatics and this is the best course design i saw so far. i had to take pauses while watching the lectures to appreciate how much effort the creators of the course put to make it this connected and comprehensive. thank you!', "I loved this course a lot. It's well organized. The lectures are clear. And the practicals are highly useful. Also, the assignments are helpful.", 'This is a super nice course. ', 'This is an excellent course. Lectures are very well prepared, practicals provide step-by-step explanations of the scripts (which is especially useful for people with little coding experience) and homeworks are well thought through, so that they force students to use the knowledge gained in the module. Some of the homeworks are challenging, but all the information needed to do the exercises is provided in lectures and practicals. All the notebooks containing scripts are provided, which makes it easy to take notes and better understand the scripts by running some examples. The way the concepts are explained in the lectures (the computational problem is described in details and then the ways of dealing with it are carefully explained in order of increasing complexity) provides insight into not only how these algorithms work but also why (what is the purpose/cause/reason behind these solutions). I can imagine how much work and thought went into preparation of these lectures and I honestly admire the teachers for their efforts. Taking this course was a great experience: I learned a lot and enjoyed it a lot. A big thank you! Please, keep up the good work.', 'Awesome, you will learn a lot about how DNA assemblers work, but very challenging and time demand in, especially if your background is in life science and not computer science.', 'This was really fun.  Really enjoyed the a-ha of the algorithms and the fun of solving the alignment and assembly problems.  Feel mildly powerful after assembling a virus genome.', 'Great but too short. I realize that it is hard to know where to start the course from but it is true that the Introductory Course for the Genomics Specialization has a lot of over lapping material.  I suggest getting rid of your intro material and go just a little farther in depth.', 'well explained', 'Excellent course, not like the first and second one of this specialization. ', 'I enjoyed the introduction to some of the algorithms used in genomics... and hope to explore these further in my career.', 'A lot of new information and work to do, really awesome!', 'This course, is the absolute best course of the entire specialization!', 'This is a high quality course!', 'Engaging course with a lot of information. ', None, 'Very good course! You end up with a repertoire of nice algorithms that might be useful in many kinds of genomic analysis. While these are far from the optimal algorithms used by the actual genomic programs, they provide a nice introduction to the subject. It would be very good to have another course for "Advanced algorithms for DNA sequencing" where strategies for dealing with the several complicators of actual genomic data are added on to the knowledge obtained in this course. ', 'This is hands-down the best course in this specialization.  There are good teachers (many of whom are teaching the other courses) and then there are the top 20% excellent teachers (Ben Langmead) who teaches this class.  In addition to being an excellent computer scientist, he is also an excellent teacher and he makes the material interesting and approachable.  The homework assignments are challenging, but created in such a way that the difficulty lies more in grappling with the concepts themselves, and less with debugging python code or whatever.  I highly recommend this course, and hope that Ben will do a "Algorithms: Part Two" covering Burrows-Wheeler and going into more depth, maybe discussing pseudo-alignment as well.  ', "it's really a helpful course, and it would show you the basic algorithms of the software we are using today.", None, 'Very Clear!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Cheng J', 'By Stephanie T E', 'By Yafremau N', 'By Carlos M', 'By Manuel C', 'By Mohamed E', 'By Omar E', 'By Yueqi C', 'By Joanna W', 'By Anastassiya Z', 'By Michael R D', 'By Matt C', 'By Ronald C', 'By Gonzalo C S', 'By Oliver S', 'By George C', 'By Kasper T K', 'By Allan T S', 'By Antoon L', 'By Tebogo M', 'By Eduardo A U', 'By Michael C', 'By 李仕廷', 'By Julia O', 'By gushengchang']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 12, 2018', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2018', 'Oct 19, 2018', 'Sep 24, 2018', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'Mar 11, 2016', 'Nov 10, 2016', 'May 03, 2017', 'Jun 29, 2017', 'Nov 14, 2016', 'Apr 12, 2018', 'Sep 17, 2017', 'Nov 27, 2017', 'Oct 31, 2016', 'Jan 11, 2017', 'Mar 14, 2016', 'Aug 18, 2017', 'Jun 28, 2017', 'Jun 02, 2018', 'Apr 18, 2017', 'Mar 16, 2016']</review_date></doc>