<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_75</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-people-analytics</course_url><course_name>People Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Cade Massey</course_instructor><course_introduction>People analytics is a data-driven approach to managing people at work. For the first time in history, business leaders can make decisions about their people based on deep analysis of data rather than the traditional methods of personal relationships, decision making based on experience, and risk avoidance. In this brand new course, three of Wharton’s top professors, all pioneers in the field of people analytics, will explore the state-of-the-art techniques used to recruit and retain great people, and demonstrate how these techniques are used at cutting-edge companies. They’ll explain how data and sophisticated analysis is brought to bear on people-related issues, such as recruiting, performance evaluation, leadership, hiring and promotion, job design, compensation, and collaboration. This course is an introduction to the theory of people analytics, and is not intended to prepare learners to perform complex talent management data analysis. By the end of this course, you’ll understand how and when hard data is used to make soft-skill decisions about hiring and talent development, so that you can position yourself as a strategic partner in your company’s talent management decisions. This course is intended to introduced you to Organizations flourish when the people who work in them flourish. Analytics can help make both happen. This course in People Analytics is designed to help you flourish in your career, too.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Leadership and Management</course_category><course_tag>Talent Management//Analytics//Performance Management//Collaboration</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to People Analytics, and Performance Evaluation//Staffing//Collaboration//Talent Management and Future Directions</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to People Analytics', 'Goals for the Course', 'Course Outline and Overview', 'People Analytics in Practice', 'Performance Evaluation: the Challenge of Noisy Data', 'Chance vs. Skill: the NFL Draft', 'Finding Persistence: Regression to the Mean', 'Extrapolating from Small Samples', 'The Wisdom of Crowds: Signal Independence', 'Process vs. Outcome', 'Summary of Performance Evaluation'], ['Introduction to Professor Bidwell', 'Staffing Analytics Overview', 'Hiring 1: Predicting Performance', 'Hiring 2: Fine-tuning Predictors', 'Hiring 3: Using Data Analysis to Predict Performance', 'Internal Mobility 1: Analyzing Promotibility', 'Internal Mobility 2: Optimizing Movement within the Organization', 'Causality 1', 'Causality 2', 'Attrition: Understanding and Reducing Turnover', 'Turnover: Predicting Attrition', 'Staffing Analytics Conclusion'], ['Introduction to Professor Haas', 'Basics of Collaboration', 'Describing Collaboration Networks', 'Mapping Collaboration Networks', 'Evaluating Collaboration Networks', 'Measuring Outcomes', 'Intervening in Collaboration Networks'], ['Talent Analytics: The Importance of Context', 'Interdependence', 'Self-fulfilling Prophecies', 'Reverse Causality', 'Special Topics: Tests and Algorithms', 'Prescriptions: Navigating the Challenges of Talent Analytics', 'Course Conclusion: Organizational Challenges 1', 'Course Conclusion: Organizational Challenges 2 and Future Directions', 'Goodbye and Good Luck!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Thank you Prof. Kassey, Prof. Haas and Prof. Bidwell. The course was nicely designed and really touched upon the pressing issues regarding people in an organization and how analytics can be used in overcoming those issues. I loved all the modules of the course and would recommend the course to anyone who wants to make a career in HR as analytics will be crucial in managing the workforce in coming time. The only recommendation is that it would be better if the course digs deeper into the techniques introduced. Overlall, great job by the team.', "It's a good high-level overview of material, but it only skims the surface. I would have preferred more depth. That said, given its short duration, the course went as deep as it could.", 'This course is an eye opener and is explained in a very comprehensive manner. The Quizes measured the actual understanding of the concept. I would like to thank all the three faculty for their best efforts. It was wonderful being a part of this course. ', 'This is a very well defined course to give a very good start to the knowledge of People Analytics. The professors have brought in numerous examples to make the understanding of analytics better.', 'A very good introductory course. I would recommend completing a basics of statistics course as well to better understand the concepts. Prof. Cade Massey does an excellent job in covering the concepts most essential for implementing people analytics.', 'Thank you so much for this very helpful module! I hope you continue to inspire HR professionals around the world to use HR Analytics as an important means to drive organizational-related decisions. ', 'I really love the course and lecturers. The knowledge l learnt is comprehensive in the revolutional business world', "would be good if some of the examples were not football and baseball, given i'm not from the us and don't understand those sports... also would be good to do some research on crossfit given their sport model seems to lend itself more to ppl analytics", 'The course does well as an intro to People Analytics... I feel that the Staffing section needs to be broken down to explain it more simply as the other sections are done. ', 'Great course with lots of interesting examples to get an idea of the theory.', 'Muy interesante, me brindó herramientas conceptuales y prácticas que me permitieron re-prensar mi quehacer diario. Lo recomiendo!', 'T', 'Incredibly valuable while remaining short and concise. Highly recommended for anyone with an interest in the People Analytics space, or evidence-based HR more generally.', 'Extraordinary', 'Great introduction to people analytics. Learned insights into drawing inferences from data.', 'Highly recommended! this course will teach you new techniques on how to use and analyze HR data.', 'Very well planned and educative course. ', 'Recomendado para quienes dirigen equipos de analytics', 'One of the best courses on People analytics that I have come across. The course helps you undertake a completely different perspective towards this field.', 'I loved the course, it is relatively difficult yet it goes into the core of the issue. So much knowledge learnt.', "prof.'s are really good at teaching a lot of things. Thanks", 'Amazing professors, really loved the collaboration professor', 'Great course', 'Excellent Course for HR Professionals.', 'A great introductory lesson on people analytics. Short but quite detailed. I was awed several times by this lesson when I linked the knowledge with my personal case (I hopped between jobs in my younger years and now I want to settle for long lasting job having found field that I enjoy the most, and now I know it\'s not a "millenial trend"). One thing as a suggestion: the last two videos (ones that are group of the lecturers) need better audio quality. The individual lectures were fine. Thank you UPenn, thank you Coursera for giving me the opportunity to learn from experts in the field.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ankur G', 'By Noah G', 'By Dr. G R K', 'By Prakriti N', 'By Alakh A', 'By Arnel M A', 'By Mohammed T T', 'By Kenneth C', 'By Rati R', 'By Christian K', 'By Pamela A', 'By Shaharol N B M', 'By Lewis S', 'By Christian F P', 'By Melody S', 'By Francis I Y', 'By Vaijayanthi J', 'By Yuri P', 'By Abhisekh M', 'By Hamed A S', 'By 박정아', 'By SOPHIA B K', 'By Adeleke A', 'By Amritesh S', 'By Siti A F']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 08, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Apr 24, 2019', 'Jul 28, 2017', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'May 01, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jun 26, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019']</review_date></doc>