<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_82</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/analytics-mysql</course_url><course_name>Managing Big Data with MySQL</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Egger</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is an introduction to how to use relational databases in business analysis.  You will learn how relational databases work, and how to use entity-relationship diagrams to display the structure of the data held within them.  This knowledge will help you understand how data needs to be collected in business contexts, and help you identify features you want to consider if you are involved in implementing new data collection efforts.  You will also learn how to execute the most useful query and table aggregation statements for business analysts, and practice using them with real databases. No more waiting 48 hours for someone else in the company to provide data to you – you will be able to get the data by yourself!

By the end of this course, you will have a clear understanding of how relational databases work, and have a portfolio of queries you can show potential employers. Businesses are collecting increasing amounts of information with the hope that data will yield novel insights into how to improve businesses. Analysts that understand how to access this data – this means you! – will have a strong competitive advantage in this data-smitten business world.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//MySQL//Teradata//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About this Specialization and Course //Understanding Relational Databases// Queries to Extract Data from Single Tables //Queries to Summarize Groups of Data from Multiple Tables // Queries to Address More Detailed Business Questions//Strengthen and Test Your Understanding </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About this Specialization', 'Welcome to Managing Big Data with MySQL', 'What You Will Learn in This Course'], ['Problems with Having a Lot of Data Used by a Lot of People', 'How Relational Databases Help Solve Those Problems', 'Database Design Tools That Will Help You Learn SQL Faster', 'How Entity-Relationship Diagrams Work', 'Database Structures Illustrated by Entity-Relationship Diagrams', 'Relational Schemas', 'How to Make Entity-Relationship Diagrams using ERDPlus', 'How to Make Relational Schemas using ERDPlus', 'Wrapping up Week 1'], ['Introduction to Week 2', 'Meet Your Dognition Data', "Meet Your Dillard's Data", 'Introduction to Query Syntax', 'How to Use Jupyter Notebooks', 'How to Use Your Jupyter Account', 'How to Use Teradata Viewpoint and SQL Scratchpad', 'You Have Already Become a Different Level of Business Analyst'], ['Welcome to Week 3', 'Habits that Help You Avoid Mistakes', 'What are Joins?', 'Joins with Many to Many Relationships and Duplicates', 'A Note about Our Join Examples', 'No More Waiting to Retrieve Your Data'], ['Welcome to Week 4', 'Start with an Analysis Plan'], ["Don't Be Afraid to Ask Questions!"]]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 24 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Sorry, I need to give this a course a 0 but since the review won't let me submit without scoring it, I'll give it a 1.  It was designed beautifully and to maximize skill building.  I really like the idea of using two different databases.  However, the Teradata database was down way too long, much longer than it was up.  People had to pay extra than planned to continue taking the course as a result.  The instructors planned everything beautifully-except developing a backup plan in case the third party Teradata server went down, which it did.  If the instructors or the university with they are affiliated have no control over this additional server, leaving the students helpless, they really should reconsider their use of materials outside of which they have direct control.", 'I recommend this course  although the exercise requires more time than the average courses in Coursera. If you complete it seriously on your own you will learn a lot in order to apply it at work.', "I legitimately believe this is the best source for Data/Business Analysts who would like to learn how to use SQL for analyzing datasets. They take you through the step by step process of learning everything and also provide a lot of material (weekly quizzes and exercises) to review and truly test your understanding of what you've learnt. This course takes quite a lot of time which is great because it means that if you get through it you will have learnt a lot! ", 'I thought it was good overall for teaching SQL and I enjoy Jana a lot... however', 'one star for the certificate;one for let me learn basic knowledge of SQL;the website often breaks down,so is the Teredata system ;the problem-solution system is also troublesome,hard to get the solution on time, maybe it is better to set a all-time online problem solver. No answer for teredata exercise also trap me for the hint in the teredata excersise sometimes not clear. Hope advancement for this course and the better experience of users.', 'The Jupyter notebook of the course had been not working for two days and I could not even see the course material in the notebook. ', None, 'Poor performance of Jupyter and the wildly underestimated time commitments really sunk this one for me. The latter, especially is inexcusable. The syllabus is lopsided and, while organized, not enough thought has been given to the exercise workload.', 'The data sets are very hard to understand. The teacher should spend more time to explain the data set before assigning excesses and quiz with them.  It took me two courses to understand what Dognition is doing (the video from the CEO is a very bad introduction, he did not explain the company very well).', 'pretty useless seriously', "Really bad course. Badly taught, strange choice of assignments and quiz questions. Unfortunately, I did the free trial and Coursera didn't process my cancellation so that I had to pay for a whole month for this. ", 'I think this course if poorly organized. The instructor is really trying to show us that the real life data sets and databases are messy, but providing only written instructions for me it proved useless. I, for one, need to see what other people are doing and not read long pages of horrible written explanations. ', 'Nunca pude hacer los ejercicios porque mi Jupiter Notebook estaba vaciá y nadie me pudo ayudar', 'My experience with Teradata has been awful. Connection issues, latency, time outs. What should have taken 45 minutes took nearly two hours because of the load times for datasets. No clock or indication of progression for the queries. ', 'I finished the course because I had to (I was exerted of paying fees) and then you agree on finishing the course. If I could I would have changed to another similar course some where else. Sorry but it is the true :)', 'Students need access to Teradata to complete the course, BUT the page providing login information is BROKEN. I have to quit in the middle of the course. That is a waste of our money and time!', "The course content is good but its very poorly arranged. I am doing exercise and often find before continuing exercise 6, please watch 'that certain' video without providing any link. I tried to find the the link and finally gave up.", 'The Teradata cannot be accessed ', 'Amazing Course with lot of hands on training', 'Fun, intuitive, full of information and practical works, I learnt so much through this course. Thank you so much, it was a pleasure to study SQL with Duke University.', 'Thank you!', 'Great course with reasonable arrangements', 'Very nice course!', 'Wonderful course, not only help you with coding but explained everything behind the scene.', 'very good and practical course']</reviews><reviewers>['By Justin G', 'By Pablo V I', 'By gcassis@bu.edu', 'By Franklin D', 'By Zhu Y', 'By Milad R', 'By Zhang J', 'By Neal D', 'By Schwinn C', 'By Venkat M K', 'By Eva', 'By Anca V', 'By Luis A A', 'By Adam B', 'By Ana C', 'By Yannan C', 'By AHSAN H S', 'By changhao L', 'By Ripal', 'By Gilles T', 'By Roshan K B', 'By Weiying Z', 'By Wei J', 'By Liu X', 'By Wa S T']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 09, 2017', 'Dec 26, 2017', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Dec 14, 2017', 'Aug 04, 2018', 'Jan 24, 2018', 'May 27, 2017', 'Feb 05, 2017', 'Aug 29, 2018', 'Sep 13, 2017', 'Apr 11, 2017', 'Dec 11, 2016', 'Dec 15, 2016', 'Jan 23, 2017', 'May 11, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Aug 08, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019']</review_date></doc>