<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_369</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/financial-regulation</course_url><course_name>Financial Regulation in Emerging Markets and the Rise of Fintech Companies</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Co-Pierre Georg</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course gives an overview of the changing regulatory environment since the 1997 Asian and 2008 global financial crisis. Following these two major crises, governments around the globe enacted a set of far-reaching new financial regulations that are aimed towards safeguarding financial stability. However, banks find it increasingly difficult to be profitable in this new regulatory environment. Technology, at the same time, has taken important leaps forward with the emergence of sophisticated models of artificial intelligence and the invention of the blockchain. These two developments fuel the emergence of fintech companies around the world. 

This course discusses fintech regulation in emerging markets using case studies from China and South Africa. The course pays special attention to the socioeconomic environment in emerging markets, as well as to political risk as a major source of uncertainty for fintech entrepreneurs. Peer-to-peer lending and remittances are used as leading examples for fintech innovation in emerging markets.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Finance</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Cape Town</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Financial Crises//Post-crisis regulations//Fintech regulation in emerging markets//Rise in Fintech Companies</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the course', 'Introduction to Week 1 - Financial Crises', 'Asian Financial Crisis - The Contributing Factors', 'Asian Financial Crisis - The Outcome', 'Global Financial Crisis - The American Dream', 'Global Financial Crisis -  Securitization of  Mortgages', 'Global Financial Crisis -  The Crises Erupts', 'Global financial crisis - The Crisis Continues', 'Bank Balance Sheets', 'Mechanisms of Mortgage Securitization', 'Mechanisms Behind Contagion Channels', 'Basel III - Liquidity Regulation and Leverage Ratios'], ['Introduction to Week 2', 'Great Depression: Stock Market Crash', 'Great Depression: Banking Crisis', 'New Deal: Emergency Measures', 'New Deal: Commercial Bank Structures', 'New Deal: Federal Reserve System', 'Regulation Q and Shadow Banking', 'Two Main Modes of the Financial System', 'Capital Regulation', 'Risk-weighted Assets', 'The Bretton Woods Agreement', 'The Bretton Woods Design Flaw'], ['Introduction to Week 3', 'How Regulation in Emerging Markets Differ', 'Fintech regulation in the US - Responsible innovation', 'Initial Coin Offerings (ICOs)', 'Initial Coin Offering Regulation', 'Smart Contracts and Law', 'Fintech Regulation in China: Market for Cryptocurrencies', 'Fintech Regulation in China: ICOs and P2P Lending', 'Fintech in China: Interview with Michael Wong', 'Fintech Regulation in Brazil', 'Fintech Regulation in South Africa', 'Fintech in South Africa: Interview with Arif Ismail'], ['Introduction to Week 4', 'Peer-to-Peer Lending', 'Peer-to-Peer Models', 'Remittances', 'Zoona: Expanding Financial Services in Africa', 'Payment Services - Yoco', 'Blockchain and Banks - Naomi Snyman', 'Blockchain and Banks - Stuart van der Veen and Aatish Ramkaran', 'ICOs, Blockchain and Banks - Farzam Ehsani', 'Fintech for Financial Freedom - StokFella', 'Fintech for Impact - The SunExchange', 'Impact Investing - Aunnie Patton Power', 'Course conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This is very good programme, it should be marketed especially to teams working with regulators . It can go a long way in assisting sharping up the Fintech regulations.', 'Excellent course which gives a great foundation in understanding the origin of financial regulation and how the evolution of banking and financial institution systems took place after the major shocks ranging from the Great Depression and especially The Global Financial Crisis and the potential and rather inevitable progress of fintech in emerging markets.', 'The course is very informative and groundbreaking.', "Financial Regulation in Emerging Markets and the Rise of Fintech Companies is an amazing course, it gives a nice introduction as to how the current financial systems were built down to why they're now so flawed. Most importantly, how these flaws greatly affect the world's economic. If you're not sure as to why you should pay more attention to financial markets, and the uprising solutions, then this course is perfect for you. If you do not why, but still uncertain of the core causes and urgent rise of FinTech Companies, then its also perfect for you. All the best!  ", 'Honestly thing it is a great course. I learnt a lot, it is well taught and the assignments test the application of the content well.', 'Great overview of an emerging and exciting topic!', 'Being a Social Science scholar, I must admit, I found this to be worthwhile.', "This course was well presented. I am a science student who's never had any Business or Financial education and I was able to perfectly understand everything with help from the required reading.", 'Excellent!', "Really excellent, one of the best Coursera courses I've done (and I've done a lot) - I would give this more than 5 stars if I could"]</reviews><reviewers>['By CHALLENGE P', 'By Boutros M', 'By Pako M', 'By Hélda M', 'By Mduduzi S', 'By Elizaveta S', 'By Israel N', 'By Matthew W B', 'By OMAKWU M I ', 'By Bronwen N']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 10, 2018', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Oct 04, 2018', 'Sep 07, 2018', 'Aug 12, 2019', 'Sep 14, 2019']</review_date></doc>