<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_171</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-integration-processing</course_url><course_name>Big Data Integration and Processing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ilkay Altintas</course_instructor><course_introduction>At the end of the course, you will be able to:

*Retrieve data from example database and big data management systems 
*Describe the connections between data management operations and the big data processing patterns needed to utilize them in large-scale analytical applications
*Identify when a big data problem needs data integration
*Execute simple big data integration and processing on Hadoop and Spark platforms

This course is for those new to data science.  Completion of Intro to Big Data is recommended.  No prior programming experience is needed, although the ability to install applications and utilize a virtual machine is necessary to complete the hands-on assignments.  Refer to the specialization technical requirements for complete hardware and software specifications.

Hardware Requirements: 
(A) Quad Core Processor (VT-x or AMD-V support recommended), 64-bit; (B) 8 GB RAM; (C) 20 GB disk free. How to find your hardware information: (Windows): Open System by clicking the Start button, right-clicking Computer, and then clicking Properties; (Mac): Open Overview by clicking on the Apple menu and clicking “About This Mac.” Most computers with 8 GB RAM purchased in the last 3 years will meet the minimum requirements.You will need a high speed internet connection because you will be downloading files up to 4 Gb in size. 

Software Requirements: 
This course relies on several open-source software tools, including Apache Hadoop. All required software can be downloaded and installed free of charge (except for data charges from your internet provider). Software requirements include: Windows 7+, Mac OS X 10.10+, Ubuntu 14.04+ or CentOS 6+ VirtualBox 5+.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Big Data//Mongodb//Splunk//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Big Data Integration and Processing//Retrieving Big Data (Part 1)//Retrieving Big Data (Part 2)//Big Data Integration//Processing Big Data//Big Data Analytics using Spark//Learn By Doing: Putting MongoDB and Spark to Work</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What is in this Course?', 'Summary of Big Data Modeling and Management', 'Why is Big Data Processing Different?'], ['What is Data Retrieval? Part 1', 'What is Data Retrieval? Part 2', 'Querying Two Relations', 'Subqueries', 'Querying Relational Data with Postgres'], ['Querying JSON Data with MongoDB', 'Aggregation Functions', 'Querying Aerospike', 'Querying Documents in MongoDB', 'Exploring Pandas DataFrames'], ['Overview of Information Integration', 'A Data Integration Scenario', 'Integration for Multichannel Customer Analytics', 'Big Data Management and Processing Using Splunk and Datameer', 'Why Splunk?', "Connected Cars with Ford's OpenXC and Splunk", 'Big Data Management and Processing using Datameer', 'Installing Splunk Enterprise on Windows', 'Installing Splunk Enterprise on Linux', 'Exploring Splunk Queries', 'Optional: Creating Pivot Reports in Splunk'], ['Big Data Processing Pipelines', 'Some High-Level Processing Operations in Big Data Pipelines', 'Aggregation Operations in Big Data Pipelines', 'Typical Analytical Operations in Big Data Pipelines', 'Overview of Big Data Processing Systems', 'The Integration and Processing Layer', 'Introduction to Apache Spark', 'Getting Started with Spark', 'WordCount in Spark'], ['Spark Core: Programming In Spark using RDDs in Pipelines', 'Spark Core: Transformations', 'Spark Core: Actions', 'Spark SQL', 'Spark Streaming', 'Spark MLLib', 'Spark GraphX', 'Exploring SparkSQL and Spark DataFrames', 'Analyzing Sensor Data with Spark Streaming'], ["Let's Analyze Soccer Tweets!", 'Expressing Analytical Questions as MongoDB Queries', 'Exporting Data from MongoDB to a CSV File', 'Analyzing Tweets About Countries']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 19 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I found the 6th week of this course to be frustrating.  There was a big jump from the lessons to the final 2 tests, and the questions and directions were not well worded, a bit confusing.  The biggest issue was that many students had the same questions that were blocking their progress, however there were almost no replies from teachers or staff to give some guidance, tips, etc.  Some of these questions were asked over a year ago and the new students had the same questions again, and still no real activity  from the teachers in the forums.  In past classes that always happened.  ', 'The final assignment contained concepts that were not taught in the course: for example, how to remove leading space from a field, how to put 2 words in a tuple, how to filter lines/texts with null, how to deal with country names with more than one word (e.g. United States), etc. The final assignment requirement far more advanced Spark programming skill than what was taught in the rest of the course. ', 'This course provides a good overview and positioning of relevant big data technologies. In the latter weeks, the hands-on exercises become increasingly challenging, which is a good thing. I have a much better grasp of Apache Spark and its role in big data processing and integration as a result of this course. ', "Great course and content; I just would like that I've felt better prepared for the last challenge with Spark. @ week6. But still an excellent course and hands-on exercises.", "I did liked the subjects on this course! but it would be highly appreciated and would bring more potential students to this course if the setup instructions where more clear and right on the issue. Students come with various discipline backgrounds and 100% of us are new to Big Data Tools, so troubleshooting and issue while trying to do a lab or quiz is very stressful and encouraging. Even better PLEASE add a Troubleshooting section on a week's course should you see that many students are stuck with the same or similar issue...PLEASE!", 'I liked the subject, and I achieved my main goal with this course. So I am globally satisfied. ', "This course was a lot more challenging, the assignments requires that you have some knowledge with scripting even though the practice runs through some but if you do not have the background it is very challenging.  But, don't give up since you have the vm running on your local machine you can continue to practice with the course examples.", 'The course content is good, however, main issue is with the hands on and assignments instructions - they are not completely clear and lack many things.', "The lectures are so mundane and abstract. I enjoy the hands on portions, but they are so disconnected from the lectures when concepts are to be explained, that they ultimately feel like we're just executing code from the material that we may not fully understand. By the time the quizzes come up, we're expected to put everything together as if we're regularly practicing the methods used in the hands-on portions. Very disappointed.", "It was a tough last project and I had to use outside resources with limited examples and that is why I could not finish on time. I don't like being late on anything but this was by far my worst time management due to vague instructions and lack of supp", "A lot of the instructions for the assignments were incomplete or just wrong. The installation for Splunk never worked as written, forums were of no help; I ended up downloading an older version of Splunk just to complete that week's assignment. This course was extremely frustrating to complete.", "This course continued the trend of this specialization where the lectures are full of vague jargon/diagrams and name-dropping of various applications without teaching us practical skills and then quizzing us on whether we listened to the video verbatim as opposed to challenging our minds conceptually. Only the exercises are redeeming in giving some useful, hands-on experience with some applications but then the final project required extensive googling to figure out how to work with pyspark dataframes that weren't taught in the course. Instead this course should have just been full of hands-on teaching of pyspark, mongodb, and python. Also the splunk module was a total tangent/distraction and should be dropped.", 'I have to give this course a low rating, simply because the week 6 assignment "Analysis using Spark" was a terrible experience.  All other assignments throughout these course have been great, but the "Analysis using Spark" assignment was poorly constructed. Essentially the assignment could not be completed as prescribed in the instructions. The data required modifying in order to complete the exercise - which I was never able to complete. The goal of the exercise was to use what we learned from the lessons and work with data frames, not deal with and repair broken csv data. This was extremely disappointing!', 'Lecture material and instructions are very limited and confusing. There are so many places that the order of the steps to perform certain tasks are flipped making the students spending several none sense hours. I wish somebody would care and review the material and fix all these issues!!!  ', 'instalation for pyspark is not working properly', 'Enjoyed the class.  It was very enlightening.', 'Great course :)', 'Perfect ', 'This course was very informative and provided some very good hands on exercises', 'Very good explanation of Spark layers and processes and how it differs from MapReduce. Thank you.', 'amazing course great assignments', "it's really useful course for data integration. and you will understand the basic of data integration and processing which is really important part of big data as well.", "This is awesome course for beginner who didn't have any knowledge of bigdata", 'Great experience towards learning this course', "This has been one of the most exciting courses I've done. The final project makes a good job on making you apply a Big Data Processing Pipeline to solve a common task these days with SparkSQL: analyzing data on social media."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Scott M', 'By Sam M', 'By Dwayne D', 'By Roberto G C', 'By Prospero-Martin R', 'By Federico S', 'By King W N', 'By Manoj D', 'By Brian M', 'By Charles G', 'By Ana L', 'By Jason R', 'By Phillip M', 'By Alireza A B', 'By Andreas D S', 'By Nick B', 'By Esteban E C', 'By José G d A L N', 'By Prashant N N', 'By Zeinab T', 'By vasudha k', 'By Mahamat N A M', 'By Chetan H', 'By Srishti R', 'By Jorge V']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 19, 2018', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Jul 23, 2018', 'Jun 09, 2018', 'Apr 13, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2018', 'Oct 29, 2018', 'Oct 14, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2017', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Oct 21, 2017', 'Sep 04, 2017', 'Oct 22, 2017', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018']</review_date></doc>