<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_391</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/digital-thread-implementation</course_url><course_name>Digital Thread: Implementation</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ken English</course_instructor><course_introduction>There are opportunities throughout the design process of any product to make significant changes, and ultimately impact the future of manufacturing, by embracing the digital thread. In this course, you will dig into the transformation taking place in how products are designed and manufactured throughout the world. It is the second of two courses that focuses on the "digital thread" – the stream that starts at the creation of a product concept and continues to accumulate information and data throughout the product life cycle.  

Hear about the realities of implementing the digital thread, directly from someone responsible for making it happen at a company. Learn how the digital thread can fit into product development processes in an office, on a shop floor, and even across an enterprise. Be prepared to talk about the benefits, and limitations, of enacting it.

Main concepts of this course will be delivered through lectures, readings, discussions and various videos. 

This is the third course in the Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design Technology specialization that explores the many facets of manufacturing’s “Fourth Revolution,”  aka Industry 4.0, and features a culminating project involving creation of a roadmap to achieve a self-established DMD-related professional goal.

To learn more about the Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology specialization, please watch the overview video by copying and pasting the following link into your web browser: https://youtu.be/wETK1O9c-CA</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Mechanical Engineering</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Strategic issues in implementing the digital thread//Cyberinfrastructure Components of the Digital Thread//Technologies used in the Design Process//Digital Thread on the Shop Floor//Digital Thread and the Manufacturing Enterprise</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Digital Thread: Implementation', 'A Business Case for the Digital Thread', 'Transitioning to the Digital Thread', 'Challenges and Benefits of Implementing the Digital Thread'], ['Information Technology Components', 'Computing Resources', 'Virtualization', 'Resources for Cloud-based Computing'], ['Design Process Technologies', 'Finite Element Analysis', 'Computational Fluid Dynamics', 'Mold Design', 'Verification and Validation'], ['The Production Process', 'Additive Manufacturing', 'Digital Work Instructions', 'Digital Documents and Records', 'Digital Metrology Approaches'], ['DMD Connections Throughout the Enterprise', 'The Industrial Internet of Things (IIOT)', 'Factory Simulation Tools', 'MRP, ERP, MES', 'Your 4.0 Roadmap to Success']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very useful course. ', 'After having completed the Digital Thread transformations, framework, components and strategies in the first two courses, I was pleased with the opportunity for exploring the transformation taking place in how products are designed and manufactured throughout the world integrates with the digital thread tactical implementation addressed in the third course, providing closed loop. I look forward to even more depth and breadth of applications in the real world with opportunity to continue building my  4.0 Roadmap to Success in Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology.', 'ONE OF THE BEST COURSE TO LEARN TO WORK ON INNOVATIVE IDEAS ON DMDI ', '  Good  ', 'Really enjoyed the course.  It is informative and I learned a lot.  Looking forward to the next course in the sequence.', 'Ótimo material de referência', 'Excellent Course on Digital Thread...Thanks to Kin for sharing knowledge on Digital Thread implementation.', 'Practical point of view. Very interesting.', 'Excellent course! Gives you a more practical perspective of how the Digital Manufacturing will be incorporated on the shop floor.', 'I am very satisfied with the course that i open my mind and possibilities.', None, 'Already a bit outdated, but a gives me alot of insight.', 'IT WAS AN AWESOME EXPERIENCE  WITH LEARNING ABOUT ADVANCED MANUFECTURING  ENTERPRISE WITH SIR KEN ENGLISH AND I AM VERY THANKFUL FOR SIR ', 'Nice Course.!!', 'Excellent', 'ah. probably the most important course so far and most interesting. Not sure what follows but will comment on it too.', 'Great', 'Innovative course design and Informative lecture sessions and reference materials', 'Good overview of how the Digital Thread is utilized in organizations to cut costs and improve operations and customer service.  Good resources.', 'For a Manufacturing Scan project to be well implemented it is essential to understand the components of Cyber Infrastructure, the main technologies used and how to bring all this to the shop floor. This course introduces all of these components and teaches you how to implement them.', 'Superb Course and overall a great experience.', None, None, 'I found the Digital Thread: Implementation course to be a good survey course of many topics that need to be understood to implement the digital thread.  It gives you an idea of what the issues are, what the benefits are, and a great set of resources on where to dig deeper.', 'So amazing and exciting to part of the participatant the courses']</reviews><reviewers>['By TCHOUMKEU N m L', 'By Richard L', 'By NAGA S P', 'By Atichat P', 'By Scott C', 'By Lucas M S', 'By Tejo R B', 'By Glauber H d O S', 'By Natalie B', 'By Allan d M G', 'By Malcolm J', 'By Marcel D', 'By akhilesh k k ', 'By K P k', 'By VENKATESAN S', 'By Vancho D', 'By yashar k s', 'By Senthilkumar', 'By David C', 'By Wesley T', 'By Ashwin', 'By Meetkumar J P', 'By Shivoh C', 'By Konrad G R R', 'By kayode O']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 24, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2017', 'Oct 24, 2017', 'Jul 09, 2017', 'Feb 27, 2018', 'Aug 29, 2017', 'May 15, 2017', 'Jan 14, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2017', 'Jun 23, 2017', 'Apr 02, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2018', 'May 30, 2018', 'Jul 22, 2017', 'Jan 05, 2018', 'May 02, 2018', 'Apr 24, 2017', 'Apr 30, 2017', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'Aug 11, 2019', 'Aug 17, 2019']</review_date></doc>