<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_348</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-capstone-analytics</course_url><course_name>Business Analytics Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Wharton Teaching Staff</course_instructor><course_introduction>The Business Analytics Capstone Project gives you the opportunity to apply what you've learned about how to make data-driven decisions to a real business challenge faced by global technology companies like Yahoo, Google, and Facebook. At the end of this Capstone, you'll be able to ask the right questions of the data, and know how to use data effectively to address business challenges of your own. You’ll understand how cutting-edge businesses use data to optimize marketing, maximize revenue, make operations efficient, and make hiring and management decisions so that you can apply these strategies to your own company or business. Designed with Yahoo to give you invaluable experience in evaluating and creating data-driven decisions, the Business Analytics Capstone Project provides the chance for you to devise a plan of action for optimizing data itself to provide key insights and analysis, and to describe the interaction between key financial and non-financial indicators. Once you complete your analysis, you'll be better prepared to make better data-driven business decisions of your own.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Customer Analytics//Strategic Management//Data Analysis//Business Analytics</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter> Module 1: Capstone Project Topic - The Problem of Adblocking//Module 2:  Defining the Problem//Module 3:  Your Strategy//Module 4:  Effects of Your Strategy/Measuring these Effects//Module 5:  Final Project Submission</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Start Here! Project Description: Business Analytics Capstone', 'GYF Company Profile', 'The Importance of Mobile Advertising', 'Further Exploration into Online Advertising Response Models', 'How Internet Ads Work', 'Project Template'], ['What is Descriptive Analytics? (Customer Analytics)', 'Descriptive Data Collection (Customer Analytics)', 'Passive Data Collection (Customer Analytics)', 'Beyond Period 2 (Customer Analytics)', 'Causality 1 (People Analytics)', 'Causality 2 (People Analytics)', 'Reverse Causality (People Analytics)', 'Causal Data Collection and Summary (Customer Analytics)'], ['Performance Evaluation: the Challenge of Noisy Data (People Analytics)', 'Finding Persistence: Regression to the Mean (People Analytics)', 'Extrapolating from Small Samples (People Analytics)', 'The Wisdom of Crowds: Signal Independence (People Analytics)', 'Process vs. Outcome (People Analytics)', 'Hiring 1 (People Analytics)', 'Hiring 2 (People Analytics)'], ['The Newsvendor Problem (Operations Analytics)', 'How to Build an Optimization Model (Operations Analytics)', 'Optimizing with Solver (Operations Analytics)', 'Simulating Uncertain Outcomes in Excel (Operations Analytics)', 'Decision Trees (Operations Analytics)', 'Linking Non-financial Metrics to Financial Performance: Overview (Accounting Analytics)', 'Steps to Linking Non-financial Metrics to Financial Performance (Accounting Analytics)', 'Incorporating Analysis Results in Financial Models (Accounting Analytics)'], ['Applications: ROI (Customer Analytics)', 'Radically New Data Sets in Marketing (Customer Analytics)', "Analytics Applied: Kohl's, Netflix, AmEx and more (Customer Analytics)"]]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Why should my course completion be held back because other participants are  not available to review my submission and provide feedback...this is very unfair and I feel complete wastage of my money.', "I have a passionate dislike for peer graded assignments. There is nothing worse than having to redo an assignment two or three times because your 'peers' lack the language skills or understanding of your submission to grade it appropriately. If this were a free course I would happily accept peer grading as a cost of education. But for a paid course, to have someone who is in the process of learning the material grade my understanding of it is unacceptable. Peer graded assignments are actually the reason I will be discontinuing my Coursera specializations and search for an alternative source of online e", 'I think may be a little bit more description about what are the requirements are needed to enroll in courses as customer analytics which the learners should have a good statistics skills. ', 'The course provides a case. We have to identify the problem. I appreciated the fact that how I define a problem decides on how I propose to address it. A different definition leads to altogether different steps! The course also provides a good template and sufficient guidelines to help us develop a strategy to address the problem we have defined. Finally , we have to think about how we can test if our strategy is viable. We are also guided to think about the changes that might be necessary in our organization in terms of structure, KPIs, skills etc. Given the nature of this capstone project one cannot expect it to be too specific and have a heavy application of analytics. What it does is provide you with a good idea of how to put all that you have learned in each of the specializations in a comprenesive manner, and that how these ideas fit together to create a big picture. If you are looking at complex  number crunching excerices then you will not find it here. If you are looking for excerices that will make you think and think and think then you will be quite satisfied. I am!', 'I really enjoyed the capstone project.', 'An awesome experience for sharing all learned knowledge with classmates!', 'Great ending to the specialization. Great way of applying content. Really interesting example!', 'ES UN CURSO PERFECTO PARA DESARROLLAR TODO LO APRENDIDO', 'I am very grateful for the learning and practice that I can give to this graduation project, which has made me gain a lot in strategic decision-making and business analysis.', 'amzing ', 'Excellent course, grading through p2p is. very good idea', 'Excellent course!!! Strongly recommended!', 'Very hand-on. It let you think on your own and apply concepts previously studied. The review process may be improved.', 'Good project to cover all the lessons learned so far..', 'I think that to reviewed by classmates is nbot the best way to get an education. Anyway - thank you', 'The peer review is not a good idea for this course. I expected to have valuable inputs from Wharton staff to my submission.', 'Great course outstanding examples from a really talented staff. The level of engagement and pace of teaching was perfect. ', 'While some of the courses were more difficult than others, I was overall impressed with the certification.  Highly recommended for any business generalist looking for a basic introduction to the analytics field. ', 'Capstone provided a very good platform to use all the knowledge gained in the specialization courses...', 'I loved it.', 'Fantastic Course', 'Greats courses', 'good course', 'Great Learning ! Helps reinforce understanding of core concepts,methodologies &amp; approaches.', 'It improves my systematic approach toward solving problems ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Rashmi K', 'By Grant I', 'By Andre T S', 'By Raman K', 'By Kostas K', 'By Daniel C', 'By Federico C', 'By Silvio A G B', 'By 刘峰', 'By ANUJ K Y', 'By Mohamed M', 'By Andrey S', 'By Falcone A', 'By Shivani A', 'By Evgeniy G', 'By Vu H G', 'By Rob K', 'By Andrew N', 'By Gowtham T', 'By Navjot S', 'By LN Y A', 'By Jose M G C', 'By Mohamad S A W', 'By VIJAYA G', 'By Mhd R A']</reviewers><review_date>['May 04, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2017', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Apr 20, 2017', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'May 13, 2019', 'Apr 25, 2019', 'Apr 19, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Sep 11, 2018', 'Apr 26, 2016', 'Sep 27, 2018', 'May 08, 2016', 'May 08, 2016', 'Aug 29, 2017', 'Aug 24, 2017', 'Jun 20, 2016', 'Jul 29, 2016', 'Jul 18, 2017', 'May 15, 2016', 'Mar 02, 2017', 'Apr 19, 2017', 'May 15, 2016']</review_date></doc>