<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_272</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/healthcare-data-literacy</course_url><course_name>Healthcare Data Literacy</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian Paciotti</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will help lay the foundation of your healthcare data journey and provide you with knowledge and skills necessary to work in the healthcare industry as a data scientist. Healthcare is unique because it is associated with continually evolving and complex processes associated with health management and medical care. We'll learn about the many facets to consider in healthcare and determine the value and growing need for data analysts in healthcare. We'll learn about the Triple Aim and other data-enabled healthcare drivers. We'll cover different concepts and categories of healthcare data and describe how ontologies and related terms such as taxonomy and terminology organize concepts and facilitate computation. We'll discuss the common clinical representations of data in healthcare systems, including ICD-10, SNOMED, LOINC, drug vocabularies (e.g., RxNorm), and clinical data standards. We’ll discuss the various types of healthcare data and assess the complexity that occurs as you work with pulling in all the different types of data to aid in decisions. We will analyze various types and sources of healthcare data, including clinical, operational claims, and patient generated data as well as differentiate unstructured, semi-structured and structured data within health data contexts. We'll examine the inner workings of data and conceptual harmony  offer some solutions to the data integration problem by defining some important concepts, methods, and applications that are important to this domain.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Health Informatics</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Healthcare 101//Concepts and Categories//Healthcare Data//Data and Conceptual Harmony</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Module 1 Introduction', 'Context of Human Systems and Human Biology', 'Healthcare Systems', 'Opportunities for Improvement: High Costs and Waste', 'Opportunities for Improvement: Knowing Doing Gaps', 'Opportunities for Improvement: Patient Management'], ['Module 2 Introduction', 'Ontologies - Descriptions of the World', 'Standard Terminologies', 'Diagnoses: ICD-9/10', 'SNOMED, CPT, LOINC, Drug Terminologies', 'Information Exchange Standards'], ['Module 3 Introduction', 'From Concepts to Data: Information to Knowledge', 'Clinical Data', 'Administrative Data', 'Genomic Data', 'Big Data'], ['Module 4 Introduction', 'Data Archaeology', 'Data Harmonization', 'Data Integration', 'Data Mapping', 'Entity Resolution', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is well loaded with information that is useful for data scientists (or intending data scientists) in healthcare. The instructor did a wonderful job.', 'Good introduction', 'Great Course', 'Overall I liked the course. I am giving 4 star due to issue with lack of forum responses. Did not look any TA was assigned to the program.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Justice D A', 'By Maxwell W', 'By Edward D B', 'By Shib B']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 12, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019']</review_date></doc>