<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_269</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-science-ethics</course_url><course_name>Data Science Ethics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>H.V. Jagadish</course_instructor><course_introduction>What are the ethical considerations regarding the privacy and control of consumer information and big data, especially in the aftermath of recent large-scale data breaches?

This course provides a framework to analyze these concerns as you examine the ethical and privacy implications of collecting and managing big data. Explore the broader impact of the data science field on modern society and the principles of fairness, accountability and transparency as you gain a deeper understanding of the importance of a shared set of ethical values. You will examine the need for voluntary disclosure when leveraging metadata to inform basic algorithms and/or complex artificial intelligence systems while also learning best practices for responsible data management, understanding the significance of the Fair Information Practices Principles Act and the laws concerning the "right to be forgotten."

This course will help you answer questions such as who owns data, how do we value privacy, how to receive informed consent and what it means to be fair.

Data scientists and anyone beginning to use or expand their use of data will benefit from this course. No particular previous knowledge needed.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>What are Ethics?//History, Concept of Informed Consent//Data Ownership//Privacy//Anonymity//Data Validity//Algorithmic Fairness//Societal Consequences//Code of Ethics//Attributions</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Data Science Ethics - Course Preview', 'What are Ethics?', 'Data Science Needs Ethics', 'Case Study: Spam (not the meat)'], ['Human Subjects Research and Informed Consent: Part 1', 'Human Subjects Research and Informed Consent: Part 2', 'Limitations of Informed Consent', "Case Study: It's Not OKCupid"], ['Data Ownership', 'Limits on Recording and Use', 'Data Ownership Finale', 'Case Study: Rate My Professor', 'Case Study: Privacy After Bankruptcy'], ['Privacy', 'History of Privacy', 'Degrees of Privacy', 'Modern Privacy Risks', 'Case Study: Targeted Ads', 'Case Study: The Naked Mile', 'Case Study: Sneaky Mobile Apps'], ['Anonymity', 'De-identification Has Limited Value: Part 1', 'De-identification Has Limited Value: Part 2', 'Case Study: Credit Card Statements'], ['Validity', 'Choice of Attributes and Measures', 'Errors in Data Processing', 'Errors in Model Design', 'Managing Change', 'Case Study: Three Blind Mice', 'Case Study: Algorithms and Race', 'Case Study: Algorithms in the Office', 'Case Study: GermanWings Crash', 'Case Study: Google Flu'], ['Algorithmic Fairness', 'Correct But Misleading Results', 'P Hacking', 'Case Study: High Throughput Biology', 'Case Study: Geopricing', 'Case Study: Your Safety Is My Lost Income'], ['Societal Impact', 'Ossification', 'Surveillance', 'Case Study: Social Credit Scores', 'Case Study: Predictive Policing'], ['Code of Ethics', 'Wrap Up', 'Case Study: Algorithms and Facial Recognition'], ['Week 1 Attributions', 'Week 2 Attributions', 'Week 3 Attributions', 'Week 4 Attributions']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This is really a great course. It is a starting point for anyone who want to get deeper into Data Science Ethics. Even if I feel that I am fairly familiar with the topic, I learned a lot and particular the case studies were really great. It should be a must for anyone in Data Science.', 'This couse presented some interesting case studies, but never presented a real ethical system.  In particular, the instructor frequently equated ethical behavior with socially acceptable behavior (this activity by corporation x was unethical because it resulted in public outcry).  Someone with a background in ethics really should have been consulted in course developement.  ', 'Excellent Course!', 'Terrific course reviewing the ethical considerations surrounding use of big data.', 'Taking course showed me the usually neglected ethics of Data. Simple yet very vital.', 'Crisp with lot of examples', 'Absolutely delightful to have Professor Jagadish walking us through the course.  The course was informative and very stimulating.  Opens up to a new world of data science ethics.  Thank you! ', 'Best course for Data Science Ethics', 'Very much interactive and content ful', 'Really liked the way the info was presented.', "This course is short, slow, and easy, but I ranked it five stars because the content is important in today's growing reliance on data science.", 'A rigorous, mind-opening course on the ethical questions raised by the collection and use of data. ', 'Excellent Course. Gives interesting and detailed perspectives on ethical matters related to how data can be used and should be used. ', 'Definitely a good choice fo the beginners in this topic. Highly recommended for the Europeans as the American regulations differ and the course covers most of them. Interesting reading materials that encourage to do research on your own.', 'I liked this course very much and Data Science Ethics explained very nice manner. I will recommend to join this course. ', "I like to think I'm an ethical person, but this course challenged me about some biases I hadn't even considered.  It's a well presented course that won't demand that you put hours and hours in every week. ", 'Very informative and enough case studies to show examples. Highly recommended for data scientists.', 'Very relevant and interesting course. I recommend it.', 'It is quite amazing I took this course. I was able to apply it to other scenarios in my personal online life. ', 'liked the case study at end of each topic', 'Short, but great course for beginners that gives interesting perspectives on some ethical matters in data science.', 'As I expected, the course provided me a lot of food for thought.', 'The course has been well developed with the learner in mind. The material was interesting and covered some topics in which I was interested. The assessment aided the learning process.', 'It is really good course, all described topics are highly important to know for everyone who working with data and information. ', 'I really enjoyed the material and the way it was presented. Even though I am not new to the topic, still more avenues and perspectives were supported with very good examples. Very refreshing.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Kim K L', 'By Aaron Z', 'By adriana s l e', 'By Lyn M R', 'By Dunsin F', 'By Ramkumar I', 'By Anny Y', 'By PRANAV P K', 'By Amitkumar H B', 'By Menashe M', 'By Joel D M', 'By Nicole R', 'By Sahibzada A M', 'By Lukasz S', 'By BHAVESH N P', 'By Christopher A', 'By Senthanal S M', 'By Greg S', 'By Philip A', 'By Vibha14', 'By Eise d V', 'By Marco M', 'By Keith C', 'By Yevhenii S', 'By Leila T A']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 09, 2018', 'Feb 17, 2018', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Apr 22, 2018', 'Jul 05, 2018', 'Jun 12, 2018', 'Jul 01, 2018', 'May 13, 2018', 'May 15, 2018', 'Feb 15, 2018', 'Mar 06, 2018', 'Feb 13, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2017', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Aug 20, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Jun 03, 2019', 'Jun 09, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>