<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_225</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/real-life-data-science</course_url><course_name>Data Science in Real Life</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian Caffo, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Have you ever had the perfect data science experience? The data pull went perfectly. There were no merging errors or missing data. Hypotheses were clearly defined prior to analyses. Randomization was performed for the treatment of interest. The analytic plan was outlined prior to analysis and followed exactly. The conclusions were clear and actionable decisions were obvious. Has that every happened to you? Of course not. Data analysis in real life is messy. How does one manage a team facing real data analyses? In this one-week course, we contrast the ideal with what happens in real life. By contrasting the ideal, you will learn key concepts that will help you manage real life analyses. 

This is a focused course designed to rapidly get you up to speed on doing data science in real life. Our goal was to make this as convenient as possible for you without sacrificing any essential content. We've left the technical information aside so that you can focus on managing your team and moving it forward.

After completing this course you will know how to:

1, Describe the “perfect” data science experience
2. Identify strengths and weaknesses in experimental designs
3. Describe possible pitfalls when pulling / assembling data and learn solutions for managing data pulls.
4. Challenge statistical modeling assumptions and drive feedback to data analysts
5. Describe common pitfalls in communicating data analyses
6. Get a glimpse into a day in the life of a data analysis manager.

The course will be taught at a conceptual level for active managers of data scientists and statisticians.  Some key concepts being discussed include:
1. Experimental design, randomization, A/B testing
2. Causal inference, counterfactuals, 
3. Strategies for managing data quality.
4. Bias and confounding
5. Contrasting machine learning versus classical statistical inference

Course promo:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9BIYmw5wnBI

Course cover image by Jonathan Gross. Creative Commons BY-ND https://flic.kr/p/q1vudb</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Data Science//Data Analysis//Data Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction, the perfect data science experience</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Just for fun, course promotional video', 'Data science in the ideal versus real life Part 1', 'Data science in the ideal versus real life Part 2', 'Examples', 'Machine Learning vs. Traditional Statistics Part 1', 'Machine Learning vs. Traditional Statistics Part 2', 'Managing the Data Pull', 'Experimental design and observational analysis', 'Causality part 1', 'Causality Part 2', 'What Can Go Wrong?: Confounding', 'A/B Testing', 'Sampling bias and random sampling', 'Blocking and adjustment', 'Multiplicity', 'Effect size, significance, &amp; modeling', 'Comparison with benchmark effects', 'Negative controls', 'Non-significance', 'Estimation Target is Relevant', 'Report writing', 'Version control']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 6 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This is a recommended course where you understand what are the requirements for a data engineer, data manager and data scientis', 'GREAT COURSE!!! ', 'Good learning', 'Great practice example, great team at Zillow, and that to DataCamp', "It's an excellent course. I have learnt a lot.", 'It is a helpful course about a statistical area. I recommend it. ', 'thanks!', 'Very informative and a good introduction into the aspects faced while doing Data Science!', '  Interesting for a Non-Data Science Executive despite some minor spelling errors in video transcripts.  ', 'Excellent course! Very interesting!', None, 'Very easy to follow with good examples. The focus on this course was on practicality and I really appreciated that', 'Excellent', None, 'Excellent course. The material is good enough that will help me where to look for information, considerations, a', 'Excellent presentation.  Very practical and relevant.', 'Good review on how to work and interact with the team during the data analysis pipeline!', 'An excellent overview of the topic material without a lot of unnecessary clutter. Well-organized and -communicated. Kudos.', 'I just finished this course but I cant enroll to the last one (I have 4/5 course in this moment). Can you please help me?? thanks!!!', 'Excellent course, material and superior teaching.', 'This course was really good. Good articulation on randomization and why we do randomization.', 'Detailed view on how to look at real life data', 'Was great!!! love it ;)', 'Clear explanation of various concepts with good examples. Of course, reference to some cool cartoons from time to time made the concepts more memorable!', 'The course is a good compilation of essential concepts to avoid pitfalls during analysis. Most material is given a short intro only, so a good data science background is needed to appreciate the material presented here.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Liping L', 'By Kim K R', 'By Ng T C', 'By ELINGUI P U', 'By Alzum S M', 'By BAHAR A', 'By Hector R C C', 'By Jason G', 'By Elton K', 'By Jocelyn D', 'By Emmanuelle M', 'By Roque A', 'By Wladimir R', 'By Gabriela E L M', 'By william K', 'By Joseph S', 'By Felix E R P', 'By Michael A L', 'By Edgar A C V', 'By Ajay P', 'By Ramkumar', 'By Sanketh G', 'By Claudia Z', 'By Manjunatha V M', 'By pamandeep s g']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 29, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Sep 08, 2018', 'Oct 10, 2018', 'Sep 24, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'May 08, 2017', 'Jan 04, 2017', 'Aug 01, 2017', 'Jun 15, 2016', 'Mar 31, 2018', 'May 15, 2018', 'Feb 21, 2016', 'Jul 01, 2017', 'Aug 02, 2017', 'Aug 20, 2017', 'Jan 07, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2015']</review_date></doc>