<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_89</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/powerpoint-presentations</course_url><course_name>Effective Business Presentations with Powerpoint</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Mannella</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is all about presenting the story of the data, using PowerPoint. You'll learn how to structure a presentation, to include insights and supporting data. You'll also learn some design principles for effective visuals and slides. You'll gain skills for client-facing communication - including public speaking, executive presence and compelling storytelling. Finally, you'll be given a client profile, a business problem, and a set of basic Excel charts, which you'll need to turn into a presentation - which you'll deliver with iterative peer feedback.

This course was created by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP with an address at 300 Madison Avenue, New York, New York, 10017.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Communication//Presentation Design//Presentation</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>PwC</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Preparing a Presentation//Communication styles//Creating effective slides using PowerPoint//Delivering a presentation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Course 4', 'Welcome to Week 1', 'The eight-step approach to prepare for a presentation', 'Step 1 - Know your audience and Step 2 - Know your purpose', 'Step 3 - Structure the body of your presentation', 'Step 4 - Plan how you will start your presentation', 'Step 5 - Plan how you will end your presentation', 'Step 6 - Prepare your visual aids', 'Step 7 - Anticipate the questions you may be asked', 'Step 8 - Practice your presentation', 'Presenting on short notice', 'Week 1 Closing', 'A Message from our Chief People Officer at PwC'], ['Introduction to Week 2', 'Maximizing your professional presence', 'Communicating with confidence', 'Verbal communications', 'Non-verbal communications', 'Cultural Considerations in Communication', 'Culture and Presentations', 'Questioning and listening skills', 'Week 2 Closing'], ['Introduction to Week 3', 'Introduction to PowerPoint (2013)', 'What type of deck should you use?', 'Structure your storyline', 'Creating a storyboard', 'Primary elements of slide design', 'Displaying data', 'Finalizing your deck', 'Week 3 Closing'], ['Introduction to Week 4', 'Week 4 and Course Wrap-Up']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Classes are small, assignments are big.', 'We would have made presentation on many events, but the way we should follow the 8-steps mentioned in this course will make it more easy for us on how to approach any presentation to present our findings. Good course to build up more on your presentation skills.', 'I recommend this course to everyone . This course definitely helped me improve my presentation skills and I also got to interact with my fellow course mates .', 'good', 'Thank you for making me learn a lot about power points, tips, and other exercises', 'Very useful course with a lot of information! Thank you!', 'Excellent course!', 'The focus of this course is not how to use Powerpoint. It is meant to teach how properly do a business presentation. And it is very professional.', 'well done course! the instructors are literally delivering and set examples of the presentation techniques in the video as well.', 'It is really good, very professional, well explanations of all the  participants, clear explanations, so much materials and examples to underestand importants aspects of a professional impecable presentation at any context. EXCELENT!\n', 'great course. In this course you will learn how to present your project to the audience.Love this course. Great course. Thank You Coursera.Keep it Up!', 'Till now this course is interesting.', 'Excelent course!', 'Excellent course! Easy to understand and very professional!', 'Great course', None, 'Well designed course', 'I consider myself pretty good with Power Point, I do a lot of the best practices, but this taught me more efficient ways to do it!', 'Super bueno este curso. enseñan muchas herramientas necesarias para presentación efectiva.', 'This has been a very exciting experience mainly because of the communication process taught to us. I was highly impressed!', "It's an awesome course.", 'Love this course, particularly the emphasis on communication, beyond the slides.', 'If you have ever wondered why your presentations do not deliver the desired impact or how is it that certain presenters are able to deliver impactful presentations consistently, then this is the course for you. Thorough and thoroughly enjoyable. Plenty to take away as long as you put it into practice! ', None, 'Vey good course to imporve presentation skills. Its not only useful for Data analytics but for all business functions as we have to present our ideas, performance and analysis across all functions of business .']</reviews><reviewers>['By 柯安丽', 'By Drasti D', 'By Madhav L', 'By DHANU P K', 'By Laras S', 'By Yulia S', 'By Paul J', 'By Diego A Q', 'By sutan a m', 'By Adalis F', 'By SAYANTA S R', 'By Gyanendra K', 'By lucio m', 'By Iselie I', 'By Rebecca C', 'By Nasr S N B', 'By Syed Z A', 'By Matthew D', 'By Manuel G', 'By DONGO B K J', 'By Sankar R', 'By Chika E', 'By Avais', 'By Priyank B', 'By Abhishek K']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 19, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'Sep 28, 2018', 'Oct 25, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2017', 'Apr 18, 2017', 'Sep 08, 2017', 'Jun 04, 2017', 'Nov 23, 2017', 'Jul 31, 2017', 'May 04, 2017', 'Jan 25, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2017', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'May 13, 2017', 'Apr 03, 2018']</review_date></doc>