<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_372</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/healthcare-data-models</course_url><course_name>Healthcare Data Models</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Doug Berman</course_instructor><course_introduction>Career prospects are bright for those qualified to work in healthcare data analytics. Perhaps you work in data analytics, but are considering a move into healthcare where your work can improve people’s quality of life. If so, this course gives you a glimpse into why this work matters, what you’d be doing in this role, and what takes place on the Path to Value where data is gathered from patients at the point of care, moves into data warehouses to be prepared for analysis, then moves along the data pipeline to be transformed into valuable insights that can save lives, reduce costs, to improve healthcare and make it more accessible and affordable. Perhaps you work in healthcare but are considering a transition into a new role. If so, this course will help you see if this career path is one you want to pursue. You’ll get an overview of common data models and their uses. You’ll learn how various systems integrate data, how to ensure clear communication, measure and improve data quality. Data analytics in healthcare serves doctors, clinicians, patients, care providers, and those who carry out the business of improving health outcomes. This course of study will give you a clear picture of data analysis in today’s fast-changing healthcare field and the opportunities it holds for you.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Health Informatics</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.1</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Healthcare Data Models//Data Models and Use Cases They Support//Working with Data across Systems//Improving the Quality of Healthcare Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Module 1 Introduction', 'What is a Data Model?', 'Speaking the Same Language and Capturing the Context', 'The Uniqueness of Data Models as Used in Healthcare', 'Path to Value: Operational Systems to Actionable Information, Part 1', 'Path to Value: Operational Systems to Actionable Information, Part 2', 'Data Flows among Systems and Keeping Systems Connected', "What We're Measuring in Healthcare Data Models, Part 1", "What We're Measuring in Healthcare Data Models, Part 2"], ['Module 2 Introduction', 'Selecting a Data Model', 'The Hierarchical Model and Supported Use Cases', 'The Relational Schema and Supported Use Cases', 'The Star Schema and Supported Use Cases', 'Comparing and Contrasting Healthcare Data Models'], ['Module 3 Introduction', 'Purpose, Use Cases, and Measurements in Healthcare Data', 'Normalization of Healthcare Data', 'Integrating Healthcare Data Across Sources and Systems', 'Common Identifiers and The Master Patient Index (MPI)'], ['Module 4 Introduction', 'Data Quality: Driven by Questions We Ask and Levels of Use', 'Verification and Validation of Data for Consistency: Finding Data Errors', 'Data Mapping', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent instructor', 'Great examples and reinforces what the goals of each module are.', None, 'Healthcare Data Models is a great course that elaborately exposed various models relevant for healthcare data analysis.', 'Intro level. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Luke M D', 'By Rosetta T', 'By Zhikuan Q', 'By Justice D A', 'By uma k']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 30, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Apr 23, 2019']</review_date></doc>