<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_112</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/foundations-big-data-analysis-sql</course_url><course_name>Foundations for Big Data Analysis with SQL</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Glynn Durham</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, you'll get a big-picture view of using SQL for big data, starting with an overview of data, database systems, and the common querying language (SQL). Then you'll learn the characteristics of big data and SQL tools for working on big data platforms. You'll also install an exercise environment (virtual machine) to be used through the specialization courses, and you'll have an opportunity to do some initial exploration of databases and tables in that environment.

By the end of the course, you will be able to
• distinguish operational from analytic databases, and understand how these are applied in big data;
• understand how database and table design provides structures for working with data;
• appreciate how differences in volume and variety of data affects your choice of an appropriate database system;
• recognize the features and benefits of SQL dialects designed to work with big data systems for storage and analysis; and 
• explore databases and tables in a big data platform.

To use the hands-on environment for this course, you need to download and install a virtual machine and the software on which to run it. Before continuing, be sure that you have access to a computer that meets the following hardware and software requirements:
• Windows, macOS, or Linux operating system (iPads and Android tablets will not work)
• 64-bit operating system (32-bit operating systems will not work)
• 8 GB RAM or more
• 25GB free disk space or more
• Intel VT-x or AMD-V virtualization support enabled (on Mac computers with Intel processors, this is always enabled;
on Windows and Linux computers, you might need to enable it in the BIOS)
• For Windows XP computers only: You must have an unzip utility such as 7-Zip or WinZip installed (Windows XP’s built-in unzip utility will not work)</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Database (DBMS)//Data Warehousing//Data Analysis//Big Data//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Cloudera</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Data and Databases//Relational Databases and SQL//Big Data//SQL Tools for Big Data Analysis//Introduction to the Hands-On Environment</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Specialization', 'Welcome to the Course and Week 1', 'What Is Data?', 'Why Organize Data?', 'What Does a DBMS Do?', 'Relational Databases and SQL', 'The Success of RDBMSs and SQL', 'Operational and Analytic Databases', 'Comparing Operational and Analytic DBs: SELECT Statements', 'Comparing Operational and Analytic DBs: DML Activity', 'Operational and Analytic Databases: Further Comparisons'], ['Welcome to Week 2', 'Introducing Table Schemas', 'NULL Values', 'Data Types', 'Primary Keys', 'Foreign Keys', 'Two Strategies for Database Design', 'Database Normalization', 'Denormalization', 'Differences', 'Trade-offs', 'Database Transactions', 'ACID', 'Enforcing Business Rules: Constraints and Triggers', 'Business Rules and ACID for Analytics?'], ['Welcome to Week 3 and the Three Vs of Big Data', 'How Big Is Big Data?', 'Distributed Storage', 'Distributed Processing', 'Structured Data', 'Unstructured Data', 'Semi-Structured Data', 'Strengths of Traditional RDBMSs', 'Limitations of Traditional RDBMSs', 'SQL and Structured Data', 'SQL and Semi-structured Data', 'SQL and Unstructured Data'], ['Welcome to Week 4', 'Big Data Analytic Databases (Data Warehouses)', 'NoSQL: Operational, Unstructured and Semi-structured', 'Non-transactional, Structured Systems', 'Big Data ACID-Compliant RDBMSs', 'Search Engines', 'Challenges', 'What We Keep', 'What We Give Up', 'What We Add', 'Where to Store Big Data', 'Coupling of Data and Metadata'], ['Welcome to Week 5', 'Apache Hive', 'Apache Impala', 'Exploring Structured Data in Hue', 'Welcome to the Honors Track', 'Honors Track Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Big data is the one of the most emerging technologies in the world and this cloudera course will definitely help us to understand the hive and impala with practical. ', 'Best course for learning the basic concept about big data and SQL.', 'Amazing', 'very well explained. ', 'Its really a good start for beginners ', 'Amazing course, full of useful information, the quiz are good way to test your knowledge and the instructor is an expert in this field and has very good presentation skills.', "If you don't have any background about SQL and you don't know where to start, I think this is the best course to start. It simplifies the concepts into easy ideas to be understandable. ", 'good course!!!', 'Best course I have ever taken', 'If you are an "absolute" novice with no knowledge about RDBMS and Big Data systems and all help from YouTube videos and other online resources have been of little to no help then you must take this course. It teaches you the very fundamentals of database design and builds your knowledge from ground up. It takes you from "What is DBMS" to a much higher level in a very short span. And Glynn is perhaps the best teacher you\'ve ever met in your life! Give this course a try and you\'ll be happy and better off for having done so. Good luck and "THANK YOU GLYNN!".', "Great course, I'm amazed", 'Awesome foundation to build on skills of query and analysis of big data and to use big data technologies like Hive and Impala', "It was a productive experience overall and a good introduction to the world of big data. A good way to understand the difference between some SLQ engines and how to organize huge amount of data. I'm looking forward to begin the second one. "]</reviews><reviewers>['By pawan k', 'By Abhinav S U', 'By CHETAN N', 'By YipengSong', 'By Voleti L', 'By Abdullah K', 'By Anas', 'By Gianfranco P', 'By Muller H', 'By Anoop B', 'By Jose M N F', 'By Ahmed E', 'By Santiago J G M']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 27, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Jul 11, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Jul 26, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Aug 17, 2019', 'Aug 21, 2019', 'Aug 25, 2019', 'Sep 03, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019']</review_date></doc>