<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_155</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/inferential-statistical-analysis-python</course_url><course_name>Inferential Statistical Analysis with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brenda Gunderson</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, we will explore basic principles behind using data for estimation and for assessing theories. We will analyze both categorical data and quantitative data, starting with one population techniques and expanding to handle comparisons of two populations. We will learn how to construct confidence intervals. We will also use sample data to assess whether or not a theory about the value of a parameter is consistent with the data. A major focus will be on interpreting inferential results appropriately.  

At the end of each week, learners will apply what they’ve learned using Python within the course environment. During these lab-based sessions, learners will work through tutorials focusing on specific case studies to help solidify the week’s statistical concepts, which will include further deep dives into Python libraries including Statsmodels, Pandas, and Seaborn. This course utilizes the Jupyter Notebook environment within Coursera.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Confidence Interval//Python Programming//Statistical Inference//Statistical Hypothesis Testing</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>WEEK 1 - OVERVIEW &amp; INFERENCE PROCEDURES//WEEK 2 - CONFIDENCE INTERVALS//WEEK 3 - HYPOTHESIS TESTING//WEEK 4 - LEARNER APPLICATION</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course!', 'Introduction to Inference Methods: Oh the Things You Will See!', 'Bag A or Bag B?', 'Introduction to Bayesian', 'This or That? Language and Notation', 'The Python Statistics Landscape', 'Intermediate Python Concepts: Lists vs Numpy Arrays', 'Functions and Lambda Functions, Reading Help Files'], ['Estimating a Population Proportion with Confidence', 'Understanding Confidence Intervals', 'Demo: Seeing Theory', 'Assumptions for a Single Population Proportion Confidence Interval', 'Conservative Approach &amp; Sample Size Consideration', 'Estimating a Difference in Population Proportions with Confidence', 'Interpretations &amp; Assumptions for Two Population Proportion Intervals', 'Estimating a Population Mean with Confidence', 'Estimating a Mean Difference for Paired Data', 'Estimating a Difference in Population Means with Confidence (for Independent Groups)', 'Chocolate &amp; Cycling Assignment', 'Introduction to Confidence Intervals in Python', 'Confidence Intervals for Differences between Population Parameters'], ['Setting Up a Test for a Population Proportion', 'Testing a One Population Proportion', 'Setting Up a Test of Difference in Population Proportions', 'Testing a Difference in Population Proportions', 'Interview: P-Values, P-Hacking and More', 'One Mean: Testing about a Population Mean with Confidence', 'Testing a Population Mean Difference', 'Testing for a Difference in Population Means (for Independent Groups)', 'Demo: Name That Scenario', 'Introduction to Hypothesis Testing in Python', 'Walk-Through: Hypothesis Testing with NHANES'], ['The Importance of Good Research Questions for Sound Inference', 'Descriptive Inference Examples for Single Variables Using Confidence Intervals', 'Descriptive Inference Examples for Single Variables Using Hypothesis Testing', 'Comparing Means for Two Independent Samples: An Example', 'Comparing Means for Two Paired Samples: An Example', 'Comparing Proportions for Two Independent Samples: An Example']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 20 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Do you do usability tests of your courses? Like you can test a landing page - you pick a random person to perform a certain action on your landing page, and see where they struggle or what is unclear? If you did this with this course before going live, it would benefit everyone. Right now the quality of this course is too low, concepts are not explained enough, and the assignments (especially week 3) contain wrong instructions and errors.', 'If you want to learn basic and inferential statistics - I would advise checking out the courses with these name from by University of Amsterdam(you can take them without taking the specialization). they are much clearer. And then if you want examples of Python code - take this course. Just check out the forums first. As of jan2019 the Python Notebook used for the week3 assessment had various problems.', "This course attempts to cover very useful topics but falls short on several areas. 1. Multiple errors in the assignments. Practice exercises don't have any answers for students to check. 2. Course slides are not provided. 3. Lack of support to questions asked in forum. I learned a lot from the course but a significant amount of time could have been saved if the issues I mentioned were addressed.", 'Alltogether the course was great. I learned so much and understood some principles I did not understand when having read of them before.', 'Great lecture content. Poor quiz design.', "Good lectures but too little practice and quizzes that don't cover all the material. Very little Python. ", '\nThe course contents are good to an introduction or refreshing in statistics but the assigments are not really well prepared, and contains many unrepaired errors. This drops down the level an educational potential of this course (and the entire specialization) and converts it in a poor educational resource and a  waste of time, in my opinion\n\n', 'Very clear and interesting lectures, but quizzes and Jupyter notebooks could benefit from some additional proofreading and pre-release testing.  Material in last week is out of order.   Spent a few hours some week just figuring out the mistakes with the help of the course forum.', "I must say that this is a must take course for ones who are aspiring a career in Data Science. All the concepts were laid out so beautifully and it was explained very clearly with visualisations of each real-life-examples. I enrolled in this specialisation before starting my Machine Learning so that I have all the necessary fundamentals of Statistics. Brady Sir &amp; Brendra Ma'am are simply phenomenal, the way they explain the concepts are incredible. The concepts gets etched in one's memory. ", 'In this course, they cover making confidence intervals and calculating p-values given a specific test scenario (compare sample proportion to population proportion, sample mean to population mean, two sample means to each other, etc). While they go though each statistical procedure clearly, I feel like a lot of underlying context is missing. What is the different between a z- and t-distribution? Why do we use those distributions? How do the different tests relate to each other? Etc. It feels like this course needed an extra 50-60 minutes of lecture time to tie all these concepts together. A textbook to follow along would have been great too.', "This course is a good statistics course, but a poor Python course. Python is practically an after thought in each week's lesson as the focus in the lecturing learning methods is entirely verbal rather than supported by in lecture use of Python. The Python review at the end of each week before the assessment is not connected enough with the lecture materials and makes for a very disjointed week of learning.", 'If you are interested in statistics and statistical analysis, this course gets you grounded in the essential aspects of statistics. Excellent instructors. ', 'Excellent', 'Absolutely great course of inferential statistics!', 'This course is significantly better than the previous one. Nevertheless, if you want to get knowledge about Python, it’s not about this course.', 'Amazing course! Very useful for all kind of Analysis!', 'A very in-depth learning material for inferential statistics. Very good explanation of p-value which clarifies some of the prevailing misunderstandings.', 'I enjoy the lectures. The professor has a good speaking and teaching style which keeps me interested. Lots of concrete math examples which make it easier to understand. Very good slides which are well formulated and easy to understand', 'The python codes are amazing.', 'A complete course focused on teaching the details and intuition of experiment design, inferential analysis for decision making through confidence interval ans hypothesis testing and how to state effective questions. ', 'The content explanation is excellent and one of the best I have seen.', 'I really appreciate the course and let me accumulate a lot of knowledge about statistics. And I have developed a good impression of the University of Michigan teaching level.', 'It was very good course, everything was very well explained and the activities were challenging enough to practice the knowledges obtain.', 'I really enjoyed the course. ', 'Good theoretical foundation, but lacks explanation on python libraries extensively used in the course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Emil K', 'By Yaron K', 'By Jin S', 'By Tobias R', 'By David Z', 'By Daniel R', 'By José A G P', 'By Iver B', 'By Aayush G', 'By ILYA N', 'By Michael D', 'By Rajesh R', 'By cameron g', 'By Varga I K', 'By Yaroslav B', 'By EDILSON S S O J', 'By JIANG X', 'By Jafed E', 'By 고도균', 'By Vinícius G d O', 'By Parvatharajan K', 'By Bonnie', 'By Maria G', 'By Frank S Y R', 'By Yury P']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 27, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Apr 16, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'May 28, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Apr 22, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'May 29, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Jul 12, 2019', 'Jul 13, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Sep 11, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Jul 08, 2019']</review_date></doc>