<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_377</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/meaningful-predictive-modeling</course_url><course_name>Meaningful Predictive Modeling</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Julian McAuley</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will help us to evaluate and compare the models we have developed in previous courses. So far we have developed techniques for regression and classification, but how low should the error of a classifier be (for example) before we decide that the classifier is "good enough"? Or how do we decide which of two regression algorithms is better?

By the end of this course you will be familiar with diagnostic techniques that allow you to evaluate and compare classifiers, as well as performance measures that can be used in different regression and classification scenarios. We will also study the training/validation/test pipeline, which can be used to ensure that the models you develop will generalize well to new (or "unseen") data.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1: Diagnostics for Data//Week 2: Codebases, Regularization, and Evaluating a Model//Week 3: Validation and Pipelines//Final Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Course 3: Meaningful Predictive Modeling', 'Motivation Behind the MSE', 'Regression Diagnostics: MSE and R²', 'Over- and Under-Fitting', 'Classification Diagnostics: Accuracy and Error', 'Classification Diagnostics: Precision and Recall'], ['Setting Up a Codebase for Evaluation and Validation', 'Model Complexity and Regularization', 'Adding a Regularizer to our Model, and Evaluating the Regularized Model', 'Evaluating Classifiers for Ranking'], ['Validation', '“Theorems” About Training, Testing, and Validation', 'Implementing a Regularization Pipeline in Python', 'Guidelines on the Implementation of Predictive Pipelines'], ['Project Description', 'Where to Find Datasets']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>English</course_time><reviews>['Great course', 'Peer review system HAS TO CHANGE, IT IS VERY POOR currently - As I type this review, I am waiting for my assignment review for around a weeks time now, no luck in getting any feedback no matter how many threads you make or post in discussion forums like mentioned in FAQs. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Oriol P M', 'By Surendar R']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 16, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019']</review_date></doc>