<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_3</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-data-analysis</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Data Science in Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Christopher Brooks</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce the learner to the basics of the python programming environment, including fundamental python programming techniques such as lambdas, reading and manipulating csv files, and the numpy library. The course will introduce data manipulation and cleaning techniques using the popular python pandas data science library and introduce the abstraction of the Series and DataFrame as the central data structures for data analysis, along with tutorials on how to use functions such as groupby, merge, and pivot tables effectively. By the end of this course, students will be able to take tabular data, clean it, manipulate it, and run basic inferential statistical analyses. 

This course should be taken before any of the other Applied Data Science with Python courses: Applied Plotting, Charting &amp; Data Representation in Python, Applied Machine Learning in Python, Applied Text Mining in Python, Applied Social Network Analysis in Python.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Numpy//Pandas//Data Cleansing</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Specialization', 'Data Science', 'The Coursera Jupyter Notebook System', 'Python Functions', 'Python Types and Sequences', 'Python More on Strings', 'Python Demonstration: Reading and Writing CSV files', 'Python Dates and Times', 'Advanced Python Objects, map()', 'Advanced Python Lambda and List Comprehensions', 'Advanced Python Demonstration: The Numerical Python Library (NumPy)'], ['Introduction', 'The Series Data Structure', 'Querying a Series', 'The DataFrame Data Structure', 'DataFrame Indexing and Loading', 'Querying a DataFrame', 'Indexing Dataframes', 'Missing Values'], ['Merging Dataframes', 'Pandas Idioms', 'Group by', 'Scales', 'Pivot Tables', 'Date Functionality'], ['Introduction', 'Distributions', 'More Distributions', 'Hypothesis Testing in Python']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I am surprised that it was a 4-week course. It could have been condensed to 1 slide stating "Go read a few books and if you\'re stuck, consult Stackoverflow".\n', 'It was the worst experience I had in coursera. The video content is too general and has little connection with assignment. The assignments are challenging but poorly organized. Students are encouraged to search and self-learning, which is irresponsible and inefficient. I register the course to learn things systematically and save time! I spent about 8 hours on searching desperately for each assignment. My passion for Python and Data Science almost disappear. ', "Extremely dissatisfied. Lectures are useless and the instructor didn't put any effort into designing a curriculum. After struggling for days on the second assignment I purchased the recommended text for the class. Week 2 effectively starts at chapter 7 in the book. Instructor needs to replace his absurd amount of face time some slides showing the application and logic behind the methods he is trying to use. Jupiter notebook is a tool designed to make the instructors job easier, doesn't help the student at all. I could go on but this course has drained the energy from me. FYI, half the people that complete (or attempt to to complete) this course don't continue on with the specialization. This should speak volumes. ", 'Huge disparity between the course videos and the assignments provided. A background in basic programming is highly recommended. The assignments provided are of good quality however, and provide a great learning experience given one can get through them.', "I'm not sure you should be paying for a course where you have to search the Internet to learn how to do the assignmens. I could be doing that for free! Is the certificate worth it? ", 'This is not a course, rather just guidance to use StackOverflow. The trainer Prof. Brooks is highly unlively and plainly reads out/speaks some statements. He teaches only 10%, remaining 90% you need to explore on your own. The Assignments have the most difficult questions and for solving them, students are not even given any getting-started questions, to begin with! If you wish to learn Data Science/Data Analysis then I would not recommend this course since it is not worth the time, effort and money. Also, the title of the course is devaluing the efforts we put it. The entire course is focused towards using Pandas to perform Data Analysis / Data Cleaning / Data Wrangling / Data Munging / Data Preprocessing and thus I would recommend that the title of the course should be one of these rather than "Introduction ..." which hardly gives any weight to what hard work this certification demands!', 'This is a terrible course. The "instructors" give quick little lectures, then we\'re told, for the somewhat complicated (for a beginner) assignments, to look things up on StackOverflow to figure out how to do the assignments. Um, no. I want a class so I don\'t have to tear my hair out dealing with the internet.', 'Very rare I write review. And this is rare course that teaches nothing. The lector explains nothing. "I encourage you self-learning. Read the documentation. Search google. Ask stackoverflow.com. If you don\'t know python, take another python course. If you don\'t know statistics, take another statistics course. I encourage you self-learning even more." - that is what lector sais to you.\n\n', "I found this course terribly bad and was the worst experience I had in Coursera. The instructor, rushes through few minutes of video explanations and then it is basically a learn everything by yourself by reading the panda documentation. If I wanted to learn things by myself reading the panda documentation, I wouldn't have taken the course! Like someone else mentioned, I registered the course to learn things systematically and save time!\n", 'Excellent\nmaterial. Admittedly I can see why there are so many negative reviews about the\nambiguity of the assessed tasks. It won\'t be an easy course for anyone who is\nunfamiliar with programming. However, if you do have programming\nexperience under your belt, you\'ll likely find this course strikes an\nexcellent balance in terms of conciseness, practice, and theory. Each\nlecture is crafted carefully to teach you about some nuance of pandas or numpy,\nand the programming assignments are packed with coding questions that will help\nyou revise what you have learned, in a very efficient way. There is very little\n"fluff" in this course, which is a major weakness I\'ve seen in\nsimilar courses of its kind. Too much spoon feeding often does not challenge or\nengage the learner. The course is very direct about what it expects of its\nstudents. Every week there is a comment "This week\'s assignment requires\nmore self-learning than the last". And true to its word, there is less and\nless hand-holding as you go further into the course. I thoroughly enjoyed the\nmaterial and probably learned the most out of this course than any other course\nI\'ve taken on Coursera, taking in to account its length.', 'I have to say, the quality of this course is significantly inferior than the previous "Programming to everybody" . Firstly, it has something to do with the language that the lecturer uses to explain the concepts in Python. The language he uses is unnecessarily complicated. The sentences are very long and the words he uses are vague . If you want to explain a relatively complex concept, you need to use simpler and more comprehensible words. You cannot use a complex concept to explain another complex concept. The second thing is about the structure of the course, the insufficient engagement. The lecture is full of contents but only with very less interaction exercises. This will make students lost in the half way. I have to say this is not a pleasant experience even if I\'m already very familiar to some other programming languages such as R and C++.', 'There are several inherent problems with this course and how it is structured. I would like to preface this review by stating that I am likely below the level of python mastery required to complete the course; I came in with a simple background of some time spent learning from introductory texts, but I\'ve never worked with the language professionally and I have been out of practice for a couple years. The course is labeled \'intermediate\', though how \'intermediate\' is unclear since there is only one elementary course recommended to get you "up to speed" enough to take the class. I used my free week as a test to see if my background was enough to be able to hang with this; it was not. ', 'The course covers good grounds if you are new to pandas. However the content is pretty much a read-through of documentation and assignments are designed poorly:', 'I would not recommend this course at all.  I cancelled after week 2.  It is framed as an intro to data science but the teacher often packs too much information into each video without taking time to properly explain underlying concepts sufficiently.  The exercises often have issues in datasets that are not linked to current lesson which makes it confusing to follow along and you can spend hours searching forums to find solutions.  In addition, the course does not give sufficient insight in videos to help you with questions.  You have to search stack overflow and other sources to work out answers.  Whilst this is reflective of real life, for an intro course which is how this was framed, it is difficult for someone new to data science to master a concept whilst trying to solve for other non related issues searching the web.', "So, I have some strong opinions about this course. It should really be called Mastering Pandas for Data Science because despite the word introduction in it's name this course basically starts at an intermediate level and skips straight over teaching the basics of anything, including Pandas. You will have to already know quite well: Python, Pandas, Database style thinking and working, Statistics and Autograder intricacies. It basically took me well over 100 hours to get it done. If I had already learned Pandas or R elsewhere before it would have taken less than half that but basically everything I did had to be looked up on StackOverflow or in the Pandas documentation. However, at the end of it I feel like I actually know basic level Pandas and I am now intermediate level. In the end, a great course but very, very challenging.", 'I have been doing some coding in different languages and this is my first time in Python. I would say I am on intermediate level (7 years practice), but this course made me spend a lot of time on learning only a tidy bit. The course fails in the basic educational purpose: Provide theoretical lectures and apply it with practical experience. There was little to none connection between these two aspects. The exercises were also way too difficult vs the lectures. I would never recommend this course.', 'The class is mostly problem set focused with no feedback on what makes for good pandas code beyond it getting the correct result. Not a good resource for learning the pandas library. Very little teaching. ', 'I have decided to drop this course. I have worked very hard on Assignment #3 for the course and can\'t seem to get back from the grader anything more than "Your solution file either prints output to the console (e.g.\nthrough the print() function, or it fails to run (e.g. throws an error). You\nmust make sure that the py or ipynb file which you submit does not have errors.\nThe output we received from the ipthon interpretor was:"  That\'s all I seem to get back.   ', 'The difference between exercises and lectures is too big. You end up researching elsewhere more than just follow the course.', 'Poorly designed course.  Very little guidance or content provided, ended up getting most of my insights from stackoverflow...which I can do on my own.', 'It is disappointing that most of the course is basically self-learning from publicly available resources. If self-learning was what I wanted, I could do with reading the Pandas documentation instead and spare myself the subscription fee.', "My take -- assignments for week 3 and 4 leave a bad impression. I am quitting halfway through assignment 4. I won't take another class in this sequence. I have taken ~10 online classes this year and only gave up on 2, including this one.", 'Some 2 years after finishing this course, I cannot stress enough how much I have gained from this course (or the full specialization for that matter). Having started this specialization as a social science researcher with a solid background in traditional statistical research (and total beginner with Python), I have actually managed to find a job as a Data Scientist halfway through this specialization. ', 'I thought this was course was good, and was fairly challenging for an online-only course. I thought the lectures could have been a little longer to ensure proper coverage of materials and functions.', 'great course, but the auto grader needs updating']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ivan L', 'By Wang H', 'By Thomas K', 'By Saksham S', 'By Marcus M F T', 'By Pratik M', 'By Karen B', 'By Artem E', 'By Matthieu L', 'By Lingjun L', 'By Xiaoke L', 'By Nathan H', 'By Qiaohong W', 'By Ommar H', 'By Michael N', 'By Asmund B', 'By Ben N', 'By Lorraine F', 'By Henrik F', 'By Shawn W', 'By Nikolay D', 'By Mark C', 'By Martin B', 'By Nicholas F', 'By Jonathan J']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 23, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'May 06, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Apr 12, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Jul 11, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2018', 'May 17, 2019', 'May 09, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Oct 07, 2018', 'Jun 25, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2018', 'Apr 16, 2019']</review_date></doc>