<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_41</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/decision-making</course_url><course_name>Data-driven Decision Making</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Mannella</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Data-driven Decision Making. In this course you'll get an introduction to Data Analytics and its role in business decisions. You'll learn why data is important and how it has evolved. You'll be introduced to “Big Data” and how it is used. You'll also be introduced to a framework for conducting Data Analysis and what tools and techniques are commonly used. Finally, you'll have a chance to put your knowledge to work in a simulated business setting.

This course was created by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP with an address at 300 Madison Avenue, New York, New York, 10017.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data-Informed Decision-Making//Big Data//Data Analysis//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>PwC</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Data Analytics//Technology and types of data //Data analysis techniques and tools//Data-driven decision making project </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Specialization overview', 'Welcome to Data Driven Decision Making', 'What is Data Analytics?', 'Solving business problems using data analytics', 'Making business-defining decisions using data analytics', 'A Message from our Chief People Officer at PwC', 'Why do you need a data and analytics framework?', 'The 4 aspects of the data and analytics framework', 'Data and analytics framework: tools and techniques', 'Make better and faster decisions with data and analytics', 'Data and analytics at PwC', 'Week 1 recap with Amity and Mike'], ['The marketplace and emerging trends in big data analytics', 'Business impacts of technology advancements and data trends', 'What is Big Data?', "PwC's perspective on big data", 'Data and analytics examples at PwC', 'Identifying, organizing and processing data', 'Week 2 recap with Amity and Mike'], ['Types of data analysis techniques', 'The role of Excel', 'The role of SAS', 'The role of R', 'The role of Python', 'The Power of Visualization', 'The role of QlikView', 'Week 3 recap with Amity and Mike'], ['Intro to Week 4 and Course Project', 'Course recap with Amity and Mike']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Is was disheartening to put 4 weeks of effort in 1 to try and maximize the trial window period and then you don't receive the certificate because peer-to-peer review is an unstructured process and dependent on a 3rd party who has nothing to do with my investment, my time and my performance.", "Most of this information is just an introduction and promo for PWC. Cut the material down and incorporate it into the other classes of this specialization. As a stand alone class I don't see the value of the course. ", 'This course is all theoretical knowledge, nothing about real practice on analyzing tools. If you want to learn how to use tools, go to some other courses.', 'This is a great course in data and analytics for the every day professional. It gives great insight into how data and analytics can support decision making. The mode of delivery of the course is e', 'What an excellent laid out course curriculum. Bite size learning, various mediums, understandable concepts applied to real life business cases made for a 100% take away and applied knowledge. We', 'it sucks', 'Total loss of time.', 'The Data Analytics Framework and overview of approaches, techniques and technologies are so well done that prompted me to learn more and cover gaps in knowledge. The simulation and 3 cases at the end are very important, take them seriously and do them ALL following the framework provided. I would recommend that to do those cases do not hesitate to make assumptions and do a quick wiki search on how a Financial SS, CPG or Manufacturing company work', 'Explains Data Analytics and its basics in a really simple way. Also the simulation quiz and the peer graded assignments are worth a mention. ', ' This course is not really what I was looking for. It was very gerenal and providing only a big picture of what data management is. It touched a bit about the names of software or systems for different purposes, also provided a categrization of approaches/methods for data analysis, but all in very general and high level sense. I feel this course is more for CEO level managers to have an idea, but not really instructing about real skills. I will not recommend this course if you are trying to find some in-detail insturciton about decision making process.  ', "The overall course is pretty nice but there are things that tend to become annoying along the way: (a) on the videos, please delete the 10-second introduction ; (b) I understand the promotion objective of the course for PwC but there are too much about the opportunities there, etc. On the matter, one video and a small article would be more than enough ; (c) the concrete tools are surrounded by videos which only give an overview of data analytics. I'd rather suggest to write a small article to give an overview of why data analytics is important into our world today but please, use the videos to bring concrete and actionable content.", "take this course if you want a job with PWC, but there isn't much ", 'Too much useless introductions.', 'Very low level content. No strategies or actionable lessons. ', 'Too much theory, no practice. Blah-blah-bla', 'superficial', 'non-practical course, concepts are only mentioned', 'More of a webinar than a course. ', 'Content marketing for pwc instead of an actual course', 'empty talk, no content. ', 'How can a course with so many details tell you nothing at all !?!? What a complete waste of time!', 'Basically this course was an excellent promotion of PwC as a consultant. A well crafted introduction of buzz-words with very little substance (Unlike the following courses on Excel and presentations)', 'very little useful information, more like PR for PWC', "very boring lectures. expected a lot more from something like PWC. Doesn't worth it at all. Didn't learn anything new. ", 'The reason why I am giving only one star  that the course did not covered much information and the time allotted could have been less than 4 weeks. So it was not really worth the money.  ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Suman P', 'By Jeremy J W', 'By Congyi E L', 'By Alexander J F', 'By Julia', 'By DHRUV J', 'By Victor S', 'By Carlos G B ', 'By Kinjal M', 'By Jingting X', 'By Gaëtan G', 'By John S F', 'By Jack 买', 'By Jordan O', 'By Maryna K', 'By Vadim I', 'By Anastasiia M', 'By Nitesh J', 'By Ann J', 'By Marcel', 'By Mark H', 'By Yaron K', 'By Vivian Y Q', 'By Jakhongir B', 'By Rasul Y']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 19, 2019', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Apr 17, 2019', 'May 16, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2018', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Sep 19, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2017', 'Dec 26, 2017', 'Dec 14, 2017', 'Jul 06, 2018', 'Apr 10, 2017', 'Apr 12, 2017', 'Mar 21, 2017', 'Oct 14, 2016']</review_date></doc>