<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_85</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/end-to-end-ml-tensorflow-gcp</course_url><course_name>End-to-End Machine Learning with TensorFlow on GCP</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>In the first course of this specialization, we will recap what was covered in the  Machine Learning with TensorFlow on Google Cloud Platform Specialization (https://www.coursera.org/specializations/machine-learning-tensorflow-gcp).

One of the best ways to review something is to work with the concepts and technologies that you have learned.

So, this course is set up as a workshop and in this workshop, you will do End-to-End Machine Learning with TensorFlow on Google Cloud Platform

Prerequisites:
Basic SQL, familiarity with Python and TensorFlow

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this course you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the Course//Machine Learning (ML) on Google Cloud Platform (GCP)//Explore the Data//Create the dataset//Build the Model//Operationalize the model//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Intro to Specialization', 'Course Introduction'], ['Effective ML', 'Fully managed ML'], ['Exploring the dataset', 'BigQuery', 'BigQuery and AI Platform Notebooks', 'Getting Started with Google Cloud Platform and Qwiklabs', 'Lab 1 Intro : Exploring the dataset', 'Lab 1 demo and review'], ['Creating a dataset', 'Lab 2 Intro : Create a sample dataset', 'Lab 2: demo and review'], ['Build the model', 'Lab 3 Intro : Creating a TensorFlow model', 'Lab 3 : demo and review'], ['Operationalizing the model', 'Lab 4 Intro :  Preprocessing with Cloud Dataflow', 'Lab 4 demo and review', 'Cloud AI Platform', 'Train and deploy with Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab 5 : Training on Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab 5 demo and review', 'BigQuery ML', 'Lab Introduction', 'Lab Solution BigQuery ML', 'Deploying and Predicting with Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab 6 Intro : Deploying and Predicting with Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab 6 : demo and review', 'Lab 7 : Building an App Engine app to serve ML predictions', 'Lab 7 : demo and review'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Not enough hands-on labs.  Mostly just videos and running existing python code.  Had to write only a tiny amount of code.  I won't remember any of the code, I'll just remember ctrl-enter on all of the pre-written python.... could definitely use some improvement.", 'Would be nicer if students can use the google cloud with less restrictions. I got blocked multiple times from trying the codes in the videos..', 'One of my favourites Courses from Google, it provides an excellent overview of the End to End Machine LEarning process, and how to use GCP to speed up your workflow, highly recommended to anyone looking to expand their understanding of Real World application of ML', 'Definitely adds a unique perspective on thinking about machine learning systems at scale. This course is suitable for Data Scientists, Data Engineers and Machine Learning Engineers.', 'Objective of course is great. But, a lot can be improved in terms of clarity on how to execute this course. It is not clearly mentioned whether we need to just execute provided notebooks or write code from scratch. Moreover, how to copy these notebooks from Google cloud repo on github is not mentioned anywhere.', "The course is really Great! It takes you so smoothly from the beggining to the end. I didn't have to watch something for a second time. Everything is well explained!", 'Excellent up to date content, instructors, examples and labs - #1 in the field!', 'This course contains many helpful hands-on labs. The course instructors are very knowledgeable.  I would recommend this course to anyone who is  interested in learning about production machine learning pipeline using TensorFlow. ', 'Interesting to the gcp users and ml developers.', None, 'It was great course which converses entire ml learning journey', 'nice course', 'Practical Labs are really useful in learning end to end ML in GCP', 'Super, resume la especialización 1', 'This is one of the best courses i have done. It is an essential course if you want to build real life machine learning Models', 'Awesome refresher course!', 'Very Helpful', 'Thumbs Up!', 'excellent', 'Great course!', 'Good overview course', 'Good course with complete development cycle', 'This course is awesome', 'Got good insight about the data pre-processing, training the model and deploying it on ML Engine', 'End to End wwooooww']</reviews><reviewers>['By Kevin M', 'By Panit A', 'By Carlos V', 'By Serhan A', 'By Harsh S', 'By Elias P', 'By Miroslav K', 'By Javed S', 'By SAIPRIYADARSHAN C', 'By Rajdeep A', 'By bhadresh s', 'By Kesepattapu N', 'By NAVEEN K', 'By Steven P G', 'By Amitava D', 'By Jayasudan M', 'By Parul G', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By Björn S', 'By Abdul R Y', 'By Mark D', 'By Hicham A', 'By Sushrut A', 'By Amit K', 'By Raja R G']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 06, 2018', 'Apr 27, 2019', 'Oct 07, 2018', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Jun 09, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Apr 07, 2019', 'Apr 13, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Dec 08, 2018']</review_date></doc>