<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_79</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/exploratory-data-analysis</course_url><course_name>Exploratory Data Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Roger D. Peng, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course covers the essential exploratory techniques for summarizing data. These techniques are typically applied before formal modeling commences and can help inform the development of more complex statistical models. Exploratory techniques are also important for eliminating or sharpening potential hypotheses about the world that can be addressed by the data. We will cover in detail the plotting systems in R as well as some of the basic principles of constructing data graphics. We will also cover some of the common multivariate statistical techniques used to visualize high-dimensional data.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Cluster Analysis//Ggplot2//R Programming//Exploratory Data Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Installing R on Windows (3.2.1)', 'Installing R on a Mac (3.2.1)', 'Installing R Studio (Mac)', 'Setting Your Working Directory (Windows)', 'Setting Your Working Directory (Mac)', 'Principles of Analytic Graphics', 'Exploratory Graphs (part 1)', 'Exploratory Graphs (part 2) ', 'Plotting Systems in R', 'Base Plotting System (part 1)', 'Base Plotting System (part 2)', 'Base Plotting Demonstration', 'Graphics Devices in R (part 1)', 'Graphics Devices in R (part 2)'], ['Lattice Plotting System (part 1)', 'Lattice Plotting System (part 2)', 'ggplot2 (part 1)', 'ggplot2 (part 2)', 'ggplot2 (part 3)', 'ggplot2 (part 4)', 'ggplot2 (part 5)'], ['Hierarchical Clustering (part 1)', 'Hierarchical Clustering (part 2)', 'Hierarchical Clustering (part 3)', 'K-Means Clustering (part 1)', 'K-Means Clustering (part 2)', 'Dimension Reduction (part 1)', 'Dimension Reduction (part 2)', 'Dimension Reduction (part 3)', 'Working with Color in R Plots (part 1)', 'Working with Color in R Plots (part 2)', 'Working with Color in R Plots (part 3)', 'Working with Color in R Plots (part 4)'], ['Clustering Case Study', 'Air Pollution Case Study']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This has been a challenging course for me, for whatever reasons. I have devoted a great deal of time in reading Dr. Peng's books as well as reviewing work product of other students to get a better grasp of the logic and methodology. I have enjoyed this course more than any of the preceding courses. And, the struggle I believe will be worth the effort and facilitate my completion of the data science specialization program.", 'This lesson could have been significantly improved if there was at least one assignment on clustering/dimensional reduction. Those are probably the hardest concepts thought thus far, so it would have been extremely useful to have at least one challenge to work through. ', 'Once it got to the clustering section the lessons were inscrutable. Extremely difficult to understand and not explained well.', 'This course covers plotting (base, lattice, ggplot) then takes a confusing tour into heavy topics of clustering and dimension reduction, then flips back to coloring in charts.  The order of the lectures is confusing and PCA/SVD needs more background, clearer explanation and treatment (gets covered a bit more later under regression).  Assignments are good and swirl courses helped solidify the lectures.', "This course is basically plotting with R and clustering/dimensionality reduction. There's is not enough emphasis on the later in my opinion. The final assignment focuses only on plotting, which is a shame.", "This is the worst of the Data Science courses so far (they've all been pretty good up to this point).", 'Cons:', "Provides a solid overview of the base plotting system and a discussion (better elsewhere) of others. Introduces some higher level exploratory methods, without much information on either the theory or application (simply walks through the recipe). Assessments do not match the lecture material, so the credential is essentially meaningless. Read the associated book, watch the video lectures if you'd like. Don't bother with paying for the certificate.", '  This course mostly about how to use plotting libraries in R.  ', 'The videos were merely repeating the content from swirl, with absolutely no added values. ', 'When it comes down to it, there\'s simply not the support to assist a student that has a really hard problem, "hacker mentality" seems to equate to "figure it out on your own cuz nobody\'s going to help you". If things do not work perfectly for you then you are likely never to be able to finish because your "peers" don\'t know any better either. The way this class is set up makes me angry every time I have to deal with it. I would probably be just as well served doing just the swirl() exercises. I would quit if I hadn\'t paid all the way through in advance. I can\'t believe this is the type of school John Hopkins is to produce a course of this quality, but I guess I have to.', 'really interesting', 'A very good course describing commonly used graphical techniques with good examples.', 'Fabulous ', 'Great course to learn how to play with data - a good intro to things like Kmeans and hierarchical clustering, as well.', 'Excellent course. Love the case studies', 'This has been very exciting!', 'This is a great course on plotting data as well as finding underlying patterns in it.', 'good', 'great course', 'I learned so much in this course. ', 'awesome....', 'Thank you for this course. I really learn a lot!', 'I learned a lot from this course. Content which the course covers was a third of what I learnt from this course. the best thing about it is learning the pattern of thinking about exploring a whole new dataset.', 'The course is definitely useful for my job. I learned new skills and had fun!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Dale O J', 'By Faben W', 'By JM', 'By Paul R', 'By Rok B', 'By Dilyan D', 'By Roman', 'By Daniel H', 'By Sergey K', 'By Luca R', 'By Beverly A', 'By MEKIE Y R K', 'By Avizit C A', 'By Aman U', 'By James E H J', 'By Charbel L', 'By Parker O', 'By Сетдеков К Р', 'By Razib A K', 'By Rodolfo R', 'By Cynthia M P', 'By Abhay S', 'By Justin A B', 'By Rooholamin R', 'By Hathairat W']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 16, 2018', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Jul 11, 2018', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'May 15, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2018', 'Aug 30, 2018', 'May 13, 2019', 'May 10, 2016', 'Jun 10, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2016', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019']</review_date></doc>