<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_317</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/demand-analytics</course_url><course_name>Demand Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Yao Zhao</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Demand Analytics - one of the most sought-after skills in supply chain management and marketing!

Through the real-life story and data of a leading cookware manufacturer in North America, you will learn the data analytics skills for demand planning and forecasting. Upon the completion of this course, you will be able to  

1. Improve the forecasting accuracy by building and validating demand prediction models. 
2. Better stimulate and influence demand by identifying the drivers (e.g., time, seasonality, price, and other environmental factors) for demand and quantifying their impact.

AK is a leading cookware manufacturer in North America. Its newly launched top-line product was gaining momentum in the marketplace. However, a price adjustment at the peak season stimulated a significant demand surge which took AK completely by surprise and resulted in huge backorders. AK faced the risk of losing the market momentum due to the upset customers and the high cost associated with over-time production and expedited shipping. Accurate demand forecast is essential for increasing revenue and reducing cost. Identifying the drivers for demand and assessing their impact on demand can help companies better influence and stimulate demand.

I hope you enjoy the course!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Model Selection Validation Improvement//Regression Analysis//Demand Planning and Forecasting//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Marketing Analytics</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>Rutgers the State University of New Jersey</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome!//Predicting Trend//Predicting the Impact of Price and Other Environmental Factors//Predicting Seasonality</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['The story of AK MetalCrafters', 'Course overview', 'General principles of demand planning and forecasting'], ['The basics of statistical forecasting models', 'Data collection, pre-processing and visualization', 'Data visualization screencast', 'Build and interpret a linear model', 'Build and interpret a linear model screencast'], ['Model validation and improvement', 'Multiple regression for trend, price and other factors', 'Multiple regression screencast'], ['Categorical variable (seasonality) modeling and formatting', 'Forecasting and testing', 'Forecasting and testing screencast']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[]</reviews><reviewers>[]</reviewers><review_date>[]</review_date></doc>