<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_358</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/formal-concept-analysis</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Formal Concept Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sergei Obiedkov </course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is an introduction into formal concept analysis (FCA), a mathematical theory oriented at applications in knowledge representation, knowledge acquisition, data analysis and visualization. It provides tools for understanding the data by representing it as a hierarchy of concepts or, more exactly, a concept lattice. FCA can help in processing a wide class of data types providing a framework in which various data analysis and knowledge acquisition techniques can be formulated. In this course, we focus on some of these techniques, as well as cover the theoretical foundations and algorithmic issues of FCA.
Upon completion of the course, the students will be able to use the mathematical techniques and computational tools of formal concept analysis in their own research projects involving data processing. Among other things, the students will learn about FCA-based approaches to clustering and dependency mining.
The course is self-contained, although basic knowledge of elementary set theory, propositional logic, and probability theory would help.
End-of-the-week quizzes include easy questions aimed at checking basic understanding of the topic, as well as more advanced problems that may require some effort to be solved.

Do you have technical problems? Write to us: coursera@hse.ru</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>National Research University Higher School of Economics</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Formal concept analysis in a nutshell//Concept lattices and their line diagrams//Constructing concept lattices//Implications//Interactive algorithms for learning implications//Working with real data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Formal Concept Analysis', 'What is formal concept analysis?', 'Understanding the concept lattice diagram', 'Reading concepts from the lattice diagram', 'Reading implications from the lattice diagram', 'Conceptual clustering', 'Formal contexts and derivation operators', 'Formal concepts', 'Closure operators', 'Closure systems', 'Software: Concept Explorer', 'Many-valued contexts', 'Conceptual scaling schemas', 'Scaling ordinal data'], ['The partial order on concepts', 'Supremum and infimum', 'Lattices', 'The basic theorem (I)', 'The basic theorem (II)', 'Line diagrams', 'Context clarification and reduction', 'Context reduction: an example'], ['Finding the concepts', 'Drawing a concept lattice diagram', 'A naive algorithm for enumerating closed sets', 'Representing sets by bit vectors', 'Closures in lectic order', 'Next Closure through an example', 'The complexity of the algorithm', 'Basic incremental strategy', 'An example', 'The definition of implications', 'Examples of attribute implications', 'Implication inference', 'Computing the closure under implications'], ['Redundancy in implications', 'Pseudo-closed sets and canonical basis', 'Preclosed sets', 'Preclosure operator', 'Computing the canonical basis', 'An example', 'Complexity issues', 'Functional dependencies', 'Translation between functional dependencies and implications'], ['Basic introduction to learning with queries', 'Learning binary patterns', 'An easy case', 'The general case', 'Learning implications with queries', 'Membership and equivalence queries for implications', 'A polynomial-time algorithm', 'Learning domain implications with queries', 'Attribute exploration algorithm', 'Attribute exploration of pairs of squares', 'Object exploration', 'Variations of attribute exploration', 'Incompletely specified examples', 'Completing incomplete contexts'], ['Small changes in the context, big changes in the concept lattice', 'Iceberg lattices', 'Concept stability', 'Separation index', 'Concept probability', 'Nested line diagrams', 'Association rules', 'Support and confidence', 'Frequent closed sets', 'Luxenburger basis', 'Goodbye!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 37 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Brilliant. i am a mathematician and the course fulfilled my need for rigour and yet maintained an intuitive perspective. Sergei (if I may call him by his name) is a great teacher and I am looking forward to attending a more advanced course (possibly on scaling) and reading his scientific papers.', None, 'This course is a great introduction to Formal concept analysis. You might need some knowledge of mathematics, but I think you do not need so much. If you get accustomed to the way mathematicians do, it would be very helpful.', "Since there were no exercises, I treated the quiz questions as exercises.  But, that meant I could not see the correct results for answers I had gotten wrong, and I could not see a correct solution (i.e., method of arriving at the correct answer).  While the instructor did provide examples in each lecture, these were often much easier than the quiz questions.  So, for the future, I recommend a set of exercises with worked solutions to enable the students to sharpen their skill before taking a quiz.  Other than that, this was the perfect introduction to FCA for me.  I noted down a few ideas I have on some of the topics and methods discussed in the course, but I haven't had time to examine these ideas in detail.  Is there some way to contact the instructor later to get his reaction to these ideas?", 'Очень хороший курс. Для удобства прохождения не хватало презентационного материала. Была неопределенность в одном-двух тестовых вопросах. Но в целом курс полезный и очень интересный! Спасибо!  ', 'Wonderful explanations and resources.', 'It is a very nice course, I fully recommend it. It is very good organized and explained. The task some of them are challenge. ', 'Great Course. Explained nicely.', 'The last probability excercise was tough, but worth it.', 'Excelente contenido y explicaciones. Muy completo al momento de dar la introducción sobre Análisis Formal de Conceptos', 'Was quite hard. Instructor was very helpful. Instructors book helped a lot.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Franco F', 'By Francisco J V', 'By Takayuki K', 'By Douglas H', 'By Garry N', 'By Noemi Z M', 'By Edith V', 'By Aman S', 'By Sergio G', 'By Osman O P', 'By Žilvinas R']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 09, 2017', 'May 18, 2017', 'Jan 20, 2018', 'Jul 24, 2017', 'May 02, 2017', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Jul 19, 2017', 'Jan 25, 2018', 'May 19, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019']</review_date></doc>