<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_49</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-data-visualization</course_url><course_name>Capstone: Retrieving, Processing, and Visualizing Data with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Charles Russell Severance</course_instructor><course_introduction>In the capstone, students will build a series of applications to retrieve, process and visualize data using Python.   The projects will involve all the elements of the specialization.  In the first part of the capstone, students will do some visualizations to become familiar with the technologies in use and then will pursue their own project to visualize some other data that they have or can find.  Chapters 15 and 16 from the book “Python for Everybody” will serve as the backbone for the capstone. This course covers Python 3.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Python Programming//Database (DBMS)//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the Capstone//Building a Search Engine//Exploring Data Sources (Project)//Spidering and Modeling Email Data//Accessing New Data Sources (Project)//Visualizing Email Data//Visualizing new Data Sources (Project)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction: Welcome to the Class', 'Unicode Characters and Strings', 'Office Hours in Den Haag, Netherlands', 'Interview: John Resig and Pam Fox - Khan Academy'], ['Page Rank Overview', 'Worked Example: Page Rank - Spidering (Chapter 16)', 'Worked Example: Page Rank - Computation (Chapter 16)', 'Worked Example: Page Rank - Visualization (Chapter 16)', 'Office Hours Detroit, Michigan', 'Interview: Anil Jain - Image Processing'], ["Dr. Chuck's New Kitten - Sakaiger", 'Interview: Bruce Schneier - The Security Mindset'], ['Gmane Introduction', 'Worked Example: Gmane / Mail - Retrieval (Chapter 16)', 'Worked Example: Gmane / Mail - Model (Chapter 16)', 'Office Hours Baltimore, MD', 'Interview: Bruce Schneier - Building Cryptographic Systems'], ['Office Hours: Dr. Chuck Pretends to be Anthony Bourdain'], ['Worked Example: Gmane / Mail - Visualization (Chapter 16)', 'Office Hours, Montreal, Canada', 'Interview: Nathaniel Borenstein - The Father of MIME'], ["Office Hours - Dr. Chuck's Office - Ann Arbor, Michigan", 'Video: Steve Jobs, NeXT and the Internet']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["If this entire specialization were a bag of potato chips, the Capstone would be that bland chip that didn't get any salt. ", 'This should not be called a capstone. It is way too complicated to understand which is why the assignments have been kept to simplistic (this is reasonable). A bunch of small programs testing smooth amalgamation and application of the learnt concepts would have been more fruitful.', 'peer grading for mentors very slow.', "Didn't learn as much as the previous chapters. Markers are slow to mark, my subscription actually expired before they marked, not ", "I thought this was poor. It was basically a re-hash of the previous module with slightly different tasks. Given that I had to wait three months for the capstone to be ready, I found it a bit rich that my deadline to finish it was a couple of weeks! Don't waste your money/time on this particular module.", None, 'No code writing required to complete the course.', 'Very poor quality course, both from a content perspective as well as from an implementation perspective. ', 'I have completed the whole specialization successfully and Coursera and FFE and ofcourse, my guide, Dr. Chuck have been a constant source of motivation. I am really really thankful for this whole support of yours.', 'This course helped me a lot in understanding the web and the data retrieval from it.', 'Beautiful Course. Worth your time . Dr. Chuck is amazing', "It's an excellent course!! Im glad to do it. Thaks to everyone who made it possible.", "For some reason, I lost my motivation so I don't think I'm going complete the capstone. But it is a good course, and the instructor is good too. It might take you some time if you try to comprehend every line of codes. I don't think I would recommend you to enroll this one if you just want to skate through and get the certificate like me. If you are passionate about data science, please enroll. Cheers.", 'one of the best python courses ', "It's a good course to summarize all topics learnt in the specialization.", "This Capstone was okay....I went through it, I think it wasn't as thorough as the other classes. ", 'Honestly not a very good course. The first 3 courses in this specialization were great. We were really challenged to write our own logic and learned a lot of python. The last two courses, however, were disappointing. We essentially just ran pre-written code to "see how a complex app works." It would have been much more useful to have us write our own code.', "My expectation was I will do the coding (get my hands dirty) based on the suggestion or ideas from the instructor. I didn't expect to run the code that was written by the instructor and share the screenshots. It would had been good, if the course involved in working on a project.", 'Bad experience with grades not get in on time. Have to had back and forth btw the instructor and support.', 'Not much to learn from project perspective. This course definitely needs improvement.', 'I enjoyed the specialization a lot, overall! Absolutely fantastic teaching by Dr. Chuck, I learned so much. Unfortunately, the capstone didn\'t have the right structure for me. The required assignments didn\'t really teach anything new, it was just run this code and take screenshots. The " can anyone review my assignment" forum spam was just sad, and I think a better solution must be found for the course conclusion. The optional data visualization assignment is great, but I don\'t feel I had the tools necessary to complete it yet. I do plan to come back to  it after I learn a bit more.  ', "It's not such interesting as previous courses. Mostly it contains some practical solutions which you have to execute (with some small changes). ", 'Instructions for assignments not clear. TA not helpful with providing clarity on completing the assignments. ', 'Should focus on data types and usage while allowing students do actual homework.', "Need harder assignments which involve editing code and get the user thinking more about what is going on in the videos.This course is basically running premade code and taking screenshots. The optional element is a bit confusing as there is no focus given. I still haven't decided what data to use and what analysis to perform. All in all, Capstone is a waste of time, do first 4. "]</reviews><reviewers>['By Morgan S', 'By ali s', 'By Ayush B', 'By Hanyani A M', 'By Jeffrey B', 'By Christopher H', 'By Alex S', 'By Brendan C', 'By PRANSHU P', 'By Amit K', 'By Abrar W', 'By Diego N F', 'By Zhisheng Y', 'By Allen B V', 'By Nguyen N T A', 'By Anthony S', 'By Spencer H', 'By Ponrajadurai S', 'By Grace', 'By Milap S', 'By daniel m', 'By Dmitry E', 'By Stuart O Y M', 'By Marc A G', 'By Paras K']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 06, 2016', 'Aug 04, 2018', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'May 29, 2016', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2018', 'May 02, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Jun 03, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'May 06, 2019', 'May 31, 2019', 'Aug 30, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2018', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'May 09, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Oct 09, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>