<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_208</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/fitting-statistical-models-data-python</course_url><course_name>Fitting Statistical Models to Data with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brenda Gunderson</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, we will expand our exploration of statistical inference techniques by focusing on the science and art of fitting statistical models to data. We will build on the concepts presented in the Statistical Inference course (Course 2) to emphasize the importance of connecting research questions to our data analysis methods. We will also focus on various modeling objectives, including making inference about relationships between variables and generating predictions for future observations.

This course will introduce and explore various statistical modeling techniques, including linear regression, logistic regression, generalized linear models, hierarchical and mixed effects (or multilevel) models, and Bayesian inference techniques. All techniques will be illustrated using a variety of real data sets, and the course will emphasize different modeling approaches for different types of data sets, depending on the study design underlying the data (referring back to Course 1, Understanding and Visualizing Data with Python).

During these lab-based sessions, learners will work through tutorials focusing on specific case studies to help solidify the week’s statistical concepts, which will include further deep dives into Python libraries including Statsmodels, Pandas, and Seaborn. This course utilizes the Jupyter Notebook environment within Coursera.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Bayesian Statistics//Python Programming//Statistical Model//statistical regression</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>WEEK 1 - OVERVIEW &amp; CONSIDERATIONS FOR STATISTICAL MODELING//WEEK 2 - FITTING MODELS TO INDEPENDENT DATA//WEEK 3 - FITTING MODELS TO DEPENDENT DATA//WEEK 4: Special Topics</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course!', "What Do We Mean by Fitting Models to Data'?", 'Types of Variables in Statistical Modeling', 'Different Study Designs Generate Different Types of Data: Implications for Modeling', 'Objectives of Model Fitting: Inference vs. Prediction', 'Plotting Predictions and Prediction Uncertainty', 'Python Statistics Landscape'], ['Linear Regression Introduction', 'Linear Regression Inference', 'Interview: Causation vs Correlation', 'Logistic Regression Introduction', 'Logistic Regression Inference', 'NHANES Case Study Tutorial (Linear and Logistic Regression)'], ['What are Multilevel Models and Why Do We Fit Them?', 'Multilevel Linear Regression Models', 'Multilevel Logistic Regression models', 'Practice with Multilevel Modeling: The Cal Poly App', 'What are Marginal Models and Why Do We Fit Them?', 'Marginal Linear Regression Models', 'Marginal Logistic Regression', 'NHANES Case Study Tutorial (Marginal and Multilevel Regression)'], ['Should We Use Survey Weights When Fitting Models?', 'Bayesian Approaches to Statistics and Modeling', 'Bayesian Approaches Case Study: Part I', 'Bayesian Approaches Case Study: Part II', 'Bayesian Approaches Case Study - Part III', 'Bayesian in Python']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The content itself is great but some notebooks were a bit unready. Otherwise great course! ', "I must say that this is a must take course for ones who are aspiring a career in Data Science. All the concepts were laid out so beautifully and it was explained very clearly with visualisations of each real-life-examples. I enrolled in this specialisation before starting my Machine Learning so that I have all the necessary fundamentals of Statistics. Brady Sir &amp; Brendra Ma'am are simply phenomenal, the way they explain the concepts are incredible. The concepts gets etched in one's memory.", 'Content of course was good. Some issue with quiz. ', 'The course is actually pretty good, however the mix between basic subjects (like univariate linear regression) and relatively advanced topics (marginal models) may discourage some students.', 'Great review of machine learning used in statistics finished up with some overview on bayesian math.', 'Very informative and the example', 'Spectacular Course!', 'Really thorough and in-depth material about statistical models with python. ', 'I enjoy the lectures. The professor has a good speaking and teaching style which keeps me interested. Lots of concrete math examples which make it easier to understand. Very good slides which are well formulated and easy to understand', 'Thank you for creating this course. I have learned basic knowledge to succeed my incoming business education. I have a bachelor degree of laws and am transferring to a master of management. I used this course to learn the prior knowledge that I need about statistics. I finished this specialization and feel more confident about the numerical analysis. Thank you again Michigan Online for your great courses!', 'It was good - Thanks.!', 'Very good course, I like many practices and evaluations focused on database of real cases, perhaps it would be advisable to reproduce results from the same sources .....', "I had never given much thought to multilevel models and their implications (for example how clustering or the interviewer effected the results). So the course was definitely interesting. However the Python notebooks that are part of the course don't give enough detail to be able to apply the theoretic material to other models. ", 'Great lecture content, poor quiz design. Hard to apply any of the concepts that you learn.', "If you don't already understand the topic don't bother with this course, the lectures are 95% hand waving  and showing formulas they don't explain how to make sense of and then the quizzes are answering questions on what they didn't bother to explain."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Tobias R', 'By Aayush G', 'By Harish S', 'By Alvaro F', 'By Varga I K', 'By nipunjeet s g', 'By EDILSON S S O J', 'By JIANG X', 'By Jafed E', 'By HUNG H L', 'By jose H C', 'By Joffre L V', 'By Yaron K', 'By David Z', 'By Kristoffer H']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 10, 2019', 'May 29, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'May 25, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019']</review_date></doc>