<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_117</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/building-resilient-streaming-systems-gcp</course_url><course_name>Building Resilient Streaming Systems on Google Cloud Platform</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>This 1-week, accelerated on-demand course builds upon Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals. Through a combination of video lectures, demonstrations, and hands-on labs, you'll learn how to build streaming data pipelines using Google Cloud Pub/Sub and Dataflow to enable real-time decision making. You will also learn how to build dashboards to render tailored output for various stakeholder audience.

Prerequisites:
• Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals (or equivalent experience)
• Some knowledge of Java

Objectives:
• Understand use-cases for real-time streaming analytics
• Use Google Cloud PubSub asynchronous messaging service to manage data events
• Write streaming pipelines and run transformations where necessary
• Get familiar with both sides of a streaming pipeline: production and consumption
• Interoperate Dataflow, BigQuery and Cloud Pub/Sub for real-time streaming and analysis</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Bigquery//Bigtable//Dataflow//Publish–Subscribe Pattern</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Architecture of Streaming Analytics Pipelines//Module 2: Ingesting Variable Volumes//Module 3: Implementing Streaming Pipelines//Module 4: Streaming analytics and dashboards//Module 5: Handling Throughput and Latency Requirements</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What is Streaming ?', 'Challenge #1: Variable volumes require ability of ingest to scale and be fault-tolerant', 'Challenge #2 : Latency is to be expected', 'Challenge #3 : Need instant insights', 'Discuss some streaming scenarios'], ['What is Pub/Sub ?', 'How it works: Topics and Subscriptions', 'Lab Overview', 'Lab demo and review'], ['Dataflow Streaming', 'Challenges in stream processing', 'Build a stream processing pipeline for live traffic data', 'Handle late data: watermarks, triggers, accumulation', 'Lab overview', 'Lab demo and review'], ['Streaming analytics and dashboards', 'Lab overview', 'Lab demo and review'], ['Throughput and Latency', 'Bigtable: big, fast, autoscaling NoSQL', 'Ingesting into Bigtable', 'Designing for Bigtable', 'Streaming into Bigtable', 'Lab demo and review', 'Performance considerations', 'Summary of Data Engineering on GCP Specialization']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Streaming pull on Pub/Sub can also be added.', 'Very interesting!!', 'good', 'All concept explained nicely.', 'Very Good content...', 'Good', 'Very useful.', 'Though the subject was the most obscure and least relevant to me of all 5 courses in the specialization, I think I learned the most during this one. ', 'great', 'Sick', 'Excelent way of learning Pub Sub.', 'good', 'Un curso maravilloso.', 'I understand how bigtable works and how to design a good table. That is the biggest take for me! ', 'Thanks Lak and the team for detailed information. The way of teaching is best which will clears the doubts of the everyone.', 'Very goods course', 'I recommend this course to learn the fundamentals of Building Resilient Streaming Systems on Google Cloud Platform', 'Great course to combined and test the knowledge from other modules.', 'Thorough and challenging.', 'Excellent course! Great exercises and a solid background on how to build resilient streaming systems with GCP', 'This was a pleasure to attend. Some minor frustrations when tests failed or just stopped, but support was excellent and by revisiting your site 2 stopped tests resulted in a pass!  Note that some of the current web pages have changed since the course was created - so the tests are more real-world as you have to figure stuff out yourself - not such a bad thing!', 'This has been a great course. All the theory and practical content I find useful to get me started in the field of machine learning', 'Wonderful and powerful features in google  ... Ultimate Powerful cloud Platform', 'Awesome', 'This course was very helpful to understand how to built high throughput streaming work flows on google cloud. It described in detail how to model big table for efficient application. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Onur U', 'By Peter S', 'By Sudeshna D', 'By Preetish K D', 'By Raja R G', 'By Amit K', 'By Javier R', 'By Christof G v R', 'By Mnason A P', 'By Adam E', 'By Vicente G d S', 'By Chandrasekar B', 'By Alejandro J A', 'By Morgan G', 'By Mohammed A M F S', 'By Jumpod P', 'By William M', 'By Peeya I', 'By Agha A A', 'By Brian C G', 'By Julian K', 'By harada h', 'By Rambabu A', 'By Soumya R B', 'By Parag G']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Sep 15, 2018', 'Sep 15, 2018', 'Aug 25, 2018']</review_date></doc>