<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_14</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/sql-data-science</course_url><course_name>Databases and SQL for Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rav Ahuja</course_instructor><course_introduction>Much of the world's data resides in databases. SQL (or Structured Query Language) is a powerful language which is used for communicating with and extracting data from databases. A working knowledge of databases and SQL is a must if you want to become a data scientist.

The purpose of this course is to introduce relational database concepts and help you learn and apply foundational knowledge of the SQL language. It is also intended to get you started with performing SQL access in a data science environment.  

The emphasis in this course is on hands-on and practical learning . As such, you will work with real databases, real data science tools, and real-world datasets. You will create a database instance in the cloud. Through a series of hands-on labs you will practice building and running SQL queries. You will also learn how to access databases from Jupyter notebooks using SQL and Python.

No prior knowledge of databases, SQL, Python, or programming is required.

Anyone can audit this course at no-charge. If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you can also earn an IBM digital badge upon successful completion of the course.

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Cloud Databases//Python Programming//Ipython//Relational Database Management System (RDBMS)//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1 - Introduction to Databases and Basic SQL//Week 2 - Advanced SQL//Week 3 - Accessing Databases using Python//Week 4: Course Assignment</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to SQL for Data Science', 'Introduction to Databases', 'How to create a Database instance on Cloud?', 'CREATE Table Statement', 'SELECT Statement', 'COUNT, DISTINCT, LIMIT', 'INSERT Statement', 'UPDATE and DELETE Statements', 'Information and Data Models', 'Types of Relationships', 'Mapping Entities to Tables', 'Relational Model Concepts'], ['Using String Patterns, Ranges', 'Sorting Result Sets', 'Grouping Result Sets', 'Built-in Database Functions', 'Date and Time Built-in Functions', 'Sub-Queries and Nested Selects', 'Working with Multiple Tables', 'Relational Model Constraints', 'Relational Model Constraints - Advanced'], ['How to access databases using Python?', 'Writing code using DB-API', 'Connecting to a database using ibm_db API', 'Creating tables, loading data and querying data', 'Analyzing data with Python', 'Join Overview', 'Inner Join', 'Left Outer Join', 'Right Outer Join', 'Full Outer Join'], ['Working with Real World Datasets', 'Getting Table and Column Details']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["If you are located outside USA or Canada, don't take this course. ", "This course is more about IBM roping you into using a bloated cloud ecosystem, than it is about teaching you SQL.  You will only learn DB2 stuff, and only through their cloud dashboard.  This entire specialization is disappointing, but if you've made it this far, masochism may carry you through it.", "The course teaches SQL quite well. But it doesn't teach and make practice about the connection to a database and use of sql magic. Hence, its very frustrating to understand the significance of '%sql' in a Final Assignment review. I think a lot of students are facing the same problem. ", "I would've given a five-star rating gladly, if it weren't for the terrible user experience of IBM DB2 Console, which wasted 4 hours of my time trying to load three small csv files into database tables.", 'Only one star and I think it does not deserve it. On week 3 the assignment  ask you to establish a connection with database and because It gives me an error for more than 3 weeks, I decided to use Forums. After  a couple of dozen messages requesting for help, I received only 2 answers from the professor:', 'No live examples, no tutorial on how to navigate Db2 cloud. Maybe I was expecting too much; disappointed. ', 'Overall good course but a few typos and unclear instructions, mostly with the labs and our own \'user specific" DB2 specs which were needed for the 1st and 2nd lab - yet, clear instructions for doing so were posted several labs afterward. Labeling of individual labs (their titles/ filenames, when opened in Jupyter notebooks, did not correspond with the actual weeks in the course that the should have - wks 2 were called wks 4 and wks 3 were called wks 6) That made it a bit confusing at times. They appear to have been from a different course or earlier revision. Maybe revisit and revise this course soon for better flow. Also, please check the comments/discussion boards and address those concerns that are repeatedly coming up. Quite a few more students than just myself were stumped or confused over the same issues. Thank you.', "In case IBMER's fails to have DB console lite access, its difficult to complete the assessments, hence there should be other alternative to  practice it.", "No videos for week 2, sub-queries were confusing and questions 9 and 10 on final project are very 'vague' and 'confusing' with asking questions about Area(s) when in examples and previous course work we were taught to use group by, but correct answers did not use group by.", 'This course teaches you the basics of SQL completely unrelated to Data Science. SQL is not mentioned in any further courses in the specialization. Could have very well skipped this course from the specialization. There was not even a single assignment that involved both SQL and Data Science. ', 'Amazing. The difficult in the SQL is very good to make you think in real life problems.', 'The hands-on labs were extremely engaging and the quizzes were very informative.', 'Practice lab assignments were excellent in reinforcing my learning, they were just the right kind of challenging. This course has been the best one in the Data Science Professional series by far. ', 'it is a great course for beginners who wants to have an understanding of Database concepts and hands on experience as well', 'Good course with practical exercise, however some problem on lab exercise connection', 'The course is very helpful and easy to understand. The reason I only gave it 4 stars is because learners had to deal with many technical issues which were not relevant to the study, while doing labs and assignment. The upside is I guess it is part of shaping the right learning attitude. Many thanks!', 'please give details on how to connect database with notebook', "  Worth all the effort..! Great coursework if you're willing to spend some time to understand DB2 infrastructure,creating Db2 database on IBM Cloud, compose and execute SQL queries, and access a database from Python based Jupyter notebooks. Key takeaways from the course : \n- Creating databases on IBM Cloud\n- Troubleshooting basic loading errors\n- Working closely on creating tables on real time IBM DB2 instances\n- Connecting to db instances using python and perform basic data summarization\n- Performing data loading through RestAPI's  ", 'Although the material was clear and concise, working with IBM Db2 Cloud was a headache due to its  unresponsiveness', 'The lectures were confusing at first, because the syntax in the lectures did not exactly match the syntax for the assignments (though this issue went away in subsequent weeks). ', 'Guidance is not sufficient. Questions are not answered as needed. ', 'Too much IBM oriented and specific.', 'Horrible experience. The course is not updated. The ibm cloud function doesnt work at all. There are hardly any videos. Most of the content is just theory which you can read from anywhere. Dont waste your money.', 'Using days to find solutions, which are not presented in the course but necessary to get along. ', 'The IBM cloud "service" leaves much to be desired. Multiple times I\'ve experienced outages while I was in the middle of lab assignments. It\'s a paid course where they give you "free" credits to do the course work in their cloud "service." But the credits are inadequate for the labs and they constantly ask for your credit card to buy more "service." While the class is okay I wouldn\'t recommend it to anyone because of the poor IBM cloud support.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mohamed H I', 'By Michael K', 'By SNEHAL B', 'By Zhu L', 'By Maria', 'By aniket c', 'By Jody A K', 'By Sumit M', 'By Derek A', 'By Pranay C', 'By Juan A', 'By MB', 'By Tejas P', 'By Laxmi Y', 'By Thanakrit  P', 'By Duy N', 'By pranav v', 'By Tanveer J', 'By Kshitij P', 'By Alula M', 'By Kifle M', 'By Sergiy T', 'By Saurabh M K', 'By Bernhard M', 'By Steve O']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 28, 2018', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Apr 27, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Oct 25, 2018', 'Jul 19, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2018', 'Jul 01, 2018', 'May 29, 2019', 'Jun 06, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Oct 30, 2018']</review_date></doc>