<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_34</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning</course_url><course_name>Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Martha White</course_instructor><course_introduction>Reinforcement Learning is a subfield of Machine Learning, but is also a general purpose formalism for automated decision-making and AI. This course introduces you to statistical learning techniques where an agent explicitly takes actions and interacts with the world. Understanding the importance and challenges of learning agents that make decisions is of vital importance today, with more and more companies interested in interactive agents and intelligent decision-making. 

This course introduces you to the fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning. When you finish this course, you will:
- Formalize problems as Markov Decision Processes 
- Understand basic exploration methods and the exploration/exploitation tradeoff
- Understand value functions, as a general-purpose tool for optimal decision-making
- Know how to implement dynamic programming as an efficient solution approach to an industrial control problem

This course teaches you the key concepts of Reinforcement Learning, underlying classic and modern algorithms in RL. After completing this course, you will be able to start using RL for real problems, where you have or can specify the MDP. 

This is the first course of the Reinforcement Learning Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Artificial Intelligence (AI)//Machine Learning//Reinforcement Learning//Function Approximation//Intelligent Systems</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Alberta</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the Course! //The K-Armed Bandit Problem//Markov Decision Processes//Value Functions &amp; Bellman Equations //Dynamic Programming</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Specialization Introduction', 'Course Introduction', 'Meet your instructors!', 'Your Specialization Roadmap'], ['Sequential Decision Making with Evaluative Feedback', 'Learning Action Values', 'Estimating Action Values Incrementally', 'What is the trade-off?', 'Optimistic Initial Values', 'Upper-Confidence Bound (UCB) Action Selection', 'Jonathan Langford: Contextual Bandits for Real World Reinforcement Learning', 'Week 1 Summary'], ['Markov Decision Processes', 'Examples of MDPs', 'The Goal of Reinforcement Learning', 'Continuing Tasks', 'Examples of Episodic and Continuing Tasks', 'Week 2 Summary'], ['Specifying Policies', 'Value Functions', 'Rich Sutton and Andy Barto: A brief History of RL', 'Bellman Equation Derivation', 'Why Bellman Equations?', 'Optimal Policies', 'Optimal Value Functions', 'Using Optimal Value Functions to Get Optimal Policies', 'Week 3 Summary'], ['Policy Evaluation vs. Control', 'Iterative Policy Evaluation', 'Policy Improvement', 'Policy Iteration', 'Flexibility of the Policy Iteration Framework', 'Efficiency of Dynamic Programming', 'Week 4 Summary', 'Congratulations!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Fantastic Course. That's the RL MOOC I have been waiting for so long. No surprise it is from Students of RL guru R. Sutton at Uni of Alberta. Very clearly and simply explained. Exercise and Test difficulty spot on. Wouldn't change a yota from this Course. Can't wait to access the rest of this specialization", "Course material is standard and mostly follows Sutton and Barto textbook.  Unfortunately, most contents overlap with the existing reinforcement learning course on Coursera and David Silver's youtube videos.  The course will be much more useful if it covers more practical stuff instead.  ", 'I found the explanations of theory of RL to replicate what was written in the book. Without examples the videos were no value add. ', 'Very clear and engaging presentation, well thought out and typical Coursera-style programming assignments.  Definitely looking forward to taking the rest of the sequence.', 'Very good courses. It helps me to understand reinforcement learning a lot.', "I've just finished this course, it is really wonderful and I learnt a lot, as a professional Backend Developer without a formal background in Machine Learning. It has a lot of mathematical theory and exercises, derivations, really good explanations, and even some coding tasks to apply this knowledge.", 'Is a very good introduction to Reinforcement Learning. It also gives a very nice foundation of the basics of this area without being shy of showing some math. Could use more examples about modeling real world problems as MDPs but otherwise is a very complete course.', 'The main reason I enrolled in this course was to have  an opportunity to have my questions answered. I had already gone through videos of RL lectures from different universities before this. Hence,  the value of the course diminished for me when  some of my questions were not always answered by the TAs or the Staff', 'Great course and awesome instructors. Wish this course should have been announced much earlier. Thanks for offering such a wonderful course.', 'The course is very comprehensive and gave a very good introduction to and initial overview of reinforcement learning. It was a bit more theoretic than I expected (after doing the Machine Learning course by Prof Ng) and I did have some problems in completing the last programming assignment due to this. In the end it all turned out well though. The instructors were quite pedagogic and structured (if anything a bit too structured), and the assignments were well chosen. One could tell that this is a new course as there were still a few small quirks, but overall a very worthwhile course!', 'Good introduction :-)', 'Exceptional course, the fundamental of RL explanations are excellent! I in particular I found it insightful the focus on thinking about examples in real-life that can be modeled as Markov Decision process. Additionally, great quizzes questions and assignments all helped in deepening my understanding of topics such as Dynamic Programing, Bellman Optimality, and Generalized Policy Iteration.  ', 'The ideal course to go with the book Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction.  The quizzes and coding workshops are pitched just right in my opinion, neither too easy nor too hard.', 'I love their way of teaching, they ask you to read, understand firstly, and then start to give a lecture about what it is, which helps a lot to understand.', "I've enjoyed it. It pushes me to do stuff and not to cut corners.", 'Excellent! Great content and delivery quality.', 'Good course following the classic book but it is kept at an easy pace for diverse people to be able to understand and apply the concepts of reinforcement learning.', 'Explained in a very simple way, with helpful assignments.', 'Excellent course', 'It is the perfect course.', 'great course!! thanks Adam, Martha and team!!', 'The concepts are explained in a very simple manner. Reading book then watching videos helps a lot to understand the essential ideas. ', 'Excellent beginners course of a very interesting topic!', 'Excellent Course! The level of difficulty is perfect. It is difficult but not impossible if you do the readings in the textbook and understand the lectures. I strongly suggest reading the book before watching the lectures. This helped my understanding significantly. The material and assignments are very interesting and informative.', 'Very well explained, with amazing examples. Thanks!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Luiz C', 'By Kota M', 'By Avinash K', 'By Andrei T', 'By 姚佳奇', 'By Santiago M Z O', 'By Sebastian P B', 'By Ritu P', 'By braghadeesh', 'By Tomas L', 'By Marvin F', 'By Christian C C', 'By Neil S', 'By June X', 'By Pawel P', 'By Alejandro D', 'By Saikat M', 'By Garrett S', 'By Md O H', 'By Shaji, N ', 'By Kyle N', 'By Mert İ', 'By Ignacio O', 'By Justin S', 'By Daniel D V']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 04, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'Aug 20, 2019', 'Aug 25, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Aug 19, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019']</review_date></doc>