<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_116</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-introduction-spreadsheets-models</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Spreadsheets and Models</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Don Huesman</course_instructor><course_introduction>The simple spreadsheet is one of the most powerful data analysis tools that exists, and it’s available to almost anyone. Major corporations and small businesses alike use spreadsheet models to determine where key measures of their success are now, and where they are likely to be in the future. But in order to get the most out of a spreadsheet, you have the know-how to use it. This course is designed to give you an introduction to basic spreadsheet tools and formulas so that you can begin harness the power of spreadsheets to map the data you have now and to predict the data you may have in the future. Through short, easy-to-follow demonstrations, you’ll learn how to use Excel or Sheets so that you can begin to build models and decision trees in future courses in this Specialization. 
Basic familiarity with, and access to, Excel or Sheets is required.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Monte Carlo Method//Microsoft Excel//Linear Programming (LP)//Solver</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Spreadsheets: A Tool for Thinking with Numbers//From Spreadsheet to Model//Addressing Uncertainty and Probability in Models// Simulation and Optimization</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.1 Objectives and a Little Spreadsheet History', '1.2 Navigating a spreadsheet and crafting formulas', '1.3 Using functions', '1.4 Using conditional expressions in formulas', '1.5 Common errors in spreadsheets', '1.6 Differences between Sheets and Excel'], ['2.0 Module Introduction', '2.1 Using assumptions and decision variables in spreadsheet models', '2.2 Structuring a spreadsheet to model variables, objectives, and objective functions', '2.3 Constructing simple cashflow model', '2.4 What-if analysis and sensitivity analysis', '2.5 Limits to simple, deterministic models'], ['3.0 Introduction', '3.1 Random variables and probability distributions', '3.2 Changes in discrete and continuous time', '3.3 Power, exponential, and log functions', '3.4 Probability trees and decision trees', '3.5 Correlation and Regression'], ['4.0 Introduction', '4.1 Monte Carlo Simulations', '4.2 Linear Programming', '4.3 Next Steps, and Differences between Excel and Sheets']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Quizzes need to explain why some question answers are incorrect, or else learning is almost impossible. ', 'The information is glossed over quickly and does not prepare the learners for the quiz questions at all.  The quizzes are set up in such a manner that it is extremely difficult to learn from them.  There is no feedback on written in answers, which makes it impossible to understand the mistake that was being made.  The questions on the quiz were also more specific and demanding than any lecture or material from the course would suggest.  Interesting material presented in a poor manner.', 'While the course can be useful to learn some modelling tricks with Excel, I found the quizz somehow badly designed for some questions, especially the one requiring entering formulas as in real life, a goal could be achieved using several different ways of writing formulas.', 'No theory, Very vague. Questions asked unrelated to what the teacher said.', "Extremely content light. Quizzes are bizarre and basically rely that you go back to the lecture and find the one sentence where a comment was made. There's no interactivity. Really pales in comparison to the first course in the sequence. I really hope this specialization gets better or this will be a SLOG. I expected better from Wharton!", 'The lectures are very thin, and questions very arbitrary. In the end I felt this course was very low value. ', 'I thought this was a great course. I have an undergraduate finance degree and it encompasses a lot of the econ/ math/ finance courses I took and actually shows you how all of these elements are applied. Eye opening for me and very helpful.', 'I felt modules 1 and 2 tests where a bit misleading in some questions. I think there could be better questions to assess the learning of those modules', 'Course content is generally very good, but could go a bit deeper on the formulation of optimization models, but that may be coming in future classes.  Some quiz questions are a bit ambiguous, causes grades to be lower than what should be achievable.', 'The slides were not informative.', "I did not find it as hands on as I would like and found that the answers to the quiz's were not really in the material", 'Useful Course', 'Many questions in the tests was subjective for me.', 'Muy útil para aprender lo básico en esta materia. Tal vez se podrían ver más ejemplos de modelos más complejos, solo para abrir la mente de los participantes a las posibilidades en el trabajo de la vida real. En todo caso, me ha resultado muy útil y lo recomendaré a mis colegas. Gracias por su apoyo y estoy a sus órdenes en Colombia. + 57 317 366 2160', 'Good material, the downloadable spreadsheets were of great help!', 'its a great course for finance', 'Very useful course for business students. The course explains wide range of topics in short period of time. At the same, it was very challenging. Thank you Professor and coursera for this wonderful course.', 'I gained more capability in excel and give me a new horizon to use it in my work and makes me want to do research.', 'What I have learnt in this course is really useful but I hope I could learn more. Maybe video time could be longer containing more content.', 'A little more technical compared to the first Course in this Business &amp; Finance Specialization and requires more time to understand the various uses of modelling. Definitely useful if one has intention of mastering Data Analysis and projections. ', 'Awesome course!', 'Very useful', 'it was very hard course for me to accomplish, but I really liked the lecturer helping me out at every juncture of class. introduction to spreadsheets and models is a must to go with course, it enhances your ability to understand all the basic and much needed knowledge for ms-excel.', 'Wonderful guided explanation on how to solve optimization problems with excel/google sheets', 'Great and helpful!!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Robert P', 'By  N B', 'By Hayk L', 'By Aditya P', 'By Nicholas J C', 'By Ravi D', 'By Evan H', 'By Guillermo E F', 'By Steven B', 'By Loh T J', 'By Joe M', 'By Chan H K', 'By Marcel M R', 'By Ivan D A G', 'By Fernando N', 'By Ankur P', 'By Sheraz K', 'By Mesa I N', 'By SIYUAN Y', 'By Janice N C W', 'By Zhongyuan Z', 'By POKOU K A', 'By maanas s', 'By Filippo L', 'By Yibei S']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 19, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'May 13, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'May 11, 2019', 'May 16, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Nov 10, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Aug 22, 2018']</review_date></doc>