<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_127</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-graph-analytics</course_url><course_name>Graph Analytics for Big Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Amarnath Gupta</course_instructor><course_introduction>Want to understand your data network structure and how it changes under different conditions? Curious to know how to identify closely interacting clusters within a graph? Have you heard of the fast-growing area of graph analytics and want to learn more? This course gives you a broad overview of the field of graph analytics so you can learn new ways to model, store, retrieve and analyze graph-structured data.

After completing this course, you will be able to model a problem into a graph database and perform analytical tasks over the graph in a scalable manner.  Better yet, you will be able to apply these techniques to understand the significance of your data sets for your own projects.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Graph Theory//Neo4j//Analytics//Graph Database</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Graph Analytics//Introduction to Graphs//Graph Analytics//Graph Analytics Techniques//Computing Platforms for Graph Analytics</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Graph Analytics for Big Data'], ['What is a Graph?', 'Why Graphs?', 'Why Graphs? Example 1: Social Networking', 'Why Graphs? Example 2: Biological Networks', 'Why Graphs? Example 3: Human Information Network Analytics', 'Why Graphs? Example 4: Smart Cities', 'The Purpose of Analytics', "What are the impact of Big Data's V's on Graphs?"], ['Focusing On Graph Analytics Techniques', 'Path Analytics', 'The Basic Path Analytics Question: What is the Best Path?', "Applying Dijkstra's Algorithm", 'Inclusion and Exclusion Constraints', 'Connectivity Analytics', 'Disconnecting a Graph', 'Connectedness: Indegree and Outdegree', 'Community Analytics and Local Properties', 'Global Property: Modularity', 'Centrality Analytics', 'Optional Lecture 1: Bi-directional Dijkstra Algorithm', 'Optional Lecture 2: Goal-directed Dijkstra Algorithm', 'Optional Lecture 3: Power Law Graphs', 'Optional Lecture 4: Measuring Graph Evolution', 'Optional Lecture 5: Eigenvector Centrality', 'Optional Lecture 6: Key Player Problems'], ['Welcome to Graph Analytics Techniques', 'Hands-On: Downloading, Installing, and Running Neo4j', 'Hands-On: Getting Started With Neo4j', 'Hands-On: Modifying a Graph With Neo4j', 'Hands-On: Importing Data Into Neo4j', 'Hands-On: Basic Queries in Neo4j With Cypher - Part 1', 'Hands-On: Basic Queries in Neo4j With Cypher - Part 2', 'Hands-On: Path Analytics in Neo4j Using Cypher - Part 1', 'Hands-On: Path Analytics in Neo4j Using Cypher - Part 2', 'Hands-On: Connectivity Analytics in Neo4j With Cypher'], ['Introduction: Large Scale Graph Processing', 'A Parallel Programming Model for Graphs', 'Pregel: The System That Changed Graph Processing', 'Giraph and GraphX', 'Beyond Single Vertex Computation', 'Introduction to GraphX: Hands-On Demonstrations', 'Hands On: Building a Graph', 'Hands On: Building a Degree Histogram', 'Hands On: Plot the Degree Histogram', 'Hands On: Network Connectedness and Clustering Components', 'Hands On: Joining Graph Datasets']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Lots of efforts wasted to struggle with setup. ', 'Some parts explain very scarcely the strengths of concepts like power laws. A bunch of ideas surely important but shown in a very confused way.', 'This is the more challenging course of the Specialization. The course is not as well built as the other ones. Week 1 does not include any lessons; week 5 is very fastidious and time consuming. The course should mention up front to run the Cloudera VM with one CPU only to avoid getting wrong metro vertex results and crash the system when using the filter method. The author may want to consider using Python instead of Scala as Python was used in all the previous courses of the specialization.', 'Nice introduction of multiple graph packages, however I missed some more applied cases, covering a real graph problem investigation (particularly how to associate Neo4j with GraphX).', 'Very interesting and well explained, but little practical.', "The last week was hard to follow with it's handson exercise. There was a lot of code which wasn't explained very well. It would be better if it was explained in more detail what the code was doing.", 'The staff is not attending this course, and has not kept the forum up to date with notes on changes to the Neo4j Syntax requirements. The commands as given in the lectures, in the supplemental materials, and in the forums by the staff do not work. A few students have tried to post updates to the forum, but these too are out date, and more recent requests for help go unanswered.', 'course is well designed and structured.', 'Excellent course for beginners in graph analytics.', 'Fun course to learn', 'Good!', 'Thanks', 'Good Course', 'Nice &amp; complete. intuitive way to learn', 'Great course!! Please update the Hands on!', "So useful. As our company consider using this technique for modeling customer's behaviors, this course give me an overall introduction for graph analysis.", '  beautiful  ', 'Very interesting', 'My name is Jose Antonio from Brazil. I am looking for a new Data Scientist career (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseantonio11).', 'Very insightful course', 'Great course!!! excellent information, instructions and examples (including some troubleshooting that helps us to learn things simulating everyday challenges).', 'I found a new love in this course Neo4j. Graphs are really powerful. You should expect a very intensive theoretical and hands-on knowledge to takeaway from this course. Think like a vertex ....', 'Good course.', 'Great Course Material and presentation plus nice and interesting hands-on examples!', "i feel power!!! thank's a lot. : )"]</reviews><reviewers>['By Manoj D', 'By Dimitri M', 'By Vincent R', 'By Leandro S', 'By Miguel T', 'By Stefan K', 'By Charles S', 'By Tejprakash U', 'By Оболенский И А', 'By To P H', 'By gregorius a', 'By David C', 'By Sajal S R', 'By Carlos M P M', 'By Jose L R', 'By Fei T', 'By Arnold J', 'By David B', 'By Jose A R N', 'By Manikandan P', 'By Roberto G C', 'By Jamiil T A', 'By Pijush K G', 'By Christoph R', 'By Arthur-Lance']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 30, 2018', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Jun 02, 2018', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Sep 29, 2018', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'Jun 11, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Oct 13, 2018', 'Sep 12, 2018', 'Aug 19, 2018', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Oct 06, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Oct 28, 2018', 'Jun 16, 2018', 'Feb 27, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2017']</review_date></doc>