<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_71</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/practical-time-series-analysis</course_url><course_name>Practical Time Series Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Tural Sadigov</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Practical Time Series Analysis!

Many of us are "accidental" data analysts. We trained in the sciences, business, or engineering and then found ourselves confronted with data for which we have no formal analytic training.  This course is designed for people with some technical competencies who would like more than a "cookbook" approach, but who still need to concentrate on the routine sorts of presentation and analysis that deepen the understanding of our professional topics. 

In practical Time Series Analysis we look at data sets that represent sequential information, such as stock prices, annual rainfall, sunspot activity, the price of agricultural products, and more.  We look at several mathematical models that might be used to describe the processes which generate these types of data. We also look at graphical representations that provide insights into our data. Finally, we also learn how to make forecasts that say intelligent things about what we might expect in the future.

Please take a few minutes to explore the course site. You will find video lectures with supporting written materials as well as quizzes to help emphasize important points. The language for the course is R, a free implementation of the S language. It is a professional environment and fairly easy to learn.

You can discuss material from the course with your fellow learners. Please take a moment to introduce yourself!

Time Series Analysis can take effort to learn- we have tried to present those ideas that are "mission critical" in a way where you understand enough of the math to fell satisfied while also being immediately productive. We hope you enjoy the class!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Time Series Forecasting//Time Series//Time Series Models</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>The State University of New York</course_orgnization><course_chapter>WEEK 1: Basic Statistics//Week 2: Visualizing Time Series, and Beginning to Model Time Series//Week 3: Stationarity, MA(q) and AR(p) processes//Week 4: AR(p) processes, Yule-Walker equations, PACF//Week 5: Akaike Information Criterion (AIC), Mixed Models, Integrated Models//Week 6: Seasonality, SARIMA, Forecasting</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Week 1 Welcome Video', 'Getting Started in R: Download and Install R on Windows', 'Getting Started in R: Download and Install R on Mac', 'Getting Started in R: Using Packages', 'Concatenation, Five-number summary, Standard Deviation', 'Histogram in R', 'Scatterplot in R', 'Review of  Basic Statistics I - Simple Linear Regression', 'Reviewing Basic Statistics II More Linear Regression', 'Reviewing Basic Statistics III - Inference', 'Reviewing Basic Statistics IV'], ['Week 2 Welcome Video', 'Introduction', 'Time plots', 'First Intuitions on (Weak) Stationarity', 'Autocovariance function', 'Autocovariance coefficients', 'Autocorrelation Function (ACF)', 'Random Walk', 'Introduction to Moving Average Processes', 'Simulating MA(2) process'], ['Week 3 Welcome Video', 'Stationarity - Intuition and Definition', 'Stationarity -  First Examples...White Noise and Random Walks', 'Stationarity - First Examples...ACF of Moving Average', 'Series and Series Representation', 'Backward shift operator', 'Introduction to Invertibility', 'Duality', 'Mean Square Convergence (Optional)', 'Autoregressive Processes - Definition, Simulation, and First Examples', 'Autoregressive Processes - Backshift Operator and the ACF', 'Difference equations', 'Yule - Walker equations'], ['Week 4 Welcome Video', 'Partial Autocorrelation and the PACF First Examples', 'Partial Autocorrelation and the PACF - Concept Development', 'Yule-Walker Equations in Matrix Form', 'Yule Walker Estimation - AR(2) Simulation', 'Yule Walker Estimation - AR(3) Simulation', 'Recruitment data - model fitting', 'Johnson &amp; Johnson-model fitting'], ['Week 5 Welcome Video', 'Akaike Information Criterion and Model Quality', 'ARMA Models (And a  Little Theory)', 'ARMA Properties and Examples', 'ARIMA Processes', 'Q-Statistic', 'Daily births in California in 1959'], ['Week 6 Welcome Video', 'SARIMA processes', 'ACF of SARIMA models', 'SARIMA fitting: Johnson &amp; Johnson', 'SARIMA fitting: Milk production', 'SARIMA fitting: Sales at a souvenir shop', 'Forecasting Using Simple Exponential Smoothing', 'Double Exponential Smoothing', 'Triple Exponential Smoothing Concept Development', 'Triple Exponential Smoothing Implementation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 25 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great introductory course on time series. Focus on ARIMA model most of the time while the last lecture capture a little bit of exponential smoothing. Would be great if there if summary lecture regarding to when to use which modeling technique. would be even better if there is a optional lecture to cover some of the more advanced time series models. ', "This is one of the best courses I've taken so far on Coursera. The exercises and delivery are so practical. I had taken a college course in Time Series Analysis, but didn't pretty much understand the concepts. This course has given me far better theoretical and practical understanding of TMS. A big thanks to the professors.", 'a good course on univariate time series modelling by ARMA type models, with additional details on Yule Walker equations, seasonal models, and forecasting. ', 'Excellent ', 'Terrible explanations... they do not make any sense....', 'Grateful to the instructors for the engaging and fruitful learning I enjoyed in the course Practical Time Series Analysis! Thank you :)  ', 'First I started out reading Intro to Time Series and Forecasting, the book suggested by everyone. But, I could not understand the math because it was too tough. I did not lose hope. I completed this course because sometimes you need to get an overview of what needs to be done and then if you dive into the math of it, it will be easy. Much recommended course for the beginning of time series and forecasting techniques. 5 stars! Thank you', 'A Well structured and well taught course thank you !', 'Great course, I highly recommend!', 'Decent course with a right balance between math, coding and high level explanation. AR, MA and ARMA (ARIMA) models are very well explained.  I am not a big fan of R (even after this course) but it seems its time series analysis libraries and datasets are comprehensive. The best part of the course is the in-course coding examples and tasks. They really help you get hands-on into analysing various time series objects. A little more emphasis should have been made on forecasting.', 'The course is very insightful substantively covering both theory and practical in a balanced manner. I liked it very much.', "great course even for newbies who're learning R.", 'The instructors provided detailed background for the theoretically inclined while gradually developing practical implementations in R using many real time series. Having finished the course I have a firm grasp of the process of analyzing time series and forecasting from them, as well as greater general facility in R. Overall an excellent and useful course.', 'Excellent coursework !! Very less amount of theory is required and hence a very useful for beginners. ', 'The topic is very difficult, but lectures explain everything in very clear way.', 'very good course for time series study', 'Terrific! Thanks the teachers! Both of You are very good. You make the complexity easy to learn.', 'imperfections in it but really practical and good enough', 'Análisis de series temporales explicado de la mejor manera posible, de lo más básico hacia lo más complejo, incluyendo código en R. Recomendable', 'I only wanted to look at a few lectures from this course, but they were so good that I decided to go through the rest of it.  I was not let down.', 'A great introduction to time series!', 'Good for the beginners.', 'Great, starts off slow and detailed and then moves onto a variety of practical problems', 'Very motivating course, quite easier as it is intermediate one, but still satisfying and moving the knowledge forward! Recommend!', 'Very good and structured lessons about fundamentals of time series modeling. Well done! I missed a bit the forecasting part though']</reviews><reviewers>['By xun y', 'By Benjamin O A ', 'By Lingbing F', 'By Roberto G A', 'By Laurentiu N', 'By Mohammed M A', 'By Sai R', 'By anas', 'By Matthew C Z', 'By Ramachandra R K', 'By Vidhyalakshmi K', 'By Ahmad L', 'By Robert S', 'By Chinmay J D', 'By Krzysztof S', 'By Jie F', 'By Dongliang Z', 'By XINGHUA L', 'By Begoña R H', 'By Kyle C', 'By RUOCHEN Z', 'By kapil g', 'By Aaron D', 'By Krzysztof R', 'By Sergi']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 16, 2018', 'Jul 26, 2018', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019']</review_date></doc>