<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_373</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/healthcare-data-quality-governance</course_url><course_name>Healthcare Data Quality and Governance</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Doug Berman</course_instructor><course_introduction>Career prospects are bright for those qualified to work with healthcare data or as Health Information Management (HIM) professionals. Perhaps you work in data analytics but are considering a move into healthcare, or you work in healthcare but are considering a transition into a new role. In either case, Healthcare Data Quality and Governance will provide insight into how valuable data assets are protected to maintain data quality. This serves care providers, patients, doctors, clinicians, and those who carry out the business of improving health outcomes. 

"Big Data" makes headlines, but that data must be managed to maintain quality. High-quality data is one of the most valuable assets gathered and used by any business. This holds greater significance in healthcare where the maintenance and governance of data quality directly impact people’s lives. This course will explain how data quality is improved and maintained. You’ll learn why data quality matters, then see how healthcare professionals monitor, manage and improve data quality. You’ll see how human and computerized systems interact to sustain data quality through data governance. You’ll discover how to measure data quality with metadata, tracking data provenance, validating and verifying data, along with a communication framework commonly used in healthcare settings. 

This knowledge matters because high-quality data will be transformed into valuable insights that can save lives, reduce costs, to improve healthcare and make it more accessible and affordable. You will make yourself more of an asset in the healthcare field by what you gain from this course.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Health Informatics</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Why Data Quality Matters//Measuring Data Quality// Monitoring, Managing and Improving Data Quality//Sustaining Quality through Data Governance</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Module 1 Introduction', 'Why Data is Collected and Defining Quality', 'Why Data Quality Matters, Part 1', 'Why Data Quality Matters, Part 2', 'How Data Quality Assessment Varies in Different Data Uses'], ['Module 2 Introduction', 'Describing Metadata in Healthcare', 'Data Provenance in Healthcare', 'Components of Data Quality', 'Data Validation Methods', 'A Framework for Validating and Verifying Data', 'The SBAR Methodology'], ['Module 3 Introduction', 'Establishing the Culture of Quality throughout the Data Lifecycle', 'Improving Data Quality from the Baseline', 'Managing Data Quality: Expected and Unexpected Changes', 'Monitoring Strategies Along the Data Pipeline'], ['Module 4 Introduction', 'Defining Data Governance in Healthcare', 'Why Data Governance Matters in Healthcare', 'Data Governance Committees in Healthcare', 'Data Governance Systems in Healthcare', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Data quality is very essential in the world of data science and it's applications in healthcare in particular."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Justice D A']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>