<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_84</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/advanced-excel</course_url><course_name>Data Visualization with Advanced Excel</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Mannella</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, you will get hands-on instruction of advanced Excel 2013 functions.  You’ll learn to use PowerPivot to build databases and data models.  We’ll show you how to perform different types of scenario and simulation analysis and you’ll have an opportunity to practice these skills by leveraging some of Excel's built in tools including, solver, data tables, scenario manager and goal seek.  In the second half of the course, will cover how to visualize data, tell a story and explore data by reviewing core principles of data visualization and dashboarding.  You’ll use Excel to build complex graphs and Power View reports and then start to combine them into dynamic dashboards.

Note: Learners will need PowerPivot to complete some of the exercises. Please use MS Excel 2013 version. If you have other MS Excel versions or a MAC you might not be able to complete all assignments.

This course was created by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP with an address at 300 Madison Avenue, New York, New York, 10017.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Dashboard (Business)//Microsoft Excel//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>PwC</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Preparing a Professional Excel //Advanced Scenario Analysis //Data Visualization//Dashboarding </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Course 3', 'Introduction to the Scenarios Used in this Course', 'Tao of Excel Recap and Guiding Principles', 'The Power of Visualization', 'Introduction to Working with Data Sets', 'Introduction to the Components of Data Sets and the Relational Database Model', 'Introduction to Keys and Forming Data Tables', 'Introduction to Joins', 'Overview of SQL and Other Database Tools', 'A Message from our Chief People Officer at PwC', 'PowerPivot: Importing and Preparing Data', 'Linking Data Tables and Building the Relational Model', 'Using PowerPivot to Visualize Data', 'Calculated Fields', 'Multiple Data Tables and Filters', 'Week 1 closing'], ['Introduction to Week 2', 'Advanced Scenario Analysis', 'Goal Seek', 'Scenario Manager', 'One-way Data Tables', 'Two-way Data Tables', 'Simulations', 'Solver', 'Week 2 Closing'], ['Week 3 Opening', 'Introduction to Data Visualization', 'Effective and Ineffective Charting', 'Selecting the Right Type of Chart', 'Introduction to Chart Navigation', 'Column Chart', 'Combo Chart', 'Stacked Column Chart', 'Heatmap', 'Gantt Project Plan', 'Power View', 'Week 3 closing'], ['Introduction to Week 4', 'Introduction to Dashboarding', 'Dashboarding: Beyond the basics', 'Form Controls and Grouping', 'Slicers and PowerPivot', 'Conditional Formatting and KPIs', 'Dashboard Finalization and Securing the Workbook', 'Week 4 Closing and Course Recap']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course took me from Basic level knowledge of Excel to a really advanced level. Course practice exercises are developed in a very appropriate way to teach the advanced level. ', 'I am very grateful to the Coursera and PWC for this course. This course gives me new learning which will help to boost my carrier and productivity as well as increase the thirst of my knowledge about data analysis and finance.', 'Simple and effective guidance on the more advanced Excel functions like PowerPivot, scenario analyses and the developer tools were really helpful.', 'Very Simple and Very Professional, i really learned and enjoyed', "Great presentation. A 'cheat-sheet' at the end of every week could be made, giving a snapshot in not more than a page of all that has happened.", 'Highly practical and easy to follow', 'I have already recommended this course to my juniors in the firm who have recently joined.', 'Excelent course, great to introduce in data analysis and visualization.', None, 'Excellent Course! I have long wanted to learn how to create interactive dashboards using MS Excel. This course, developed and delivered by PwC, has taught me the necessary skills in an effective manner! Simply put, the course showed me the ocean of tools that exist in Excel. From making geo-tagged graphs using Power View to using Power Pivot and Pivot tables to insert slicers etc! What is useful here is that, we still need to know the use of advanced formula like SUMIFS, Index and Match, VlookUp etc to develop and design the dashboards. I must congratulate and thank the folks at PwC to make the course totally hands-on!', 'One can excel in excel!', 'very useful and informative!', 'excellent course', 'Extraordinary course to learn advanced excel skills', 'Dashboards are extremely useful and effective as well as impressive, I really appreciate the course for insights on how to build them and use in real life', 'Very easy way to explain some key functions of excel that can help a lot in the art of visualization, thanks!', 'course is very nice plese give the link for certificate it does not show my certificate', 'Nicely planned course with good practice cases which gives hands-on experience of working with data.', 'Incredible all these functionalities of excel that can be applied on my daily work.', "kind of amazed how I didn't know about excel and how dashboarding until this course. great for analytical practices.", 'Very Good Modul', 'This Course exactly met my requirement . Its designed in a very friendly manner for the learners , hence could complete the course in the stipulated timeframe. ', 'Great content,great explaining and wonderful examples. very applicable stuff.', 'Be on the advice that some exercises require powerpivot', 'Excel course with very good exercises that give you practice. Widened my horizon about Excel.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Raheel Z', 'By A.H.M. A', 'By Henry K', 'By Mina J', 'By Ramachandran S', 'By Dan I', 'By Zohair A', 'By Jaime M', 'By Kristen P', 'By Harish P J', 'By SHREYANSH K', 'By Hermin', 'By Siddharth K', 'By Manpreet K J', 'By Inal K', 'By Felipe B', 'By prashant s', 'By Utsav S', 'By Yineth A R', 'By sutan a m', 'By Srinivasa R A', 'By Vani N', 'By FELIX K R', 'By Alberto R', 'By Lokesh M']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 23, 2019', 'Jul 07, 2019', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Nov 16, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018']</review_date></doc>