<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_309</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/matrix-factorization</course_url><course_name>Matrix Factorization and Advanced Techniques</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Michael D. Ekstrand</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will learn a variety of matrix factorization and hybrid machine learning techniques for recommender systems.  Starting with basic matrix factorization, you will understand both the intuition and the practical details of building recommender systems based on reducing the dimensionality of the user-product preference space.  Then you will learn about techniques that combine the strengths of different algorithms into powerful hybrid recommenders.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Minnesota</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Preface//Matrix Factorization (Part 1)//Matrix Factorization (Part 2)//Hybrid Recommenders//Advanced Machine Learning//Advanced Topics</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Matrix Factorization and Advanced Techniques'], ['Introduction to Matrix Factorization and Dimensionality Reduction', 'Singular Value Decomposition', 'Gradient Descent Techniques', 'Deriving FunkSVD', 'Probabilistic Matrix Factorization'], ['Assignment Introduction', 'Programming Matrix Factorization'], ['Hybrid Recommenders', 'Hybrids with Robin Burke', 'Hybridization through Matrix Factorization', 'Matrix Factorization Hybrids with George Karypis', 'Interview with Arindam Banerjee', 'Interview with Yehuda Koren'], ['Learning Recommenders', 'Learning to Rank:  Interview with Xavier Amatriain', 'Personalized Ranking (with Daniel Kluver)'], ['Context-Aware Recommendation I :  Interview with Francesco Ricci', 'Context-Aware Recommendation II:  Interview with Bamshad Mobasher (Part 1)', 'Context-Aware Recommendation II:  Interview with Bamshad Mobasher (Part 2)', 'Industry Practical Issues:  Inteview with Anmol Bhasin', 'Recommending Music - Interview with Paul Lamere', 'Specialization Wrap Up', 'Programming Hybrids &amp; Learning to Rank']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['the way of explaining every concept is very boring', 'Great to have people from industry to talk about recommenders as well.  Thanks a lot!', 'Awesome course especially for those doing Ph.D in recommender systems ', "Great course. Professors do an excellent job of breaking down this stuff into digestible bits without losing much substance. Highly recommend. You'll need to do some outside exploration and learning though. ", 'Based on my experience with the previous courses in this specialization, I was very positively surprised by the amount and depth of material provided in this course. It covers almost everything that is there to be known. The comprehensive interviews are a big plus point. Also, this course provides guidelines as to how to develop, employ and evaluate a recommender system in real life. I would definitely recommend anyone interested in the field to take this course.', 'great courses! They invite a lot of interviews to let me understand the sea of recommend system!', 'Great course to understand the fundamentals of recommender systems, as well the diversity &amp; challenges of different recommender systems. The interviews with people from relevant academic fields &amp; industry were particularly useful', 'This is THE BEST course in Recommendation Systems. Probably getting a bit outdated as the field is moving rapidly into deep learning and other techniques, but the problems faced by any recommendation system developer would be the same - ratings measurement, sparse matrices, ranking metrics... And THAT is probably the best contribution of the whole training: not only talking about the methods but pin-pointing the main REAL problems to solve.', 'The Hybrid recommenders i.e. Week 4 needs more explanation especially what is Tensor factorization etc, Week 4 was difficult to grasp.  Week 5 and Week 6 was informative especially the LinkedIn video and Learning to Rank: Interview with Xavier Amatriain in which a problem was discussed of having that popularity vs Ranking issue.', 'Programming Assignments are not clear enough and the quiz for the last one seems to be a bit off.', 'Interview with Francesco Ricci\n', 'It would be better if explaining how to build latent features', "It will be great, if we can do honor's track with Python or R", '-some videos need better editing', '内容还是蛮有意思的。 就是 Interview 太多, 而且interview 的人的 上课水平参差不齐， 所以干货 不多。 另外 希望honor assignment 的 参考结果 应该比较 reproducible， 否则很难知道自己的 code 错在哪里。 ', "Very interesting topic which I was really stoked to learn but unfortunately this course is missing the deep insight into the algorithms, it explains just one algorithm and its variations. The content is overall to little for 6 weeks course and the honor's assignment has very bad task description with errors and lack of validating possibilities.", "The topics that were covered were done well, but I was expecting (and hoping for) way more on probabilistic matrix factorization (I still struggle to understand how it differs from regular MF) and Boltzmann machines.  Also, only one assignment in the standard track?  And you couldn't auto-grade standard track assignments and quizzes without charging a fee?  Weak", 'Few quizes. Easy tests. We need more information on the core techniques.', "Content okay, if a little basic. Second honor's track assignment is a complete mess; can't even build properly. Complaints on discussion board have gone unanswered for months."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Amine D', 'By Joeri K', 'By Sanjay K', 'By Blake C', 'By Keshaw S', 'By Light0617', 'By Ankur S', 'By Evaristo C', 'By Rahul G', 'By Alberto G', 'By aankitakaur', 'By LU W', 'By Su L', 'By Nicolás A', 'By Siwei Y', 'By Daniel P', 'By Bret', 'By Kemal C K', 'By Daniel M']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 27, 2017', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Dec 05, 2017', 'Jan 13, 2018', 'Mar 07, 2018', 'Jul 19, 2017', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Sep 17, 2017', 'Feb 19, 2018', 'Jun 10, 2018', 'Aug 14, 2017', 'Aug 25, 2018', 'Sep 12, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2018', 'Jun 29, 2017', 'Jan 07, 2018', 'Jun 16, 2017', 'Dec 28, 2017', 'Aug 31, 2019']</review_date></doc>