<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_214</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/digital-manufacturing-design</course_url><course_name>Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ken English</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will expose you to the transformation taking place, throughout the world, in the way that products are being designed and manufactured. The transformation is happening through digital manufacturing and design (DM&amp;D) – a shift from paper-based processes to digital processes in the manufacturing industry. By the end of this course, you’ll understand what DMD is and how it is impacting careers, practices and processes in companies both large and small.  

You will gain an understanding of and appreciation for the role that technology is playing in this transition. The technology we use every day – whether it is communicating with friends and family, purchasing products or streaming entertainment – can benefit design and manufacturing, making companies and workers more competitive, agile and productive. Discover how this new approach to making products makes companies more responsive, and employees more involved and engaged, as new career paths in advanced manufacturing evolve.

Main concepts of this course will be delivered through lectures, readings, discussions and various videos. 

This is the first course in the Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design Technology specialization that explores the many facets of manufacturing’s “Fourth Revolution,” aka Industry 4.0, and features a culminating project involving creation of a roadmap to achieve a self-established DMD-related professional goal.

To learn more about the Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology specialization, please watch the overview video by copying and pasting the following link into your web browser: https://youtu.be/wETK1O9c-CA</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Mechanical Engineering</course_category><course_tag>Artificial Intelligence (AI)//Digital Design//Manufacturing Engineer//Industry 4.0</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Big Picture//Components of the Paradigm</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design Technology', 'Introduction to Digital Manufacturing and Design', 'Digital Manufacturing and Design', 'Impact on Manufacturing Careers', 'Advantages of Digital Manufacturing and Design', 'Information Sharing in the Digital Thread', 'Multiple Organizations in the Manufacturing Process'], ['Components', 'Gaining Insight from Data', 'A Closed Loop Approach', 'Integrated Information Systems in the Product Lifecycle', 'Protecting Your Organization', 'Your 4.0 Roadmap to Success: Overview']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 6 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The course has a lot of basic information, and this isn't an intensive course as mentioned. but overall the information was clear and informative. thanks coursera.", 'The course is very helpful the content and references provided are good. helped a lot to learn about  possibilities in this area', 'This is very interesting course, thank you!', 'The course was well organized in terms of materials, video lectures and links to resources for us to have more clearer vision of Advanced Industry 4.0. The teachings are simplified to my understanding. I advice them to keep the good work.', 'Mit optionalen weiteren Übungen würde das erlangte Wissen weiter vertieft werden können.', 'Very interesting and informative', 'Good to learn again ', 'Good', 'Got to know about industrial revolutions and essential components of digital manufacturing.', None, 'learned new things', 'Knowledgeable', 'it is the best i learn', 'good', 'Excellent presentation and course material', 'After the introductory videos, I wish to take the full course. Thank you the information', 'Excellent quality of the course material and thanks to the instructor very easy way made to understand the language ', "Un cours permettant d'avoir une idée claire sur les bases de la digital Manufacturing &amp; Design. Je recommande ce cours à toute personne qui cherche à savoir qu'est ce que c'est que l'industrie 4.0 et comment elle va changer le monde.", None, 'The Course was helpful and it really helped me a  lot to understand what Industry 4.0 is.', 'The course is well structured covering the latest developments and  changes happening in the manufacturing world.', 'very useful ', 'The course provides a very informative overview of digital manufacturing and design. i had found it very useful for my workplace activities.....', 'Do this course if you want to know about digital manufacturing ', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Sriram P', 'By KUNAL D R', 'By Lyadanov D', 'By Israel B', 'By Kimo G', 'By Ashraf S', 'By subham k g', 'By Atichat P', 'By NADKARNI S B', 'By Richard L', 'By Pulkit j', 'By Pagadala B', 'By Amr E S E', 'By RAVI K', 'By Mohammed G A', 'By DineshKumar M', 'By Umang S M', 'By Asma H', 'By Abdullah T R', 'By Himanshu G', 'By Abhijit A B', 'By Skyler.Zhao', 'By ZAFAR I', 'By Vikash S', 'By Shivoh C']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Jul 29, 2018', 'Aug 04, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Jul 22, 2018', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Sep 05, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Oct 09, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Sep 14, 2018']</review_date></doc>