<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_91</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/pca-machine-learning</course_url><course_name>Mathematics for Machine Learning: PCA</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Marc P. Deisenroth</course_instructor><course_introduction>This intermediate-level course introduces the mathematical foundations to derive Principal Component Analysis (PCA), a fundamental dimensionality reduction technique. We'll cover some basic statistics of data sets, such as mean values and variances, we'll compute distances and angles between vectors using inner products and derive orthogonal projections of data onto lower-dimensional subspaces. Using all these tools, we'll then derive PCA as a method that minimizes the average squared reconstruction error between data points and their reconstruction.

At the end of this course, you'll be familiar with important mathematical concepts and you can implement PCA all by yourself. If you’re struggling, you'll find a set of jupyter notebooks that will allow you to explore properties of the techniques and walk you through what you need to do to get on track. If you are already an expert, this course may refresh some of your knowledge.

The lectures, examples and exercises require:
1. Some ability of abstract thinking
2. Good background in linear algebra (e.g., matrix and vector algebra, linear independence, basis)
3. Basic background in multivariate calculus (e.g., partial derivatives, basic optimization)
4. Basic knowledge in python programming and numpy

Disclaimer: This course is substantially more abstract and requires more programming than the other two courses of the specialization. However, this type of abstract thinking, algebraic manipulation and programming is necessary if you want to understand and develop machine learning algorithms.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Principal Component Analysis (PCA)//Projection Matrix//Mathematical Optimization</course_tag><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Statistics of Datasets//Inner Products//Orthogonal Projections//Principal Component Analysis</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the course', 'Welcome to module 1', 'Mean of a dataset', 'Variance of one-dimensional datasets', 'Variance of higher-dimensional datasets', 'Effect on the mean', 'Effect on the (co)variance', 'See you next module!'], ['Welcome to module 2', 'Dot product', 'Inner product: definition', 'Inner product: length of vectors', 'Inner product: distances between vectors', 'Inner product: angles and orthogonality', 'Inner products of functions and random variables (optional)', 'Heading for the next module!'], ['Welcome to module 3', 'Projection onto 1D subspaces', 'Example: projection onto 1D subspaces', 'Projections onto higher-dimensional subspaces', 'Example: projection onto a 2D subspace', 'This was module 3!'], ['Welcome to module 4', 'Problem setting and PCA objective', 'Finding the coordinates of the projected data', 'Reformulation of the objective', 'Finding the basis vectors that span the principal subspace', 'Steps of PCA', 'PCA in high dimensions', 'Other interpretations of PCA (optional)', 'Summary of this module', 'This was the course on PCA']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course does not include real-world examples as compared with other 2 courses in the series. The other lecturers energy was quite obvious and the lecturer in this course does nothing extra. This is the traditional teaching method where we should keep on grasping theory without understanding applications.', 'There is little reason to take this course except for gaining the satisfaction of completing the three courses in the series. There are briefer, more satisfying introductions to PCA elsewhere. This course has too little of what made the other courses in the series so good and shares too much of their shortcomings. Where the other two courses excelled in demonstrating an intuitive understanding of both the maths and their applications, this course really avoids all effort at intuition or examples and instead just throws formula after formula at you.  You are then given programming assignments where at least half the effort is to try to understand what is being asked before you start to work to implement it. This leaves you more with a feeling of only having completed assignments and less a sense that you’ve developed a capability in either the maths or their applications. In the end, I am left with a strong desire to learn more about the maths of PCA and their application only because I am eager to hear the subject matter explained by someone else.  ', 'The first two courses in the Mathematics for Machine Learning specialisation are excellent - even amongst the best online or traditional maths courses I have taken. This course was seriously lacking. Not in content, or even the ability of the lecturer, but rather in how the information is conveyed. There are some excellent reviews which elaborate further in to the problems with this course, so I will not labour over them all. In essence, if you are learning in your own free time, the poorer information transfer  is not appreciated.', 'Algebra course is excellent. Calculus course is good. PCA is so bad that I am still upset that I spent my time on it.', 'Very poorly written/performed material with inadequate coding help. The engagement level is quite low. Will not recommend if you have novice programming background or new to math concepts.', 'Unfortunately this course does is of much lower quality than the previous courses of the specialization. There is no progression towards the assignments which basically ask you to implement something without any context. There was even a  technical issue with the grader for the first assignment.', 'I am very disappointed with this course. It was very hard to follow, and not because this is challenging, but partly because the instructor is not so good. I had to read a lot on my own to be able to complete some assignments. I hope you can improve the content of this course. The best course of this specialization is the second one, and this is the worst.', "This course is harder that the the two first ones. You have to do a lot more by yourself. There will be some frustrations with assignments that are not always easy or clear, with confusing python/numpy notations not really introduced during the course. Also, most assignment didn't work online, so I had to install python3 and jupyter to work on them locally and submit them manually. You should expect to spend more time than announced. All in all, I've learned new things and that's the most important. I believe there are room for improvement for this course.", 'Overall: worthwhile content, but poor execution. Especially assignments need improvement.', 'Explanation of course material is not clear', 'Way too hard compared to the other courses in the specialization. I feel like I wasted my money on this. ', 'The instruction is absolutely bad and not worth it. However, if you have patience to re-watch, refer to other supporting materials, learn on your own a  lot and then have patience to deal with programming asssignments ,...then you might find the final result useful. ', "Worth auditing because the video lessons are good but unless you have solid Python programming experience, the assignments and some quiz questions will take you days instead of hours. The course info states that you would need 'Basic knowledge in python programming and numpy'. This is to be understood as 'solid practice, at least intermediate level'. 'Basic knowledge' simply does not make it possible to finish these exercises within the given timeframe (1-2 or even 3-4 hours).  ", 'This course needs a lot of work to get to the level of quality of its two predecessors. ', 'The instruction content was superb, though the tests were unrelated to content. I realize that there is a lot of criticism of the course here, but if you understand and code in Python, they are not hard. I wish the course staff had made the Jupyter notebooks more clear, giving us an understanding of what was required, if that was done this is a good, though very hard (in terms of mathematics) course.', 'I was frustrated at several points during the course - I had to scour the internet for material to improve my understanding which defeated the purpose of taking the course (math and intuition behind PCA for instance). I felt as if the instructor was reproducing material from textbook on the board. I would guess that the abandonment rate for this course is relatively high (in-spite of the introductory nature) because of monotonous delivery and lack of intuitive explanation of concepts (vs. Khan Academy/Andrew Ng for instance).  ', None, 'It is a good course but some problems must be reported. Despite the previous courses from the specialization, I missed the conceptual explanations, the development of intuitive understanding. The support is almost inexistent: questions on forums are not answered by lecturers or mentors, some programming exercises requires knowledge not even mentioned on classes and I feel it is a non necessary knowledge at all to the purpose of the course. Some tutorials would help. Only other students make things clearer at some points. Some lectures have "magic passes" not explained, specially on PCA subject itself, week 4. Maybe the courser could have a additional week to teach things in a better way.', None, 'Loved the first two courses but felt like killing myself in this course. One of the worst professors i have ever encountered. ', 'After taking/passing the two previous courses, this course is very disappointing. The programming assignments are more about numpy/python peculiarities (which dimension is D or N) and deciphering cryptographic specifications (X is documented as an input but not a parameter to the function). The misleading templates appear to be intentional - it is not clear what educational purpose this serves. The difficulty in this course is not conceptual understanding - it is difficult because the assignments are intentionally confusing. Another point regarding programming in general. This course prefers implementing numerous functions (no testing), generating large amounts of random data as input, and assuming all goes well. Perhaps each function should be tested for correctness individually with known input/output - this is not a novel idea.', "Great course !! Definitely it's an intermediate course so if you don't have a college level in lineal algebra and calculus you'll struggle with the videos and the notebooks (besides you need basic level programing in python and numpy)", 'This is one hell of an inspiring course that demystified the difficult concepts and math behind PCA.  Excellent instructors in imparting the these knowledge with easy-to-understand illustrations.', 'Make sure you have time and be ready for python code debug. If you are just an average programmer with limited python exposure like me. It will take you a day to complete the programming assignment.', "This course is hard, and contains a lot of mathematical derivations and concepts that might be overwhelming for somebody not completely fresh in maths. Nevertheless, it offers a good balance between rigour and practical application, and if some lectures turn out to be too complicated, there's always the chance to deepen the matter more quitely using the course material or online resources. I think that the course would have benefited from a more aneddoctical approach at times: for instance restating in english what the general purpose of PCA is, could help the less mathematically inclined to better seize the idea. But I know this is not always easy to do."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Hashaam S', 'By Eric P', 'By Maximilian W', 'By Ткаченко В Е', 'By Avirup G', 'By Chris M', 'By Miguel V', 'By José D', 'By Martin B', 'By JICHEN W', 'By Brock I', 'By sreekar', 'By Alexandra S', 'By Bryan S', 'By Rahul M', 'By Sanjay k', 'By Sergii T', 'By João C L S', 'By Christian R', 'By Harshit D', 'By James P', 'By Israel J L', 'By Jong H S', 'By Ruarob T', 'By Andrea V']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 30, 2018', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'Apr 29, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Apr 27, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Oct 31, 2018', 'Oct 22, 2018', 'Oct 27, 2018', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Aug 14, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'May 02, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2018', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Jun 10, 2018', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2018', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019']</review_date></doc>