<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_455</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-machine-learning-for-investment-management</course_url><course_name>Python and Machine Learning for Asset Management</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>John Mulvey - Princeton University</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will enable you mastering machine-learning approaches in the area of investment management. It has been designed by two thought leaders in their field, Lionel Martellini from EDHEC-Risk Institute and John Mulvey from Princeton University. Starting from the basics, they will help you build practical skills to understand data science so you can make the best portfolio decisions.

The course will start with an introduction to the fundamentals of machine learning, followed by an in-depth discussion of the application of these techniques to portfolio management decisions, including the design of more robust factor models, the construction of portfolios with improved diversification benefits, and the implementation of more efficient risk management models. 

We have designed a 3-step learning process: first, we will introduce a meaningful investment problem and see how this problem can be addressed using statistical techniques. Then, we will see how this new insight from Machine learning can complete and improve the relevance of the analysis.

You will have the opportunity to capitalize on videos and recommended readings to level up your financial expertise, and to use the quizzes and Jupiter notebooks to ensure grasp of concept.

At the end of this course, you will master the various machine learning techniques in investment management.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Finance</course_category><course_tag>Programming skills//Managing your own personal invetsments//Investment management knowledge//Computer Science//Expertise in data science</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>EDHEC Business School</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introducing the fundamentals of machine learning//Machine learning techniques for robust estimation of factor models//Machine learning techniques for efficient portfolio diversification//Machine learning techniques for regime analysis //Identifying recessions, crash regimes and feature selection</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Python Machine-Learning for Investment Management course', 'Introduction to machine-learning', 'Financial applications', 'Supervised learning', 'First algorithms', 'Highlights of best practice', 'Unsupervised learning', 'Challenges ahead'], ['Introduction to module 2 - Basics of factor investing', 'Introducing Factor Models', 'Typology of factor models', 'Using factor models in portfolio construction and analysis', 'Penalty methods', 'Setting factor loadings and examples', 'Shrinkage concepts', 'Lab session - Jupiter notebook on Factor Models'], ['Introduction to module 3 -Machine learning techniques for efficient portfolio diversification', 'Benefits of portfolio diversification', 'Portfolio diversification measures', 'Principle component analysis', 'Role of clustering', 'Graphical analysis', 'Selecting a portfolio of assets'], ['Introduction to economic regimes', 'Portfolio Decisions with Time-Varying Market Conditions', 'Trend filtering', 'A scenario based portfolio model', 'A two regime portfolio example', 'A multi regime model for a University Endowment', 'Lab session- Jupyter notebook on regime-based investment model'], ['Introduction to module 5', 'Traditional approaches', 'Machine-Learning Processes', 'Several Machine Learning Methods', 'Predicting recessions', 'Challenges ahead', 'Lab session - Jupiter notebook on Forecasting recessions with machine-learning']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[]</reviews><reviewers>[]</reviewers><review_date>[]</review_date></doc>