<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_409</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/global-statistics</course_url><course_name>Global Statistics - Composite Indices for International Comparisons</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Stefan Andreas Sperlich</course_instructor><course_introduction>The number of composite indices that are constructed and used internationally is growing very fast; but whilst the complexity of quantitative techniques has increased dramatically, the education and training in this area has been dragging and lagging behind. As a consequence, these simple numbers, expected to synthesize quite complex issues, are often presented to the public and used in the political debate without proper emphasis on their intrinsic limitations and correct interpretations. 

In this course on global statistics, offered by the University of Geneva jointly with the ETH Zürich KOF, you will learn the general approach of constructing composite indices and some of resulting problems. We will discuss the technical properties, the internal structure (like aggregation, weighting, stability of time series), the primary data used and the variable selection methods.  These concepts will be illustrated using a sample of the most popular composite indices. We will try to address not only statistical questions but also focus on the distinction between policy-, media- and paradigm-driven indicators.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>5.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Geneva</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome module//Some introductory issues//The steps of constructing a composite index//Globalization and Youth labour market indices (ETH Zurich/KOF)//Export Potential Assessment (ITC)//Liner shipping connectivity indices (UNCTAD) and Human development index (UNDP)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Trailer', '1.1.1 Welcome - introduction to the objectives and content of the course'], ['2.1.1 Definition of indicators and composite indices', '2.1.2 Need, use, pros and cons of composite indices', '2.2.2 Statistical offices and the public demand, part I', '2.2.3 Statistical offices and the public demand, part II', '2.2.4 The demand for social indicators', '2.2.5 The political demand, part I', '2.2.6 The political demand, part II', '2.3.1 Good practices for composite indices, part I', '2.3.2 Good practices for composite indices, part II', '2.4.1 Constructing composite indices: an overview'], ['3.1.1 Developing an economic/statistical framework, part I', '3.1.2 Developing an economic/statistical framework, part II', '3.1.3 Selecting variables and data issues', '3.2.1 A unifying framework for composite indices', '3.2.2 The transformation functions', '3.2.3 The elasticity of substitution', '3.3.1 Choosing the weights, part I', '3.3.2 Choosing the weights, part II', '3.3.3 Choosing the weights, part III', '3.4.1 Robustness of results'], ['4.1.1 Introduction', '4.1.2 Introduction to the index and YLMI tool', '4.1.3 Index components', '4.1.4 Index aggregation and results', '4.1.5 User perspective', '4.2.1 Motivation of the KOF Globalization index', '4.2.2 Selection of variables', '4.2.3 Normalization, weighting and aggregation', '4.2.4 Results', '4.2.5 User perspective'], ['5.1.1 Introduction', '5.1.2 Global overview of the export potential assessment', '5.1.3 Motivation and data treatment', '5.1.4 Economic framework', '5.1.5 First dimension: the supply side', '5.1.6 Second dimension: the demand side', '5.1.7 Third dimension: the bilateral trade relations, and results', '5.1.8 Aggregation and final indicator construction', '5.2.1 Overview of PDI, motivation and data treatment', '5.2.2 The product space methodology', '5.2.3 Dimensions of the index: supply and demand sides, and results', '5.2.4 User perspective'], ['6.1.1 Introduction', '6.1.2 Introduction of the UNCTAD  institution', '6.1.3 Motivation and plan', '6.1.4 LSCI: history and data', '6.1.5 LSCI: component and computation', '6.1.6 LSCI: stylized facts', '6.1.7 LSBCI: motivation and data', '6.1.8 LSBCI: components and computation', '6.1.9 LSBCI: stylized facts', '6.1.10 Conclusion remarks', '6.1.11 User perspective', '6.2.1 Introduction and motivation for the Human Development index', '6.2.2 Indicators: selection and data issues', '6.2.3 Aggregation, methods and reasoning', '6.2.4 Interview of Flavio Comim: A response to the common criticisms of the HDI', '6.2.6 Interview of Selim Jahan, part I: History of the Human Development index, and its major strengths and weaknesses', '6.2.7 Interview of Selim Jahan, part II: Other indices in the Human Development Report (HDR), and future of the HDR', 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['With CIs everywhere, this is a nice course for a wider audience to get an understanding of how they get constructed and matters that have to be taken into account while doing so.  Plenty of use-cases about well-known indices and presentations from people involved in their creation. If you are working with data, it is highly likely that you may come up with ideas in the end!', 'Ha sido un curso genial. Realmente didáctico y formal.  ', 'This is definitely a great course to acquire a real grasp of the methodology required for the construction of composite indices! ', "Eventhough this isn't something I want to particularly do in the future I would like to say that I have enjoyed learning about composite indicators. I would highly recommend this MOOC to anyone.", 'Ce cours m\'a permis de comprendre la théorie et les méthodes utilisées pour élaborer les indices composites qui, jusque là, étaient des "boites noires". J\'ai pu en saisir toute la richesse analytique. Je me réjouis d\'utiliser et de partager les acquis de ce cours avec toutes les personnes partageant les mêmes préoccupations : rendre intelligible une grande quantité d\'informations en les synthétisant en une grandeur explicite, informative. Je recommande vivement le suivi de ce cours.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Stellios S', 'By José L V P', 'By Liliana F D V A', 'By Mohamed A M J', 'By Vianney B B E M ']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 29, 2018', 'May 02, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Mar 30, 2019', 'May 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>