<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_190</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/build-data-science-team</course_url><course_name>Building a Data Science Team</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Data science is a team sport. As a data science executive it is your job to recruit, organize, and manage the team to success. In this one-week course, we will cover how you can find the right people to fill out your data science team, how to organize them to give them the best chance to feel empowered and successful, and how to manage your team as it grows. 

This is a focused course designed to rapidly get you up to speed on the process of building and managing a data science team. Our goal was to make this as convenient as possible for you without sacrificing any essential content. We've left the technical information aside so that you can focus on managing your team and moving it forward.

After completing this course you will know.

1. The different roles in the data science team including data scientist and data engineer
2. How the data science team relates to other teams in an organization
3. What are the expected qualifications of different data science team members
4. Relevant questions for interviewing data scientists
5. How to manage the onboarding process for the team
6. How to guide data science teams to success
7. How to encourage and empower data science teams

Commitment: 1 week of study, 4-6 hours

Course cover image by JaredZammit. Creative Commons BY-SA. https://flic.kr/p/5vuWZz</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Team Building//Data Science//Management//Team Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Building a Data Science Team</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About your instructor', 'The Data Team', 'When Do You Need Data Science?', 'Data Engineer: Qualifications &amp; Skills', 'Data Scientist: Qualifications &amp; Skills', 'Data Science Manager: Qualifications &amp; Skills', 'Where To Find The Data Team', 'Interviewing For Data Science', 'Onboarding the Data Science Team', 'Managing the Data Science Team', 'Evaluating Success of the Team', 'Embedded Teams vs. Dedicated Groups', 'How Does Data Science Interact with Other Groups', 'Empowering Others to Use Data', 'Common Interaction Difficulties', 'Common Internal Difficulties', 'Wrap-Up']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 4 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It's a really good overview with severals useful tips and tricks on how to build our team!", 'Очень полезный и интересный курс, дает достаточно теории и идей о том, с чего стоит начать работу по построению команды и на что нужно обращать внимание, будучи DS менеджером', 'Excellent inputs', 'EXCELENT CURSE, SO WELL EXPLAINED AND WELL PLANNED', None, 'Very good lesson', 'Really insightful, touching on a wide variety of subjects that are relevant to building a data science team. Thank you very much.', 'I great course completed. ', 'Very insightful!', 'Good course. Helps you visualize what you need to build a data science team.', 'Fabulous and easy to understand and internalize!', 'Very good material. Concise and simple. It has been thoroughly worked out. Good job!', 'Straight to the point! Very objective information.', 'The Professors are world class and the courses provide a great overview of an emerging field. ', 'very nice course!', 'I found the subject matter well-presented.  The content is actionable and the instructor engaging.', '  Interesting for a Non-Data Science Executive despite some minor spelling errors in video transcripts.  ', 'Good', 'This is a very well structured and really useful course, with several real-life examples and some interesting blog posts and articles on the subject.', 'Liked the way the course topics are organized to understand the basics.', 'Really great course, quick yet informative!', 'Excellent material.', 'great course and instructor!', 'Very Important with Managing Data Analysis course  ', 'Thank you very much Instructors for introducing this course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Diego B', 'By Самигуллин А', 'By Jay P', 'By Claudia K J', 'By Tan L', 'By Sarwono S', 'By Piet-Hein G', 'By Alzum S M', 'By Matheus M J', 'By Mallon L', 'By Promod R', 'By José L M A', 'By Livia R d C d', 'By Luis A', 'By Hector R C C', 'By ANNE G S', 'By Elton K', 'By Rachid R', 'By Andras F', 'By Nitin P', 'By James J', 'By Terry L J', 'By Josh T', 'By ABDALRAHIM A', 'By Abdul W']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 26, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Feb 26, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2017', 'Oct 23, 2016', 'Jun 20, 2017', 'Nov 20, 2016', 'Jan 06, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2017']</review_date></doc>