<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_454</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/social-science-research-chinese-society</course_url><course_name>Social Science Approaches to the Study of Chinese Society Part 2</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Cameron Campbell</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is intended as a first step for learners who seek to become producers of social science research. It is organized as an introduction to the design and execution of a research study. It introduces the key elements of a proposal for a research study, and explains the role of each. It reviews the major types of qualitative and quantitative data used in social science research, and then introduces some of the most important sources of existing data available freely or by application, worldwide and for China. The course offers an overview of basic principles in the design of surveys, including a brief introduction to sampling. Basic techniques for quantitative analysis are also introduced, along with a review of common challenges that arise in the interpretation of results. Professional and ethical issues that often arise in the conduct of research are also discussed.  The course concludes with an introduction to the options for further study available to the interested student, and an overview of the key steps involved in selecting postgraduate programs and applying for admission. Learners who complete the course will be able to make an informed decision about whether to pursue advanced studies, and should be adequately prepared to write an application for postgraduate study that exhibits basic understanding of key aspects of social science research paradigms and methodologies.

Explore the big questions in social science and learn how you can be a producer of social science research. 

Course Overview video: https://youtu.be/QuMOAlwhpvU

Part 1 should be completed before taking this course:  https://www.coursera.org/learn/social-science-study-chinese-society</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Social Sciences.Education</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Designing a Study//Evidence//Sampling//Public Data for China//Quantitative Analysis//Research and Professional Ethics//Where to go from here//Final exam</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course overview', '1.1 Designing a Study', '1.2 The Research Proposal', '1.3 Aims', '1.4 Impact and Significance', '1.5 Background-Literature Review', '1.6 Methodology', '1.7 Data', '1.8 Summary'], ['2.1 Evidence', '2.2 Survey data', '2.3 Public data', '2.4. Administrative and archival microdata', '2.5. Multi-generational microdata', '2.6 Aggregated data', '2.7 Sources of aggregated data', '2.8 Qualitative sources', '2.9 New sources', '2.10 Summary'], ['3.1. Overview: Sampling', '3.2. Surveys and sampling', '3.3. Probability sampling', '3.4. Clustered sampling', '3.5. Stratification, oversampling', '3.6. Respondent-driven sampling', '3.7(a) Conducting a survey - Preparation', '3.7(b) Conducting a survey - Designing a Questionnaire', '3.8. Response rates and follow-up', '3.9. Summary'], ['4.1. Overview: Public data for China', '4.2. China General Social Survey', '4.3. China Health and Retirement Longitudinal Survey', '4.4. China Family Panel Studies', '4.5. China Health and Nutrition Survey', '4.6. The China Multigenerational Panel Datasets (CMGPD)', '4.7. Other major datasets', '4.8. Summary'], ['5.1 Overview: Quantitative Analysis', '5.2 Tabulations', '5.3a Correlation and regression I', '5.3b Correlation and regression II', '5.4 Regression to the mean', '5.5 Statistical significance', '5.6 Type I errors', '5.7 Type II errors', '5.8 Summary Quantitative Analysis'], ['6.1 Overview of research and professional ethics', '6.2 The protection of subjects', '6.3 Consent', '6.4 Confidentiality', '6.5 International research', '6.6 Research funding and publication', '6.7 Data sharing', '6.8 Mentor/student relationship', '6.9 Summary:  Research and professional ethics'], ['7.1 Overview - where to go from here', '7.2 Options for advanced study in social science', '7.3 Choosing a PG program', '7.4 Writing the personal statement', '7.5 Research proposals and writing samples', '7.6 Recommendation letters', '7.7 Summary - where to go from here'], ['Part 2: Concluding remarks']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Thank you for this course. ', 'By focusing on understanding the implications, tips and pitfalls in social science research, this course is wonderfully complementary to other more technical-focused courses. The professor is generous in giving recommendation and advise which would be really useful for would be useful to not only would-be social science research students but also other research students in general. ', ' this course was dreadfully boring and made no sense.']</reviews><reviewers>['By CHRISTINE M', 'By PC', 'By Jonathan G']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 30, 2019', 'May 12, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2018']</review_date></doc>