<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_477</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/visualization-for-data-journalism</course_url><course_name>Visualization for Data Journalism</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Margaret Ng</course_instructor><course_introduction>While telling stories with data has been part of the news practice since its earliest days, it is in the midst of a renaissance. Graphics desks which used to be deemed as “the art department,” a subfield outside the work of newsrooms, are becoming a core part of newsrooms’ operation. Those people (they often have various titles: data journalists, news artists, graphic reporters, developers, etc.) who design news graphics are expected to be full-fledged journalists and work closely with reporters and editors. The purpose of this class is to learn how to think about the visual presentation of data, how and why it works, and how to doit the right way. We will learn how to make graphs like The New York Times, Vox, Pew, and FiveThirtyEight. In the end, you can share–embed your beautiful charts in publications, blog posts, and websites.

This course assumes you understand basic coding skills, preferably Python. However, we also provide a brief review on Python in Module 1, in case you want to refresh yourself on the basics and perform simple data analysis.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Libraries//Data Analysis//Plotly//Data Reporting//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Orientation//Module 1: Visualization in Newsrooms//Module 2: Data and Visual Perception//Module 3: Narrative Storytelling//Module 4: Cognitive Load and Color Perception//Course Conclusion</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction'], ['1.1 Data Visualization in Journalism: History and Development', '1.2 Types of Charts and Graphs: Choosing the Right Chart for the Right Task', '1.3 What Makes a Good Data Visualization?'], ['2.1 Journalism First', '2.2 Drilling Down on Numbers', '2.3 Data Visualization &amp; Visual Perception'], ['3.1 Narrative Storytelling 1', '3.2 Narrative Storytelling 2', '3.3 CRAP: The Principles of Design'], ['4.1 How Color Communicates Meaning', '4.2 Gestalt Principles', '4.3 The Role of Memory in Vision'], ['End of Course Survey']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[]</reviews><reviewers>[]</reviewers><review_date>[]</review_date></doc>