<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_379</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/scientific-approach-innovation-management</course_url><course_name>A Scientific Approach to Innovation Management</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alfonso Gambardella</course_instructor><course_introduction>How can innovators understand if their idea is worth developing and pursuing? In this course, we lay out a systematic process to make strategic decisions about innovative product or services that will help entrepreneurs, managers and innovators to avoid common pitfalls. We teach students to assess the feasibility of an innovative idea through problem-framing techniques and rigorous data analysis labelled ‘a scientific approach’. The course is highly interactive and includes exercises and real-world applications. We will also show the implications of a scientific approach to innovation management through a wide range of examples and case studies.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Strategy</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating /><course_orgnization>Università Bocconi</course_orgnization><course_chapter>THE INNOVATION DECISION//THEORY AND DATA FOR INNOVATION MANAGEMENT//DATA ANALYSIS//ADVANCED TOOLS FOR INNOVATION MANAGEMENT DECISIONS //FINAL PROJECT</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the course', 'Operation efficiency vs strategic efficiency', 'What data can and cannot do', 'Strategic efficiency', 'What does the scientific approach do: the Galilean manager', 'Inkdome case', 'What is innovation', 'The structure of the innovation decision', 'Risk and Uncertainty', 'Type I and type II errors in innovation decisions', 'Interactive tour of the Museum of Failure', 'The Building blocks: Theory, Hypotheses, Tests, Analysis', 'Formulate and apply theories to managerial problems', 'Tools: business model canvas and other tools'], ['Basic tools: probabilities', 'Conditional probabilities and the Bayes Theorem', 'The scientific approach', 'Using the organization to set the decision rule', 'How to derive hypotheses from a theory', 'Hypotheses and their context [p values don’t always matter]', 'Cases', 'Design and logic of hypothesis testing (download the attached datasets)', 'The use of experiments in innovation management', 'Randomized Control Trials', 'Split and multivariate tests', 'Quasi Experimental Design', 'Innovation metrics', 'Metrics validity and reliability', 'Metrics validity', 'Metrics reliability'], ['Correlation vs causality', 'Regression analysis: Theory', 'Regression analysi: Application', 'Interview with Mimoto: paving the way for electric mobility using a scientific approach', 'Interview with Eni Gas and Power: leveraging big data to uncover customer preferences', 'Using data to answer important questions at Google', 'How firms and startups can gather and analyze data to test hypotheses', 'Reflection critical evaluation'], ['Difference-in-difference approach: Theory (download the attached datasets)', 'Difference-in-difference approach: Examples (download the attached datasets)', 'Instrumental variables: Theory (download the attached datasets)', 'Instrumental variables: Examples (download the attached datasets)', 'Data science vs causal links', 'Machine learning for innovation management decisions', 'Summary, conclusions, limitations of the scientific approach'], ['$null$']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[]</reviews><reviewers>[]</reviewers><review_date>[]</review_date></doc>