<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_140</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/mcmc-bayesian-statistics</course_url><course_name>Bayesian Statistics: Techniques and Models</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Matthew Heiner</course_instructor><course_introduction>This is the second of a two-course sequence introducing the fundamentals of Bayesian statistics. It builds on the course Bayesian Statistics: From Concept to Data Analysis, which introduces Bayesian methods through use of simple conjugate models. Real-world data often require more sophisticated models to reach realistic conclusions. This course aims to expand our “Bayesian toolbox” with more general models, and computational techniques to fit them. In particular, we will introduce Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods, which allow sampling from posterior distributions that have no analytical solution. We will use the open-source, freely available software R (some experience is assumed, e.g., completing the previous course in R) and JAGS (no experience required). We will learn how to construct, fit, assess, and compare Bayesian statistical models to answer scientific questions involving continuous, binary, and count data. This course combines lecture videos, computer demonstrations, readings, exercises, and discussion boards to create an active learning experience. The lectures provide some of the basic mathematical development, explanations of the statistical modeling process, and a few basic modeling techniques commonly used by statisticians. Computer demonstrations provide concrete, practical walkthroughs. Completion of this course will give you access to a wide range of Bayesian analytical tools, customizable to your data.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Gibbs Sampling//Bayesian Statistics//Bayesian Inference//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Santa Cruz</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Statistical modeling and Monte Carlo estimation//Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC)//Common statistical models//Count data and hierarchical modeling//Capstone project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course introduction', 'Objectives', 'Modeling process', 'Components of Bayesian models', 'Model specification', 'Posterior derivation', 'Non-conjugate models', 'Monte Carlo integration', 'Monte Carlo error and marginalization', 'Computing examples', 'Computing Monte Carlo error'], ['Algorithm', 'Demonstration', 'Random walk example, Part 1', 'Random walk example, Part 2', 'Download, install, setup', 'Model writing, running, and post-processing', 'Multiple parameter sampling and full conditional distributions', 'Conditionally conjugate prior example with Normal likelihood', 'Computing example with Normal likelihood', 'Trace plots, autocorrelation', 'Multiple chains, burn-in, Gelman-Rubin diagnostic'], ['Introduction to linear regression', 'Setup in R', 'JAGS model (linear regression)', 'Model checking', 'Alternative models', 'Deviance information criterion (DIC)', 'Introduction to ANOVA', 'One way model using JAGS', 'Introduction to logistic regression', 'JAGS model (logistic regression)', 'Prediction'], ['Introduction to Poisson regression', 'JAGS model (Poisson regression)', 'Predictive distributions', 'Correlated data', 'Prior predictive simulation', 'JAGS model and model checking (hierarchical modeling)', 'Posterior predictive simulation', 'Linear regression example', 'Linear regression example in JAGS', 'Mixture model in JAGS'], ['Course conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 36 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent course!  This covered a large amount of material, but it was well organized, with a good number of problems to solve.  Matthew Heiner does an excellent job with the lectures and explains things well.  Coming from the frequentist worldview, I found this course to be a definite challenge, but well worth the time.', 'Really interesting course. The coding session are useful and can be use cases for lots of various situations.', 'The second course of the great series. The knowledge and skills gained in this course allow to actually do statistical analysis on scientific data. The course is very clear, systematic and well presented. Thank you!', 'Just finishing this class now......it is very good.  Much better than the first one in this series.  The videos and examples are better explained, and you leave with a solid understanding of Bayesian Analysis.  When I signed up for this class I really wanted to know how I could use tools like MCMC to perform real analysis, and I feel like I got what I signed up for.  Well done!', 'Brilliant course! Very well organized and with useful study cases.Suggestion: It would be nice to have the same examples in Python using, e.g. Stan or PyMC.', 'Great materials and well organized lecture structure. But in the meanwhile, it requires quite a lot preliminary knowledge. ', 'Muy recomendable para los investigadores y profesionales que quieren desarrollar productos y procesos nuevos.', 'This course helped me to get some experience at building Bayesian models and how they are applied.', 'If you want to become good in modelling it is recommended to enrol.', 'Fairly good introduction to basic Bayesian statistical models and JAGS, the package to fit those models.', 'A very good practical and theoretical course', 'Great course to learn both theories and techniques!', 'Very thorough instruction. Excellent feedback and support on forums.', 'I found this course very interesting and informative.', 'Great class.', 'The course requires good understanding of Bayesian methods and linear modelling, something that is covered in previous course of this track from University of California Santa Cruz.', 'A great course, very detailed and a very good instructor!', 'Great course!', "Very cool, probably the best course I've done in Coursera. Keep rocking! :)", "This course is a perfect continuation of the Bayesian Statistics course by Prof. Herbert Lee. It's not only mathematically rigorous but also very applied. Excellent for the beginners to the Bayesian Statistics as it allows to start confidently using Bayesian models in practice. ", "Excellent course. R usage straight from the beginning, a much useful addition to the previous course. It's very complete and when something mentioned and not explained further additional sources are recommended. Lot's of practical work and the final project I found amazing, a very practical approach that should prepare you to write reports and seriously analyse data. I would just recommend to put in the course prerequisites some basic R and some experience with statistics and probability. Although the course can be taken in isolation, the previous one is almost a prerequisite (if bayes thinking is new to you)", 'great course', 'Very challenging but interesting!', "terrific, so I've learn quite a lot basic knowledge about MCMC. So I can build kinds of models with better understanding.", 'Very helpful! ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Brian K', 'By Arnaud D', 'By Georgy M', 'By Jonathan', 'By Hugo R C R', 'By Wangtx', 'By Juan C', 'By Cardy M I', 'By Ahmed M', 'By Stephen H', 'By Victor Z', 'By Hsiaoyi H', 'By Nicholas W T', 'By Ilia S', 'By Dongliang Y', 'By Vladimir Y', 'By nicole s', 'By Michael B R', 'By Víthor R F', 'By Igor K', 'By Oaní d S d C', 'By Dallam M', 'By JOSE F', 'By Dongxiao H', 'By Yiran W']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 01, 2019', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jun 19, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Sep 06, 2018', 'Sep 24, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2017', 'Nov 07, 2017', 'Dec 29, 2017', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Jun 13, 2017', 'Jun 07, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2017', 'Feb 11, 2018', 'Nov 15, 2017', 'Jun 11, 2017']</review_date></doc>