<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_65</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/erasmus-econometrics</course_url><course_name>Econometrics: Methods and Applications</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Philip Hans Franses</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome!
Do you wish to know how to analyze and solve business and economic questions with data analysis tools? Then Econometrics by Erasmus University Rotterdam is the right course for you, as you learn how to translate data into models to make forecasts and to support decision making.

* What do I learn?
When you know econometrics, you are able to translate data into models to make forecasts and to support decision making in a wide variety of fields, ranging from macroeconomics to finance and marketing. Our course starts with introductory lectures on simple and multiple regression, followed by topics of special interest to deal with model specification, endogenous variables, binary choice data, and time series data.  You learn these key topics in econometrics by watching the videos with in-video quizzes and by making post-video training exercises. 

* Do I need prior knowledge?
The course is suitable for (advanced undergraduate) students in economics, finance, business, engineering, and data analysis, as well as for those who work in these fields. The course requires some basics of matrices, probability, and statistics, which are reviewed in the Building Blocks module. 

* What literature can I consult to support my studies?
You can follow the MOOC without studying additional sources. Further reading of the discussed topics (including the Building Blocks) is provided in the textbook that we wrote and on which the MOOC is based: Econometric Methods with Applications in Business and Economics, Oxford University Press. The connection between the MOOC modules and the book chapters is shown in the Course Guide – Further Information – How can I continue my studies.

* Will there be teaching assistants active to guide me through the course?
Staff and PhD students of our Econometric Institute will provide guidance in January and February of each year. In other periods, we provide only elementary guidance. We always advise you to connect with fellow learners of this course to discuss topics and exercises.

* How will I get a certificate?
To gain the certificate of this course, you are asked to make six Test Exercises (one per module) and a Case Project. Further, you perform peer-reviewing activities of the work of three of your fellow learners of this MOOC. You gain the certificate if you pass all seven assignments.

Have a nice journey into the world of Econometrics!
The Econometrics team</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Linear Regression//Time Series//Econometrics//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Erasmus University Rotterdam</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome Module//Simple Regression//Multiple Regression//Model Specification//Endogeneity//Binary Choice//Time Series//Case Project//OPTIONAL: Building Blocks</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to our MOOC on Econometrics', 'About this course'], ['Lecture 1.1 on Simple Regression: Motivation', 'Lecture 1.2 on Simple Regression: Representation', 'Lecture 1.3 on Simple Regression: Estimation', 'Lecture 1.4 on Simple Regression: Evaluation', 'Lecture 1.5 on Simple Regression: Application'], ['Lecture 2.1 on Multiple Regression: Motivation', 'Lecture 2.2 on Multiple Regression: Representation', 'Lecture 2.3 on Multiple Regression: Estimation', 'Lecture 2.4.1 on Multiple Regression: Evaluation - Statistical Properties', 'Lecture 2.4.2 on Multiple Regression: Evaluation - Statistical Tests', 'Lecture 2.5 on Multiple Regression: Application'], ['Lecture 3.1 on Model Specification: Motivation', 'Lecture 3.2 on Model Specification: Specification', 'Lecture 3.3 on Model Specification: Transformation', 'Lecture 3.4 on Model Specification: Evaluation', 'Lecture 3.5 on Model Specification: Application'], ['Lecture 4.1 on Endogeneity: Motivation', 'Lecture 4.2 on Endogeneity: Consequences', 'Lecture 4.3 on Endogeneity: Estimation', 'Lecture 4.4 on Endogeneity: Testing', 'Lecture 4.5 on Endogeneity: Application'], ['Lecture 5.1 on Binary Choice: Motivation', 'Lecture 5.2 on Binary Choice: Representation', 'Lecture 5.3 on Binary Choice: Estimation', 'Lecture 5.4 on Binary Choice: Evaluation', 'Lecture 5.5 on Binary Choice: Application'], ['Lecture 6.1 on Time Series: Motivation', 'Lecture 6.2 on Time Series: Representation', 'Lecture 6.3 on Time Series: Specification and Estimation', 'Lecture 6.4 on Time Series: Evaluation and Illustration', 'Lecture 6.5 on Time Series: Application'], ['$null$'], ['Lecture M.1: Introduction to Vectors and Matrices', 'Lecture M.2: Special Matrix Operations', 'Lecture M.3: Vectors and Differentiation', 'Lecture P.1: Random Variables', 'Lecture P.2: Probability Distributions', 'Lecture S.1: Parameter Estimation', 'Lecture S.2: Statistical Testing']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 31 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["One thing I regret from this course is the content of the video lectures. Having watch the first week's videos, I found that the professor mostly just read the slides - and did it in a very faithful and careful manner, not to miss a subscript .... This is quite devastating for me. I can read the slides myself (although I have to download it first, since the fonts on the screen are very small). What I need is the professor to explain the logic behind the formulas, the *why* behind what is written, instead of just reading *what* is written on the slides.", 'Rigorous condensed econometrics course with clear instruction. Great for my review of the subject, and most likely for anyone new to it who has the prerequisite skills.', "Amazing for a person who would like to start with Econometric models at the most fundamental level. You will get a load of knowledge after you complete even if you know about econometrics. If you have difficulty in algebra and statistics, do start with the last week's lectures. They are the most difficult, but follow them until the end and do all the exercises. Also, the support of the teaching staff is outstanding when you have questions. Cannot recommend it more.", "The course it's great , however in my opinion it's  too theoretical with few practical examples.", 'Old fashioned Econometrics course, still using the ideas of fixed regressors (rather than the more sensible conditional models approach), emphasizing prediction instead of causal interpretation, etc.\n', "it's a very deep course ", 'Very Good Course. However, The exercises were a bit challenging . Walk through of related examples would have helped a lot for the exercises.', 'EXCELENTE', 'Depending on what you are looking for, this course might be too theoretic or mot theoretic enough:) IMHO it strikes the balamce quite nicely, although the forced theoretical parts in the tests kept me from buying the certificate. I simply want to be able to perform the analysis.', "I love this course. I'm a student in Economics and I took this course to have a complementary view to other econometric courses I have in my program; your explanations are good and intuitive. Thanks", 'Excellent learning , though some hands on practice on tools like R and other software should also be made the part of the course. ', "C'est une formation très intéressante", 'Helpful for me. Thanks a lot!', 'I think it is good have a link and support for download statical softwares and guidance for use are.', 'Good revision for me of linear regression and basic time series. ', 'This course very usefull ', None, 'explain clearly', None, 'Nice overview of econometric theory.', 'Excelente curso, muy bien ideado con muchos ejercicios para que queden bien grabados los conceptos, en un nivel no tan básico pero con toda la información necesaria para lograrlo. De los mejores cursos que he tomado en Coursera. Soy economista y lo tomé para repasar y fue mejor de lo que esperaba.', 'Very good course, not many available online courses on this subject.', None, 'very good', 'Good and challenging course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Andrea K I', 'By Graham T', 'By Bruno A C A', 'By Zoltan A S', 'By Pedro A', 'By Alesia N', 'By Nishikant C', 'By Daniela C', 'By Christian K', 'By Axel-Cleris G', 'By mittal.hitesh.92@gmail.com', 'By mohammed a', 'By DƯ T T', 'By Dayane G', 'By Rudolf V', 'By hiras n', 'By Antonio B', 'By Thongchart B', 'By Ke-Chung " L', 'By Don A E', 'By Carlos J R R', 'By Venu R', 'By Danilo C P', 'By Bilous V', 'By Filip N']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 26, 2016', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Sep 06, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2016', 'Oct 05, 2017', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'May 07, 2019', 'Apr 09, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Sep 19, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2016', 'Nov 24, 2016', 'Jan 12, 2016', 'Nov 01, 2017', 'Mar 14, 2017', 'Jan 01, 2016', 'Jan 07, 2016', 'Dec 17, 2015', 'Feb 10, 2017', 'Nov 03, 2015', 'May 05, 2016']</review_date></doc>