<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_151</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/feature-engineering</course_url><course_name>Feature Engineering</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>Want to know how you can improve the accuracy of your machine learning models? What about how to find which data columns make the most useful features? Welcome to Feature Engineering on Google Cloud Platform where we will discuss the elements of good vs bad features and how you can preprocess and transform them for optimal use in your machine learning models.

In this course you will get hands-on practice choosing features and preprocessing them inside of Google Cloud Platform with interactive labs. Our instructors will walk you through the code solutions which will also be made public for your reference as you work on your own future data science projects.

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this course you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Raw Data to Features//Preprocessing and Feature Creation//Feature Crosses//TF Transform//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Feature Engineering'], ['Raw Data to Features', 'Good vs Bad Features', 'Quiz: Features are Related to the Objective', 'Features Known at Prediction-time', 'Quiz: Features are Knowable at Prediction Time', 'Features should be Numeric', 'Quiz: Features Should be Numeric', 'Features Should Have Enough Examples', 'Quiz: Features Should Have Enough Examples (p1)', 'Quiz: Features Should Have Enough Examples (p2)', 'Bringing Human Insight', 'Representing Features', 'ML vs Statistics', 'Lab Solution: Improve model accuracy with new features'], ['Preprocessing and Feature Creation', 'Beam and Dataflow', 'Lab Intro: Simple Dataflow Pipeline', 'Lab Solution: Simple Dataflow Pipeline', 'Data Pipelines that Scale', 'Lab Intro: MapReduce in Dataflow', 'Lab Solution: MapReduce in Dataflow', 'Preprocessing with Cloud Dataprep', 'Lab Intro: Computing Time-Windowed Features in Cloud Dataprep', 'Lab Solution: Computing Time-Windowed Features in Cloud Dataprep'], ['Introducing Feature Crosses', 'What is a Feature Cross?', 'Discretization', 'Memorization vs. Generalization', 'Taxi colors', 'Lab Intro: Feature Crosses to create a good classifier', 'Lab Solution: Feature Crosses to create a good classifier', 'Sparsity + Quiz', 'Lab Intro: Too Much of a Good Thing', 'Lab Solution: Too Much of a Good Thing', 'Implementing Feature Crosses', 'Embedding Feature Crosses', 'Where to Do Feature Engineering', 'Feature Creation in TensorFlow', 'Feature Creation in DataFlow', 'Lab Intro: Improve ML Model with Feature Engineering', 'Lab Solution (p1): ML Fairness Debrief', 'Lab Solution (p2): Improve ML Model with Feature Engineering'], ['Introducing TensorFlow Transform', 'TensorFlow Transform', 'Analyze phase', 'Transform phase', 'Supporting serving', 'Lab Intro: Exploring tf.transform', 'Lab Solution: Exploring tf.transform'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The tf.transform and Apache Beam concepts are not explained in simple ways. ', 'A lot of the code, did not work. ', 'Had a lot issues with the quiz grader.', 'The videos are good and better than the last two courses in the specialization; however, the labs lack proper instructions and not that helpful. This course seems like more of an advertisement for Google Cloud Platform than feature engineering: details of engineering part is hardly covered in the course; more emphasis is on demonstrating on how to do it on GCP.', 'Would appreciate more guidance on the exercises', 'The notebook based demos are unfortunately pretty useless as labs. All of these courses would be much improved with real labs that require the student to build the system.', 'The assessments do not actually require writing any code; you just execute the given code blocks. Little knowledge will be retained unless students actually write code and solve problems, even for the motivated ones who read through all the given code.', "It's a pretty interesting course, specially that's the only one that teaches featuring engineering with a focus on production issues, but it assumes some knowledge with apache beam, and dataflow.", 'Great Course!', 'Very useful. Good job.', 'This course should be mandatory for any ML practitioner. It teaches you that ML is not only about throwing whatever you want to (sort of) a model and expect to get reasonable results. It is about getting to know your problem and squeeze the data available.', 'Amazing course! Gives insight into one of the most important part of solving Machine Learning problems; feature engineering!!', 'had a great experience', 'Learned a lot', 'Great, Labs were redundant at times. ', 'Great teaching', 'The content is great, not just from a technical point of view but for all the know-how that the different instructors share during in the videos and labs. ', 'Learned lots of stuff on feature engineering', 'Hope all the materials in this course will be updated soon. However , thanks to all of you!', 'Great series!', 'This course is a little bit harder than the former three courses. But the intuition of feature cross and embedding is very inspiring. ', 'Very Detailed and good for individuals who do not have statistical background. Thank you.', "Great course. A bit more difficult than the other 3, because the topic is more complex. Once finished the course you'll get the big picture. It may take some time to digest all little details, but everything is very well explained in a more than exhaustive way. Teachers are also very engaging and never boring. Highly recommend to anyone interested in the topic!", 'Comprehensive Overview on Feature Engg', 'Excellent Course and advice from experts about Feature Engineering and data pipelines utilizing advanced processes on GCP, thanks to Google and Coursera.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Yasim K', 'By Stephen R', 'By Ian M', 'By Sudesh A', 'By Martin A K', 'By Mike W', 'By Robert U', 'By Omar M A', 'By Abdul R Y', 'By Mark B', 'By Mario R', 'By Putcha L N R', 'By SULTHAN M N', 'By Eric', 'By Sujeethan V', 'By Stephen Y', 'By Patxi G ', 'By Raja R G', 'By Hua S', 'By Serhan A', 'By Jun W', 'By Sanjay K', 'By Giovanni S', 'By Vishal K', 'By Carlos V']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 12, 2018', 'Aug 27, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Jul 28, 2018', 'May 31, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jun 11, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'May 28, 2018', 'Jun 06, 2018', 'Jun 02, 2018', 'Jun 18, 2018', 'Jul 01, 2018']</review_date></doc>