<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_339</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/computational-phenotyping</course_url><course_name>Identifying Patient Populations</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Laura K. Wiley, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course teaches you the fundamentals of computational phenotyping, a biomedical informatics method for identifying patient populations. In this course you will learn how different clinical data types perform when trying to identify patients with a particular disease or trait. You will also learn how to program different data manipulations and combinations to increase the complexity and improve the performance of your algorithms. Finally, you will have a chance to put your skills to the test with a real-world practical application where you develop a computational phenotyping algorithm to identify patients who have hypertension. You will complete this work using a real clinical data set while using a free, online computational environment for data science hosted by our Industry Partner Google Cloud.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado System</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction: Identifying Patient Populations//Tools: Clinical Data Types//Techniques: Data Manipulations and Combinations//Techniques: Algorithm Selection and Portability//Practical Application: Develop a Computational Phenotyping Algorithm to Identify Patients with Hypertension</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Identifying Patient Populations', 'Introduction to Computational Phenotyping', 'Introduction to Manual Record Review', 'Manual Record Review: Selecting Reviewers and Records', 'Manual Record Review: Tools and Techniques'], ['Data Types for Computational Phenotyping', 'Computational Phenotyping: Billing Data', 'Computational Phenotyping: Laboratory Data', 'Computational Phenotyping: Clinical Observations', 'Computational Phenotyping: Medications'], ['Manipulating Individual Data Types', 'Combining Multiple Data Types'], ['Selecting a Final Algorithm'], ['Welcome to Practical Applications!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This is a well-presented course. I highly recommend. ', 'excellent course.', 'Great course, gives a solid understanding of computational phenotyping. Also teaches some R programming!', "The instructor does a great job of providing hands-on teaching in addition to lecture. However, this course required a lot of knowledge of R, which wasn't provided in the introductory course.", 'A good course on identifying patient populations with R. However, some concepts/use of functions in R programming do not get fully-explained and needs learnt from other sources.', 'I am simply not able to finish the course because no peer reviewers available.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Angela B', 'By qianmengxiao', 'By Mor K', 'By William H', 'By Vu T T T', 'By rroddema']</reviewers><review_date>['May 13, 2019', 'Jun 20, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Apr 05, 2019', 'Sep 16, 2019', 'Sep 16, 2019']</review_date></doc>