<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_55</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/analytics-excel</course_url><course_name>Mastering Data Analysis in Excel</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jana Schaich Borg</course_instructor><course_introduction>Important: The focus of this course is on math - specifically, data-analysis concepts and methods - not on Excel for its own sake. We use Excel to do our calculations, and all math formulas are given as Excel Spreadsheets, but we do not attempt to cover Excel Macros, Visual Basic, Pivot Tables, or other intermediate-to-advanced Excel functionality.

This course will prepare you to design and implement realistic predictive models based on data. In the Final Project (module 6) you will assume the role of a business data analyst for a bank, and develop two different predictive models to determine which applicants for credit cards should be accepted and which rejected. Your first model will focus on minimizing default risk, and your second on maximizing bank profits. The two models should demonstrate to you in a practical, hands-on way the idea that your choice of business metric drives your choice of an optimal model.

The second big idea this course seeks to demonstrate is that your data-analysis results cannot and should not aim to eliminate all uncertainty. Your role as a data-analyst is to reduce uncertainty for decision-makers by a financially valuable increment, while quantifying how much uncertainty remains. You will learn to calculate and apply to real-world examples the most important uncertainty measures used in business, including classification error rates, entropy of information, and confidence intervals for linear regression.

All the data you need is provided within the course, all assignments are designed to be done in MS Excel, and you will learn enough Excel to complete all assignments. The course will give you enough practice with Excel to become fluent in its most commonly used business functions, and you’ll be ready to learn any other Excel functionality you might need in the future (module 1).

The course does not cover Visual Basic or Pivot Tables and you will not need them to complete the assignments. All advanced concepts are demonstrated in individual Excel spreadsheet templates that you can use to answer relevant questions. You will emerge with substantial vocabulary and practical knowledge of how to apply business data analysis methods based on binary classification (module 2), information theory and entropy measures (module 3), and linear regression (module 4 and 5), all using no software tools more complex than Excel.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Binary Classification//Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Linear Regression</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About This Course//Excel Essentials for Beginners//Binary Classification//Information Measures//Linear Regression//Additional Skills for Model Building//Final Course Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About This Specialization', 'Introduction to Mastering Data Analysis in Excel'], ['Introduction to Using Excel in this Course', 'Basic Excel Vocabulary; Intro to Charting', 'Arithmetic in Excel', 'Functions on Individual Cells', 'Functions on a Set of Numbers', 'Functions on Ordered Pairs of Data', 'Sorting Data in Excel', 'Introduction to the Solver Plug-in'], ['Introduction to Binary Classification', 'Bombers and Seagulls:  Confusion Matrix', 'Costs Determine Optimal Threshold', 'Calculating Positive and Negative Predictive Values', 'How to Calculate the Area Under the ROC Curve', 'Binary Classification with More than One Input Variable'], ['Quantifying the Informational Edge', 'Probability and Entropy', 'Entropy of a Guessing Game', 'Dependence and Mutual Information', 'The Monty Hall Problem', 'Learning from One Coin Toss, Part 1', 'Learning From One Coin Toss, Part 2'], ['Introducing the Gaussian', 'Introduction to Standardization', 'Standard Normal Probability Distribution in Excel', 'Calculating Probabilities from Z-scores', 'Central Limit Theorem', 'Algebra with Gaussians', 'Markowitz Portfolio Optimization', 'Standardizing x and y Coordinates for Linear Regression', 'Standardization Simplifies Linear Regression', 'Modeling Error in Linear Regression', 'Information Gain from Linear Regression'], ['Describing Histograms and Probability Distributions Functions', 'Some Important and Frequently Encountered PDFs', 'Linear Regression with More than One Input Variable', 'Understanding Why Over-fitting Happens'], ['Final Project Information:  Part 1', 'Final Project Information:  Part 2']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 29 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course has more holes than swiss cheese. The instructor makes major leaps without thoroughly explaining things. A lot of times when I started to do a problem set it felt like I had missed 2 or 3 lectures. But I had not, the instructor just leaves you to figure a lot out on your own. The videos are choppy often containing errors that sometimes have a note stating the accurate information. The excel sheets are posted at the end of the lecture as opposed to the beginning. But they have nothing to do with the lectures other than the calculus behind the formulas. So you have to go through cell by cell to figure out what the hell the instructor did and what calculus was being used. I appreciate how the instructor combined a lot of material here but unless you are fresh of calculus 3 or several statistics class then this is complexly crap course. ', 'Horrible instruction. Little to no motivation is supplied for each topic. Moreover, the statistical concepts taught in this course are not preceded by preliminary concepts. For instance, I believe it is not until the course is almost over that the concept of a random variable is discussed. Do not waste your time with this course if your goal is to be more skilled in excel.', "Great course. My one caveat would be that, as other reviews have stated, the name of the course is misleading. In my opinion, this course isn't nearly about Excel as much as it is about probability and statistical analysis. If you haven't taken classes and don't have any experience with these, you will be in for a very rough ride. However, Professor Eggers does a good job of guiding you through it and gives you the resources you need to succeed. It will undoubtedly be tough, but if you are persistent and believe in yourself, you will succeed. And you will come out on the other side better for the wear. Cheers! ", "1. The scribbling on the videos is not legible.  How do you expect students to learn when we can't read that scribble.", 'The course is great as it allows you to apply all the concepts taught in scenarios that are really practical. The resources supplied with the course are extremely useful,and all in all the course is good for anyone trying to understand data analytics.', 'es un curso que te va a ayudar a saber manejar excel y ademas de aprender los temas básicos aprenderás de temas como teste de modelos. ', 'its a good course but maybe in the future you can add another case for participants  to build another model beside bank credit model', 'Excellent course, I learnt a lot and really enjoyed it. Definitely recommend ! ', 'Great course improves data analysis insight', 'Very comprehensive. Lot of theory and practical. My request would be to add a week focusing on a couple models and a couple methods to select metrics and validate confidence.', 'This is overall a great course for learning how to use Excel to analyse and manage data. However, the topics covered do not prepare you for the final project. I had to do a lot of trial and error, and research how to complete certain tasks, as the information given in the lessons is not substantial enough to complete the final project. On the plus side, this forced me to figure things out on my own and and taught me a lesson in perseverance. Coming from a humanities background, this course showed me the basics of using Excel and I now feel comfortable using Excel to analyse and manage large data sets. ', 'There were a lot of holes in the teaching of this class. We covered more statistics content than I did in my full-time MBA statistics class over a few 10 minute YouTube videos. Additionally, there is some calculus which I have not studied in 10 years or so. I would have liked to see more excel functionalities explained to add to my tool bag. With all that being said, I learned from the class and enjoyed some of the spreadsheets that were provided. I expected to be challenged since the course is done through a prestigious university and definitely was. ', 'The exercises, resources and quizzes were really good. I felt they were putting to you to the test to see if you had applicable Excel knowledge.', "I learned a lot in this course, but it is definitely not what you would expect from the title! Like many others before me have mentioned, it's more of an advanced statistics course than an excel-based data analytics course. They provide spreadsheets that are already filled with formulas (you really don't get the opportunity to create them yourself, but they are pretty cool nonetheless), BUT they never use the spreadsheets in the lessons and DON'T properly explain how to use them; that said, you're required to understand how to use them for the exams!", 'Sheet is hard and too high complex for understand.', 'The video just explains the basics but they dont take up detailed examples which are asked in the quizes and then it becomes very difficult to understand the concept', 'I would not recommend this course to any one. The things they teach in videos and questions they ask on test are pretty different. First few things are fine then the course turns the other way', 'One of the best course that i have ever done. Just make a patience and repeat the lecture if u find any difficulty , every time you realise that you are increasing your capablities or knowledge in Data Analytics sector.I will surely recommmcend this course .', 'ccol', 'Great !', 'This course has enabled me to think the way a data analyst need to think. This course helps in independent growth and getting know the topics by own research. Loved it ! Thank you !', 'Lots of information in a short period of time. Last Final was challenging to say the least, but by reading the Discussion Form you are able to get through it.', 'please provide chinese for us  Thx you very much', 'really helped me understand the material for my job ', 'great course got great knowledge about the models used for data analysis']</reviews><reviewers>['By GBT', 'By Thomas S', 'By Kenneth W', 'By Krishna K', 'By Hardik M', 'By Marcela E', 'By Achmad R A', 'By Soukaina K', 'By valentine M', 'By Doug J', 'By Amy H', 'By Matthew T', 'By Santiago H', 'By Courtney B', 'By Thanapich T', 'By Mohammad A P', 'By KRUTI S', 'By Jitesh g', 'By Meenal C ', 'By Jagmohan M', 'By Aditya S', 'By Jennifer L', 'By chehaoming', 'By Aysharjo H', 'By Rajat K']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Oct 12, 2018', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Jun 21, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'May 02, 2019', 'Apr 12, 2019', 'Apr 29, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Apr 30, 2019', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'May 08, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019']</review_date></doc>