<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_349</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/visual-recognition</course_url><course_name>Visual Recognition &amp; Understanding</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Radhakrishna Dasari</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course immerses learners in deep learning, preparing them to solve computer vision problems. Learners plunge into the field of computer vision that deals with recognizing, identifying and understanding visual information from visual data, whether the information is from a single image or video sequence. Topics include object detection, face detection and recognition (using Adaboost and Eigenfaces), and the progression of deep learning techniques (CNN, AlexNet, REsNet, and Generative Models.)      
  
This course is ideal for anyone curious about or interested in exploring the concepts of visual recognition and deep learning computer vision. Learners should have basic programming skills and experience (understanding of for loops, if/else statements), specifically in MATLAB (free introductory tutorial: https://www.mathworks.com/learn/tutorials/matlab-onramp.html). Learners should also be familiar with the following: basic linear algebra (matrix vector operations and notation), 3D co-ordinate systems and transformations, basic calculus (derivatives and integration) and basic probability (random variables). It is highly recommended that learners take the “Deep Learning Onramp” course available at https://matlabacademy.mathworks.com/.   

Material includes online lectures, videos, demos, hands-on exercises, project work, readings and discussions. Learners gain experience writing computer vision programs through online labs using MATLAB* and supporting toolboxes.

This is the fourth course in the Computer Vision specialization that lays the groundwork necessary for designing sophisticated vision applications. To learn more about the specialization, check out a video overview at https://youtu.be/OfxVUSCPXd0. 

 * A free license to install MATLAB for the duration of the course is available from MathWorks.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Algorithms</course_category><course_tag>Deep Learning//Matlab//Machine Learning//Computer Programming//Computer Vision</course_tag><course_rating>3.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Visual Recognition &amp; Understanding//Early Techniques//Deep Learning Overview//Deep Learning in Computer Vision: Applications</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Visual Recognition', 'Health Care &amp; Visual Perception', 'Detection, Localization &amp; Classification', 'Recognition', 'Product Identification', 'Recognition: Progress &amp; Unsolved Problems', 'More Unsolved Problems &amp; Gaps', 'Machine Learning in Computer Vision', 'Machine Learning: Past &amp; Present'], ['Neural Networks for Optical Character Recognition', 'Techniques: Before Deep Learning', 'Adaboost for Face Detection', 'Eigenfaces for Face Recognition', 'SVMs for Object Detection'], ['Deep Learning Overview', 'Introduction to Deep Learning', 'Insight on Deep Learning', 'Convolutional Neural Networks', 'LSTM, RNN &amp; ResNet', 'Generative Models'], ['Object Detection &amp; Transfer Learning', 'Deep Learning: Key Applications', 'Face Detection &amp; Recognition', 'Image Segmentation', 'Video Understanding', 'Future of Computer Vision', 'Human-Machine Interaction', 'Future Research Areas', 'Evolution of Computer Vision']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The first test answer is not formal enough. The answer can not let % and 0. ... as the right answer.', 'It is a bit better than the previous classes of this specialization but still not great. On the positive side, there is a lot of presentations of the visual recognition techniques and the classes relies on the Matlab tutorials to develop practical skills. On the negative side, like in the previous classes, the videos miss many parts so you will hear a lot from the trainer "let us see something" but nothing will show up.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Hongming Z', 'By Brice L']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 20, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019']</review_date></doc>