<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_252</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/gcp-production-ml-systems</course_url><course_name>Production Machine Learning Systems</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>In the second course of this specialization, we will dive into the components and best practices of a high-performing ML system in production environments. 

Prerequisites: Basic SQL, familiarity with Python and TensorFlow</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the course//Architecting Production ML Systems//Ingesting data for Cloud-based analytics and ML//Designing Adaptable ML systems//Designing High-performance ML systems//Hybrid ML systems//Course Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Getting Started with Google Cloud Platform and Qwiklabs'], ['Introduction', 'The Components of an ML System', 'The Components of an ML System: Data Analysis and Validation', 'The Components of an ML System: Data Transformation + Trainer', 'The Components of an ML System: Tuner + Model Evaluation and Validation', 'The Components of an ML System: Serving', 'The Components of an ML System: Orchestration + Workflow', 'The Components of an ML System: Integrated Frontend + Storage', 'Training Design Decisions', 'Serving Design Decisions', 'Lab Intro: Serving on Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab Solution: Serving on Cloud AI Platform', 'Designing from Scratch'], ['Introduction', 'Data On-Premise', 'Large Datasets', 'Data on Other Clouds', 'Existing Databases', 'Demo: Load data into BigQuery', 'Demo: Automatic ETL Pipelines into GCP'], ['Introduction', 'Adapting to Data', 'Changing Distributions', 'Exercise: Adapting to Data', 'Right and Wrong Decisions', 'System Failure', 'Mitigating Training-Serving Skew through Design', 'Lab Intro: Serving ML Predictions in batch and real-time', 'Lab Solution: Serving ML Predictions in batch and real-time', 'Debugging a Production Model', 'Summary'], ['Introduction', 'Training', 'Predictions', 'Why distributed training?', 'Distributed training architectures', 'Faster input pipelines', 'Native TensorFlow Operations', 'TensorFlow Records', 'Parallel pipelines', 'Data parallelism with All Reduce', 'Parameter Server Approach', 'Inference'], ['Introduction', 'Machine Learning on Hybrid Cloud', 'KubeFlow', 'Demo: KubeFlow', 'Embedded Models', 'TensorFlow Lite', 'Optimizing for Mobile', 'Summary'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['A lot of great production examples, labs and reviews but perhaps too many issues for a single course - however I understand that it was perhaps to provide an overview of the possibilities, a kind of "toolbox" for production ML.', 'It is very good course, gives good overview over large ML systems on cloud, a lot of examples from real implementations gives good understunding about problematics in projects realisations', 'I did not realize the many aspects to consider implementing a Production ML system. This course presents all of them and provides guidance for evaluating alternative', 'It was bit hard course but lab work was great and learn many production level consideration for ml systems. ', 'Very practical which was nice. Thank you for adding the Quicklabs that helped a lot.', 'While most of the content is sufficiently informative for a course, the implementation itself has too many issues: wrong videos in some modules, errors in quizzes, and so on. Once they organize the material properly, this course can definitely be 5 stars.', "Subscribing to this course only gives you option to run assignments on Qwik labs, and they're very poor for these kinds of assignments. You won't get any feedback on assignments anyway since there is no grader.", 'Very informative on production systems....', 'wow gcp michael feldman', 'excellent', 'Rich course, although a little tedious, the info is priceless almost all the time. good for consultation', 'much meatier of a course.', 'very useful for consider data enigerring', 'Good', 'This course reveals some practical techniques in Production Machine Learning Systems. I like the real world examples introduced in this course.', 'Thumbs Up@', 'Really informative and insightful. ', 'very good information. Lot of unknown facts in ML are brought up in the course. ', 'very good', 'good', 'Great Course', 'Good Job!!!!', 'Perfect for my study ML', '아주 좋아요', 'Very Good!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Sinan G', 'By Artur K', 'By Armando F', 'By bhadresh s', 'By Mark D', 'By Cristobal S', 'By Jakub B', 'By Raja R G', 'By Michael F', 'By Alexander K', 'By Facundo F', 'By Cameron S B', 'By 林佳佑', 'By Atichat P', 'By Jun W', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By Skander H', 'By Venkata P I', 'By Kim J W', 'By 이전규', 'By SOYOUNG J', 'By Jincheol W', 'By 김민지', 'By 최일훈', 'By 최철웅']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 27, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'May 07, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Oct 29, 2018', 'Jun 26, 2019', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Oct 04, 2018', 'Nov 04, 2018', 'Apr 13, 2019', 'May 25, 2019', 'May 30, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Jul 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>