<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_22</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-machine-learning</course_url><course_name>Applied Machine Learning in Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Kevyn Collins-Thompson</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce the learner to applied machine learning, focusing more on the techniques and methods than on the statistics behind these methods. The course will start with a discussion of how machine learning is different than descriptive statistics, and introduce the scikit learn toolkit through a tutorial. The issue of dimensionality of data will be discussed, and the task of clustering data, as well as evaluating those clusters, will be tackled. Supervised approaches for creating predictive models will be described, and learners will be able to apply the scikit learn predictive modelling methods while understanding process issues related to data generalizability (e.g. cross validation, overfitting). The course will end with a look at more advanced techniques, such as building ensembles, and practical limitations of predictive models. By the end of this course, students will be able to identify the difference between a supervised (classification) and unsupervised (clustering) technique, identify which technique they need to apply for a particular dataset and need, engineer features to meet that need, and write python code to carry out an analysis. 

This course should be taken after Introduction to Data Science in Python and Applied Plotting, Charting &amp; Data Representation in Python and before Applied Text Mining in Python and Applied Social Analysis in Python.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Machine Learning (ML) Algorithms//Machine Learning//Scikit-Learn</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Fundamentals of Machine Learning - Intro to SciKit Learn//Module 2: Supervised Machine Learning - Part 1//Module 3: Evaluation//Module 4: Supervised Machine Learning - Part 2</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Key Concepts in Machine Learning', 'Python Tools for Machine Learning', 'An Example Machine Learning Problem', 'Examining the Data', 'K-Nearest Neighbors Classification'], ['Introduction to Supervised Machine Learning', 'Overfitting and Underfitting', 'Supervised Learning: Datasets', 'K-Nearest Neighbors: Classification and Regression', 'Linear Regression: Least-Squares', 'Linear Regression: Ridge, Lasso, and Polynomial Regression', 'Logistic Regression', 'Linear Classifiers: Support Vector Machines', 'Multi-Class Classification', 'Kernelized Support Vector Machines', 'Cross-Validation', 'Decision Trees'], ['Model Evaluation &amp; Selection', 'Confusion Matrices &amp; Basic Evaluation Metrics', 'Classifier Decision Functions', 'Precision-recall and ROC curves', 'Multi-Class Evaluation', 'Regression Evaluation', 'Model Selection: Optimizing Classifiers for Different Evaluation Metrics'], ['Naive Bayes Classifiers', 'Random Forests', 'Gradient Boosted Decision Trees', 'Neural Networks', 'Deep Learning (Optional)', 'Data Leakage', 'Introduction', 'Dimensionality Reduction and Manifold Learning', 'Clustering', 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 24 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Glosses over material (much like prior courses in this specialization), the professor is audibly nervous during recorded lectures, and many assignments require information and functions not covered in the lectures. Additionally, out of date Python modules are used in the notebooks, so you're learning often deprecated usage patterns, not to mention the constant struggle that is the auto-grader. You can teach yourself with free resources and save yourself the money and unhelpful bouts of rage against the auto-grader.", "I want to give this course a higher score because I do think I learned A TON. However, I learned a ton because the course had some flaws in instructions and assignments that required some frustrating moments and a lot of outside work to correct. If you take this course, DISCUSSION FORUMS are a must because of all the errors and bugs in assignments. The explanations are a little 'too rosy' in the videos in my opinion (they show best case scenarios) so there's a disconnect in what i actually had to do to pass the assignments which tended to have lots of room for improvement. That said, if you are willing to go out on your own and figure it out (mentors are so-so in actually helping), then this course is a great ML workout!", 'This is a great course for those with limited experience of machine learning, wishing to quickly grasp how to apply machine learning methods and get their hands dirty. In my opinion, this is the best course in the specialization so far and as in previous courses you are expected to dig into further theoretical/usage details yourself from online documentation (hence the name applied). Concise lectures and interesting reading materials, as well as hands-on assignments. My recommendation is to either start with this course or take it together with more theoretical courses (such as "Machine Learning" from Stanford or "Machine Learning Fundamentals" from UCSD) to get the full flavour of what machine learning has to offer.', "This could the single most interesting course amongst all the 5 courses in this specialization. It made Machine Learning easy to interpret and fun to explore for beginners. The assignments are very thorough, though with some autograder issues. I strongly recommend anyone who's interested in ML to take this introductory course to again some knowledge in the different methods and applications of ML in various fields.", "A lot of stuff, compressed in a short time. It's more about memorizing a lot of concepts rather than understanding them. I strongly recommend to take the course of professor Andrew Ng before this one.", "Not very good compared to the first two courses :( :( :( ... I took a Machine Learning Class from Stanford which was incredibly well put together and presented (though to be fair, it was 12 weeks), but it was in MatLab and I wanted to take a course in Python just to have a different perspective and solidify my understanding. Unfortunately, I find this course to be confusing more than anything. If I hadn't taken the Stanford course before, I'd be completely lost. It's very dry, dense, and hand-wavy and doesn't go into a whole lot of details with anything leaving you wondering what's happening and why and how... I don't approve of jumping straight to using the built-in functions if you don't understand the processes behind them (which I personally don't have a solid grasp on them still) ... I think they are just trying to fit too much information into four weeks and it's really lacking. Maybe if you're already familiar with linear regression, it's not as hard to follow. Either way, I'd recommend either taking the Stanford class first, or learning about this stuff elsewhere before starting this course.", 'The course is so informative and interseting.', 'Gives practical experience with ML in Python.', '어려웠어요 ㅠㅠ', 'This course is an survey on how to implement many machine learning techniques using the SciKit Learn library. Following the course, you can learn several interesting details about how to work in the field, but it is important to take into account that it is not possible to learn the algorithms during the course, since a huge amount of material is covered during a short time; to make the most of the course you have to know them in advance. It bothered me to discover that the course was planned for five weeks but Coursera has reduced it to four, removing the possibility of practicing exercises on unsupervised learning.', 'Since there are many theoretical concepts in this course, like model evaluation and tuning parameters, it would be much better if those are explained using real or semi-real life problem examples. Especially the quizzes needed more context as to why a particular situatrion might occur, and why that particular variable of interest is necessary. ', "There is a huge difference between teaching / tutoring and just reading some pre-written scripts. Even on an online course. Andrew Ng's Machine Learning course is a great example of teaching and this was one of the worst courses I have ever taken in coursera / udacity.", 'My biggest critique of this class is that it is not challenging at all. Homework assignments are just a repeat of the lectures and take less than an hour if you took notes on the lectures. In other words, there is no value in the homework assignments. ', 'I am unenrolling because of the following reasons: ', 'Me gusto muchísimo, los temas, la dinámica para el aprendizaje y el trabajo final', 'Great class!  I had fun learning many new things in this course.  The professor did a very good job at taking a complex subject and making it simple and easy to understand.  The code and assignments were straightforward and not overly difficult.  The real quizzes/tests in this course were appreciated as this felt more like a "real class" where one can really learn a lot.  One of the best online classes that I have taken.', 'Awesome course', 'An excellent resource to immerse yourself into machine learning methods. Professor Kevyn explains key concepts in the most intuitive way possible. It does require some previous experience in Python.', 'Excellent Course', 'i love this course', 'Wonderful program, great teacher. Learned a lot and have used a bit in the real world!', 'Great course - balanced and very revealing for direct application.', 'contents are good.', 'The course was very well designed. The pace of the lectures are perfect unlike other course when the instructor moves very fast.', 'In depth understanding is required to complete the assignments. Challenging without being demanding. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Brendan B', 'By Sarah H H', 'By Max B', 'By Lin Y', 'By Riccardo T', 'By solarmew', 'By Athira C', 'By Haim S R', 'By Choi H', 'By Oliverio J S J', 'By Raivis J', 'By SeyedAlireza K', 'By Aziz J', 'By Arpan S', 'By Romel C B', 'By Michael T B', 'By George G', 'By Angelo S', 'By Akash C', 'By TAIBUR R', 'By Daniel R', 'By Phillip L C', 'By Nithin R', 'By SURENDRA O', 'By Megan J']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 06, 2019', 'May 02, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jul 09, 2019', 'Sep 21, 2018', 'Jun 13, 2017', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Nov 23, 2018', 'Feb 04, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2017', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018']</review_date></doc>