<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_48</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/uva-darden-market-analytics</course_url><course_name>Marketing Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rajkumar Venkatesan</course_instructor><course_introduction>Organizations large and small are inundated with data about consumer choices. But that wealth of information does not always translate into better decisions. Knowing how to interpret data is the challenge -- and marketers in particular are increasingly expected to use analytics to inform and justify their decisions. 

Marketing analytics enables marketers to measure, manage and analyze marketing performance to maximize its effectiveness and optimize return on investment (ROI). Beyond the obvious sales and lead generation applications, marketing analytics can offer profound insights into customer preferences and trends, which can be further utilized for future marketing and business decisions. 

This course gives you the tools to measure brand and customer assets, understand regression analysis, and design experiments as a way to evaluate and optimize marketing campaigns. You'll leave the course with a solid understanding of how to use marketing analytics to predict outcomes and systematically allocate resources.

For more information on marketing analytics, you may visit; http://dmanalytics.org. You can also follow my posts in Twitter, @rajkumarvenk, and on linkedin; www.linkedin.com/in/rajkumar-venkatesan-14970a3.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Marketing</course_category><course_tag>Marketing Experiments//Customer Lifetime Value//Regression Analysis//Marketing Analytics//Brand Equity</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Virginia</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Marketing Process//Metrics for Measuring Brand Assets//Customer Lifetime Value//Marketing Experiments//Regression Basics</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Data, Data Everywhere!', 'Course Overview', 'Why Marketing Analytics?', 'Introduction to the Marketing Process', 'Airbnb Marketing Process', "Airbnb's Strategic Challenge", "Airbnb's Marketing Strategy with Data", 'Using Text Analytics', 'Utilizing Data to Improve Marketing Strategy', 'Takeaways: Improving the Marketing Process with Analytics'], ['Intro to Metrics for Measuring Brand Assets', 'Snapple and Brand Value', 'Developing Brand Personality', 'Brand Personality: Red Bull', 'Developing Brand Architecture', 'Brand Architecture: Red Bull', 'Brand Architecture: Etch A Sketch', 'Measuring Brand Value', 'Measuring Brand Value: Key Points', 'Revenue Premium as a Measure of Brand Equity', 'Calculating Brand Value: Snapple', 'Takeaways: Measuring Brand Value'], ['Welcome to Week 3', 'Customer Lifetime Value (CLV)', 'Customer Lifetime Value: Netflix', 'Calculating CLV', 'Understanding the CLV Formula', 'Applying the CLV Formula: Netflix', 'Extending the CLV Formula, Part 1', 'Extending the CLV Formula, Part 2', 'Using CLV to Make Decisions: IBM', 'CLV: A Forward Looking Measure', 'Takeaways: CLV'], ['Welcome to Week 4', 'Determining Cause and Effect through Experiments', 'Designing Basic Experiments', 'Designing Before - After Experiments', 'Designing Full Factorial Web Experiments', 'Designing an Experiment: Etch A Sketch', 'Analyzing an Experiment: Etch A Sketch', 'Analyzing an Experiment: Betty Spaghetty', 'Projecting Lift', 'Calculating Projected Lift: Betty Spaghetty', 'Pitfalls of Marketing Experiments: Betty Spaghetty', 'Maximizing Effectiveness: Nanoblocks', 'Takeaways: Marketing Experiments'], ['Welcome to Week 5', 'Using Regression Analysis', 'What Regressions Reveal', 'Interpreting Regression Outputs', 'Multivariable Regressions', 'Omitted Variable Bias', 'Using Price Elasticity to Evaluate Marketing', 'Understanding Log-Log Models', 'Marketing Mix Models', 'Takeaways: Regressions', 'Course Conclusion', 'Interview with Jennifer Chick, VP Marketing, Hilton Worldwide - Part 1', 'Interview with Jennifer Chick, VP Marketing, Hilton Worldwide - Part 2', 'Interview with Paul Hunter, Head of Operations, dunnhumby, on Using Data - Part 1', 'Interview with Paul Hunter, Head of Operations, dunnhumby, on Using Data - Part 2', 'Interview with Paul Flugel, VP of Global Marketing Performance - Part 1', 'Interview with Paul Flugel, VP of Global Marketing Performance - Part 2']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 24 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Good theoretical knowledge. The program create awareness about Marketing analytics, The program could be improved with more detailed examples across different industry. It would be logical to have a part 2 where theory is applied for practical learning. ', 'basic. Not advanced enough no real analysis to be done. no hands on activity', 'course is awesome and got a lot of interesting things', 'great course', 'Extremely valuable course, in the going market environment where big data is changing the way of how companies performed in past. learning analytics is going to provide real help in the future job and the changing  dynamics of how companies analyze data and take actions. The Teacher is super awesome, very polite and friendly way of teaching and providing the key knowledge. Thankyou SIr, ThankYou coursera . ', "It's a great platform to learn. Module are very interesting and user friendly. Each and everything is explained with such an ease that it clarifies all things at once. Real time and industry based examples make the topics more relevent and practical. I will recommend this course from coursera to everyone who want to do an online certification in Marketing Analytics.", 'It is a good course and it develops my insight in marketing analytics which will help me in my further career in business area', 'course is awesome but it could be more analytical. more algorithms could have explained in addition to regression. Over all its good. waiting for my certificate ', "It's my first contact with this discipline and I really appreciate that it's very friendly with beginners. They provide clear explanations and relevant examples to which one can easy relate, as the companies are well known to the public. Highly recommended for those who make their first steps under the marketing curtains", 'Very informative! Had to go over some videos a couple of times, especially when there were some equations involved. Professor is great and very engaging, quizzes and assignments really measured for understanding. Real case studies and examples. Highly recommended!', "Mr. Raj's lecture is very understandable, course was very convenient and allows us to reset the deadline. i recommend this course.", 'Great learning experience and good exposure ', 'The course was good and detailed made me understand basics of analytics.', "It is a very knowledgeable course. I am extremely grateful to Professor Venkatesan for teaching this course of  'Marketing Analytics'  and making us understand the concepts in a sequential manner. Thank you", 'a once in a life time experience for my career in marketing, the course was awesome, effective lectures and relevant test.', 'Made Marketing Analytics simple straight forward and interesting', 'Great examples from real life!', 'Very informative and interesting! Loved learning analytics. I built confidence in numbers. Amazing course,clears every little basic thing a person needs to start up with.', 'The professor, Raj is very cute and nice. Thanks for your teaching.', "Designed perfectly with easy to understand &amp; practical examples, good teaching and can't wait to implement this in my work.", "If you're looking to touch upon the various key concepts in Marketing Analytics, this course is for you. The content is laid out very neatly with enough quizzes and assignment to strengthen your basic understanding. The instructor has beautifully conducted the course with his sense of humour and fluid method of explanation.", 'Best learning ever', 'Very practical learning course, very dedicated instructor, highly recommended.', 'A professor that makes the class fun and interesting, and an enjoyable subject make this course a great one. Not only did I learn some valuable and real world skills in this course, I also am able to leverage it in in future work that I undertake. I certainly recommend it!', "Professor Raj is very nice. He explains it way that it's very easy to comprehend and not too overwhelming in terminologies. It is very useful for my marketing career"]</reviews><reviewers>['By Manish T', 'By Stefano A M', 'By Vivek R', 'By Alejandro L', 'By Waqas A A', 'By UTKARSH B', 'By Ni P C D S', 'By Praneet M K', 'By Oana T', 'By Anne C S', 'By Golla R', 'By PRADYUMNA R', 'By SUMIT K S', 'By Siddharth S', 'By Sanni T E ', 'By Daruri V S K', 'By Ji, C', 'By Bhavishya G ', 'By 洪一舟', 'By Subramanian R', 'By Tejas S', 'By Tulasi B', 'By Kitcha I', 'By Chanse W', 'By GEMMA J']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 19, 2016', 'Jun 15, 2017', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Nov 10, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 08, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2018', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Jul 22, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Oct 11, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Aug 29, 2018', 'Jul 26, 2018', 'Jul 17, 2018']</review_date></doc>