<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_15</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-analysis-with-python</course_url><course_name>Data Analysis with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Joseph Santarcangelo</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn how to analyze data using Python. This course will take you from the basics of Python to exploring many different types of data. You will learn how to prepare data for analysis, perform simple statistical analysis, create meaningful data visualizations, predict future trends from data, and more!

Topics covered:

1) Importing Datasets
2) Cleaning the Data
3) Data frame manipulation
4) Summarizing the Data
5) Building machine learning Regression models
6) Building data pipelines

 Data Analysis with Python will be delivered through lecture, lab, and assignments. It includes following parts:

Data Analysis libraries: will learn to use Pandas, Numpy and Scipy libraries to work with a sample dataset. We will introduce you to pandas, an open-source library, and we will use it to load, manipulate, analyze, and visualize cool datasets. Then we will introduce you to another open-source library, scikit-learn, and we will use some of its machine learning algorithms to build smart models and make cool predictions.

If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you will also earn an IBM digital badge.  

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Predictive Modelling//Python Programming//Data Analysis//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Model Selection</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Importing Datasets//Data Wrangling// Exploratory Data Analysis//Model Development// Model Evaluation//Final Assignment//IBM Digital Badge</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['The Problem', 'Understanding the Data', 'Python Packages for Data Science', 'Importing and Exporting Data in Python', 'Getting Started Analyzing Data in Python'], ['Pre-processing Data in Python', 'Dealing with Missing Values in Python', 'Data Formatting in Python', 'Data Normalization in Python', 'Binning in Python', 'Turning categorical variables into quantitative variables in Python'], ['Exploratory Data Analysis', 'Descriptive Statistics', 'GroupBy in Python', 'Correlation', 'Correlation - Statistics', 'Analysis of Variance ANOVA'], ['Model Development', 'Linear Regression and Multiple Linear Regression', 'Model Evaluation using Visualization', 'Polynomial Regression and Pipelines', 'Measures for In-Sample Evaluation', 'Prediction and Decision Making'], ['Model Evaluation and Refinement', 'Overfitting, Underfitting and Model Selection', 'Ridge Regression', 'Grid Search'], ['$null$'], ['IBM Digital Badge']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Very low quality of the course. The structure of the course is illogical. Also it takes too little effort to accomplish the course. In the beginning  of th course labs contain all the code so a pupil doesn't have to do his/her best to solve tasks. I can just constantly press ctrl+enter and get my certificates. It is not what I expected from the course. Also quizes never contain  coding practice, so to accomplish I just need to show the understanding of the basic aspects of the topic, not the coding skills. The, at the end of the course (after I have lost all the motivation during the first weeks you give us difficult function, including custom functions, never explaining them at all). Have a huge doubt about buying the subscribe for the next month.", 'So many mistakes in videos and labs, including spelling errors, misnaming functions and code that causes errors.', "I am working through the IBM Data Science Certificate courses (in order) and this is easily the best one I have taken so far. Once again, the labs provide a variety of hands-on exercises that help to cement the topics introduced in the lectures (which, to be fair, are very fast-paced). Everything taught is practical and relevant. One request would be to fix the pacing of the videos and lecture quizzes, which often appear to test students' comprehension mere seconds after the topic was discussed! I did also notice a few errors in the labs, but they did not stop me from learning the material. Overall, great course.", 'perfect for beginner level. all the concepts with code and parameter wise have been explained excellently. overall best course in making anyone eager to learn from basics to handle advances with ease.', 'Very serious, professional, empowering course. Clear straightforward detailed explanations. A good deal of practice.', 'None', 'A seriouse deal of statistical modelling taught with a perfect content. I really appricate the effort put in order to not being "hard-to-understand", but still finding the way to teach complex statistics. You will have a very good useful knowledge of statistical modelling without getting lost through too many greek symbols and long explanations.', 'best course for beginners', 'Thank you so much! - Oana', 'Does an excellent job in providing the Python commands needed to do data analysis, along with some descriptions of what the steps actually involve. Has quite a few typos and minor issues -- looks a little sloppy.', 'Many typos and other errors. My favorite was the video where they said "150 - 50 = 50"', 'Recommended course to understand the how to do data analysis using python', 'Overall apt content for beginners and naive learners.', 'Well organized, good explanations, and very good labs. ', 'Great experience', "This was a great review of stuff math I learned in high school and college. Of course it's all easy now because it's baked into Python. We used to do it by hand and with slide rules back in the early 1970s", 'I have really learned many things in this course which are meaningful and helpful in real life. It is not just lines and numbers , it is exciting how you can apply these methods to find solutions in your real life problems. Combined with strong Python skills , you will enjoy more..Thank you', 'It is really a good course, simple to understand and very complete. Thank you !', "Decent introduction to basic concepts of data analysis. However, the 'labs' and quizzes feel insufficient to practice the theoretical aspects. Further on the downside, the quality of the material in this course is quite poor. Even worse, several months after learners mention errors in the discussion forums (and partly get an instructor response), the mistakes remain in the material. ", 'This needs to go much more in depth on the options for analysis, and provide more examples.', 'The course had plenty of errors in the videos, Labs and quizzes. The explanations were rushed at times and quite a bit was not easy to follow. The worst course so far! ', "I felt the course isn't designed well as it takes you little fast than expected and doesn't explain all the terms! May be one has to be very good at math or revise all the topics before taking this course.", 'Really great! Tons of information complemented with exercises. To deal with the amount of material, I suggest following the labs very closely and doing a bit of research in the Python documentation avalaible online. I have to say you really hit the core of the matter in this course!', 'Tough but useful. ', 'A very complete course of Data Analysis. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Alexandr D', 'By Guy P', 'By Amy P', 'By Rohit P', 'By Maksim M', 'By Aditya J', 'By Firat G', 'By Sampras G', 'By Oana M', 'By Karen B', 'By Pauli H', 'By ashirwad s', 'By Aditya M', 'By Jim C', 'By Vineet M N D', 'By Daniel T', 'By Uygar H', 'By Firat E', 'By Florian P', 'By Theodore G', 'By Ivo M', 'By Vikram R', 'By Nora I', 'By Mahmood H', 'By Paulo B M d S']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 17, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'May 19, 2019', 'Apr 20, 2019', 'Apr 18, 2019', 'May 18, 2019', 'May 18, 2019', 'May 19, 2019', 'May 22, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'May 22, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'May 20, 2019', 'May 20, 2019', 'Apr 09, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'May 19, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019']</review_date></doc>