<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_21</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-databases</course_url><course_name>Using Databases with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Charles Russell Severance</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce students to the basics of the Structured Query Language (SQL) as well as basic database design for storing data as part of a multi-step data gathering, analysis, and processing effort.  The course will use SQLite3 as its database.  We will also build web crawlers and multi-step data gathering and visualization processes.  We will use the D3.js library to do basic data visualization.  This course will cover Chapters 14-15 of the book “Python for Everybody”. To succeed in this course, you should be familiar with the material covered in Chapters 1-13 of the textbook and the first three courses in this specialization. This course covers Python 3.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Database (DBMS)//Sqlite//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Object Oriented Python//Basic Structured Query Language//Data Models and Relational SQL//Many-to-Many Relationships in SQL//Databases and Visualization</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Using Databases with Python', 'Unicode Characters and Strings', '14.1 - Object Oriented Definitions and Terminology', '14.2 - Our First Class and Object', '14.3 - Object Life Cycle', '14.4 - Object Inheritance', 'Bonus: Interview - Software Engineering - Bertrand Meyer', 'Bonus: Office Hours - London'], ['15.1 Relational Databases', '15.2 - Using Databases', '15.3 - Single Table CRUD', 'Worked Example: Counting Email in a Database', 'Bonus: Office Hours Zagreb, Croatia', 'Interview: Elizabeth Fong - The Early Years of SQL', 'Worked Example: Twspider.py (Chapter 15)'], ['15.4 - Designing a Data Model', '15.5 - Representing a Data Model in Tables', '15.6 - Inserting Relational Data', '15.7 - Reconstructing Data with JOIN', 'Worked Example: Tracks.py (Chapter 15)', 'Bonus: Office Hours Perth, Australia', 'Bonus Interview: Niklaus Wirth', 'Bonus: Office Hours Barcelona'], ['15.8 - Many-to-Many Relationships', 'Worked Example: roster.py (Chapter 15)', 'Bonus: Office Hours Mexico, City', 'Bonus Interview: Andrew Tannenbaum - Minix', 'Worked Example: Twfriends.py (Chapter 15)'], ['16.1 - Geocoding', '16.2 - Geocoding Visualization', 'Worked Example: Geodata (Chapter 16)', 'Bonus: Office Hours - Amsterdam', 'Bonus Interview: Richard Stallman - Free Software Foundation', 'Bonus Interview: Brian Behlendorf - Apache Foundation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It's a great toy introduction to database technologies - I wish the assignments involved more than just running starter code and making a few lines of modifications.", "i don't enjoy with this course at all. this course is not good . i don't like copying code and paste it into other place. also to explain code was written before is not good for beginner the code must be written live to understand whole code . Also the assignment wasn't clear at all. you had to search to know what they want exactly. I hope to improve it for next people who will take it ", 'The course is great... You can  definitely learn many things... Was kind of hard for me and i went many times back and forth through most of the lectures... However i think  i learn many new things....', 'This course is well designed to get fast launching in programming &amp; talking to data with python. As the name suggests " Python For Everybody ", courses in this specialization really signifies that.', 'This course was great! I enjoyed parsing different types of data: from documents and the web. This course is definitely (rudimentary) a must take course for anyone who wants to go into data science.', 'Instructor is engaging, conceptual overviews were excellent.', 'sql语言的内容偏多', 'Excellent course with very good materials', 'It was great !!', 'A very good course where you learn SQL&amp;Python', 'Awesome refresher course! ', 'A wonderful course!', 'great course!', 'Dr.Chuck is just amazing professor! ', 'Great course! Thanks!', 'i highly recommend anyone who want to learn python to take this course above all.', 'Good', 'Useful', 'very useful and concise course.', None, 'Great course and great professor', 'Great simple explanation of databases! SQLite is a great tool ', 'Never felt that learning database will be so easy , This was all because of the course instructor and material used to explain', 'I had some experience with SQL from many years ago and a little practice in php for web programming.  Even without this knowledge from before I think that this course gives a good introduction into working with databases with Python. I enjoyed it.', 'Great introduction into how to use Python in combination with SOQL databases. Very useful for ones own small projects.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Connor H', 'By Alie E A A O ', 'By Miroslav M', 'By RAJPUT R G S', 'By Jesse G', 'By Peter B', 'By 齐振', 'By Luciana M G', 'By Sharob S', 'By Liang Z', 'By Kafilah A M', 'By Gabriel A O ', 'By Xiao F', 'By Sai L', 'By Sergey P', 'By yonathan c', 'By Dao X H', 'By Adrian V', 'By Mohammad K', 'By Dwaipayan D', 'By Prashant B', 'By Ignacio A G H', 'By VIJAY K S', 'By Thommes T', 'By Maxwell B']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 11, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2018', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Jun 17, 2016', 'Sep 06, 2018', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Dec 26, 2018']</review_date></doc>