<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_157</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-products</course_url><course_name>Developing Data Products</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian Caffo, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>A data product is the production output from a statistical analysis. Data products automate complex analysis tasks or use technology to expand the utility of a data informed model, algorithm or inference. This course covers the basics of creating data products using Shiny, R packages, and interactive graphics. The course will focus on the statistical fundamentals of creating a data product that can be used to tell a story about data to a mass audience.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Interactivity//Plotly//Web Application//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview//Shiny, GoogleVis, and Plotly//R Markdown and Leaflet//R Packages//Swirl and Course Project </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Developing Data Products'], ['Shiny 1.1', 'Shiny 1.2', 'Shiny 1.3', 'Shiny 1.4', 'Shiny 1.5', 'Shiny 2.1', 'Shiny 2.2', 'Shiny 2.3', 'Shiny 2.4', 'Shiny 2.5', 'Shiny 2.6', 'Shiny Gadgets 1.1', 'Shiny Gadgets 1.2', 'Shiny Gadgets 1.3', 'GoogleVis 1.1', 'GoogleVis 1.2', 'Plotly 1.1', 'Plotly 1.2', 'Plotly 1.3', 'Plotly 1.4', 'Plotly 1.5', 'Plotly 1.6', 'Plotly 1.7', 'Plotly 1.8'], ['R Markdown 1.1', 'R Markdown 1.2', 'R Markdown 1.3', 'R Markdown 1.4', 'R Markdown 1.5', 'R Markdown 1.6', 'Leaflet 1.1', 'Leaflet 1.2', 'Leaflet 1.3', 'Leaflet 1.4', 'Leaflet 1.5', 'Leaflet 1.6'], ['R Packages (Part 1)', 'R Packages (Part 2)', 'Building R Packages Demo', 'R Classes and Methods (Part 1)', 'R Classes and Methods (Part 2)'], ['Swirl 1.1', 'Swirl 1.2', 'Swirl 1.3']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['very helpful and teaching. learning practical tools for producting data products. examples in the course are not very complex, but give a very good intro for several tools.', 'Course content was helpful.  Some confusion in assignment questions not aligning with what was covered in lectures where it would have helped to clarify that was intentional.', 'this curious course teaches about tools and techniques for communication with audiences on data science. some tools are very interesting and deserve a deep research from the learner, this course is mostly informative about the potential of such tools.', 'This course was amazing, it could definetly be more deep in each of the subjects, but gives you so much practice in tools that are very useful in the day by day of a data scientist', 'I learned very useful techniques', 'discovery of amazing tools and possible applications of rstudio and additional packages.', 'Great course, practical and very informative ', 'Really enjoyed this course. But you can only get as much as you put into it. A lot of students end up doing pretty mediocre apps that contain just enough to pass but never get creative. If you want to get as much as you can, then put some effort and create a nice app/presentations.', 'a very good beginner level course for those learning how to develop Data Products in R.', 'A lot of useful parts for visualization here! plotly and shiny are super useful in a business context. swirl and leaflet a bit niche perhaps.', 'Demanding if you are not used to do this kind of things, but, worth It if you give yourself a time to get into it.', 'Excellent course (like the previous 8 in the specialization) and very useful for anyone working with data and involved in data storytelling. Brian (the teacher) does an awesome job explaining the concepts and how the functions and scripts in R work and interact with each other to bring about shiny apps and other visualizations. A big "Thank you!" to everyone who created this course!', 'Awesome Lessons!', None, 'Great course!!!', 'This course helped to get the knowledge how to create shiny apps and r packages. Very usefull, thank you every lecturer and masters how create this course.', 'Awesome course, maybe more complex examples, but is fine as an introductory program.', 'Good content, useful assignments, some of the tools talked about are out of date', 'nice aand easy. I do not know why you focus on creation of custom libraries withou any practical assignemens on it', 'Very useful, very well taught. I enjoyed the project as well. ', 'Very useful stuff, and nicely presented too by Brian Caffo.', 'excellent course!', 'Very good course for creating your own data product', 'Great course with great materials. Easy to understand and to learn.', 'great course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Idan R', 'By Robert O', 'By Bruno R d C S', 'By Rafael d R S', 'By Adham A', 'By Julien N', 'By Mohammad A', 'By Samuel Q', 'By Raunak S', 'By Simon', 'By César A', 'By João F', 'By Saah N T G', 'By Daniel M Á', 'By Norberto O', 'By Keidzh S', 'By Laro N P', 'By benjamin s', 'By Grigory S', 'By Sheila B', 'By Ehsan D', 'By Cristian G R', 'By Saurabh Y', 'By Bojan B', 'By Shashwat K']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 10, 2017', 'Jul 28, 2017', 'Apr 20, 2019', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Jul 29, 2018', 'Aug 06, 2018', 'Aug 15, 2018', 'Jul 21, 2018', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Sep 08, 2018', 'Sep 10, 2018', 'Oct 08, 2018', 'Oct 14, 2018', 'Oct 15, 2018']</review_date></doc>