<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_18</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-scientists-tools</course_url><course_name>The Data Scientist’s Toolbox</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will get an introduction to the main tools and ideas in the data scientist's toolbox. The course gives an overview of the data, questions, and tools that data analysts and data scientists work with. There are two components to this course. The first is a conceptual introduction to the ideas behind turning data into actionable knowledge. The second is a practical introduction to the tools that will be used in the program like version control, markdown, git, GitHub, R, and RStudio.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Github//R Programming//Rstudio</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1//Week 2: Installing the Toolbox//Week 3: Conceptual Issues//Week 4: Course Project Submission &amp; Evaluation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Specialization Motivation', "The Data Scientist's Toolbox", 'Getting Help', 'Finding Answers', 'R Programming Overview', 'Getting Data Overview', 'Exploratory Data Analysis Overview', 'Reproducible Research Overview', 'Statistical Inference Overview', 'Regression Models Overview', 'Practical Machine Learning Overview', 'Building Data Products Overview', 'Installing R on Windows  {Roger Peng}', 'Install R on a Mac  {Roger Peng}', 'Installing Rstudio  {Roger Peng}', 'Installing Outside Software on Mac (OS X Mavericks)'], ['Tips from Coursera Users - Optional Video ', 'Command Line Interface', 'Introduction to Git', 'Introduction to Github', 'Creating a Github Repository', 'Basic Git Commands', 'Basic Markdown', 'Installing R Packages', 'Installing Rtools'], ['Types of Questions', 'What is Data?', 'What About Big Data?', 'Experimental Design'], ['Post-Course Survey']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Good to set you up for advance courses.', 'Great course, really helps get you into the right mindset for becoming a data scientist.', "Not met what offered. I really don't know why but Instructor was in a hurry and like, he was in the position of instructor by obligation. ", 'Great intro', 'This course was a good intro especially in setting all the necessary software for future courses. I suggest to read the manuals, books and other readings the profs suggest. The resources are helpful. ', "I really don't know much about this stuff, I think the jury's still out on whether the last four weeks will be helpful in the future. We'll see how much I think I've learned at the end of the course", "This course was in many ways the first day of lectures, get your syllabus, buy your books, install your tools, etc.  I would give it 5 stars but the lectures inclusion of internet addresses that aren't links and aren't included in the transcript led to a lot of time paused and typing out long addresses.", 'Providing feedback means giving students an explanation of what they are doing correctly AND incorrectly.  However, the focus of the feedback should be based essentially on what the students is doing right.  It is most productive to a student’s learning when they are provided with an explanation and example as to what is accurate and inaccurate about their work.', None, 'A great intro to the course. I am not the biggest fan of the automated voice, but it gets the job done. I do like the secondary lessons written out with bulleted lists and close-ups of the slides. That is like a helpful review.', 'SIMPLESMENTE SENSACIONAL !', 'This is a very good course as it tells you some basic and is mostly the introductive course for the entire specialization.', 'it was simply the best', 'execellent i am very to gland get this certificate .. it is so valueable for me. the first one of data science track', 'Great Primer for what Data Science is about.  It also provides the infrastructure of tools needed.  This was what I was after, a way to provide other data scientist hardware and infrastructure support.', 'Good but need more explanations for topics.', 'Would be great to have more reading materials', 'Teaching of lessons are simply amazing.', 'The course is clear and good to learn,', 'More clarity on creation of .md file should be included in lectures ', 'A bit basic, but a great start for beginners.', "The course contents are thorough and clear, but the UI and the platform of the web course could use some thought. I find it a bit tricky to take notes and copy url's and command lines from the video. Perhaps this is just a matter of getting use to the platform. Excited to proceed to the next course!", "Basic introduction for the specialization, principles of data science, and installing stuff, it's fine to get started but could get hands dirty with R more quickly.  Overall the plethora of 4-5 star reviews for this specialization seem generous.  You will learn a good deal but there is heavy focus on R and academics of data science (Rmarkdown, Knitr, shiny apps etc), only 3 courses (6,7,8) get into meat of statistics/regression models and ML; the capstone project is interesting but doesn't use much of this stuff, it gets bogged down in technical work with new R libraries for text processing.  The material is a few years old and not being maintained, discussion forums and interest/participation feels stale.  Take some time to look at syllabus and compare to other courses for what you want to learn before committing many months to this specialization.", 'Good overview of the ideas/concepts in data science and the set of courses coming up, but mostly seems to be a place for people to work out any issues getting Git, R, and RStudio set up before they head into the R programming intro. Very light on useful content outside of that. Definitely not 4 weeks worth of course material - can do the whole thing in a couple hours or less.', "!!!STOP DON'T TAKE THIS COURSE!!!"]</reviews><reviewers>['By Jitin V', 'By Anthony V', 'By kaan b', 'By Frederik C', 'By Annette I', 'By William C', 'By David S', 'By sonal g', 'By SANJEEVE K G', 'By Andrea R C', 'By JEFFERSON D S N', 'By Aryan G', 'By anubhavbbd', 'By Khaleel u r', 'By Alexander M', 'By Aman U', 'By Usenaliev N', 'By PALAKOLLU S M ', 'By Jasmine P G', 'By SOMA C', 'By Pratyush M', 'By Annina H', 'By Paul R', 'By Erica R', 'By Tolga T']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 13, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'May 28, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Apr 24, 2018', 'Sep 26, 2017', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'May 22, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2017', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Dec 08, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Aug 14, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Jul 14, 2019', 'Nov 24, 2018']</review_date></doc>