<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_77</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/inferential-statistics-intro</course_url><course_name>Inferential Statistics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mine Çetinkaya-Rundel</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course covers commonly used statistical inference methods for numerical and categorical data. You will learn how to set up and perform hypothesis tests, interpret p-values, and report the results of your analysis in a way that is interpretable for clients or the public. Using numerous data examples, you will learn to report estimates of quantities in a way that expresses the uncertainty of the quantity of interest. You will be guided through installing and using R and RStudio (free statistical software), and will use this software for lab exercises and a final project. The course introduces practical tools for performing data analysis and explores the fundamental concepts necessary to interpret and report results for both categorical and numerical data</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Statistical Inference//Statistical Hypothesis Testing//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About the Specialization and the Course//Central Limit Theorem and Confidence Interval//Inference and Significance//Inference for Comparing Means//Inference for Proportions// Data Analysis Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About Statistics with R Specialization', 'More about Inferential Statistics'], ['Introduction', 'Sampling Variability and CLT', 'CLT (for the mean) examples', 'Confidence Interval (for a mean)', 'Accuracy vs. Precision', 'Required Sample Size for ME', 'CI (for the mean) examples'], ['Another Introduction to Inference', 'Hypothesis Testing (for a mean)', 'HT (for the mean) examples', 'Inference for Other Estimators', 'Decision Errors', 'Significance vs. Confidence Level', 'Statistical vs. Practical Significance'], ['Introduction', 't-distribution', 'Inference for a mean', 'Inference for comparing two independent means', 'Inference for comparing two paired means', 'Power', 'Comparing more than two means', 'ANOVA', 'Conditions for ANOVA', 'Multiple comparisons', 'Bootstrapping'], ['Introduction', 'Sampling Variability and CLT for Proportions', 'Confidence Interval for a Proportion', 'Hypothesis Test for a Proportion', 'Estimating the Difference Between Two Proportions', 'Hypothesis Test for Comparing Two Proportions', 'Small Sample Proportions', 'Examples', 'Comparing Two Small Sample Proportions', 'Chi-Square GOF Test', 'The Chi-Square Independence Test'], ['Project Information']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 26 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course is very useful and helps me understand the formal testing process of data analysis. I just hope it would cover more of non-parametric testing techniques and dive into a bit more into effect size testing. Anyway, It also provides a lot of insights into important statistical measures of information, which could potentially be extended to the field of predictive modeling and machine learning.', "A very good introduction to the fundamentals of inference and NHST. It's very important that you do all excercises and readings or you will not learn as much. Also, the course won't provide a lot of information on how to use R, but if you spend a good amount of time on your project and make sure that it's good you will learn enough. I had to review a lot of R projects that were not very good, which suggests that some students aren't learning what they should.", 'G', None, "Solid 3 stars. Lots of material is covered quickly and I learned a lot. The lectures are informative and supplement the book (I definitely recommend reading the (free) book). On the negative side, I noticed that the online discussion forum for the course isn't monitored by the instructors and the mentors seem to respond to only some questions. I noticed that almost all of the questions posted by students in the past year that went unanswered. I mean no one even bothered to respond to them at all. That's shameful, esp. if those students who submitted questions are paying for a certificate. ", "While I understand and appreciate that the scope of the class is more focused on the application / ideas of the statistical methods without delving too much into the mathematics, I would appreciate if some of it was used to explain why some equations work the way that they do. For example, in talking about F test statistics, it was difficult to understand the reasoning behind F = variance between groups / variance within groups until I had to look up other explanations elsewhere. While I believe that the instructor teaches well in most parts, I often find it difficult to follow along because she goes through a lot of assumptions and I'm unclear as how / why she is allowed to go on her assumptions.", 'The course did teach statistics but there were some problems with R commands, assignment expectations and grading outcomes. For one, this course really needs to do a better job of emphasizing that the student is expected to use R commands provided by Course 1 (I think it\'s called "Exploring Data") as well as this one. It would be helpful if students had easy access to all of the labs in that course as well as this one. Secondly, the list of expectations given out for the final project omitted several requirements (apparently we are expected to use R commands learned) though this is a small problem. ', "It was good. But I feel like I've spent half of the time untangling sly phrasing of questions.", 'I should not be charged if I have completed the project and simply waiting for other users to review it. This is dependent on how many users are taking the course at any given time. A bad system that results in users paying more for uncontrollable uncertain factors...', "An overview of inference, light on the math, light on the theory, and with an unfortunate failure to reinforce what may be the most important part of practice: what should be done when conditions for a particular method are not met. When  you teach students how to evaluate the conditions required for certain methods, but then walk through those methods even when the conditions aren't met, you reinforce poor practice. If you want to use an example where the conditions aren't met, STOP once you find out the conditions aren't met. STOP and REINFORCE the fact that you cannot use a method without meeting conditions. It is not a valuable exercise to walk through the plug and chug calculations anyway. STOP, discuss why you can't proceed, and then move on to another example if you want to give your students an opportunity to practice taking the method through to its conclusion. ", 'This cours helps me a lot to understand the mechanism under the numbers and statistic, I really recommend u to follow it if you wanna to be a data scientist!', 'Yet another superb course in this specialization.', 'It was a great course, one of the best things was the R programming for statistical test and inference.', 'Excelente.', 'nice course. it will definitely gives you skill. ', 'I found the treasure.', None, 'This is a great course. One can learn so many things from this course.', 'This course is super and explained so well by the professor. I would recommend this course to anyone who has interest in data science', 'Expertly designed course, Useful.', 'Amazing!', 'very informative', '-', 'Excellent! Clear and very interesting.', 'Much better than the course offered by John Hopkins University on the same subject. Concepts are clearly explained with detailed examples. Nice course to solidify your statistics skills. And BTW, really cute professor :)']</reviews><reviewers>['By Chanuwas A', 'By Diego R G', 'By Henri M', 'By Duane S', 'By Jeremy L', 'By Try K', 'By Ian R', 'By Aydar A', 'By Jamison T', 'By Daniel H', 'By 海鹏 李', 'By Toan T L', 'By Luis F S S', 'By Gilberto S G', 'By Hidetake T', 'By YASHKUMAR R T', 'By Prakhar P', 'By Sidhant P', 'By priyesh s', 'By Afzal A', 'By Alfredo J N', 'By Odera P F', 'By Saravanan', 'By Aleix D', 'By Chen N']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 21, 2018', 'May 25, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Mar 08, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2018', 'Mar 23, 2018', 'Feb 07, 2018', 'Nov 03, 2017', 'Jul 05, 2018', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019']</review_date></doc>