<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_17</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning-projects</course_url><course_name>Structuring Machine Learning Projects</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Andrew Ng</course_instructor><course_introduction>You will learn how to build a successful machine learning project. If you aspire to be a technical leader in AI, and know how to set direction for your team's work, this course will show you how.

Much of this content has never been taught elsewhere, and is drawn from my experience building and shipping many deep learning products. This course also has two "flight simulators" that let you practice decision-making as a machine learning project leader. This provides "industry experience" that you might otherwise get only after years of ML work experience.

After 2 weeks, you will: 
- Understand how to diagnose errors in a machine learning system, and 
- Be able to prioritize the most promising directions for reducing error
- Understand complex ML settings, such as mismatched training/test sets, and comparing to and/or surpassing human-level performance
- Know how to apply end-to-end learning, transfer learning, and multi-task learning

I've seen teams waste months or years through not understanding the principles taught in this course. I hope this two week course will save you months of time.

This is a standalone course, and you can take this so long as you have basic machine learning knowledge. This is the third course in the Deep Learning Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Machine Learning//Deep Learning//Inductive Transfer//Multi-Task Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>deeplearning.ai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>ML Strategy (1)//ML Strategy (2)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Why ML Strategy', 'Orthogonalization', 'Single number evaluation metric', 'Satisficing and Optimizing metric', 'Train/dev/test distributions', 'Size of the dev and test sets', 'When to change dev/test sets and metrics', 'Why human-level performance?', 'Avoidable bias', 'Understanding human-level performance', 'Surpassing human-level performance', 'Improving your model performance', 'Andrej Karpathy interview'], ['Carrying out error analysis', 'Cleaning up incorrectly labeled data', 'Build your first system quickly, then iterate', 'Training and testing on different distributions', 'Bias and Variance with mismatched data distributions', 'Addressing data mismatch', 'Transfer learning', 'Multi-task learning', 'What is end-to-end deep learning?', 'Whether to use end-to-end deep learning', 'Ruslan Salakhutdinov interview']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course would be immensely helpful for those who have not started on their first machine learning project. However, the insights shared are quite commonsensical and intuitive for those who have already had some minimal experience in machine learning. This course also does not feel as substantial as the other courses in the specialization, though the tips provided are definitely valuable.', 'I recommend this course. This will be a bit of theoretical which is good. It will talk about real world scenarios over the errors which is what we deal in day-to-day life and how to deal with it.', 'more practice!', "Though it might not seem imminently useful, the course notes I've referred back to the most come from this class. This course is could be summarized as a machine learning master giving useful advice. ", 'I learned so many things in this module. I learned that how to do error analysys and different kind of the learning techniques. Thanks  Professor Andrew Ng to provide such a valuable and updated stuff.  ', 'This is a must course in the entire specialization. It covers the step by step procedure to approach and solve a problem. The case studies provided are real world problems  which are so much helpful.', 'A lot of concrete examples, including those in the lectures and in the tests. Gained some thoughts on how to manage a ML project. Thanks Andrew and deeplearning.ai for providing such a great course.', 'This is the knowledge in which we will get from lots of experience only, but the andrew has shared in this course which might help us in future by saving a lot of time through this course experience', 'Going beyond the technical details, this part of the course goes into the high level view on how to direct your efforts in a ML project. Really enjoyable and useful. Thanks for making this available!', 'I\'m glad I spent some time on the "Flight simulator" assignments in this course. It\'s the first time in the specialization when I actually found the quiz questions challenging, and that\'s a welcome change. However, I didn\'t learn too much from the lectures. They were too repetitive, either repeating themselves or the material from the previous course. One or two videos could also do with better editing work: I could hear Andrew making a soundcheck, and there\'s a 30sec segment that\'s played twice in a row. Overall, it\'s probably worth doing this course, given that it requires very little time, and the assignments are useful.', 'Informative but extremely theoretical.', None, 'Very well structured course with lots of practical wisdom regarding structuring projects and managing implementation with respect to real world applications', 'Great, it helps to build a good deep learning models quickly.', 'Useful course not only for deep learning but for other ML algorithms.  Reviews issues that one needs to be careful about using statistical methods.', 'Valuable insight to ML system design', 'Fascinating strategic insights', '  cool  ', 'Great course!', 'Very important common practices in ML, especially the tips of error analysis and ways to solve very common problems.', 'really good lesson，thank coursera and deeplearning.ai', 'I like it', 'Excellent course. Loved the case study format - good break from the other style of the rest of the courses.', 'very informative course', 'excellent overview of best practices when organizing your ML project']</reviews><reviewers>['By Liu H', 'By ABHISHEK K', 'By Nazarii N', 'By Walter G', 'By ANKIT M', 'By THAMMANA S R', 'By Ziping Z', 'By SAI V K', 'By Damian C', 'By Matei I', 'By Vasu M', 'By shijiatongxue', 'By Faiz R', 'By Khoo T S', 'By Mahmut K', 'By Oleksiy S', 'By Laurence C', 'By Jhon S', 'By Jabberwoo', 'By Javier O', 'By 李子龙', 'By 谢宇敏', 'By Bhaskar D', 'By Manish N', 'By Wadigzon D']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 11, 2019', 'May 31, 2019', 'May 25, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Nov 23, 2017', 'Sep 22, 2018', 'Apr 07, 2018', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Mar 08, 2018', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018']</review_date></doc>