<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_54</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/excel-analysis</course_url><course_name>Problem Solving with Excel</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Mannella</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course explores Excel as a tool for solving business problems. In this course you will learn the basic functions of excel through guided demonstration. Each week you will build on your excel skills and be provided an opportunity to practice what you’ve learned. Finally, you will have a chance to put your knowledge to work in a final project.  Please note, the content in this course was developed using a Windows version of Excel 2013.  

This course was created by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP with an address at 300 Madison Avenue, New York, New York, 10017.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Pivot Table//Data Cleansing</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>PwC</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Overview of Excel//vLookups and Data Cleansing//Logical Functions &amp; Pivot Tables//More Advanced Formulas</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Problem Solving with Excel', 'Tao of Excel', 'Week 1 Welcome', 'Excel Basics and Navigation Part 1', 'Excel Basics and Navigation Part 2', 'A Message from our Chief People Officer at PwC', 'Paste Special - Part 1', 'Paste Special - Part 2', 'Cell Locking - Part 1', 'Cell Locking - Part 2', 'Named Ranges', 'Subtotal - Part 1', 'Subtotal - Part 2'], ['Welcome to Week 2', 'VLookup', 'Use VLOOKUP, data validation and multiple VLOOKUPs together', 'HLOOKUP', 'Nesting', 'Data Cleansing: Values - CLEAN- 1a', 'Data Cleansing: Values - CLEAN -1b', 'Data Cleansing: Values - TRIM', 'Data Cleansing: Values - SUBSTITUTE -3a', 'Data Cleansing: Values - SUBSTITUTE - 3b', 'Data Cleansing: Values - STORED AS TEXT', 'Data Cleansing: Values - De-DUPLICATING', 'Data Cleansing: Text Functions', 'Text - LEN &amp; FIND', 'Text - CONCATENATE', 'Text - Data Validation'], ['Welcome to Week 3', 'Logical Functions: Introduction', 'Logical Functions - COUNTIFS', 'Logical Functions - COUNTIFS Part 2', 'Logical Functions - SUMIFS', 'Logical Functions - SUMIFS Part 2', 'Logical Functions - IF + THEN', 'Logical Functions - IF + AND', 'Logical Functions - IF + OR', 'Logical Functions - Nesting', 'Bringing Value with Excel', 'Pivot Tables', 'Navigate a Pivot Table', 'Sort a Pivot Table', 'Advanced Filtering', 'Calculated Fields', 'Slicers'], ['Welcome to Week 4', 'Intro to Statistical Forecasting', 'Statistical Forecasting - Part 1', 'Statistical Forecasting - Part 2', 'Index Match', 'Index Match: MATCH Formula', 'x and y Variables', '2 Variable Lookup', 'Financial Function - NPV and IRR', 'Financial Function - Calculating Payment Schedule', 'Financial Function - Calculating Payment Period', 'Course Wrap-up']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Best course to learn excel from the beginning.', "Great for a beginner, especially for those just starting their career life as an intern. Also a wonderful enlightment for data analysis and related fields. I'm considering a more analysis-oriented major after the undergraduate. What should be fixed: Some instructions are so wrong that the forum has given clear tips, but they haven't yet been modified in the course", "100% perfect course. Exactly what I needed. Thought I knew how to use Excel but I actually didn't. Covers useful knowledge which I didn't have the chance to learn in university.", 'awesome', 'It was very helpful', 'very interesting', 'All excel important concepts and formulae are covered in this course. A must course for every beginner who want to enter into basic analytics. Thank you PWC for providing such modules. Looking forward for more', 'Good course from a respected company. The assignments realistic and challenging, and can be finished in the estimated time for the course.', 'Very useful and practical.', 'An amazing course with very interactive video lessons and exercises that made sure that candidates were equipped with good knowledge by the end of the course. Thank You for the opportunity', 'Good quality with reasonable length !!! ', 'v', 'One of the most useful courses I have taken. Skills immediately applicable on any job that requires data analysis.', 'Excellent content coverage and explanation.', 'Niceee', "Problem solving is what they call it, but I call it excel nitty gritty. if you don't know this you don't know anything at all. Great videos and exercises were challenging.  ", 'A perfect course to start with data analysis in excel and data-science in general. Highly recommended for all those who wish to kisck start their data career. ', 'A very thorough course that provides easy instructions on basic to complex excel formulas as well as tips. This course has really solidified my basic understanding of excel and I would recommend it to others. ', 'The functions introduced in this course are very useful for me to utilize the excel in my academic studies and I also think this will help me to develop greatly in my future career.', 'Good information delivered and great opportunities to do with example problems. ', 'This course really helped in understanding the usage of Excel tool. The professionals who taught the course were brilliant. Thank you sir, for taking out the time from your busy schedule and create this wonderful course. ', 'good  course with a lot of practical and helpful excel skills!', "There's something for everyone in this course. If you are a student, working through this course as early in your career may improve your grades, but will certainly let you produce higher-quality work with less time and struggle on your part. Ditto for entry-level professionals. If you have been doing it longer, like I have, you will be reminded of some important things you have forgotten, but more importantly you will pick up some tips to make future work also higher quality with less work. Highly Recommended.", 'This course was a great refresher course for me. I had intermediate Excel skills but needed to put all the components together. It was very helpful to tackle the cumulative exercises that involved multiple skills. Week 3 was especially more involved so I would advise using the forums for help if you get stuck during any module. ', 'Thank you so much for sharing the learning experience. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Rishabh S', 'By StephaneBai', 'By Yuchen Z', 'By NKETIAH E', 'By Twinkle S', 'By Pallavi D D', 'By Akshay G', 'By Velvet B', 'By Carlos A M M', 'By Zohair A', 'By Jess C', 'By Inal K', 'By Faris S', 'By Nishima A', 'By Manoj M S', 'By Alfred K', 'By Neel s', 'By Sara A R', 'By Benjie Y', 'By Yufan G', 'By Swarnakshi S', 'By Hermin', 'By Doug C', 'By MICHAEL D S', 'By ShirleyL']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Nov 23, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2019']</review_date></doc>