<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_179</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/iiot-google-cloud-platform</course_url><course_name>Industrial IoT on Google Cloud Platform</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>By enrolling in this specialization you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;

Welcome to the Coursera course, Industrial Internet of Things (IoT) on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) brought to you by the Google Cloud team. I’m Catherine Gamboa and I’m going to be your guide.

This course covers the entire Industrial IoT network architecture from sensors and devices to analysis. The course discusses sensors and devices but the focus is on the cloud side.  You'll learn about the importance of scaling, device communication, and processing streaming data. The course uses simulated devices in the labs to allow you to concentrate on learning the cloud side of IIoT.  The course is a little different than most Coursera courses because there is very little video. Most of the learning is done with short readings, quizzes, and labs.  

This course takes about two weeks to complete, 11-12 hours of work with 6 of those hours spent in labs.  By the end of this course, you’ll be able to: create a streaming data pipeline, to create registries with Cloud IoT Core, topics and subscriptions with Cloud Pub/Sub, store data on Google Cloud Storage, query the data in BigQuery, and gain data insights with Dataprep.  You'll learn and practice these skills in 7 labs.  Then you'll have an opportunity to test yourself in an optional capstone lab using simulated devices or Cloud IoT Core Inspector.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Bigquery//Internet Of Things (IOT)//Cloud Computing//Communications Protocol</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Industrial IoT on GCP//Foundations of GCP Architecture//Sensors, Devices, and Communication//Google Cloud IoT Platform//Creating IoT Data Pipelines//Analyzing Data with BigQuery//Analyzing IoT Dataprep and Data Studio//Optional Capstone Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to IIoT on GCP', 'IoT on GCP Overview', 'Getting Started with Google Cloud Platform and Qwiklabs'], ['Module Introduction', 'What is IoT?'], ['Module Introduction'], ['Module Introduction', 'Cloud Pub/Sub', 'Simplify Event Driven Processing with Cloud Pub/Sub', 'Introduction to IoT Cloud Core', 'Google Cloud Storage: Massive Scalability Plus More'], ['Module Introduction'], ['Module Introduction', 'Introduction to BigQuery', 'Explore \u200b9 \u200bFundamental \u200bGoogle \u200bBigQuery \u200bFeatures', 'Query Basics'], ['Module Introduction', 'Introduction to Dataprep', 'An integrated data pipeline', 'Dataprep Lab Demo', 'Introduction to Data Studio', 'Connect to your Data', 'Share Reports'], ['Module Introduction']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 19 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Very well done Google Cloud IoT getting start lab, i've grasped all basic info i needed to start handle all the data in the IoT environment. ", 'Wonderful course! easy language, clear concepts and well-descriptive labs', 'This is an interesting course and I was able to navigate to complete it quickly in the allotted time. I am looking forward to similar courses in the future', 'The course content is more than I expected. I will highly recommended to those who want to explore and work on IOT on google platform. It will help the student in understanding various components. My special thanks to the instructors for their excellent delivery of subject. ', 'good content', "it's a very interesting course ", 'Nice one , I got the idea of IIOT', 'This course is an excellent introduction to using the Google Cloud Platform for practical IoT applications.', 'Very nice', 'very good one for beginners', 'Nice Course', "I've learnt a lot. Thanks", 'muy buen curso!', 'I personally enjoyed it so much! It is challenging and very fun. I learned so many new skills I am going to apply asap.', 'interesting and fast', 'The course was very well organized and gives  overview as well as hands on experience on Google Cloud Platform for IIOT. Would recommend anyone who are interested in IoT.', 'Great One!', 'Great course! I had made a rudimentary project using the Cloud IoT Core prior to taking this course, after finishing it I had a better understanding of the underlying architecture and uses of cloud services Google provided. Looking forward to creating more advanced solutions.', 'this course is more useful and more easier to learn ', 'Definitely interesting course. it completely covers from device to data collection, and getting insights of data. to presentation. ', 'Muy enriquecedor', 'Nice session. Useful for beginners to get the list of topics to be learnt for IoT.', 'Might be good for some one wants to have a very general idea of IoT and some operation experience on the GCP platform. This is more of a GCP operation course than a IoT course. Overall, provided knowledge of the structure of how IoT works on GCP/ cloud', 'Course very interesting, but felt messy and not ready for "production"', 'Fue interesante para conocer el alcance de GCP. Falta mas aterrizar todo lo que se aprendió con la vida real, por eso era tan importante el ultimo proyecto.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Marco C', 'By Ahmad K', 'By Narayana G', 'By Trivenugopal K', 'By Isuru N', 'By Nkaira O', 'By Barath K R K', 'By Ricardo L', 'By Rishikesh G', 'By PARAMESH T S', 'By Jose L C V', 'By Diaa S', 'By Sergio A', 'By Alejandra M L', 'By Tomasz K', 'By Tek R C', 'By Firas A', 'By Azaz A', 'By karthick', 'By victor d', 'By Christian G', 'By Sugumar', 'By Jingchao Y', 'By Ave J C', 'By Julian L']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 15, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'May 15, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Jul 23, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019', 'Aug 25, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019', 'Aug 30, 2019', 'Sep 09, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>