<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_226</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/linear-regression-business-statistics</course_url><course_name>Linear Regression for Business Statistics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sharad Borle</course_instructor><course_introduction>Regression Analysis is perhaps the single most important Business Statistics tool used in the industry. Regression is the engine behind a multitude of data analytics applications used for many forms of forecasting and prediction.  
This is the fourth course in the specialization, "Business Statistics and Analysis". The course  introduces you to the very important tool known as Linear Regression. You will learn to apply various procedures such as dummy variable regressions, transforming variables, and interaction effects. All these are introduced and explained using easy to understand examples in Microsoft Excel.
The focus of the course is on understanding and application, rather than detailed mathematical derivations.
Note: This course uses the ‘Data Analysis’ tool box which is standard with the Windows version of Microsoft Excel. It is also standard with the 2016 or later Mac version of Excel. However, it is not standard with earlier versions of Excel for Mac. 


WEEK 1
Module 1: Regression Analysis: An Introduction
In this module you will get introduced to the Linear Regression Model. We will build a regression model and estimate it using Excel. We will use the estimated model to infer relationships between various variables and use the model to make predictions. The module also introduces the notion of errors, residuals and R-square in a regression model.

Topics covered include:
•	Introducing the Linear Regression
•	Building a Regression Model and estimating it using Excel
•	Making inferences using the estimated model
•	Using the Regression model to make predictions
•	Errors, Residuals and R-square
 

WEEK 2
Module 2: Regression Analysis: Hypothesis Testing and Goodness of Fit
This module presents different hypothesis tests you could do using the Regression output. These tests are an important part of inference and the module introduces them using Excel based examples. The p-values are introduced along with goodness of fit measures R-square and the adjusted R-square. Towards the end of module we introduce the ‘Dummy variable regression’ which is used to incorporate categorical variables in a regression. 

Topics covered include:
•	Hypothesis testing in a Linear Regression
•	‘Goodness of Fit’ measures (R-square, adjusted R-square)
•	Dummy variable Regression (using Categorical variables in a Regression)
 

WEEK 3
Module 3: Regression Analysis: Dummy Variables, Multicollinearity
This module continues with the application of Dummy variable Regression. You get to understand the interpretation of Regression output in the presence of categorical variables. Examples are worked out to re-inforce various concepts introduced. The module also explains what is Multicollinearity and how to deal with it. 

Topics covered include:
•	Dummy variable Regression (using Categorical variables in a Regression)
•	Interpretation of coefficients and p-values in the presence of Dummy variables
•	Multicollinearity in Regression Models
 

WEEK 4
Module 4: Regression Analysis: Various Extensions
The module extends your understanding of the Linear Regression, introducing techniques such as mean-centering of variables and building confidence bounds for predictions using the Regression model. A powerful regression extension known as ‘Interaction variables’ is introduced and explained using examples. We also study the transformation of variables in a regression and in that context introduce the log-log and the semi-log regression models. 

Topics covered include:
•	Mean centering of variables in a Regression model
•	Building confidence bounds for predictions using a Regression model
•	Interaction effects in a Regression
•	Transformation of variables
•	The log-log and semi-log regression models</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Log–Log Plot//Interaction (Statistics)//Linear Regression//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Regression Analysis: An Introduction//Regression Analysis: Hypothesis Testing and Goodness of Fit//Regression Analysis: Dummy Variables, Multicollinearity//Regression Analysis: Various Extensions</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Meet the Professor', 'Introducing Linear Regression: Building a Model', 'Introducing Linear Regression: Estimating the Model', 'Introducing Linear Regression: Interpreting the Model', 'Introducing Linear Regression: Predictions using the Model', 'Errors, Residuals and R-square', 'Normality Assumption on the Errors'], ['Hypothesis Testing in a Linear Regression', "Hypothesis Testing in a Linear Regression: using 'p-values'", 'Hypothesis Testing in a Linear Regression: Confidence Intervals', 'A Regression Application Using Housing Data', "'Goodness of Fit' measures: R-square and Adjusted R-square", 'Categorical Variables in a Regression: Dummy Variables'], ['Dummy Variable Regression: Extension to Multiple Categories', 'Dummy Variable Regression: Interpretation of Coefficients', 'Dummy Variable Regression: Estimation, Interpretation of p-values', 'A Regression Application Using Refrigerator data', 'A Regression Application Using Refrigerator data (continued...)', 'Multicollinearity in Regression Models: What it is and How to Deal with it'], ['Mean Centering Variables in a Regression Model', 'Building Confidence Bounds for Prediction Using a Regression Model', 'Interaction Effects in a Regression: An Introduction', 'Interaction Effects in a Regression: An Application', 'Transformation of Variables in a Regression: Improving Linearity', 'The Log-Log and the Semi-Log Regression Models', 'Course 4 Recap']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I love this Specialization, and look forward to completing it! It's an amazing journey in Statistics with Excel! If you're a beginner in Statistics, you might see the whole Specialization a bit difficult and will need to look for a Statistics course. The instructor is also a huge plus!", "Could have been more challenging. Moderate courses are easy to pass but doesn't bring about extreme competitive spirit. Some peer graded assignments could be better.", 'Excelent course to gain a deep and solid understanding about linear regressions. The course is very focused on this, which is great!!', 'Excellent course! added a lot to my understanding', 'VERY GOOD COURSE. Professor is great', 'Excellent course, perfectly planned and explained. Great mentor. Thank you so much.', 'Marvellous course! Gives a very good idea of linear regression. A must for students and practicing managers.', 'Thanks S', "Excellent introduction to Linear Regression. As you progress, you learn how to use dummy (category) variables as well as interaction variables. Examples are explained in detail so you can understand how it works. This course isn't about understanding all the detailed math &amp; theory, but explains enough to you understand (at a high level) what you're doing and why. Then, you learn how to do it in Excel. I really enjoyed this class!", 'I loved this course and the videos and lecture were clearly explained. Doing the Regression model was a whole new experience for me!', 'Excellent course!', 'Very nicely structured and implemented', 'The course is essential for those who have no background in linear regression. The Lecturer of this course is amazing. ', 'Completion of the four courses in the specialization makes me feel more interested and confident in the vast art of Business Statistics and Analytics', "Though I was briefly introduced to linear regression in my graduate studies, I found the structure and presentation of this material to be more helpful to learning and understanding the material AND it's use cases.", 'Great course, very thorough with very good examples and explanations.', 'Very well structured course. Sharad is an excellent teacher. Learnt a lot from this course.', 'I have found Course 3 and 4 of this specialization to be challenging, but rewarding.  It has helped me build confidence that I can do just about anything with data provided to increase positive impact.', 'A very good course on Regression statistics with examples from the business sector that can be used later in work or life. Prof. Borle explained  all topics slowly and clearly. i would extend the course to more Regression topics (residuals@ more)', 'Good course, examples are very constructive and instructor presentations are vey good', 'excellent content.', 'Great course, easy-to-understand teaching approaches!', 'very east to understand and quick to learn. strong recommendation!', 'It was great! ', 'Best Course to understand Linear Regression.Thank you team Rice University for simple yet effective course on Linear Regression.Do enroll for this course if you want to understand linear regression thoroughly.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Shady N S T', 'By Rishav k', 'By Jordi M', 'By Padmapriyadarshini', 'By Nazmus S S', 'By Ketevani A', 'By ARVIND K S', 'By shubhangi P M', 'By Karen S Z', 'By Sofia L', 'By Esther K', 'By Achyut D U', 'By Abdullatif A', 'By Ramasubramaniyam S', 'By Scott L', 'By John D I', 'By Siddharth S', 'By William B', 'By Avi G', 'By jorge l', 'By Parul', 'By Songly H', 'By Olivia Z', 'By GAYATHRI S', 'By Akshay H']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 27, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2018', 'Aug 01, 2018', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Oct 10, 2018', 'Oct 18, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Oct 01, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2017', 'Jun 21, 2018', 'Sep 17, 2017', 'Nov 23, 2017', 'Jul 05, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2018', 'May 05, 2017']</review_date></doc>