<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_167</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-risk-models</course_url><course_name>Modeling Risk and Realities</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sergei Savin</course_instructor><course_introduction>Useful quantitative models help you to make informed decisions both in situations in which the factors affecting your decision are clear, as well as in situations in which some important factors are not clear at all. In this course, you can learn how to create quantitative models to reflect complex realities, and how to include in your model elements of risk and uncertainty. You’ll also learn the methods for creating predictive models for identifying optimal choices; and how those choices change in response to changes in the model’s assumptions. You’ll also learn the basics of the measurement and management of risk. By the end of this course, you’ll be able to build your own models with your own data, so that you can begin making data-informed decisions. You’ll also be prepared for the next course in the Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Modeling//Risk//Microsoft Excel//Simulation</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1: Modeling Decisions in Low Uncertainty Settings//Week 2: Risk and Reward: Modeling High Uncertainty Settings//Week 3: Choosing Distributions that Fit Your Data//Week 4: Balancing Risk and Reward Using Simulation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', '1.1 How To Build an Optimization Model: Hudson Readers Ad Campaign', '1.2 Optimizing with Solver, and Alternative Data Inputs', '1.3 Adding Risk: Managing Investments at Epsilon Delta Capital'], ['2.1 High Uncertainty Settings, Probability Distributions, Uncertainty and Risk', '2.2 Common Scenarios for Multiple Random Variables, Risk Reduction, and Calculating and Interpreting Correlation Values', '2.3 Using Scenarios for Optimizing Under High Uncertainty, Sensitivity Analysis and Efficient Frontier'], ['3.1 Data and Visualization: Graphical Representation', '3.2, pt 1: Choosing Among Distributions: Discrete Distributions', '3.2, pt 2: Choosing Among Distributions: Continuous Distributions', '3.3 Hypothesis Testing and Goodness of Fit'], ['4.1: Modeling Uncertainty: From Scenarios to Continuous Distributions', '4.2 Connecting Random Inputs and Random Outputs in a Simulation', '4.3 Analyzing and Interpreting Simulation Output: Evaluating Alternatives Using Simulation Results', 'Course Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Professor Savin is a rare kind, who explains very clear and brilliant. My excel skills were also sharpened. Overall, a course is worth attending.', 'So nice it provide concept how to deals with the risk associated with market.', 'good', 'Great course.', 'Excellent illustrations on Excel. However, in my opinion, Week 3 can be improved.', 'very useful', 'Great Course', 'Amazing experience', 'Crystal clear! Very helpful! I love the slides and excel sheets! ', 'Wow! I was worried after the previous course in the certificate series, and frankly it could be skipped! This course does everything the last course should have done. I loved the way you could work along with the instructors and do the work yourself in excel instead of simply watching. The quizzes were directed and used the classwork, not just random nonsense! Much better!', 'Great to get in the world of real uncertainty and model designing, great profeessors', 'Muy completo ', 'Course with full  of knowledge regarding Financial modelling and how to tackle with uncertainty by generating several scenarios. Ultimate teaching pedagogy with perfect excel examples.', 'Apreciei os exercícios em Excel com as simulações.', 'This is a very helpful course for a lot of fields in managing risks and realities by using numerical analysis. Thank you for incredible lessons.  Hope the website have more students and more useful courses like this. ', 'A very useful course mainly because it shows to its audience a way of thinking', 'My only concern is that the assessments had very short mathematical exercises. I would have loved to dive deeper into the different types of distributions, and experimented with how different assumptions about the initial data would lead to different simulations. This WAS a part of the course, but maybe there will be a more advanced course that dives even deeper into that subject.', 'The course was what I expected it to be. I was desperately looking for enlightenment in model risk and realities which was well delivered in the course.', 'Revisited the course from time to time. Good lesson for data analysis work.', 'Well explained, very interesting and relevant', 'the examples were really helpful and easy to understand', 'Really excellent', 'good course', 'Re-watching these videos months after completing the course! Fantastic!  ', 'Very comprehensive module! Thank you! ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Aleksandra Y', 'By Ashish k j', 'By deepak', 'By NIKHIL V', 'By Niket J', 'By Preetty G', 'By Prateek S', 'By Anupriya ', 'By Zhongyuan Z', 'By Nicholas J C', 'By Adrian J M S', 'By Ana M C R', 'By Shivam c', 'By Sergio L F', 'By Nguyen T T', 'By Dimitar P', 'By Emem M', 'By Ambuya J', 'By Shane L G Q', 'By Neil K', 'By Bintang A S', 'By Artem S', 'By Akash A', 'By Jonathan G', 'By Ho B H']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 04, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Sep 22, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Oct 26, 2018', 'Oct 29, 2018', 'Nov 02, 2017', 'Dec 22, 2017', 'Jun 25, 2016', 'May 11, 2016', 'Sep 27, 2016', 'Jul 13, 2016', 'Jul 16, 2017']</review_date></doc>