<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_344</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/nosql-databases</course_url><course_name>NoSQL systems</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>María del Pilar Ángeles</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to the specialization course of NoSQL Systems. 
This course will be completed on six weeks, it will be supported with videos and exercises that will allow you to identify the differences between the relational and NoSQL databases. 
As part of these alternative technologies the student will learn the main characteristics and how to implement the typical NoSQL databases, such as Key-value, columnar, document and graph. 
Let's start!

After completing this course, a learner will be able to
●	Identify what type of NoSQL database to implement based on business requirements (key-value, document, full text, graph, etc.)
●	Apply NoSQL data modeling from application specific queries
●	Use Atomic Aggregates and denormalization as data modelling techniques to optimize query processing

Software to download:
MongoDB
Neo4j
SAPIQ
Cassandra

In case you have a Mac / IOS operating system you will need to use a virtual Machine (VirtualBox, Vmware).</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México</course_orgnization><course_chapter>NOSQL Systems//Key-value database //Columnar Databases//Document databases with MongoDB //Graph Databases//How to design reliable, scalable and maintainable applications</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to NoSQL', 'Disadvantages of NoSQL technology'], ['Key values database', 'More elements of key values database'], ['Characteristics of a columnar database'], ['Implement a document database with Mongo Db', 'Mongo Db'], ['Graph databases', 'Neo4j'], ['Reliable, maintainable and scalable', 'Different information systems']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Se contemplan sutilmente\nlos principales\nelementos de los temas haciéndolos fácil de entender sin perder de vista la\nimportancia de cada uno.', 'It was difficult to complete the course within 6 weeks due to the "peer" evaluation mechanism', 'The lessons and the material in general are of good quality, I had some issues with the rating of the assignments', 'Very average content', 'Even though I have learned about Cassandra, MongoDB, Neo4j and some other concepts, the proposed exercises need to be rebuilt from scratch.', "This course does not have much content. You can find most of the content with a quick Google and I don't see why anyone should pay for this. The exercise in week 2 was just a copy-pasting exercise. The exercise in week 3 and 4 are not doable since the data is not given. The exercise for week 5 was great and I enjoyed it. I feel that the exercises for the other weeks should follow the one in week 5. Week 6 just had two super short quizzes. I did not learn much from this course. ", 'just awful.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ivan S C A', 'By Daniela D', 'By Matteo', 'By MANU V', 'By Enric E T', 'By Rayson L J K', 'By Amir G']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 24, 2019', 'May 31, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'May 29, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Sep 09, 2019']</review_date></doc>