<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_448</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/strategic-business-analytics-capstone</course_url><course_name>Capstone:  Create Value from Open Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Nicolas Glady </course_instructor><course_introduction>The Capstone project is an individual assignment.
Participants decide the theme they want to explore and define the issue they want to solve. Their “playing field” should provide data from various sectors (such as farming and nutrition, culture, economy and employment, Education &amp; Research, International &amp; Europe, Housing, Sustainable, Development &amp; Energies, Health &amp; Social, Society, Territories &amp; Transport). Participants are encouraged to mix the different fields and leverage the existing information with other (properly sourced) open data sets.

Deliverable 1 is the preliminary preparation and problem qualification step. The objectives is to define the what, why &amp; how. What issue do we want to solve? Why does it promise value for public authorities, companies, citizens? How do we want to explore the provided data? 

For Deliverable 2, the participant needs to present the intermediary outputs and adjustments to the analysis framework. The objectives is to confirm the how and the relevancy of the first results. 

Finally, with Deliverable 3, the participant needs to present the final outputs and the value case. The objective is to confirm the why. Why will it create value for public authorities, companies, and citizens.

Assessment and grading: the participants will present their results to their peers on a regular basis. An evaluation framework will be provided for the participants to assess the quality of each other’s deliverables.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Strategy</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>ESSEC Business School</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction and step 1 : Define the analysis framework//Required assignement 1: Define the analysis framework//Required feed back on Delivery 1:Define the analysis framework and preparation of deliverable 2//Practice for Deliverable 2//Required assignement 2: Present the intermediary outputs and adjustments to the analysis framework//Required feedback for delivery 2 and preparation of delivery 3//Required Delivery 3: Present the final outputs and value case//Required feedback on Assignment 3: Present the final outputs and value case</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Reporting your results: introduction', "It's all about the story", 'One slide, One idea', 'A picture is worth a thousand words', 'Recital M5 - How to present your findings', 'Wrap-up: Reporting your results', 'How to create value from data? - Fabrice Marque', 'Wrap up  - Mickael Svilar', 'Data exploration is an iterative process - Nicolas Glady', 'Analytics exploration - Oonagh O’Shea &amp; Noelle Doody', 'Wrap up &amp; Capstone guidelines  - Nicolas Glady'], ['Assignment:Define the analysis framework.'], ['This week is dedicated to the required feed back on deliverable 1&gt;&gt;', 'Prepare deliverable 2: Present the intermediary outputs and adjustments to the analysis framework'], ['Optional delivery 2: Present the intermediary outputs and adjustments to the analysis framework'], ['$null$'], ['This week is dedicated to the required feedback on delivery 2', 'Prepare deliverable 3: Present the final outputs and value case'], ['$null$'], ['This week is dedicated to the required feedback on deliverable 3&gt;&gt;']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The Course provided valuable insights in Strategy, Marketing. Introduced me to R and its vast capacity to analyse data. Accenture cases were helpful. And it has definitely improved my presentation skills.', "I think the contents of this specialization were interesting, but it was very difficult to reach a compromise between the time that was supposed to be dedicated to the peer-review assignments and the expectations that many participants had on the deliveries. Even if all tasks were supposed to be done in around 2 hours, it is definitely not possible to satisfy your classmates' expectations if you only invest 2 hours... it will be even difficult to satisfy them if you invest less than 8-12 hours per assignment. This might be due to the differences in backgrounds of the participants and also to the examples provided in the courses (which were clearly not made in 2 hours).", 'The initial setting is attractive. Unfortunately, the second half is repetitive. Further, grading scale appears to be somewhat inappropriate: If your topic is not frequently in the news, you have only 2 points left to lose. If the expected revenue is not in the range of billions you are already very close to failing the project. The grading scale is something that can be improved very easily. Further, working with more than one dataset should be encouraged, which would invite to explore more ways of data analysis and visualization.', 'Great course!', '\n', "Great specialization! I my opinion it's the best business analytics MOOC. By far.", 'The worse course ever', 'I would not recommend this specialization to anyone. The first assignment is just a first review of the final project, but it is almost impossible to pass, because the questions are not organized in a manner of constructive feedback. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Vishal V M', 'By Nadia V N', 'By Wolf-Dietrich Z', 'By Tim S', 'By ELINGUI P U', 'By Nino P', 'By William F', 'By Wendy B']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 08, 2017', 'Aug 02, 2017', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Feb 12, 2017', 'Jul 11, 2016', 'May 24, 2019', 'Oct 11, 2016', 'Apr 12, 2016']</review_date></doc>