<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_141</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/julia-programming</course_url><course_name>Julia Scientific Programming</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Juan H Klopper</course_instructor><course_introduction>This four-module course introduces users to Julia as a first language.  Julia is a high-level, high-performance dynamic programming language developed specifically for scientific computing. This language will be particularly useful for applications in physics, chemistry, astronomy, engineering, data science, bioinformatics and many more. As open source software, you will always have it available throughout your working life. It can also be used from the command line, program files or a new type of interface known as a Jupyter notebook (which is freely available as a service from JuliaBox.com).

Julia is designed to address the requirements of high-performance numerical and scientific computing while also being effective for general-purpose programming. You will be able to access all the available processors and memory, scrape data from anywhere on the web, and have it always accessible through any device you care to use as long as it has a browser.  Join us to discover new computing possibilities. Let's get started on learning Julia.

By the end of the course you will be able to:
- Programme using the Julia language by practising through assignments
- Write your own simple Julia programs from scratch
- Understand the advantages and capacities of Julia as a computing language
- Work in Jupyter notebooks using the Julia language
- Use various Julia packages such as  Plots, DataFrames and Stats

The course is delivered through video lectures, on-screen demonstrations, quizzes and practical peer-reviewed projects designed to give you an opportunity to work with the packages.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Julia (Programming Language)//Computer Programming//Ipython//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Cape Town</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the course//A context for exploring Julia: Working with data//Notebooks as Julia Programs//Structuring data and functions in Julia</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Julia scientific programming', 'Julia version 1.0', 'Programming languages and why Julia is special', 'Getting Ready: JuliaBox', 'The Julia REPL - Read, Evaluate and Print Loop', 'Arithmetical expressions', 'Logical expressions', "Julia's Type System", 'Variables in Julia', 'Functions in Julia', 'User-defined functions - part 1', 'User-defined functions - part 2', 'Week 1: Getting Practice', 'Installing Juno using Julia 1.0'], ['Introduction to Week 2', 'The Ebola Epidemic of 2014', 'Loading data using Julia', 'Creating .csv from data tables', 'For Loops and Date-Time Formats', 'Simple plots with the Plots package', 'Multiple curves in a single diagram', 'Week 2: Getting Practice', 'How to do a Peer Graded Assignment'], ['Introduction to Week 3', 'SIR Models of Disease Dynamics', 'The SIR model in Julia code', 'More on SIR Models', 'Plotting Data and an Approximately Fitted Line Simultaneously', 'Using the Data - fitting the model parameters', 'Week 3: Getting practice', 'Practicing fitting a circle to data', 'Week 3: Wrap Up'], ['Using Julia for descriptive statistics', 'Installing packages for this lesson', 'Creating simulated data', 'Descriptive statistics', 'Creating a dataframe', 'Descriptive statistics', 'Visualizing data', 'Inferential statistics', 'Exporting data as a csv file']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 23 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent, engaging teaching that makes me want to use Julia language (and Jupyter notebooks) all the time. As the language evolves, you need to adjust to newer Julia versions - just a part of fun.', 'Great course, well taught and thorough. I would only add that it needs to be updated from the version in the course (0.4.6) to the latest, full version of Julia, e.g. (1.x). I would have given 5 stars but for that fact.', 'Good pace, materials and choices of problem sets.', 'This was a great course for overcoming the inertia of learning a new language.  ', 'Amazing course, introduces the Julia Programming Language in a very intuitive way. Honor Assignments are a great bonus that give a more in-depth Julia experience. Highly recommended for anyone entering the Julia landscape.', 'I love this course especially honor cert  ', 'It was very exciting. I widen further, my computing horizons', "The course was a good overview of Julia, starting from the very basics. This makes it relevant for programming beginners at the start. As the course builds up, it nicely introduces Julia's complexity in the assignments, and introduced many of Julia's must-know features such as multiple dispatch and user defined types, without getting too daunting. The explanation was clear and crisp at all times. More content could be covered for data analysis and perhaps more forum discussion could be encouraged. The course didn't take a great deal of time to complete. Perhaps there is a need in the industry for a multiple Julia certification as the language gains momentum. I would recommend this course for those who want to get to know Julia and many key libraries in it for data analysis and visualization. ", None, 'The best thorough course for the foundations in analysis in Julia. I have not found any easy and complete explanation of Julia basics than this course. I completed the books Julia for Data Science by Anshul Joshi and other by Zacharias Voulgaris but they did not have as a solid foundation as this course has provided. Those books show more complex examples which will be easier to solve and understand after taking this course than the foundation provided in those books. Worth every penny for beginners to learn and experts to improve or polish their knowledge in Julia. Best course for beginners/expert I have ever had in my programming career.', 'It teaches the basics of programming in Julia and it is a good initation for getting familiar with Julia.', 'Wonderful course to know the basics of Julia progamming', 'Very good way to start learning julia', 'Un excelente curso para iniciarse en la programación cientifica. ', 'Great course!', None, "I wasn't completely familiar with types in Julia and this course helped me understand a very important aspect of Julia programming. Now, I feel I have a much better understanding of how Julia works. The professors were amazing and the course was extremely crisp and fun. I would like to extend them my warm wishes and would want to know if an advanced level of Julia Programming course could be planned in the future", "Liked the Honors course content. A good introduction to Julia. Recommended to all freshers in coding, especially for those who are pursuing courses in numerical techniques. You'll be able to write very intractable and efficient codes. ", 'I learn a lot about Julia and many packages that are availables.', 'Nice introduction to Julia.', 'This is a great course to begin Julia programming!', 'A clear and well presented course.', 'Great introduction to Julia and programming', 'The course was excellent. Thank you for all the work that has gone into this. I recommend it for anyone who wishes to start using Julia or is simply curious about Julia.', "It's a very good course for beginners of Julia, though I have learned Julia for more than one year, I still learned many useful things in this course. Julia is so beautiful, wonderful and powerful, and two honorable professors have deep insight about it, I hope there are more and more people will learn it through this course and make the world better.  "]</reviews><reviewers>['By Svyatoslav P', 'By Paul F G', 'By A. C T', 'By Bruce M F', 'By Yanal K', 'By Balaji N', 'By Nikolaos P', 'By Rajesh S', 'By Yi-Yang L', 'By Vinicius G', 'By Josué T C', 'By Ananda N', 'By k s k t', 'By MARIO Z A', 'By Bradley T D', 'By Robin R', 'By Varun R', 'By Shlok M', 'By Braulio U A A', 'By Francois C', 'By Sergio-Feliciano M', 'By Keith W', 'By Uriel A A R', 'By Mark S', 'By 刘晶']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 27, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2016', 'May 21, 2017', 'Jan 29, 2017', 'Aug 06, 2017', 'Oct 08, 2016', 'Apr 10, 2017', 'Jun 07, 2017', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Nov 21, 2017', 'Oct 27, 2016', 'May 09, 2018', 'Dec 16, 2016', 'Feb 12, 2017', 'Jan 14, 2017', 'Aug 26, 2017', 'Oct 24, 2016', 'May 11, 2018', 'Sep 05, 2017', 'Mar 17, 2017', 'Mar 29, 2017', 'Nov 22, 2017', 'Jan 16, 2018']</review_date></doc>