<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_163</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/image-understanding-tensorflow-gcp</course_url><course_name>Image Understanding with TensorFlow on GCP</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>This is the third course of the Advanced Machine Learning on GCP specialization. In this course,
We will take a look at different strategies for building an image classifier using convolutional neural networks. We'll improve the model's accuracy with augmentation, feature extraction, and fine-tuning hyperparameters while trying to avoid overfitting our data. We will also look at practical issues that arise, for example, when you don’t have enough data and how to incorporate the latest research findings into our models.

You will get hands-on practice building and optimizing your own image classification models on a variety of public datasets in the labs we’ll work on together.  

Prerequisites: Basic SQL, familiarity with Python and TensorFlow</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Tensorflow//Convolutional Neural Network//Estimator//Advanced Machine Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Image Understanding with TensorFlow on GCP//Linear and DNN Models//Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs)//Dealing with Data Scarcity//Going Deeper Faster//Pre-built ML Models for Image Classification//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Getting Started with Google Cloud Platform and Qwiklabs', 'Images as Visual Data', 'Structured vs Unstructured Data'], ['Introduction', 'Linear Models', 'Lab Intro: Linear Models for Image Classification', 'Lab Solution: Linear Models for Image Classification', 'DNN Models Review', 'Lab Intro: DNN Models for Image Classification', 'Lab Solution: DNN Models for Image Classification', 'Review: What is Dropout?', 'Lab Intro: DNNs with Dropout Layer for Image Classification', 'Lab Solution: DNNs with Dropout Layer for Image Classification'], ['Introduction', 'Understanding Convolutions', 'CNN Model Parameters', 'Working with Pooling Layers', 'Implementing CNNs with TensorFlow', 'Lab Intro: Creating an Image Classifier with a Convolutional Neural Network', 'Lab Solution: Creating an Image Classifier with a Convolutional Neural Network'], ['The Data Scarcity Problem', 'Data Augmentation', 'Lab Intro: Implementing image augmentation', 'Lab Solution: Implementing image augmentation', 'Transfer Learning', 'Lab Intro: Implementing Transfer Learning', 'Lab Solution: Implementing Transfer Learning', 'No Data, No Problem'], ['Introduction', 'Batch Normalization', 'Residual Networks', 'Accelerators (CPU vs GPU, TPU)', 'TPU Estimator', 'Demo: TPU Estimator', 'Neural Architecture Search', 'Summary'], ['Introduction', 'Pre-built ML Models', 'Cloud Vision API', 'Demo: Vision API', 'AutoML Vision', 'Demo: AutoML', 'AutoML Architecture', 'Lab Intro: Training with Pre-built ML Models using Cloud Vision API and AutoML', 'Lab Solution: Training with Pre-built ML Models using Cloud Vision API and AutoML'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Several quicklabs issues', "Most labs don't work or are pointless ", "Subscribing to this course only gives you option to run assignments on Qwik labs, and they're very poor for these kinds of assignments. You won't get any feedback on assignments anyway since there is no grader.", '思路很清晰，每一个课程讲解的都很明白，本觉得课程内容有些少，对于很多概念讲解的很浅显，但是想一下和门课主要是讲TensorFlow的，也就不这么苛刻了，老师语速适中，不十分推荐新手，尤其是英语不是特别棒的新手观看，少许有一些图像相关的了解看起来会快一些，还有就是觉得实验方面不是很好，主要还是感觉这种形式的实验其实自己在电脑上就可以做了，没必要很复杂的在GoogleCloud上费时间，希望改进一下Lab吧', 'Great learning on Image ML models...', 'Great Course!', 'An excellent course. Clear, concise and comprehensive. ', 'Really interesting labs in this course!.Thank you!', 'Was worried this would be just another CNN course but it was so much more. Showing out to use existing models etc. The details on CNN is a little lite but that can be found elsewhere. What was really good was the batch normalization and using pre-trained models but just changing the dense layers to provide classification,', 'It was One of the great course having labs which was really fun', 'Excelent in every aspect. contents, coding, pacing. awesome', 'Very good course on CNNs. The labs were cool. Thank you!', ' A very good course, with cutting edge research about Deep Learning, Go google :-) !', 'Good', 'this Courser teach a ongoing technique in GCP, and the world', 'Thumbs Up!', 'G', 'Good', "Amazing course! Definitely recommend the course for learning Google's way to handle images! ;)", 'The code in the labs needs updating.', 'The course provides an excellent overview of Image Understanding with TF and the utilization of all the capabilities of GCP to build productionable image systems.', 'Good Practical Experience with the concepts what that I learned . Good for recommending my friends.', 'Good material', 'You should improve the explanation of Transfer Learning from prebuilt models like ResNet. The conceptual side is not clear.', 'Highly recommended']</reviews><reviewers>['By vincent p', 'By Konstantinos S', 'By Jakub B', 'By Please', 'By Raja R G', 'By Luiz G M', 'By Jun W', 'By Anjani K S', 'By Mark D', 'By bhadresh s', 'By Facundo F', 'By Harold L M M', 'By ELINGUI P U', 'By Atichat P', 'By 林佳佑', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By Abdul R Y', 'By SOYOUNG J', 'By Putcha L N R', 'By Daniel L', 'By Carlos V', 'By Roopesh N', 'By Hemant D K', 'By Mirko J R', 'By Armando F']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 16, 2019', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Jun 26, 2019', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Nov 16, 2018', 'Sep 21, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Nov 02, 2018', 'Apr 30, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Jun 26, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019', 'Aug 12, 2019', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'May 18, 2019']</review_date></doc>