<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_408</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/social-science-study-chinese-society</course_url><course_name>Social Science Approaches to the Study of Chinese Society Part 1</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Cameron Campbell</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course seeks to turn learners into informed consumers of social science research. It introduces concepts, standards, and principles of social science research to the interested non-expert. Learners who complete the course will be able to assess evidence and critically evaluate claims about important social phenomena. It reviews the origins and development of social science, describes the process of discovery in contemporary social science research, and explains how contemporary social science differs from apparently related fields. It describes the goals, basic paradigms, and methodologies of the major social science disciplines. It offers an overview of the major questions that are the focus of much contemporary social science research, overall and for China. Special emphasis is given to explaining the challenges that social scientists face in drawing conclusions about cause and effect from their studies, and offers an overview of the approaches that are used to overcome these challenges. Explanation is non-technical and does not involve mathematics. Statistics and quantitative methods are not covered. 

Explore the big questions in social science and learn how you can be a critical, informed consumer of social science research. 

Course Overview video: https://youtu.be/QuMOAlwhpvU

After you complete Part 1, enroll in Part 2 to learn how to be a PRODUCER of Social science research. 
Part 2:  https://www.coursera.org/learn/social-science-research-chinese-society</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Social Sciences.Education</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>What is social science?//The Big Questions//Social Science Research on China//The Social Science Disciplines//Study Designs//Challenges//Cause and Effect//Final Exam</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Overview', '1.1 Overview', '1.2 Why social science is a science', '1.3 Theory and evidence in social science', '1.4 The origins of social science', '1.5 Social science as a new way to study society', '1.6 Differences between social science and other disciplines', '1.7 Summary'], ['2.1 Overview', '2.2 Inequality', '2.3 Family', '2.4 Social context and individual outcomes', '2.5 Divergence', '2.6 Political and social change', '2.7 Summary'], ['3.1 Overview', '3.2 Change and continuity', '3.3 Family', '3.4 Population aging', '3.5 Migration', '3.6 Education, Health, and Wellbeing', '3.7 Summary'], ['4.1 Overview', '4.2 Sociology', '4.3 Political Science', '4.4 Economics', '4.5 Anthropology', '4.6 Other disciplines', '4.7 Summary'], ['5.1 Overview', '5.2 What is a study?', '5.3 Experimental and observational studies', '5.4 Cross-sectional studies', '5.4 Longitudinal studies', '5.6 Qualitative and quantitative studies', '5.7 Macro and micro studies', '5.8 Summary'], ['6.1 Overview', '6.2 Representativeness', '6.3 Selection bias', '6.4 Omitted variables', '6.5 Reverse causality', '6.6 The ecological fallacy', '6.7 Validity of measures', '6.8 Summary'], ['7.1 Overview', '7.2 Experimental designs', '7.3 Cause and effect in observational studies', '7.4 Control variables', '7.5 Natural/quasi experiments', '7.6 Instrumental variables', '7.7 Matching approaches', '7.8 Summary'], ['Concluding Remarks']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great course for laying foundations, but part 1 does not really have much to do with Chinese society. Actually can start from part 2 directly if you already know the methods.', 'good', 'The course is very meaningful to learn the basic skills in social science. It is very valuable for students who wanted to study social science in university to take it as a preview', '  a general introduction with a lot of contents, great course ', 'Casts a wide net covering a wide range of topics in social science, albeit brief with this being a short course. A particular strength is the use of examples to clearly illustrate the many concepts. Professor Campbell pointed out the traps, pitfalls and controversy in many areas, so there are rich contents worth re-visiting. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Emily', 'By lichuangye', 'By wangyizhang c', 'By Rosina S', 'By PC']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 25, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2017', 'Jul 25, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'May 07, 2019']</review_date></doc>