<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_7</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-data</course_url><course_name>Python Data Structures</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Charles Russell Severance</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce the core data structures of the Python programming language. We will move past the basics of procedural programming and explore how we can use the Python built-in data structures such as lists, dictionaries, and tuples to perform increasingly complex data analysis. This course will cover Chapters 6-10 of the textbook “Python for Everybody”.  This course covers Python 3.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Python Syntax And Semantics//Data Structure//Tuple//Python Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Chapter Six: Strings//Unit: Installing and Using Python//Chapter Seven: Files//Chapter Eight: Lists//Chapter Nine: Dictionaries//Chapter Ten: Tuples//Graduation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Video Welcome - Dr. Chuck', '6.1 - Strings', '6.2 - Manipulating Strings', 'Worked Exercise: 6.5', 'Bonus: Office Hours New York City', 'Bonus: Monash Museum of Computing History', 'Fun: The Textbook Authors Meet @PyCon'], ['Demonstration: Using the Python Playground', 'Windows 10: Installing Python and Writing A Program', 'Windows: Taking Screen Shots', 'Macintosh: Using Python and Writing A Program', 'Macintosh: Taking Screen Shots'], ['7.1 - Files', '7.2 - Processing Files', 'Demonstration: Worked Exercise 7.1', 'Bonus: Office Hours Barcelona', 'Bonus: Gordon Bell - Building Blocks of Computing'], ['8.1 - Lists', '8.2 - Manipulating Lists', '8.3 - Lists and Strings', 'Fun: Python Lists in Paris', 'Worked Exercise: Lists', 'Bonus: Office Hours - Chicago', 'Bonus: Rasmus Lerdorf - Inventing the PHP Language'], ['9.1 - Dictionaries', '9.2 - Counting with Dictionaries', '9.3 - Dictionaries and Files', 'Worked Exercise: Dictionaries', 'Bonus: Office Hours - Amsterdam', 'Bonus: Brendan Eich - Inventing Javascript', 'Fun: Dr. Chuck Goes Motocross Racing'], ['10 - Tuples', 'Worked Exercise: Tuples and Sorting', 'Bonus: Office Hours - Puebla, Mexico', 'Bonus: John Resig - Inventing JQuery', 'Douglas Crockford: JavaScript Object Notation (JSON)', 'Fun: The Greatest Taco in the World'], ['Graduation Ceremony', "Dr.Chuck Wrap Up/What's Next"]]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['python_data_structures=["Great course!", "Great content!", "Great instructor!"]', 'Charles is a great teacher who has the ability to explain concepts in  lucid and yet engaging talks.', 'Excellent course to take you through the basics of data structures, by the end I was confident in my ability to complete the assignments due to the similar / building nature of how the lessons / assignments start to stack on top of each other. ', 'Amazing and really good for a novice', 'A really great course that gave me a solid grounding for using Python to retrieve specific data.  It was basic enough for me--a first time programmer--to understand, yet challenging enough for me to actually get to the point of --Wow, I am actually really programming!', 'I THANK YOU SIR FOR PROVIDING ME SUCH BEAUTIFUL MATERIAL.', 'Excelente curso, bastante intuitivo. Sigue un orden bastante lógico que permite enlazar ideas rápidamente.', 'wonderful, not only do I learn python, but I learn about computers/IT in general in a fun way!', "Absolutely awesome course. Dr. Chuck has earned my first internship earning me around 150$ per month at the age of 18. I'm now a python trainer myself at a small organisation.", 'assignment 9.4 auto grader not working .', 'This was a super-fun course! The materials were very easy to follow, and delivered in a very friendly and engaging manner. I highly recommend this course to anyone just getting started in programming.', 'I feel incredible that I knew almost nothing about programming just a month ago. Now I have done two of the courses of the specialization and I can actually understand other basic codes. Great course!', 'This course is too much about text and have a lot of  data structures, which I found to be non useful for majority of users.', 'One of the funniest/most interactive computer science teachers I have ever had, all explained in a simple and concise yet still engaging manner', 'wow !!!!!!! what a great experience', 'I love the professor! He makes the learning so much fun. I think it really helps beginner students to develop an interest at the start and become wiling to continue the exploration.', 'Very informative. ', 'this second part was very interesting, i gonna keep going on the course', 'very good! It is really a wonderful class!', 'Really The best Course to understand data structure ', 'Professor Severance makes learning Python easy and fun!', 'simple but useful', 'Very clear, informative, nice and enjoyable.', 'Dr Chuck makes it easy', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Oluwafemi R', 'By Shreyansh J', 'By Christopher M', 'By Jaineel N', 'By Troy E', 'By Samarth K S', 'By Ricardo M', 'By Jonathan W O G', 'By Aditya A', 'By Pavani M', 'By Maurice E', 'By Daniel A', 'By Farid H', 'By Daniel H', 'By Abhishek G', 'By Yidan X', 'By Samuel I K', 'By Abraham G V', 'By cyc', 'By maboseteit', 'By ARUN S', 'By Changhui S', 'By Yasser W', 'By Amar S', 'By Jeremiah S']</reviewers><review_date>['May 07, 2019', 'May 31, 2019', 'May 14, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Jul 26, 2019', 'Oct 08, 2017', 'Jul 19, 2019', 'Nov 10, 2017', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018']</review_date></doc>