<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_169</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-insights-gcp-apply-ml</course_url><course_name>Applying Machine Learning to your Data with GCP</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>Want to know how to query and process petabytes of data in seconds? Curious about data analysis that scales automatically as your data grows? Welcome to the Data Insights course!

This 1-week, accelerated online course teaches participants how to derive insights through data analysis and visualization using the Google Cloud Platform. The course features interactive scenarios and hands-on labs where participants explore, mine, load, visualize, and extract insights from diverse Google BigQuery datasets. The course covers data loading, querying, schema modeling, optimizing performance, query pricing,  and data visualization.

PREREQUISITES
To get the most out of this course, participants must complete the prior courses in this specialization:
• Exploring and Preparing your Data
• Storing and Visualizing your Data
• Architecture and Performance

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this specialization you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Information Technology.Data Management</course_category><course_tag>Bigquery//Machine Learning//Google Cloud Platform//Cloud Computing</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Introduction to Machine Learning//Pre-trained ML APIs//Creating ​ML Datasets in BigQuery//Creating ML Models in BigQuery//End of Course Recap</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Qwiklabs Overview'], ['Introduction to Machine Learning', 'Demo: Google Photos', 'What is deep learning?', 'ML Applications for Business', 'ML Terms: Instances, Features, Labels', 'The Spectrum of ML Tools'], ['Pre-Trained ML Models', 'Demo: Cloud Translate and Vision APIs', 'Demo: Natural Language Processing API', 'Collaborative Notebooks in the Cloud', 'Demo: Cloud Datalab with BigQuery and Google Analytics', 'Accessing BigQuery datasets from Cloud Datalab', 'Visualizing Datasets in Charts', 'Lab Overview', 'Lab Walkthrough'], ['What makes a dataset good for ML?', 'Choosing good features', 'Exploring and Preprocessing Data', 'Demo: Exploring and Preprocessing Data', 'Other Tools for Creating Data Pipelines', 'Knowing the Unknowable', 'Creating Repeatable Dataset Splits', 'Lab Solution: Creating Repeatable Dataset Splits'], ['Introducing BigQuery Machine Learning', 'Phases of Model Building', 'Demo: Predicting Taxi Cab Fare', 'Demo: Creating a Classification Model', 'Lab Intro: Predicting Visitor Return Purchases with BigQuery', 'Lab Solution: Predicting Visitor Return Purchases in BigQuery'], ['Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Enjoyed.  I would add more in-depth ML part for BigQuery and different scenario. it also good to explain metric how and how to choose right features etc ', 'The instructor Evan is super great to rolling out machine learning in an easy /understandable way. hope he can tech more in-depth of machine learning.', 'Thank you Evan for such a good training', 'nice course', 'Easy to understand ', 'ok', 'This was a great course in going beyond the lecture to applying the concepts of creating, training, testing and deploying a machine learning model', 'This was a great course on Machine Learning with BigQuery and Cloud Datalab. The exploration was very good for starters.', 'Very professional Google course. ', 'Really amazing instructor and very helpful course, highly recommended.', 'good', 'Great Training', 'Love Google Cloud :):):):)', 'Interesting labs and handy things to learn', 'Pengalaman bagus untuk belajar Machine Learning pertama kali di GCP.', 'AMAZING COURSE AND VERY WELL TRUGHT BY INSTRUCTOR', 'Course give good insights for using ML using SQL and other Models ', 'Machine Learning, SQL', 'Excellent way to introduce to Google Big Query and Machine Learning Applications!', 'Excellent', 'Good Course to Understand the basics of Big query and running ML using Big query', 'Good', 'Good introduction to ml for me given i had no previous knowledge on the basics.', 'It would be nice if the labs had additional/different code then the one explained over the videos.', 'Nice Course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mustafa B', 'By LIJUN L', 'By Laurent L', 'By Oleg Z', 'By Nguyen D P', 'By José R P', 'By Scott M', 'By Harold L M M', 'By Guy G', 'By M. J I', 'By Ekta M', 'By Hitesh', 'By Aditya S', 'By Zakhar P', 'By Citrananda A', 'By Arslan M', 'By Pratik S', 'By Gary T', 'By Srinivasulu K', 'By Saiyed M H R', 'By Avinash R K', 'By Atichat P', 'By Christopher C', 'By Chariton C', 'By Hernán D R S']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 22, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'May 11, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2018', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Aug 20, 2018', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Oct 21, 2018', 'Jul 25, 2018', 'May 24, 2019', 'May 19, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019', 'Sep 04, 2019', 'Sep 11, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2018', 'Sep 14, 2018', 'Jun 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>