<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_109</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning-business-professionals</course_url><course_name>Machine Learning for Business Professionals</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is intended to be an introduction to machine learning for non-technical business professionals. There is a lot of hype around machine learning and many people are concerned that in order to use machine learning in business, you need to have a technical background. For reasons that are covered in this course, that's not the case. In actuality, your knowledge of your business is far more important than your ability to build an ML model from scratch.

By the end of this course, you will have learned how to:
• Formulate machine learning solutions to real-world problems
• Identify whether the data you have is sufficient for ML
• Carry a project through various ML phases including training, evaluation, and deployment
• Perform AI responsibly and avoid reinforcing existing bias
• Discover ML use cases
• Be successful at ML

You'll need a desktop web browser to run this course's interactive labs via Qwiklabs and Google Cloud Platform.

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this course you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//What is Machine Learning?//Employing ML//Discovering ML Use Cases//How to be successful at ML//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Getting Started with Google Cloud Platform and Qwiklabs'], ['Standard Use Cases and Algorithms', 'Characteristics of Data', 'ML vs. Artificial Intelligence', 'Predictive Insights and Repeated Decisions', 'Real Life Use Cases', 'Building a Chatbot Lab Review', 'Why ML now? Part 1', 'Why ML Now? Part 2', 'Understanding Images Lab Review', 'Using AI Responsibly'], ['Introduction', 'ML Terminology in Context', 'Acquiring Labeled Data Part 1', 'Acquiring Labeled Data Part 2', 'Labeling Service Demo', 'Model Training Part 1', 'Model Training Part 2', 'Model Evaluating', 'General Best Practices', 'Human Bias in ML Part 1', 'Human Bias in ML Part 2', 'Human Bias in ML Part 3', 'Activity: Understanding Learned Relationships using the Embedding Projector Review', 'Fairness in ML Part 1', 'Fairness in ML Part 2', 'Activity: Applying Fairness Concerns with the What-If tool Review'], ['Introduction', 'Simplifying Rule-based Systems Part 1', 'Simplifying Rule-based Systems Part 2', 'Simplifying Rule-based Systems Part 3', 'Streamlining Business Processes', 'Understanding Unstructured Data', 'Personalizing Experiences', 'Recommender Systems Part 1', 'Recommender Systems Part 2', 'Inspiring ML Use Cases', 'When to Use ML', 'Activity: Generating Novel Rhythms with Machine Learning Review', 'ML in Series', 'Summary'], ['Introduction', 'Data Strategy Part 1', 'Data Strategy Part 2', 'Data Strategy Part 3', 'Predicting visitor purchases with BQML model', 'Data Governance Part 1', 'Data Masking Demo', 'Data Governance Part 2', 'Data Governance Part 3', 'Creating a Culture of Innovation Part 1', 'Creating a Culture of Innovation Part 2'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course material and coverage is very good and vast. It covers a lot of good use cases from different kind of industries. ', 'Concise overview of what ML is and what it might be used for  with brief, but good intro to GCP tools.  Not very deep technically, but this is by design.  Instead, it covers some important points that some more technical courses skip past, that are important for a successful ML project in your company.', 'This course is very good for someone who wants to just get a feeling of how machine learning can be used in different scenarios and how to get a hang of some of the machine learning tools without explicit coding knowledge. But before doing this course I would suggest everyone to go through AI for everyone course by Andrew Ng. After that course, this course will look a lot more approachable.', 'Very interesting overview of ML', 'Great Course!', "great course really like Lak's explanation ", "This is one of the best online courses I have ever taken, it was easy to go through and I feel like I learnt so much.  The information was just enough to trigger curiosity and keep me motivated.  Access to GCP labs and playing around was awesome, it was more than you could bargain for the fees.  The Quiz weren't that challenging except the one in Week #1.  It would be great I can continue to have access the material so I can further reinforce the information I learned by reviewing them again.  Thanks for making the learning easy.", 'Excelent introduction to ML', 'Very informative course, Great learning!', 'Very good introduction for business professionals.', 'Great overview of the basics of AI and how to think about when it makes the most sense to use it, as well as its limitations. ', 'Very good course, it goes beyond the basic concepts, and the hands on labs help to understand better the concepts. ', '$50 well spent!  I was able to apply my learnings immediately on an hypothesis for an ML project being proposed.  ', 'Excellent Lab sections. Elaborated discussions and lecture videos. ', 'Есть некоторые несоответствия между описанием и реальным интерфейсом в активностях. В остальном - все отлично.', 'Very good quality and easy to understand', 'excellent content from coursera and GCP! Kudos!', 'This really helps put business dynamics and ML concepts in perfect alignment; to an extent that a clarity of thought is achieved. If you want to gear up towards jumping from your world of Dashboards, reports powered by in BI to a new frontier of ML and AI, then this course is perfect place to start. ', 'Loved this course! ', "It's a very good starting point for business professionals interested on a deep overview of Machine Learning, its characteristics, usage and benefits.", 'I had no idea about the subject before i started this program. But when i finished, i feel i need to more. I am more excited, enthusiastic to learn more about AI, ML &amp; DL. These will be the future of business and must learn for each business guy.', 'Excelent Course. Highly recommended for Tech Lead Managers and AI Business Professionals', 'Good Course on ML for Non technical professionals to understand the world of Machine Language.', 'Excellent course to give us an idea of how machine learning works, how to set up machine learning teams within your company, how to identify potential use cases in your business and the importance of sensitive data governance. I feel much more comfortable with machine learning concepts now and ready to pursue a more technical course. Highly recommended!', "I really like the course, I have suggested some minor updates and I believe the Bias should be explained more since they can be a bit tricky to understand, but it was the course that I was looking for years since most of them are either too technical or the lack of certain statistical or mathematical information in my case, it made impossible to jump on it! But now, I'm thinking how to use ML for a PhD."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Parag G', 'By Michael C', 'By Gourab M', 'By Colin B', 'By Emanuel M', 'By saleem a', 'By Phaneendra R', 'By Ricardo A M', 'By Nishtha A', 'By Javier G', 'By Ronald P', 'By Victor D R', 'By Marcelo C', 'By Hariharan V', 'By Irina Z', 'By Alfredo P C', 'By GAJANAN R V', 'By Khwaja F A W', 'By Jonathan A D', 'By Lucas M S L', 'By nipun a', 'By Juan A', 'By Arunkumar M', 'By Marcelo C d A', 'By Federico N']</reviewers><review_date>['May 22, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'May 30, 2019', 'May 02, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'Jun 05, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Jul 02, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Jul 04, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jul 08, 2019', 'Jul 16, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2019', 'Aug 20, 2019', 'Aug 21, 2019', 'Aug 20, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019']</review_date></doc>