<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_248</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-patterns</course_url><course_name>Pattern Discovery in Data Mining</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jiawei Han</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn the general concepts of data mining along with basic methodologies and applications. Then dive into one subfield in data mining: pattern discovery. Learn in-depth concepts, methods, and applications of pattern discovery in data mining. We will also introduce methods for data-driven phrase mining and some interesting applications of pattern discovery. This course provides you the opportunity to learn skills and content to practice and engage in scalable pattern discovery methods on massive transactional data, discuss pattern evaluation measures, and study methods for mining diverse kinds of patterns, sequential patterns, and sub-graph patterns.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Streams//Sequential Pattern Mining//Data Mining Algorithms//Data Mining</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Orientation//Module 1//Module 2//Module 3//Week 4</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction'], ['1.1. What Is Pattern Discovery? Why Is It Important?', '1.2. Frequent Patterns and Association Rules', '1.3. Compressed Representation: Closed Patterns and Max-Patterns', '2.1. The Downward Closure Property of Frequent Patterns', '2.2. The Apriori Algorithm', '2.3. Extensions or Improvements of Apriori', '2.4. Mining Frequent Patterns by Exploring Vertical Data Format', '2.5. FPGrowth: A Pattern Growth Approach', '2.6. Mining Closed Patterns'], ['3.1. Limitation of the Support-Confidence Framework', '3.2. Interestingness Measures: Lift and χ2', '3.3. Null Invariance Measures', '3.4. Comparison of Null-Invariant Measures', '4.1. Mining Multi-Level Associations', '4.2. Mining Multi-Dimensional Associations', '4.3. Mining Quantitative Associations', '4.4. Mining Negative Correlations', '4.5. Mining Compressed Patterns'], ['5.1. Sequential Pattern and Sequential Pattern Mining', '5.2. GSP: Apriori-Based Sequential Pattern Mining', '5.3. SPADE—Sequential Pattern Mining in Vertical Data Format', '5.4. PrefixSpan—Sequential Pattern Mining by Pattern-Growth', '5.5. CloSpan—Mining Closed Sequential Patterns', '6.1. Mining Spatial Associations', '6.2. Mining Spatial Colocation Patterns', '6.3. Mining and Aggregating Patterns over Multiple Trajectories', '6.4. Mining Semantics-Rich Movement Patterns', '6.5. Mining Periodic Movement Patterns'], ['7.1. From Frequent Pattern Mining to Phrase Mining', '7.2. Previous Phrase Mining Methods', '7.3. ToPMine: Phrase Mining without Training Data', '7.4. SegPhrase: Phrase Mining with Tiny Training Sets', '8.1. Frequent Pattern Mining in Data Streams', '8.2. Pattern Discovery for Software Bug Mining', '8.3. Pattern Discovery for Image Analysis', '8.4. Advanced Topics on Pattern Discovery: Pattern Mining and Society—Privacy Issue', '8.5. Advanced Topics on Pattern Discovery: Looking Forward']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I'd review this course for two parts: lectures and programming assignments.", 'Very poor. ', 'very unhelpful lecture, basically learn everything by yourself', 'nice', 'Very interesting and very clearly explained.', "very great！it's very helpful for me! thank you !", 'Very usefull course. I learned too much about pattern discovering.', 'Very well taught. The teacher has a very good understanding of the level of detail that can be addressed. He uses clear examples and keeps each lesson to the point. The quizzes are short and focussed on what was taught in the course.', 'Very well-organised course. I especially liked the assignments: programming assignments were helpful to apply the course (this makes you implement the methods you learn), so were multiple-choice questions that really make you think on the course content. The instructor was clear and provided good materials. I would recommend this course.', 'Nice work plan ', 'Excellent course. Now I have a big picture about pattern discovery and understand some popular algorithm. Also professor points out the direction for further study.', 'The course is very helpful and brings fascinating insights for projects.', 'very nice!', 'Amazing!', 'The first several chapters are very impressive. The last three lessons are a little difficult for first-learners. The illustration are clear and easy to understand.', 'Excel', 'Great course for beginners without experience in Python programming', 'compact class which teaches you lots of knowledge without wasting any time, using frequent tests to renew your memory and test your comprehension.', 'Gave a very good introduction of Pattern Discovery and different mechanisms/algorithms for pattern discovery. Talks about different pattern discovery approaches, pros &amp; cons of each. Found it very helpful for my investment analysis project', 'The course exercises are medium-hard. But the topic coverage is spot on.', 'It is a good course but more knowledge are expected to be filled, e.g, some algorithm can be detailed or illustrated with simple-case instantiation.', '\nToo much material. Not enough real examples.\n\n', 'Should be more support in the forum for quiz and assignement', 'Excellent course that summarizes a very broad and complex topic. Definitely recommend.', 'I learned a lot from this lecture. And I believe the lecture is excellent except that if he could become a little bit funny, then it would be perfect. Thanks,']</reviews><reviewers>['By Prashant K', 'By Luca B', 'By Vivian Y Q', 'By SAURABH K', 'By Eric A S', 'By chenjing', 'By Carlos R', 'By Felix K', 'By Mykola K', 'By Vaibhav K', 'By GANG L', 'By Anubhav B', 'By Lu Y', 'By Hernan C V', 'By Darren', 'By Valerie P', 'By Deleted A', 'By Ian W', 'By Srinath R M', 'By Rahul M', 'By Cheng-shuo Y', 'By Piotr B', 'By Tanan K', 'By Gary C', 'By Tao Y']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 05, 2017', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Oct 13, 2017', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Sep 10, 2018', 'May 25, 2018', 'Mar 26, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2016', 'Feb 05, 2017', 'May 04, 2017', 'Sep 10, 2017', 'Jul 11, 2017', 'Apr 28, 2017', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Mar 05, 2017', 'Dec 12, 2017', 'Aug 03, 2017', 'Apr 24, 2017', 'Jun 27, 2017', 'Feb 01, 2017']</review_date></doc>