<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_165</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-analysis</course_url><course_name>Big Data Analysis: Hive, Spark SQL, DataFrames and GraphFrames</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Natalia Pritykovskaya</course_instructor><course_introduction>No doubt working with huge data volumes is hard, but to move a mountain, you have to deal with a lot of small stones. But why strain yourself? Using  Mapreduce and Spark you tackle the issue partially, thus leaving some space for high-level tools. Stop  struggling to make your big data workflow productive and efficient,  make use of the tools we are offering you.
 
This course will teach you how to:
- Warehouse your data efficiently using Hive, Spark SQL and Spark DataFframes. 
- Work with large graphs, such as social graphs or networks. 
- Optimize your Spark applications for maximum performance.

Precisely, you will master your knowledge in:
- Writing and executing Hive &amp; Spark SQL queries;
- Reasoning how the queries are translated into actual execution primitives (be it MapReduce jobs or Spark transformations);
- Organizing your data in Hive to optimize disk space usage and execution times;
- Constructing Spark DataFrames and using them to write ad-hoc analytical jobs easily;
- Processing large graphs with Spark GraphFrames;
- Debugging, profiling and optimizing Spark application performance.
 
Still in doubt? Check this out. Become a data ninja by taking this course!

Special thanks to:
- Prof. Mikhail Roytberg, APT dept., MIPT, who was the initial reviewer of the project, the supervisor and mentor of half of the BigData team. He was the one, who helped to get this show on the road.
- Oleg Sukhoroslov (PhD, Senior Researcher at IITP RAS), who has been teaching  MapReduce, Hadoop and friends since 2008. Now he is leading the infrastructure team.
- Oleg Ivchenko (PhD student APT dept., MIPT), Pavel Akhtyamov (MSc. student at APT dept., MIPT) and Vladimir Kuznetsov (Assistant at P.G. Demidov Yaroslavl State University), superbrains who have developed and now maintain the infrastructure used for practical assignments in this course.
- Asya Roitberg, Eugene Baulin, Marina Sudarikova. These people never sleep to babysit this course day and night, to make your learning experience productive, smooth and exciting.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Graphs//Hive//Apache Hive//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Yandex</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the Second Course: Big Data Analysis//Big Data SQL: Hive//Big Data SQL: Hive (practice week)//Spark SQL and Spark Dataframe//Graph Analysis from Big Data Perspective//PageRank and Recent Advances//Spark Internals and Optimization</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Computations Optimization', 'What is BigData Analysis?', 'Tools For BigData Analysis', 'Graph Data Analysis', 'Meet Alexey Dral', 'Meet Pavel Mezentsev', 'Meet Natalia Pritykovskaya', 'Meet Pavel Klemenkov'], ['Analytics: Business Use Cases', 'HTTP Web Service: Access Log Format', 'Business Use Cases: Solution with Hive', '(optional) SQL: likbez', 'Hive Data Definition Language (DDL)', 'Hive Data Manipulation Language (DML)', 'Hive Analytics: RegexSerDe, Views', '(optional) Regular Expressions, Likbez', 'Hive Analytics: UDF, UDAF, UDTF', 'Hive Streaming', 'Hive PTF (Window Functions)', 'Hive Optimization: Partitioning, Bucketing and Sampling', 'Hive Map-Side Joins: Plain, Bucket, Sort-Merge', 'Hive Optimization: Data Skew', 'Hive Optimization: Row-Columnar File Formats, Compression'], ['How to submit your first assignment', 'How to Install Docker on Windows 7, 8, 10', 'How to submit your first Hadoop assignment'], ['Advantages of Spark SQL', 'What is Pandas DataFrame and how to create it', 'How to process a DataFrame as SQL', 'Working with Hive', 'Reading and Writing Files', 'RDD vs. DF vs. SQL', 'Projection and Filtering', 'Functions', 'Aggregates', 'Join', 'User Defined Functions', 'Time Processing', 'Window Functions', 'Two-Dimensional Distributions'], ['Graph examples', 'Graph representation', 'Counting common friends. Part I', 'Counting common friends. Part II', 'Counting common friends. Part III', 'GraphFrames: Introduction', 'Motif Finding: DSL', 'Motif Finding: Counting Mutual Friends', 'Motif Finding: Under The Hood. Part 1', 'Motif Finding: Under The Hood. Part 2', 'Triangles Count: Introduction', 'Triangles Count: Edge Lists', 'Triangles Count: GraphFrame'], ['Introduction', 'Algorithm', 'GraphFrames', 'Random Walk', 'Page Rank Algorithm', 'RDD Implementation', 'GraphFrames API', 'Taste Graph. Part I', 'Taste Graph. Part II', 'Taste Graph. Part III'], ['Welcome', 'Spark Execution Model', 'Shuffle. Where to send data?', 'Shuffle. How to send data?', 'Optimizing Functions', 'PageRank Optimization', 'Spark SQL. Motivation', 'Catalyst', 'Catalyst Optimization Example', 'Joins', 'Optimizing Joins', 'UDF Optimization', 'Persistance and Checkpointing', 'Memory Management', 'Resource Allocation', 'Dynamic Allocation', 'Speculative Execution']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 72 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['A decent course with lots of room for improvement to be great.  ', "This course has a very good content for me. But I really tired fighting with the assignment grade system. I have crushed with many technical problems. And sometimes it's not clear how to find the right way to execute the assignment. It's why I'm unenrolled from this course.", "I think lessons about GraphFrames were too hard. I cannot understood a lot about algorithmes and didn't do honor tasks ( More examples and more explanatons could help a lot ", '  Unfortunately, I often spent more time trying to get my assignments to pass the automatic grader than on solving them. This made the course a bit frustrating at times.  ', "  Good content  but  the assignment grade system is frustrating. You spend so many hours trying to understand which are the errors or the way to execute the assignment. Tutors do not answer your questions . It's why I'm unenrolled from this course.  I definitely do not recommend it. ", 'Although I do believe that the teaching in this course was adequate, and I think the teachers involved were working their hardest to convey a complex topic, it was really hard for me to follow.', 'Only  good content can not suffice for a good tutorial. I tried hard to pursue this course, but now giving up for the poor speakers, poor communication and lack of helpful visual aids.', 'minuses: GraphFrames seems useless. No tasks on them. And a lot of time were spent on algorithms, not spark functions and internals.', 'The content of the courses and some of the weeks are very good, but other are terrible with many problems in the lessons and in the assignments. Some of the teachers seems to take very little care in the preparation of the lessons and the related material and this dramatically reduce the overall quality of the course. Could and must be improved. ', 'Grader is awful', 'Very useful', 'Excellent teachers, but material from lessons on graphs required a lot of time.', 'content of the course is remarkable and the way they explained concepts is very lucid. I just want to give suggestions please give link to the data set they are using for illustrating the concepts.', 'This course is so detailed and focused on the basics of the Hive and Spark SQL frameworks. Amazing professors. ', 'I wish I could give more rating than 5 :). Excellent course. Thanks so much for such an excellent course. All the instructors are great.', 'Eye Catching career Matching course..especially lectures by Alexey Dral', 'Good informative Course', 'vey nice', 'Excellent very skill full', 'Quite a good course, but weeks about graphs I found somewhat poor. Apart from that you learn basics of Hive, details of DataFrame API of Spark and how it internally works.', 'Good. Please fix assignments explanations. i.e In week 5. ', 'Good course...Deep dive into optimization of spark for production environment.Also interesting graph implementations', 'Nice course, but the impression about practical tasks is really awful. The tasks are ok, but grading system is too buggy', "Grading system it terrible, it hadn't work for a week summary, no help from staff on Coursera forum, only Slack channel could help. Theoretical material is quite good.", 'Few Environment not supporting frequently.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nicole J L', 'By Sergei M', 'By Pismarev V', 'By Marco G', 'By Josefa C S', 'By Scott D', 'By Shubhajit S', 'By Павел С', 'By Luis V', 'By Максим У', 'By Phi H T', 'By Симкин И М', 'By shatabdi m', 'By amanpreet k', 'By sekhar', 'By Sunny J', 'By Dilip N', 'By Alok K', 'By Muhammad B', 'By Viacheslav I', 'By Luis M A P', 'By Aldrin', 'By Kiselyov A', 'By Evgenii K', 'By ANNAMALAI A']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 05, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2018', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Apr 25, 2018', 'Sep 07, 2018', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'May 13, 2018', 'May 27, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Aug 07, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2018', 'Apr 02, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019', 'Dec 09, 2017', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'May 15, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2019']</review_date></doc>