<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_93</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-operations-analytics</course_url><course_name>Operations Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Senthil Veeraraghavan</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is designed to impact the way you think about transforming data into better decisions. Recent extraordinary improvements in data-collecting technologies have changed the way firms make informed and effective business decisions. The course on operations analytics, taught by three of Wharton’s leading experts, focuses on how the data can be used to profitably match supply with demand in various business settings. In this course, you will learn how to model future demand uncertainties, how to predict the outcomes of competing policy choices and how to choose the best course of action in the face of risk. The course will introduce frameworks and ideas that provide insights into a spectrum of real-world business challenges, will teach you methods and software available for tackling these challenges quantitatively as well as the issues involved in gathering the relevant data.

This course is appropriate for beginners and business professionals with no prior analytics experience.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Strategy</course_category><course_tag>Simulation//Mathematical Optimization//Solver//Decision Tree</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction, Descriptive and Predictive Analytics//Prescriptive Analytics, Low Uncertainty//Predictive Analytics, Risk//Prescriptive Analytics, High Uncertainty </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction and Welcome', 'The Newsvendor Problem', 'Moving Averages', 'Trends, Seasonality', 'Week 1 Wrap-up, Apparel Industry'], ['How to Build an Optimization Model', 'Optimizing with Solver', 'Network Optimization Example', '(Optional) Week 2 Review', '(Optional) Solver on Mac', '(Optional) Solver in Google Sheets'], ['Comparing Decisions in Uncertain Settings', 'Simulating Uncertain Outcomes in Excel', 'Interpreting and Visualizing Simulation Output', '(Optional) Week 3 Review'], ['Decision Trees', 'Using Simulation with Decision Trees', 'Using Optimization Together with Simulation', 'Week 4 Wrap-up', '(Optional) Session 4 Review', '(Optional) Advanced Session on Optimization']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I think that this course has turned out to be too much "basic" according to my education. I believe that it was too much Excel-oriented (with really basic Excel notion).', 'Amazing course, and really informative!', "Great hands on examples that I'm already starting to use in my job now. ", 'Wonderful Course, I learned a lot!', 'The awesome effort by the Wharton Business School, Thanks to Wharton Business School &amp; all the concerns &amp; professors, who put their efforts in this course.', 'Interesting introduction course to basic analytic tools', 'very excellent course', 'Exciting!', 'A very informative course .Need for references to develop strong sense  of decision making', None, 'love it', 'great', 'A very well structured course. Thank you Coursera', 'Great course with great amount of learning. worth to try.', 'Curso básico, que da buenas ideas!', 'Great course for learning and learn about simulations tools for determining future forecasts.', 'Very intuitive and useful. They show you how to use practical tools and in a easy manner. I have enjoyed so much.', 'An Amazing course with amazing teachers! Thank you UPenn!', 'This has helped make this more palatable for me. I now get the formulas and their application, how they all work together', 'a very concise and carefully planned syllabus. thoroughly enjoyed doing this course. It gave me such a boost to my confidence. ', 'Amazing course. Great learning from the course especially for beginners.', 'Very well structured content, all instructors have provided thorough explanation on the content section, highly recommend.  ', 'I learned a lot. I recommend to do it!', 'Amazing knowledge and fantastic tools to improve analytics skills!', 'Very well explained methods, using simple explanation with excel, it makes possible to put the knowledge into practice.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Andrea M', 'By Shubhankar P', 'By John T', 'By Mirna O', 'By Muhammad H', 'By Raimundo G', 'By 阮心宇', 'By Christian F P', 'By hemantlokras', 'By Francis D', 'By ROBS J', 'By Manasvee M K', 'By Niraj A', 'By Shashikesh M', 'By Yuri P', 'By Asad M', 'By Joaquín C M', 'By Daniel C', 'By Kevin S L', 'By Yashodadevi V', 'By DOROTHY S', 'By Lin D', 'By Sasha C', 'By Andrés P B', 'By Allan K']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 05, 2016', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019']</review_date></doc>