<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_44</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/language-processing</course_url><course_name>Natural Language Processing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Anna Potapenko</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course covers a wide range of tasks in Natural Language Processing from basic to advanced: sentiment analysis, summarization, dialogue state tracking, to name a few. Upon completing, you will be able to recognize NLP tasks in your day-to-day work, propose approaches, and judge what techniques are likely to work well.  The final project is devoted to one of the most hot topics in today’s NLP. You will build your own conversational chat-bot that will assist with search on StackOverflow website. The project will be based on practical assignments of the course, that will give you hands-on experience with such tasks as text classification, named entities recognition, and duplicates detection. 

Throughout the lectures, we will aim at finding a balance between traditional and deep learning techniques in NLP and cover them in parallel. For example, we will discuss word alignment models in machine translation and see how similar it is to attention mechanism in encoder-decoder neural networks. Core techniques are not treated as black boxes. On the contrary, you will get in-depth understanding of what’s happening inside. To succeed in that, we expect your familiarity with the basics of linear algebra and probability theory, machine learning setup, and deep neural networks. Some materials are based on one-month-old papers and introduce you to the very state-of-the-art in NLP research.

Do you have technical problems? Write to us: coursera@hse.ru</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Chatterbot//Tensorflow//Deep Learning//Natural Language Processing</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>National Research University Higher School of Economics</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Intro and text classification//Language modeling and sequence tagging//Vector Space Models of Semantics//Sequence to sequence tasks//Dialog systems</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About this course', 'Welcome video', 'Main approaches in NLP', 'Brief overview of the next weeks', '[Optional] Linguistic knowledge in NLP', 'Text preprocessing', 'Feature extraction from text', 'Linear models for sentiment analysis', 'Hashing trick in spam filtering', 'Neural networks for words', 'Neural networks for characters'], ['Count! N-gram language models', 'Perplexity: is our model surprised with a real text?', 'Smoothing: what if we see new n-grams?', 'Hidden Markov Models', 'Viterbi algorithm:  what are the most probable tags?', 'MEMMs, CRFs and other sequential models for Named Entity Recognition', 'Neural Language Models', 'Whether you need to predict a next word or a label - LSTM is here to help!'], ['Distributional semantics: bee and honey vs. bee an bumblebee', 'Explicit and implicit matrix factorization', 'Word2vec and doc2vec (and how to evaluate them)', 'Word analogies without magic:  king – man + woman != queen', 'Why words? From character to sentence embeddings', 'Topic modeling: a way to navigate  through text collections', 'How to train PLSA?', 'The zoo of topic models'], ['Introduction to Machine Translation', 'Noisy channel: said in English, received in French', 'Word Alignment Models', 'Encoder-decoder architecture', 'Attention mechanism', 'How to deal with a vocabulary?', 'How to implement a conversational chat-bot?', 'Sequence to sequence learning:  one-size fits all?', 'Get to the point! Summarization with pointer-generator networks'], ['Task-oriented dialog systems', 'Intent classifier and slot tagger (NLU)', 'Adding context to NLU', 'Adding lexicon to NLU', 'State tracking in DM', 'Policy optimisation in DM', 'Final remarks']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 33 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I can't see anything educational in this course. I frustrated.  Simple recitation of facts from NLP articles and nothing more. Programming projects are disconnected from videos., i.e, upon watching video don't expect to understand how to complete a programming project or at least to understand what you have to do in order to pass the assignment.  This course is the worst I have ever seen on Coursera. ", 'The course is very poorly explained, in comparison with other similar ones in Coursera.', "Terrible final project realization. You use telegram to deploy your conversational bot, which shuts you off if you don't have people chatting with it for too long. And that can happen if nobody reviews your project for days and weeks. I give this course a one star, as this kind of thing is just unacceptable from my perspective, and I can elaborate why. You've taken my money for waiting more than a month for reviews, only to find out I did not pass because my bot shut down. I'm sorry, but I won't take another course from you again. Goodbye.", "A lot of information on a very high level but with reference to papers. Papers are a little bit dated for now, but this is due to rapid progress of NLP as a field of study. Assignments which need to be peer reviewed are painful, because you don't know when someone will check your work. This is due to not many learners simultaneously at class. In general, the course provides helpful advice when working with NLP and reveals some of the core approaches. Also, there is enough practice here, which is great.", 'Anna is a great instructor. She can explain the concept and mathematical formulas in a clear way. The design of assignment is both interesting and practical.', 'Useful videos and assignments, although some are very unclear. The last assignment has really bad documentation of what everything is actually doing and it includes setting up a ubuntu instance on AWS, chat bot on telegram and tons of other stuff, and there are very vague explanations of how everything is linked together. But in the end when everything was done, i felt like ive learned a lot, including things out of the scope of teh course.', "Very good advanced course on NLP covering both statistical and deep learning modeling approaches. Very well cemented by programming assignments in python and real-world acht bot application using Telegram and Amazon Web Services free tier solution. Check the pre-requisites because this is an advanced course requiring some previous knowledge of NLP, linguistics, machine learning, deep learning and above all python programming and some AWS and Docker basic knowledge. Staff is very responsive and supportive on the forum. Finally, don't underestimate the time it takes to go through all videos, quizzes, and programming assignments -the guidance given is on the low end.", 'This is the most rigorous NLP course that I could find on Coursera or any other MOOC provider. A thorough introduction to both classical and NN models for a variety of NLP problems and tasks, drawing upon recently published articles. ', 'Amazing course lot of stuff to learn and it is very interesting with a good mix between the  classical tools of NLP and more advanced one like deep learning.', "Are you kidding me? What are you talking about in courses? I have to re-study everything after each video because it just doesn't help you understand the theories at all.", 'The course instructors do a bad job of explaining the basic concepts for anything in the Week 1 itself. They are inclined towards using jargons form the field, providing no context of basis of using the different algorithms or concepts. This course is probably, only, suitable for people who need a quick refresher on something they already know very well. I will not recommend this course if your aim is to LEARN NLP. ', "Course material is not up-to-date: You cannot imagine an NLP course that doesn't know Transformer or Bert in 2019.", 'Very good course with tough assignments. Expect to take more time to digest the material on the video and work on the assignments', 'Definitely best course in the Specialization! Lecturers, projects and forum - everything is super organized. Only StarSpace was pain in the ass, but I managed :)', 'Great introduction to NLP. But NLP is too huge topic so need to study more about this when really want to work at company.', 'Very interesting, qquite advanced and you need to invest time for the assignments, but worth it in my opinion', "Deadline passed, no review.  I submitted my Honors assignment 8 hours before the submission deadline, exactly when I was supposed to in order to ensure a peer review.  I performed reviews on a number of other students' works, as required.  Yet my work remained unreviewed for months, until a student from one of the next classes felt charitable.", 'great course!', 'お疲れ様です。ありがとうございます。', None, 'Content is so good. Cheers for the makers.', 'I like this course very much. It is a good introduction for NLP. But if you want to know more about the NLP, you need to search and read a lot of posts during the learning process.', 'Is the best NLP course i have ever seen !!!!!!!!', 'Very good course with broad introduction of the state of the art technologies for NLP. Well designed and interesting homework as well.', 'Awesome course, I really learned a lot and the projects are really interesting, especially the final project!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Bayram K', 'By Daniel I', 'By Aleksandar J', 'By Hanna P', 'By Tianqi L', 'By Gabriel P', 'By Jaime A', 'By Alexander S', 'By mirgahney h a m', 'By Xinghao G', 'By Vasudha A', 'By Qingsheng L', 'By Glorian Y', 'By Milos V', 'By Seongeun S', 'By Patrick R', 'By Mike D', 'By Alexander R', 'By Cindy P', 'By 芦昌灏', 'By Anurag', 'By yang', 'By Hassan B', 'By Xuan W', 'By Christian G']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 19, 2018', 'Jun 03, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Jul 08, 2018', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Jun 21, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'May 07, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2018', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Jun 14, 2018', 'Jul 12, 2019', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019']</review_date></doc>