<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_251</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/information-visualization-programming-d3js</course_url><course_name>Information Visualization: Programming with D3.js</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Enrico Bertini </course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will learn how to use D3.js to create powerful visualizations for web. Learning D3.js will enable you to create many different types of visualization and to visualize many different data types. It will give you the freedom to create something as simple as a bar chart as well your own new revolutionary technique. 

In this course we will cover the basics of creating visualizations with D3 as well as how to deal with tabular data, geography and networks. By the end of this course you will be able to:

- Create bar and line charts
- Create choropleth and symbol maps
- Create node-link diagrams and tree maps
- Implement zooming and brushing
- Link two or more views through interaction

The course mixes theoretical and practical lectures. We will show you step by step how to use the library to build actual visualizations and what theoretical concepts lie behind them. Throughout the course you will learn skills that will lead you to building a whole application by the end of the lectures (a fully working visualization system to visualize airlines routes).

This course is the third one of the “Specialization in Information Visualization". The course expects you to have some basic knowledge of programming as well as some basic visualization skills.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Information Technology.Data Management</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>New York University Tandon School of Engineering</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to web and d3//Dealing  &amp; drawing with data//Lines, Arcs, and maps//Layouts and interaction</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Specialization', 'Welcome to the Course', 'Intro to the Week 1', 'Introduction to HTML', 'Practice: Introduction to HTML', 'Introduction to CSS', 'Practice: Introduction to CSS', 'Introduction to Javascript', 'Javascript - Control Structures', 'Practice: Introduction to Javascript', 'Practice: Javascript - Control Structures', 'Introduction to D3', 'D3 Selections', 'Practice: D3 Selections', 'Changing Content', 'Practice: Changing Content', 'Adding and Removing Elements', 'Practice: Adding and Removing Elements', 'Changing Properties', 'Practice: Changing Properties', 'Setting up the environment'], ['Intro: Week 2', 'Loading Data', 'Practice: Loading Data', 'Filtering and Sorting', 'Practice: Filtering and Sorting', 'Transforming Data', 'Practice: Transforming Data', 'Computing Simple Statistics', 'Practice: Computing Simple Statistics', 'SVG', 'Practice: SVG', 'Binding Data', 'Practice: Binding Data', 'Numeric Scales', 'Practice: Numeric Scales', 'Ordinal Scales', 'Practice: Ordinal Scales', 'Adding Axes Annotations', 'Practice: Adding Annotations'], ['Intro: Week 3', 'Drawing Lines', 'Practice: Line Chart Part 1', 'Practice: Line Chart Part 2', 'Drawing Arcs', 'Practice: Pie and Donut Charts Part 1', 'Practice: Pie and Donut Charts Part 2', 'Projections', 'Drawing Maps', 'Practice: Drawing Base for Map', 'Choropleth Map', 'Practice: Choropleth Map', 'Adding Additional Marks', 'Practice: Adding Additional Marks'], ['Week 4: Intro', 'Visualizing Networks', 'Practice: Visualizing Networks Part 1', 'Practice: Visualizing Networks Part 2', 'Hierarchical Data', 'Practice: Tree Map Part 1', 'Practice: Tree Map Part 2', 'Listening to Events', 'Practice: Listening to Events', 'Updating Data', 'Practice: Updating Data', 'Brushing', 'Practice: Brushing', 'Zoom', 'Practice: Zoom', 'Practice: Creating Tooltips', 'Practice: Creating Linked Views', 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great course, even for those who want to audit! d3 can be a very overwhelming to get started with, however, Cristian does a great job breaking down many parts of the library. He then weaves them together again through practice and the assignments. I definitely feel more confident working with d3.', 'Very good intro for people with some mild programming experience.', 'Wonderful course! It gives you basic knowledge about D3.js. Highly recommend!  ', 'Great practice and ensuring explanation of details. ', 'Excellent course. Excellent content. Some corrections on the example codes are necessary. The instructor is very good.', "Wanted to learn d3.js and found this course, it's very nice !! Much more fun and clear than reading the documents :)", 'Very good course on the D3.js library. Examples and a project deployed throughout the course. Master your visualization of data thanks to this library. Thank you for this course', 'Very Informative ', 'very useful', "The best D3 course on the web right now. The course is about D3 V5. It's really necessary to have some programming skills. Also, the course uses Javascript ES6.", "Excellent course. While I didn't do any of the exams, I learned a ton about data visualization and I am able to directly apply this knowledge at my job. Also helped me a lot for a university project I am doing right now. It's much easier to absorb the information from the video lectures in this course than to read a bunch of random blog posts on the internet about the topic (speaking from experience here :-).", 'I enjoy the lectures. The professor has a good speaking and teaching style which keeps me interested. Lots of concrete math examples which make it easier to understand. Very good slides which are well formulated and easy to understand', 'Well-paced and informative. Fun assignments too. It was really well thought out course. ', 'A good introduction to D3.js and many of the associated ideas. Lecturing is clear and at a good pace and the examples were useful as well.', "Good course, I'm in love with the Airlines Routes Project. Maybe teorical content should be more related with the practice. D3.js is a very huge library, so I think could be a good idea to take the concepts necesary to develop the specific projects. For the rest, very nice course!!", 'Great course. Include more advanced examples of d3', 'One of the best hands-on course on D3.js :) ', 'Good course. Recommend to promote more understanding in the conceptual level/big picture of the D3.js API along with understanding the syntax.', 'Could have been tougher', "This course should have more hands on practice interspersed with the lectures.  Watching one lecture after another after another isn't a great way to learn.", "This course is the third one of the Information Visualization Specialization, where I've seen a brief explanation of d3.js and its core functionality. It's a lot to cover and I think a great effort is made by the instructor to make those concepts easy to understand to anyone with no prior experience in programming. ", "While I had no trouble with the instructor's accent, his pronunciation for many english words is bordering on ridiculous! It was bad enough, that it distracted me from following the lecture. Furthermore, there were some glaring typo's in the home work assignments. It looks like someone (probably the instructor) typed these up in a rush and  *nobody* else took a second look to ensure if things were correct."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Erin B', 'By David', 'By Saulet Y', 'By Averin I I', 'By Hugo B L', 'By Ian W', 'By vignaux', 'By Ebenezer K', 'By Dmitry B', 'By Mathieu L', 'By Joseph', 'By Jafed E', 'By Vishnu P P S', 'By Matt G', 'By Israel E H', 'By Muhammed J', 'By Haejin H', 'By Witchapong D', 'By Saransh G', 'By Craig A B', 'By Santiago S', 'By Adil L']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'May 12, 2019', 'May 27, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Sep 13, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'May 13, 2019', 'Sep 09, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Jun 11, 2019', 'Oct 29, 2018']</review_date></doc>