<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_76</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/leveraging-unstructured-data-dataproc-gcp</course_url><course_name>Leveraging Unstructured Data with Cloud Dataproc on Google Cloud Platform</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>This 1-week, accelerated course builds upon previous courses in the Data Engineering on Google Cloud Platform specialization. Through a combination of video lectures, demonstrations, and hands-on labs, you'll learn how to create and manage computing clusters to run Hadoop, Spark, Pig and/or Hive jobs on Google Cloud Platform.  You will also learn how to access various cloud storage options from their compute clusters and integrate Google’s machine learning capabilities into their analytics programs.  

In the hands-on labs, you will create and manage Dataproc Clusters using the Web Console and the CLI, and use cluster to run Spark and Pig jobs. You will then create iPython notebooks that integrate with BigQuery and storage and utilize Spark. Finally, you integrate the machine learning APIs into your data analysis.

Pre-requisites
• Google Cloud Platform Big Data &amp; Machine Learning Fundamentals (or equivalent experience)
• Some knowledge of Python</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Google Cloud Dataproc//Application Programming Interfaces (API)//Machine Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Introduction to Cloud Dataproc//Module 2: Running Dataproc jobs//Module 3: Leveraging GCP//Module 4: Analyzing Unstructured Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course', 'Introducing Cloud Dataproc', 'Defining unstructured data?', 'Deriving value from unstructured data', 'Approaches to working with Big Data', 'MapReduce and Hadoop origins', 'On prem Hadoop has a lot of overhead', 'Cloud Dataproc versus Hadoop alternatives', 'Creating a Dataproc cluster', 'Dataproc customization', 'Dataproc and the CLI', 'Lab 1: Overview', 'Lab 1: Demo and Review', 'Custom Machine Types', 'Preemptible VMs', 'Wrap up'], ['Overview of Running Dataproc Jobs', 'Methods for submitting jobs', 'Lab 2 Overview', 'Lab 2: Demo and Review', 'Separation of Storage and Compute', 'Evolution of data processing', 'The importance of networking in data processing', 'Separating storage and compute with Spark', 'Submitting Spark jobs', 'Overview of Spark concepts', 'Lab Overview', 'Lab 3: Demo and Review', 'Module Wrap Up'], ['Introduction to Leveraging GCP', 'BigQuery Support', 'Lab 4: Overview', 'Lab 4: Demo and Review', 'Cluster customization', 'Installing software on a Dataproc', 'Lab 5: Overview', 'Lab 5: Demo and Review', 'Wrap up', 'Review'], ['Continuing discussion of Machine Learning', 'A closer look at Machine Learning', 'Examples of applied ML', 'Natural Language Processing close-up', 'Lab 6: Overview', 'Lab 6: Demo and Review', 'Wrap up']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I think the quizzes should have had more questions, there were many more cool things you could have asked. ', 'This course is far longer than any of the other courses in the Data Engineering specialisation. I felt that it rehashed a lot of the first course as well. ', 'Wish it went in more depth about RDD transformation, which was a little bit confusing... A lab about how DataProc  can be used as an extention of BigQuery that does not overlap functionality would be nice. How to covert RDDs to Pandas DF, and vice versa.', 'Assumes the learner has an intermediate level understanding of concepts like Hadoop, Spark, HDFS, and python. Extremely hard to understand the concepts without background in the above mentioned items.', 'Videos are overlapping, some videos are not loud enough, descriptions are not fitting to the current version of the console, nearly all the same than in the fundamentals course...', 'This course is so bad that I do not want see again. I really think this course is an advertising  of google cloud , and which only teach a little useful things.  If my commit makes someone unhappy, but also hope forgive me. Thanks!', 'Course lectures are mostly fragments of another course, cut in small pieces - many of them are less than 30 seconds long! Content wise, almost everything were discussed in the previous course (Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals). ', 'Good course .Very interesting!!', 'Excellent course for Beginners with more lab experience.', 'boom!', 'I would like to have more extensive labs for Data Proc. Selection of pyspark for most of the course was quiet useful. A little bit more of dataproc use cases comparison of dataproc modules including spark, hive and then relevant proprietary options available in Google.', 'Really great everything i have learnt a lot.', 'The labs are extremely well put together. A good pace for an overview.', 'It was very good experience in learning the powers of dataproc. Gcp has made it so easy to setup that it is easy to use hdfs,hive,spark. Thanks', 'Motivating and clear instructions! Dataproc usage very well explained.', 'It follows in more detail the topics covered in the first section and it teaches different ways of working with clusters, found it very useful', 'Good', 'I learned a lot of their platform for ML. I want to begin the next course.', 'Well structured and informative course', 'nice nice nice ', 'Very interesting course.', 'easy to understand and simple to do the labs', 'Best course to learn the basics of Cloud Dataproc, Bigquery, Machine Learning and get hands-on how to install a software on cluster using CLI and how to execute the ML jobs.', 'Great']</reviews><reviewers>['By Joe S', 'By Justin E', 'By haiyang l', 'By Shivam S', 'By Marc N', 'By 苏高生', 'By Alexey M', 'By Peter S', 'By Muthu M H', 'By Raphael D', 'By Rai S', 'By Wesley S', 'By Douglas A', 'By Sarthak K S', 'By Muhammad U S', 'By Daniel E V G', 'By Mathyam G', 'By Roberto A F', 'By Ganeshkumar S', 'By Even', 'By Javier R', 'By Leandro d S', 'By  V B', 'By Witoon.p']</reviewers><review_date>['May 12, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'May 31, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2017', 'Aug 11, 2017', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019']</review_date></doc>