<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_26</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/basic-statistics</course_url><course_name>Basic Statistics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Matthijs Rooduijn</course_instructor><course_introduction>Understanding statistics is essential to understand research in the social and behavioral sciences. In this course you will learn the basics of statistics; not just how to calculate them, but also how to evaluate them. This course will also prepare you for the next course in the specialization - the course Inferential Statistics. 

In the first part of the course we will discuss methods of descriptive statistics. You will learn what cases and variables are and how you can compute measures of central tendency (mean, median and mode) and dispersion (standard deviation and variance). Next, we discuss how to assess relationships between variables, and we introduce the concepts correlation and regression. 

The second part of the course is concerned with the basics of probability: calculating probabilities, probability distributions and sampling distributions. You need to know about these things in order to understand how inferential statistics work. 

The third part of the course consists of an introduction to methods of inferential statistics - methods that help us decide whether the patterns we see in our data are strong enough to draw conclusions about the underlying population we are interested in. We will discuss confidence intervals and significance tests.

You will not only learn about all these statistical concepts, you will also be trained to calculate and generate these statistics yourself using freely available statistical software.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Confidence Interval//Statistical Hypothesis Testing//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Amsterdam</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Before we get started...//Exploring Data//Correlation and Regression//Probability//Probability Distributions//Sampling Distributions//Confidence Intervals//Significance Tests//Exam time!</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Basic Statistics!'], ['1.01 Cases, variables and levels of measurement', '1.02 Data matrix and frequency table', '1.03 Graphs and shapes of distributions', '1.04 Mode, median and mean', '1.05 Range, interquartile range and box plot', '1.06 Variance and standard deviation', '1.07 Z-scores', '1.08 Example'], ['2.01 Crosstabs and scatterplots', "2.02 Pearson's r", '2.03 Regression - Finding the line', '2.04 Regression - Describing the line', '2.05 Regression - How good is the line?', '2.06 Correlation is not causation', '2.07 Example contingency table', "2.08 Example Pearson's r and regression"], ['3.01 Randomness', '3.02 Probability', '3.03 Sample space, event, probability of event and tree diagram', '3.04 Quantifying probabilities with tree diagram', '3.05 Basic set-theoretic concepts', '3.06 Practice with sets', '3.07 Union', '3.08 Joint and marginal probabilities', '3.09 Conditional probability', '3.10 Independence between random events', "3.11 More conditional probability, decision trees and Bayes' Law"], ['4.01 Random variables and probability distributions', '4.02 Cumulative probability distributions', '4.03 The mean of a random variable', '4.04 Variance of a random variable', '4.05 Functional form of the normal distribution', '4.06 The normal distribution: probability calculations', '4.07 The standard normal distribution', '4.08 The binomial distribution'], ['5.01 Sample and population', '5.02 Sampling', '5.03 The sampling distribution', '5.04 The central limit theorem', '5.05 Three distributions', '5.06 Sampling distribution proportion', '5.07 Example'], ['6.01 Statistical inference', '6.02 CI for mean with known population sd', '6.03 CI for mean with unknown population sd', '6.04 CI for proportion', '6.05 Confidence levels', '6.06 Choosing the sample size', '6.07 Example'], ['7.01 Hypotheses', '7.02 Test about proportion', '7.03 Test about mean', '7.04 Step-by-step plan', '7.05 Significance test and confidence interval', '7.06 Type I and Type II errors', '7.07 Example'], ['Final Exam']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 36 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['One of the best courses of statistics for the beginners. The concepts are well explained, the learning path well researched and above everything the R labs were ideal for the beginners.', "This course is very good. Make sure you know very basic principals of R-programming, or just programming in general. It doesn't have to be much, but a little knowledge will spare a lot of frustration.", 'Week 3 really puts me off', 'great introduction to statistics with no prior knowledge required. Although in parts has been challenging, for me is the right degree of difficulty to push an individual to learning.', "The course is good so far...However be warned that you need to know the basics of a computing language called R. If you don't know this it would set you back by a many days. Then the option is given to reset deadlines and they charge regardless.", 'The instructor spend most of the time explaining the easy part like calculate the numbers but ignore the difficult part like explaining the concept and derive the equations. Although the whole team spend a lot of time preparing the course and try to make the course vivid, as a student with minimal statistic knowledge it is still really important for me to understand each concept and equations instead of just reciting them. For every equations that appeared in this course I was asking why, but there is no explanation of why this equation is like this and how you derive, there are just follow up examples to put the number in the equation and calculate them.', 'This class is fast paced.  Weeks 1 and 2 are the equivalent of Stats 101 at a university.  Some of the videos cover the topics too fast and would benefit from some additional examples.  To truly learn the topics, I visit other sites that cover the topics in more detail, presented in a different manner, and provide more examples.', 'The instructional videos are clear, nicely illustrated, and contain good examples that make you get an intuitive grasp of the course material. Exams are good and the feedback provided references the lecture in question, so that you can re-watch it, very nice. ', "Only the firs week of this course, but I can already tell that it's going to be incredibly useful to me. I've learned a lot and especially love the introduction to R through datacamp! ", 'It is a great course, I learned a lot but some recommendations.', 'This is great! Every single concept is explained in avery easy and intuitive way! I loved it!', 'Very well explained and timed in a good flow. All important infos are there. The handouts are correct, and the videos correspond with audio/handouts. It is very nice that the quizz has hints for those answers that were wrong. ', '非常完美~~~ 我爱了！！！敲稀饭这个组合 可萌可攻可 ... 这个basic statistics的课程 很稀饭很稀饭很稀饭', 'Excellent for understanding the basic concepts and designed for those who have no clue what R is..', 'This is an incredible curse. It has a lot of information, but they manage to deliver it in a dynamic, fun, and quite intuitive way, so it is really easy to develop an inner logic for all of the statistical concepts. Thank you very much.', 'This course was great to get an introduction of basic statistics and inferential statistics. The R exercises are great to test what you learned with practical exercises (in a real-life scenario where you have access to a tool like R). I cannot give 5 stars, because the chapters on probability are confusing and poorly explained: probabilities are one of the most difficult parts of statistics, so they require more pedagogy (with clear formulas to calculate conditional probabilities and step by step explanations)', 'Some statistical things require explanation which was missing.', 'The lecturer does not clearly explain the topics very well especially on the topics in Probability and Distribution. His presentation in English is honestly quite hard to understand.', "---------- way too much time is devoted to introducing definitions and way too little time is given for student practicing and review .   the presenter's accent is constantly impeding instant recognition of what he's saying.   the subtitles sometimes don't accurately represent what he's saying.   sometimes there are misspellings - which makes it even harder to know what he's saying.   this student was inundated with formulas that needed to be practiced - and i didn't even have time to  write them down !", 'I do  not understand why the instructors cannot use simple, daily-life examples. Why should the invented islands, rocket be involved in their examples? For a person who has no idea about planes, we should try hard to understand something unnecessary ! Please do not just stay in the ivory tower! Think about real life. ', 'Great!', 'nice course', 'Excellent explanations by both professors and very interesting illustrations and examples! Thank you to the team.', 'Interesting enough, I first thought that I had grasped all concepts. But... I had to come back to review the material.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Deleted A', 'By Mark v d S', 'By Yuqin L', 'By Alessandro F', 'By Adya K', 'By Summer', 'By Mike P', 'By Syberen v M', 'By Emilly M', 'By Luis O C', 'By Pau V A', 'By Ute T', 'By Du F', 'By Mohammed R A', 'By Francisco M A C', 'By Stefano C', 'By mridul b', 'By Daniel S', 'By Big W', 'By chengxiaoxue', 'By Laura D', 'By jyotibabu', 'By Elita R', 'By Paulo A d A']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 06, 2016', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Nov 20, 2017', 'Jan 26, 2017', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2016', 'May 12, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2018', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Apr 22, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2016', 'Jan 08, 2016', 'Oct 13, 2017', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018']</review_date></doc>