<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_25</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-for-data-visualization</course_url><course_name>Data Visualization with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Aklson</course_instructor><course_introduction>"A picture is worth a thousand words". We are all familiar with this expression. It especially applies when trying to explain the insight obtained from the analysis of increasingly large datasets. Data visualization plays an essential role in the representation of both small and large-scale data.

One of the key skills of a data scientist is the ability to tell a compelling story, visualizing data and findings in an approachable and stimulating way. Learning how to leverage a software tool to visualize data will also enable you to extract information, better understand the data, and make more effective decisions.

The main goal of this Data Visualization with Python course is to teach you how to take data that at first glance has little meaning and present that data in a form that makes sense to people. Various techniques have been developed for presenting data visually but in this course, we will be using several data visualization libraries in Python, namely Matplotlib, Seaborn, and Folium.

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Matplotlib</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Data Visualization Tools//Basic and Specialized Visualization Tools//Advanced Visualizations and Geospatial Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Introduction to Data Visualization', 'Introduction to Matplotlib', 'Basic Plotting with Matplotlib', 'Dataset on Immigration to Canada', 'Line Plots'], ['Area Plots', 'Histograms', 'Bar Charts', 'Pie Charts', 'Box Plots', 'Scatter Plots'], ['Waffle Charts', 'Word Clouds', 'Seaborn and Regression Plots', 'Introduction to Folium', 'Maps with Markers', 'Choropleth Maps']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['It was a good course that follows steps clearly and effectively. However, I cannot rate it higher that 2 stars for a very important reasons: Big Parts of the Final peer-reviewed assignment are not even covered in the course!!! I had to scour the internet and find my own solutions (and many others clearly had the same problem as seen in the discussions section). This is a big problem and needs to be addressed as we should be tested on the material actually learnt!', 'Final exam was frustrating.  It took longer to complete than the rest of the course combined.  Questions were included that were not part of the course including the need to reset keys.  Peer review was almost impossible since I could not read the tiny screen shots very well.', "Data could in most cases not be loaded, making the labs useless. Also, the videos have unnecessarily much redundancy. Really didn't learn much from this course. ", 'The final assessment was not covered in class, and it was very difficult to figure out how to do.', 'I did not like that some assignments do no rely on the material that was given in the course. For example, data visualisation with Artist layer was not covered in details in the course and you have to spend tons of time on Internet digging out how to implement that. This is a waste of time, I need a course that gives me complete and structured info, not a course that sends me out to explore the Internet.', "The course is very inconsistent, it repeats the same one minute in all of the videos, when reviewing the dataframe. Many times some things are asked without providing previous explanation, and the final assignment is also an example, I had to search all over internet to resolve it, because I couldn't find any reference in the content provided.", 'worst instructor I have ever seen,', 'It is a strange course and the worst in this specialisation so far. In one week 50% of the video is how the data is prepared. That would be ok if it won´t be the same video snippet 4 times. Also the relation of video vs. reading is 1 to 6. In one week is only 6 minuites of Video and about 1 h of ungraded assignment. ', "A lot of functions and lines of code weren't explained they were just left to be figured out by the learner. While some lines of code could be understood without much explanation, others were too complex for people new to programming (which most people taking this course are). ", 'The course labs had broken links which caused issues with several of the students. The quizzes also had several question choices where two of the answer choices were the exact same, leaving the student to guess.  Not to be so critical, although the datacamp classes are much more effective when it comes to learning.', "I would give zero if the system has. An empty course that you almost cannot learn anything especially when you're going to practice. ", "This course was really well designed. I've taken the preceding courses and I really connected with the format of this course.  I liked how the labs really explored different options and played around with the code in a variety of ways to show a more complete picture of what the code instances can do.  I especially liked how sometimes the labs would purposely use incorrect code which users might enter, and then explain why that code didn't apply or work for given scenarios.  ", 'The course material is not sufficient for completing the final graded assignment. It required many hours of internet research to collect the details necessary for the final graded assignment. ', 'The course materials are poorly structured. Labs are not well-designed and not friendly to students with little experience. This is not a very effective course.', 'No mid-lecture quizzes', "I appreciate that the videos were done in a human's voice and not a robot. It helps me focus to hear the natural pace and emphasis on certain points. Also, the labs were very clear (thank you). There was clear guidance/notes through steps which is very helpful because this is a new thing for me.  The final was also fair and comprehensive. I have a long way to go but this class was very well done. ", 'This course is really good. The instructor did a great job introducing common graphs, charts and map techniques. What they look like. How, where and when to use them. ', 'this course should come before data analysis with python', "This course was nice but there were extra stressors that weren't included in the course. ", 'Need more detailed explaination of artist layer. Very confusing. Questions on topics which are not covered in syllabus.', "A lot of the work in the final project was not in the course (in either the content or the lab work). There were plenty of topics covered that could have formed a challenging final project without asking us to do things that we weren't equipped to do by the course. Fortunately, I was able to find what I needed but after putting all of that work into the course and labs, I shouldn't have had to spend as many hours on the final project as I did. If those are things I needed to know, then the content was inadequate. If I didn't need to know those things, the project was poorly created.", "ZERO support from our teachers, assignments that have little to do with what they teach us (Videos don't even have any information explaining core concepts) Most of the learning was done by Google. Quite annoying to be honest.", "I have accumulated enormous skills that I thought wasn't possible for a beginner in Data Science", 'Excellent course, especially the labs were very useful and served as a recap of what was learnt in the previous courses of this certification course. Very clear explanation.', 'It was an amazing course very well sorted out to teach top notch visualization techniques that are in demand in the market.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Karim C N', 'By Karel H', 'By Dan S N', 'By Tom M', 'By Iakov L', 'By Ismael S', 'By Jianzhi W', 'By Nils W', 'By Sisir K', 'By Andrew C', 'By Baidi W', 'By Stephen P', 'By Roger S', 'By Yuanyuan J', 'By Nick', 'By Sarra A', 'By Toan T L', 'By umair', 'By Sarah s', 'By pawar p', 'By Joshua W', 'By Guillermo M M', 'By BRIGHT K', 'By Rama S C', 'By Muzaffar H']</reviewers><review_date>['May 29, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2019', 'Apr 23, 2019', 'Jun 05, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Apr 24, 2019', 'Apr 20, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jun 07, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Oct 21, 2018', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jul 10, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'Aug 18, 2018', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019']</review_date></doc>