<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_125</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/computer-vision-basics</course_url><course_name>Computer Vision Basics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Radhakrishna Dasari</course_instructor><course_introduction>By the end of this course, learners will understand what computer vision is, as well as its mission of making computers see and interpret the world as humans do, by learning core concepts of the field and receiving an introduction to human vision capabilities. They are equipped to identify some key application areas of computer vision and understand the digital imaging process. The course covers crucial elements that enable computer vision: digital signal processing, neuroscience and artificial intelligence. Topics include color, light and image formation; early, mid- and high-level vision; and mathematics essential for computer vision. Learners will be able to apply mathematical techniques to complete computer vision tasks. 

This course is ideal for anyone curious about or interested in exploring the concepts of computer vision. It is also useful for those who desire a refresher course in mathematical concepts of computer vision. Learners should have basic programming skills and experience (understanding of for loops, if/else statements), specifically in MATLAB (Mathworks provides the basics here: https://www.mathworks.com/learn/tutorials/matlab-onramp.html). Learners should also be familiar with the following: basic linear algebra (matrix vector operations and notation), 3D co-ordinate systems and transformations, basic calculus (derivatives and integration) and basic probability (random variables).  

Material includes online lectures, videos, demos, hands-on exercises, project work, readings and discussions. Learners gain experience writing computer vision programs through online labs using MATLAB* and supporting toolboxes.

This is the first course in the Computer Vision specialization that lays the groundwork necessary for designing sophisticated vision applications. To learn more about the specialization, check out a video overview at https://youtu.be/OfxVUSCPXd0.

 * A free license to install MATLAB for the duration of the course is available from MathWorks.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Algorithms</course_category><course_tag>Computer Vision//Computer Programming//Matlab</course_tag><course_rating>3.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Computer Vision Overview//Color, Light, &amp; Image Formation//Low-, Mid- &amp; High-Level Vision//Mathematics for Computer Vision</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Computer Vision', 'Meet Jeff Bier', 'Meet Jungsong Yuan, Ph.D.', 'What is Computer Vision?', 'Why Computer Vision?', 'Related Fields of Computer Vision', 'Relevant Fields', 'Computer Programming &amp; Computer Vision', 'Computer Vision Awareness', 'Timelines &amp; Milestones', 'Computer Vision Progression', 'Computer Vision Applications', 'CV Applications', 'CV Impact in the Field of Augmented Reality'], ['Light Sources', 'Pinhole Camera Model', 'Digital Camera', 'Color Theory'], ['Three-Level Paradigm', 'Low-, Mid-, High-Level Vision', 'Low-Level Vision', 'Mid-Level Vision', 'High-Level Vision'], ['Mathematic Skills', 'Mathematical Preliminaries', 'Linear Algebra', 'Calculus', 'Probability Theory', 'Algorithms', 'Using Algorithms', 'Aligning RGB channels']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I'll start with the positive. There were some lectures (Pinhole Camera Model) which were effective. However, this course was extremely superficial.", "This course should have a zero star.  TA's are not answering the questions on the forum discussion.  Both lectures and assignments are very poor in quality.  It's a BIG SHAME that the University of Buffalo has such a crappy material and expects people to pay for it.  It's a waste of time!!! The professors and the school should be really embarrassed to put such poor quality material and charge people for it!", "The course was full of theoretical concepts. No practical concepts were taught by the instructors. If they didn't taught any practical concepts then why they are asking in assignments. They didn't even tell ABCD about Matlab and aspect us to solve assignments in Matlab. This is ridiculous. They should have given at least some examples  to solve the assignments. I am highly disappointed with the assignment part. Rest theoretical part was good and  to the point but could be more detailed.  ", "There isn't enough in the free version of the course to push me to make a purchase. If Matlab guidance is lacking on some examples I have no faith it would be any better once I unlock the assignments. I may be biased after taking the Machine Learning course but the contrast between the two is stark. This course feels like someone is talking at you for a couple of hours rather than guiding you through material.", 'Great Course', 'This course is a good course to start computer vision for beginner level student, and I offer This course to everyone who is eager to learn computer vision conceptually.', 'The course content is good.There are too many examples and applications.I use python but using MATLAB for the computer vision is new experience for me.', 'The instructor gives pretty good in explaining things however the matlab assignment is frustrating after several attempts failure. More guidance probably should be given for the matlab assignment or it get really frustrating after 6 hrs stuck at the same position struggling to guess the real answer. You should at least familiar with matlab operation for getting started in this one. "intermediate level" is pretty accurate. I am a undergrad year-2  EE student at a Top 10 UK uni and this still remains a bit challenging. The overall level is OK but sometimes stuck at a same place for hours really make me wants to give up for some time. ', 'It is a good introduction course but I think some more demo coding for matlab in the first assignments will be a good thing so we don´t have to spend a lot of time on google and on trial and error.', 'Videos are not complete,lack examples and proper explanation.', 'I personally do not feel the course is up to the mark.', "One of the worst courses on Coursera. Very superficial. What is the point of this? For example you mentioned Least Squares. In a 1 minute video. Great, what is it? How do I apply it? Nothing, instead in the optional material you send me to a pdf from a University of Puget Sound (what?!) that mentions I was supposed to learn in the class. Huh? And this happens with every concept, some names and terms are being thrown, even the quizes that are being asked right after don't always correlate with it, and in most cases you have to use your intuition, as what is being asked was not explained. The whole course can be finished in 2 evenings (which I did) and I learned absolutely nothing except very basic usage of Matlab. ", 'G', 'very usefull', 'organised lectures.', 'Course was very well designed, it is the best course for beginners. ', 'A good theoratical introduction to the subject. I am looking now for something more practical.', 'I would like it to be more dense on content. It gives overview of many areas without diving into details. The labs feel somewhat disjointed from the rest of the course.', 'I was hoping there would be more material on the Mathematics of Computer Vision. Overall, as stated, it is a good introduction to the basics. ', 'The course material is at the basic level, and it is good for a beginner like me. I find the programming assignments quite challenging and will need a lot of extra effort outside the course material to be able to ace the assignments. Matlab documentation helps a lot too.', 'I would like to thank my course instructor. It is a short introductory course.', 'basic', 'staff not responsive on forums', "it's only an introduction to the topic. probably you the real studies begin in the second course.", 'Overall great, howeve the last assignment needed more help/background from the instructors than provided. I pass 96% of the class but still was not  able to get the certificate. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Dhritiman S', 'By An M C', 'By Ashish k', 'By Evan R', 'By Kevin C', 'By Ali K M', 'By Aayush A', 'By Mao S', 'By Lida M', 'By Pranay M', 'By Harsahib S', 'By Dmitry F', 'By Arjun S', 'By Betsy G', 'By Fahim A', 'By shubham m v', 'By Brice L', 'By Andriy P', 'By Zeyad Z', 'By Mun T Y', 'By Kush S', 'By nefelibata', 'By Hussni B M Z', 'By sharon h', 'By aryan']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 26, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Jul 11, 2019', 'Jun 17, 2019', 'May 02, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'May 06, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2019', 'Jul 04, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jul 23, 2019', 'Jul 02, 2019', 'Jun 12, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'May 09, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'Jun 17, 2019', 'Jul 13, 2019', 'May 28, 2019', 'Jun 13, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019']</review_date></doc>