<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_92</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/serverless-machine-learning-gcp</course_url><course_name>Serverless Machine Learning with Tensorflow on Google Cloud Platform</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>This one-week accelerated on-demand course provides participants a a hands-on introduction to designing and building machine learning models on Google Cloud Platform. Through a combination of presentations, demos, and hand-on labs, participants will learn machine learning (ML) and TensorFlow concepts, and develop hands-on skills in developing, evaluating, and productionizing ML models.

OBJECTIVES

This course teaches participants the following skills:

  ● Identify use cases for machine learning

  ● Build an ML model using TensorFlow

  ● Build scalable, deployable ML models using Cloud ML

  ● Know the importance of preprocessing and combining features

  ● Incorporate advanced ML concepts into their models

  ● Productionize trained ML models


PREREQUISITES

To get the most of out of this course, participants should have:

  ● Completed Google Cloud Fundamentals- Big Data and Machine Learning course OR have equivalent experience

  ● Basic proficiency with common query language such as SQL

  ● Experience with data modeling, extract, transform, load activities

  ● Developing applications using a common programming language such Python

  ● Familiarity with Machine Learning and/or statistics

Google Account Notes:
• Google services are currently unavailable in China.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Machine Learning//Google Cloud Platform//Feature Engineering//Tensorflow//Cloud Computing</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Serverless Machine Learning on Google Cloud Platform//Module 1: Getting Started with Machine Learning//Module 2: Building ML models with Tensorflow//Module 3: Scaling ML models with Cloud ML Engine//Module 4: Feature Engineering</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course', 'How to Think About Machine Learning'], ['What is Machine Learning (ML)?', 'Types of ML', 'The ML Pipeline', 'Variants of ML model', 'Framing a ML problem', 'Playing with Machine Learning (ML)', 'Optimization', 'A Neural Network Playground', 'Combining Features', 'Feature Engineering', 'Image Models', 'Effective ML', 'What makes a good dataset ?', 'Error Metrics', 'Accuracy', 'Precision and Recall', 'Creating Machine Learning Datasets', 'Splitting Dataset', 'Python Notebooks', 'Create ML Datasets Lab Overview', 'Create ML Datasets Lab Review'], ['Module 2 Overview', 'What is TensorFlow ?', 'Core TensorFlow', 'Getting Started with TensorFlow Lab Overview', 'TensorFlow Lab Review', 'Estimator API', 'Machine Learning with tf.estimator', 'Estimator Lab Review', 'Building Effective ML', 'Lab Intro: Refactoring to add batching and feature creation', 'Refactoring Lab Review', 'Train and Evaluate', 'Monitoring', 'Lab Intro: Distributed Training and Monitoring', 'Lab Review: Distributed Training and Monitoring'], ['Module 3 Overview', 'Why Cloud ML Engine?', 'Development Workflow', 'Packaging trainer', 'TensorFlow Serving', 'Lab: Scaling up ML', 'Lab Review: Scaling up ML'], ['Module 4 Overview', 'Good Features', 'Causality', 'Numeric', 'Enough Examples', 'Raw Data to Features', 'Categorical Features', 'Feature Crosses', 'Bucketizing', 'Wide and Deep', 'Where to do Feature Engineering', 'Feature Engineering Lab Overview', 'Feature Engineering Lab Review', 'Hyperparameter Tuning + Demo', 'ML Abstraction Levels', 'Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['It was rather confusing than helpful. A great overhead of doing the same configuration stuff for the first 4 labs: They could be combined to one greater Lab. The last 7th Lab was too complicated, I lost connection to the notebook all the time and had not enough time for understanding where and how I should run the predefined commands. I rather submitted the commands without thinking how, where and why, because I did not have time to think: The lab is too big for the short period of time. I would appreciate to have more time for understanding the commands (for example for ml engine and dataflow). ', "I was a bit disappointed at this course. It is after all data engineering track course but it seems like it's data science for those with ample data engineering skills. The course focuses more on basic ML concepts and less on the Google Cloud Platform specific boilerplate code. The things that are specific to Google Cloud are just viewed cursorily and I didn't really get much insight to them. Other issues with the course are that it's basically one big deprecation warning. Apache Beam cannot be run on Python 3 but Python 2 is about to deprecate. Furthermore, ML Engine is renamed to AI Platform but the course material hasn't applied that change yet. Instead it speaks about ML Engine. Additionally, distributed training isn't covered very well but it's marketed that Google Cloud does distributed training on its own. So basically after this course I learned that the services used in this course are probably not used by Google because everything is deprecated and about to become obsolete and the services are  quite cumbersome to use.", 'I wasted to much time every lab setting up the environment with not enough time to go through and actually understand complicated code.', 'To be honest this whole specialization is a scam. There is promise of preparing to Data Engineer Cert, but the course just skims most of the topics, missing a lot others entirely. Please, at least have decency not to advertise it like this and remove it from official google certification page.', 'lab 7 is rubish', "Lax is horrible. He's going around and around and around and around and around... and repeats and repeats and repeats.. mostly useless stuff. The course is Boooring... Not much about the GCP. Mostly 'intro to machine learning'", "I appreciate the difficult problem solved during this course.  The student uses many of the tools available but also gains insights on  machine learning concepts in the process by working through a comlete  solution.  Lak is a great teacher and while it's not my first exposure to mahcine learning, this course helped me solidify concepts I've learned in others.  ", 'Very useful!', 'a powerful tool in a practical and simple way to empower data engineers with this tool possibilities', 'Very good class. Definitely the hardest of the 5 for me because I had no experience with ML before this course. I will probably go through this class again to gain deeper insights.', 'Excellent course. A very good introduction to Tensorflow. Teaches basic ML as well as more advanced topics. I liked the Cloud ML engine and feature engineering parts. Must be valuable in real world applications', 'ok', 'good', 'Thanks Google, you are doing great work and producing great quality contents', 'Quite knowledgeable. It touches all the aspects of Model building along with the Google Cloud implementation . Learned a lot out of it. Thanks a lot to Lak and team for the course', "Lot of information are contained in this short course. It's a perfect approach to ML even if it's a bit confusing if you don't have previous experience. Great course learned lot of things.", 'Good course on Serverless Machine Learning with Tensorflow on Google Cloud Platform', 'Very good course, plan to take the 10 day course.', 'only Lab7 has troubled me due to incorrect code for the installation. It should be:pip install --upgrade pip', 'This is a great introductory course to Tensorflow.  I prefer if you can explain some of the concepts using animation but that may be just my preference. However, I would love if you can think about it every time you explain a more complex concepts.', 'g', 'Very good introduction to the concepts of ML in GCP', 'Hard content to learn but Labs really helped out.', 'Good Course', "Detailed and incredibly useful for DE's"]</reviews><reviewers>['By Anna K', 'By Joose R', 'By Joel G', 'By Michał J', 'By YANGYIRU', 'By Alexandre V G', 'By Chris R', 'By Mikhail M', 'By Claudio I', 'By James W', 'By Mananai S', 'By Shashank R', 'By RAGHAVENDER S', 'By ELINGUI P U', 'By Atanu G', 'By Daniele S', 'By William M', 'By Keith A', 'By Arvind K', 'By Mussie N', 'By Chandrasekar B', 'By Mark G', 'By Vicente G d S', 'By JERRIN R', 'By Scott M']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 19, 2019', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'May 02, 2019', 'Sep 14, 2018', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Dec 14, 2018']</review_date></doc>