<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_43</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/applied-data-science-capstone</course_url><course_name>Applied Data Science Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Aklson</course_instructor><course_introduction>This capstone project course will give you a taste of what data scientists go through in real life when working with data. 

You will learn about location data and different location data providers, such as Foursquare. You will learn how to make RESTful API calls to the Foursquare API to retrieve data about venues in different neighborhoods around the world. You will also learn how to be creative in situations where data are not readily available by scraping web data and parsing HTML code. You will utilize Python and its pandas library to manipulate data, which will help you refine your skills for exploring and analyzing data. 

Finally, you will be required to use the Folium library to great maps of geospatial data and to communicate your results and findings.

If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you will also earn an IBM digital badge upon successful completion of the course.  

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Foursquare API//Neighborhood Segmentation and Clustering//The Battle of Neighborhoods//The Battle of Neighborhoods (Cont'd)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Location Data Providers'], ['Introduction to Foursquare', 'Signing up for a Foursquare Developer Account', 'Foursquare - Search', 'Foursquare - Explore and Other Queries', 'Foursquare - Summary'], ['Introduction to Clustering', 'k-means Clustering'], ['$null$'], ['IBM Digital Badge']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Instead of only peers review, I think it would be better if someone professional also review our capstone project and gives us feedback', 'Had to provide a credit card for FourSquare which I did not appreciate', 'I was not too happy with the way peer grade assignment was done and it is being used as a mechanism to grade the course.  My submissions were not reviewed correctly and because of that I felt that the course duration prolonged for one more month,  and I had to pay my subscription for one more month for no reason.', 'Utilizes skills learned throughout previous courses and puts it all together in Capstone assignment.  Found the instructions to be lacking but it is a Capstone so not totally unexpected.  I did find some of the instructors comments in the forum to be somewhat unprofessional so maybe some coaching should be done on how to respond to students who pay to take the course; even those that frustrate you! ', 'The only problem is that I ran out of hours using IBM watson and the same thing happened with Foursquare when I reached the maximum numerber of records per day and per hour.', "I liked working on a project from beginning to end - finding a problem to solve, acquiring data, creating &amp; testing hypotheses. It really puts what you've learned to test. I also learned some techniques that were not covered in the course and other skills like creating Medium posts.", 'Quizzes are poorly designed. Evaluates only memorized information.', 'This course certainly made me put in the work!! The project requires alot of planning to figure out exactly what you want to focus your analysis on. It definitely forced me to do alot of self-learning in order to complete it. StackOverflow became my best friend when I would get stuck and not know the proper python syntax to execute my desired outcome. Having to create a report and blogpost to document my analysis were definitely two new skill sets I appreciated that this course helped me to learn. ', 'Must take to complete this wonderful specialization. ', 'Very easy to understand and remember this material', ' A must take capstone project. Enroll for it and you will be moved by the project... Very interesting !', 'This is really challenging course, especially that you get hint on how to use a RESTful API (of Foursquare), how to create heat maps, or create different marking on a map using folium. The Capstone was really challenging, because you can practice what you have learned during the courses of the specialization, like how to start from the scratch a project, how to apply the data science methodology, like business understanding, gathering, analyzing, and cleaning data (most of your time you will spend on this), applying the right machine learning algorithm to solve the problem (modeling), using Jupyter Notebook on IBM cloud and using github. In the end you should also prepare your final report including the business understanding, describing your data, presenting your result, and placing a discussion section in the end. It took me 4 full days to complete the capstone, but I learned a lot. ', 'Very Good. This is my first contact with data science with python and associated packages. ', 'Felt a bit constrained by the requirement to include the Foursquare API.', 'The real advantage of completing this course goes far beyond learning the skills that data scientists use every day. The capstone project requires learners to integrate skills, along with domain knowledge of meaningful use cases.Then, with a significant goal in mind, plan the project and execute successfully for peer-review. I think this course comes very close to replicating the actual work products that data scientists do in the real world to a high degree. Of course, dealing with other individuals and project teams are not possible in this format. Having said all this, the real advantage of achieving the certificate is validating to oneself that the basic data science skill set has been mastered.', 'If I have to say one thing about Coursera or IBM Data Science Professional Certificate course, I would say  it as a Fantastic thing happened in my life, I am so happy with it, and I am not going to leave Coursera for ever. ', 'Think this one should have been marked by the course moderators and not fellow students. ', "I wrote this review after I finished all four courses of Applied Data Science Specialization. Overall speaking, the specialization is good and fairly easy (especially the first two courses). In terms of the Capstone Course, it looks intimidating but it won't be a big problem if you follow the materials closely. The final project is a great opportunity to be creative and to utilize all kinds of sources (and get to know the city you are interested in better). Nevertheless, I think the specialization should include more coding exercises/assignments instead of simple quizzes at the beginning. More hands-on exercises should be added to the introductory courses. Personally speaking, I'd like to get trained more on data cleaning and writing loops/functions.", 'Did not like Foursquare and was obliged to use it to complete the course', 'Some things were outdated and did not work properly for me.', 'There should be a clear tutorial on how to scrap a website. The project should be more open and not tight to using Foursquare, and should not be reviewed by other students.', 'This course did not provide enough learning materials for students to complete the project. For example, it asks students to scrape a web page and parse the table on the website and put it into a pandas data frame in a Jupiter notebook.', "This was challenging and a project is always the only way to really learn anything and struggle through. I did however feel that the forum for this course was not useful and that the mentors/lecturer's let us down. They hardly reply to relevant questions leaving students to feel abandoned. With a project you need some support as many students are not 100% comfortable with the code. One of the other courses has the forum broken up into two separate forums: One for the tech questions and another for requests from students to review - this was clever and worked well. Im giving this 2 stars based on the support and lack of direction for the project. May have also been nice to get options for a dataset - not easy to find a dataset in the public domain (spend hours looking for good ones)", 'Thank you!!!', 'This is a very useful capstone project in which you can apply all the learning you have done throughout the course, the more practice you do the more you learn. I like this course from coursera and recommend it for data science aspirants. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Johan C', 'By Alexander D H', 'By Rajayogasri P S', 'By Debra C', 'By Ariel E', 'By Stanislav R', 'By Ali C', 'By Nchedolisa S A', 'By Toan T L', 'By Nikolay D', 'By Jamiil T A', 'By Ferenc F P', 'By LEOPOLDO S', 'By Ian C', 'By Clarence E Y ', 'By Sai T S', 'By Samir S', 'By Chutian Z', 'By Alex Y', 'By Pawel P', 'By Ismael S', 'By Yajing G', 'By Samantha R', 'By VASILEIOS M', 'By Naga M']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 17, 2018', 'Sep 29, 2018', 'Oct 26, 2018', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Mar 30, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jun 21, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 09, 2019', 'Nov 05, 2018', 'Jun 19, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 16, 2018']</review_date></doc>