<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_268</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/mathematics-sport</course_url><course_name>Math behind Moneyball</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Professor Wayne Winston</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn how probability, math, and statistics can be used to help baseball, football and basketball teams improve, player and lineup selection as well as in game strategy.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Analytics//Microsoft Excel//Probability</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Houston System</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Before you start...//Module 1//Module 2//Module 3//Module 4//Module 5//Module 6//Module 7//Module 8//Module 9//Module 10//Final Exam</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['All you will learn'], ['1.1 Introduction', '1.2 Pythagorean Theorem', '1.3 Ten runs = One win', 'Homework Problems 1 and 2', '1.4 Runs created', '1.5 Runs Created Per Game', '1.6 Multiple Regression 1', '1.7 Multiple Regression 2', '1.8 Linear Weights', '1.9 On Base Percentage + Slugging Percentage', '1.10 Barry Bonds Runs per Game'], ['2.1 Excel Range Names', '2.2 Excel Tables', '2.3 Conditional Formatting: Top Bottom Rules', '2.4 Conditional Formatting: Data Bars', '2.5 Conditional Formatting: The Formula Option', '2.6 COUNTIF and COUNTIFS functions', '2.7 SUMIF and SUMIFS Functions', '2.8 AVERAGEIF and AVERAGEIFS Functions', '2.9 PivotTables I', '2.10 PivotTables II'], ['3.1 Monte Carlo Simulation I', '3.2 Monte Carlo Simulation Part II', '3.3 Monte Carlo Simulation Part III', '3.4 Baseball Monte Carlo simulation', '3.5 Resampling', '3.6 Deflategate'], ['4.1 Bunting and Expected Runs', '4.2 Base Stealing', '4.3 Range Factor', '4.4 UZR (Ultimate Zone Rating) and Fielding', '4.5 Introduction to Fan Graphs', '4.6 DIPS (Defense Independent Pitching Statistics)', '4.7 Win Probability Added', '4.8 Runs above Average', '4.9 WAR (Wins above Replacement)', '4.10 What Makes your Team Win?', '4.11 Defensive Shifts', '4.12 Catcher Framing', '4.13 Park Factors'], ['5.1 Random Variables', '5.2 The Normal Random Variable', '5.3 Streakiness', '5.4 What makes NFL teams win?', '5.5 Deconstructing the NFL QB rating', '5.6 Football States and Values', '5.7 Football Decision Making', '5.8 The Belichick Decision', '5.9 Text functions and Analyzing NFL plays', '5.10 Texans 1st and 10 Play Selection', '5.11 STDEVIF and Too Many Field Goal Attempts'], ['6.1 Game Theory Part I', '6.2 Game Theory Part II', '6.3 Basketball Shot Selection', '6.4 Effective Field Goal Percentage (EFG)', '6.5 Hollinger Team Metrics', '6.6 Four Factors', '6.7 Basketball Box Score Models'], ['7.1 Extracting Lineup data and Computing raw + -', '7.2 Computing Pairs Lineup Statistics', '7.3 Adjusted + -', '7.4 ESPM RPM (Real Plus Minus)', '7.5 How Analytics Helped the Mavs beat the Heat', '7.6 SportsVu data', '7.7 In Game Basketball Decision-Making', '7.8 Hack a Jordan (or Dwight)'], ['8.1 Rating NFL teams', '8.2 Computing Strength of Schedule', '8.3 Rating NFL Offenses and Defenses', '8.4 Multiplicative Rating Models for Soccer', '8.5 Regularization', '8.6 Simulating the NCAA Tournament', '8.7 NCAA Props Bets'], ['9.1 Method of Maximum Likelihood', '9.2 Rating Teams Based on Wins and Losses', '9.3 Simulating the NFL Playoffs', '9.4 Rating NASCAR Drivers', '9.5 How Good are NFL Point Spreads', '9.6 Relating the Money Line to Point Spreads', '9.7 How Can you tell if a Betting System is Successful?', '9.8 Props Bets I', '9.9 Props Bet II', '9.10 Props Bet III'], ['10.1 Kelly Growth Part I', '10.2 Kelly Growth Part II', '10.3 Kelly Growth Part III', '10.4 Regression to the Mean', '10.5 Daily Fantasy Sports Part I', '10.6 Daily Fantasy Sports Part II', '10.7 Golf Analytics'], ['Download Excel Files']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I am equally disappointed in Coursera and the instructor. Test 18 provided a dead link for how we were supposed to solve the problem and there was no instruction on how to complete otherwise. I reached out to Coursera on multiple occasions asking for support and was basically ignored not counting a couple of useless responses. I will never take a Coursera course again after the embarrassing level of customer service and given the fact the course clearly had not been updated in so long that the content was so far out of date that we are receiving dead links to content. I was supposed to complete this course months ago and am just finishing now because the only way to finish this test was to blindly guess at numbers and loosely make some of those guesses based off of the feedback from other students who were struggling with this on the discussion board as well. It's a shame I leave with this impression because the course has potential and I did learn a fair amount from it, but I will not get past how poorly I was treated by Coursera's customer service and how little they cared that the course was setting students up for failure. I took this course because I do not have a strong analytics skill set and it was described as being for beginners. This content missing makes that a completely misleading description as we were not provided the knowledge or content necessary to successfully complete this course in the appropriate amount of time. ", "If you want to understand why some of the excel formulas are used you need to books recommended in the course. With the instructor just doing voiceover with excel there isn't a lot of depth given. Still, pretty cool to see how decisions and betting done using data", 'Pretty good course where you learn how to analyse performance via various statistical analysis techniques. You also learn quite a bit in  MS Excel.', 'Excellent course if you like statistics, probabilities, and how to linh sport with math. Well explained. Maybe it needs more "movement" on forums', 'Useful, broad, and practical. ', None, 'Wow, this is quite the crash course in sports analytics and Excel tricks!  I was familiar with most of the concepts, but enjoyed seeing how easily all of these advanced stats could be calculated, and learned some really useful Excel functionality (what-if analysis, solver).  The amount of material that is covered is really impressive!', 'This is one of the very the best classes I\'ve ever taken. It provided the tools in Excel and the methods to model various sports outcomes so that I can start creating my own models. The examples were wide ranging and interesting. I thoroughly enjoyed listening to Professor Winston and appreciated all the additional references he pointed out during the lectures. I would love to see a second course in sports analytics .  I do wish this course was called "Introduction to Sports Analytics", or "Sports Analytics I"  so it would be easier to find. It seems like this course should have many more reviews than it does. Also, some of the course data may need updated. Highly recommended to anyone interested in sportsbetting or fantasy sports.', 'Great course, however very heavy emphasis on Baseball and NFL. Resultantly some of the assessment questions proved impossible given the knowledge needed about the sport.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Steven M', 'By John T', 'By hasanalanam', 'By Javier O', 'By Nelson C', 'By Francisco J F N', 'By Bret', 'By Michael S', 'By Scott P']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 05, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Feb 06, 2017', 'Mar 08, 2018', 'Oct 01, 2016', 'Oct 20, 2016', 'Jun 16, 2017', 'Nov 10, 2017', 'Jul 26, 2017']</review_date></doc>