<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_126</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning-duke</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Machine Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Lawrence Carin </course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will provide you a foundational understanding of machine learning models (logistic regression, multilayer perceptrons, convolutional neural networks, natural language processing, etc.) as well as demonstrate how these models can solve complex problems in a variety of industries, from medical diagnostics to image recognition to text prediction. In addition, we have designed practice exercises that will give you hands-on experience implementing these data science models on data sets. These practice exercises will teach you how to implement machine learning algorithms with TensorFlow, open source libraries used by leading tech companies in the machine learning field (e.g., Google, NVIDIA, CocaCola, eBay, Snapchat, Uber and many more).</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Simple Introduction to Machine Learning//Basics of Model Learning//Image Analysis with Convolutional Neural Networks//Introduction to Natural Language Processing//Introduction to Reinforcement Learning</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Why Machine Learning Is Exciting', 'What Is Machine Learning?', 'Logistic Regression', 'Interpretation of Logistic Regression', 'Motivation for Multilayer Perceptron', 'Multilayer Perceptron Concepts', 'Multilayer Perceptron Math Model', 'Deep Learning', 'Example: Document Analysis', 'Interpretation of Multilayer Perceptron', 'Transfer Learning', 'Model Selection', 'Early History of Neural Networks', 'Hierarchical Structure of Images', 'Convolution Filters', 'Convolutional Neural Network', 'CNN Math Model', 'How the Model Learns', 'Advantages of Hierarchical Features', 'CNN on Real Images', 'Applications in Use and Practice', 'Deep Learning and Transfer Learning', 'Introduction to TensorFlow'], ['How Do We Define Learning?', 'How Do We Evaluate Our Networks?', 'How Do We Learn Our Network?', 'How Do We Handle Big Data?', 'Early Stopping', 'Model Learning with TensorFlow'], ['Motivation:  Diabetic Retinopathy', 'Breakdown of the Convolution (1D and 2D)', 'Core Components of the Convolutional Layer', 'Activation Functions', 'Pooling and Fully Connected Layers', 'Training the Network', 'Transfer Learning and Fine-Tuning', 'CNN with TensorFlow'], ['Introduction to the Concept of Word Vectors', 'Words to  Vectors', 'Example of Word Embeddings', 'Neural Model of Text', 'The Softmax Function', 'Methods for Learning Model Parameters', 'More Details on How to Learn Model Parameters', 'The Recurrent Neural Network', 'Long Short-Term Memory', 'Long Short-Term Memory Review', 'Use of LSTM for Text Synthesis', 'Simple and Effective Alternative Methods for Neural NLP', 'Natural Language Processing with TensorFlow'], ['Introduction to Reinforcement Learning', 'Reinforcement Learning Problem Setup', 'Example of Reinforcement Learning in Practice', 'Moving to a Non-Myopic Policy', 'Q Learning', 'Extensions of Q Learning', 'Limitations of Q Learning, and Introduction to Deep Q Learning', 'Deep Q Learning Based on Images', 'Connecting Deep Q Learning with Conventional Q Learning']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Much weaker than Stanford offerings.  Strange buildup of topics for a breezy, but not particular accurate understanding.  For example:  multiple layers of a neural network is introduced before multiple category classification.  Transfer learning is introduced incorrectly. The matrix representation of multiple features of an example with multiple examples is introduced very late in the course. The instructor is conscientious and seemingly knows the material despite using non-standard terminology.  One wonders if he is primarily a teacher/researcher and rarely a practitioner.  One wonders if Duke is a leader in machine learning research.', 'Very Good course explaining the theoretical concepts related to deep learning . Thank you ', "Excellent course. Concepts such as gradient descent and convolutions as they pertain to neural networks are explained without going into the mathematical details but, in my opinion, are explained more intuitively and better, as compared to most other courses. The course does include some ungraded Jupyter notebooks exemplifying key elements of deep learning networks. Highly recommended to 'cement' understanding of neural networks.", 'It was great to touch new professional area and to understand its fundamentals. The course gives a broad view on machine learning, so I think now I really understand, what the machine learning is and how to use it in my work and even my political investigations.', 'I like this introductory course,  very good one to start to learn machine learning. I will definitely continue studying and re-watch the videos. ', 'This was a really great course for understanding the basics of machine learning through a lot of simple but relevant, real world examples.', 'Great course ! Pr Carin is clear enough to make you understand complex concepts like LSTM. The Math, calculus, algenra and prob are not too difficult. I enjoyed to follow this course ! To conclude  a good introduction to ML  to make you go deeper into the subject', 'A very fine tuned Course,used as a warm up course for deep learning,highly recommended', 'GOOD COURSE', 'Great course for beginners, did a lot to fill in the gaps in my knowledge. There could be a little more help with the actual coding parts of the project, the work done in ipython notebook is largely self-taught.', 'Great Course! ', 'very good for getting started.', 'I have a background in pathology and I wanted to understand how machine learning works so that I can take an active part in the changes within my field and understand what is happening. This course was an amazing experience of learning, for someone like me with no background in calculus or linear algebra.  ', 'Easy to understand about machine learning ', 'Excellent introduction in to machine learning and paced ideally to keep the interest throughout the course. Ignites interest to the field.', 'Very Interesting Course ', 'Excelente', 'Simply Brilliant', 'Very good introductory course, I highly recommend it to anyone looking to get a flavour of the methods behind the recent advances in AI without going into super-technical details.', 'Amazing course', "I liked the pace and the tensor flow applications. This should be upgraded to TF 2.0 at some point. Also, I would've appreciated some GAN material.", 'Thanks', 'Best course', 'It is very good contetnt and begin in Machin learning', 'It was a very new topic for me but the video had lucid explanations to make it understand for a beginner like me. Thank you.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Lewis C L', 'By Sameera  K', 'By Michael B', 'By Shukshin I', 'By Ayse U', 'By Erica R', 'By Eric T', 'By Tarun Y', 'By KAVADIBALLARI V', 'By Noah R', 'By Tami Z', 'By Pranav R', 'By Abdul M', 'By PRADEEP K T', 'By Upul T', 'By Akhil K', 'By Oscar S', 'By Aliraza', 'By Guido C', 'By Antonio R C N', 'By Riley B', 'By Sandeep  D  D', 'By Zeeshan L', 'By Santosh G', 'By Reena P']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 22, 2019', 'Sep 19, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'May 28, 2019', 'Apr 22, 2019', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Apr 05, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'May 14, 2019', 'May 17, 2019', 'May 19, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jul 02, 2019', 'Jul 09, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Sep 14, 2019', 'Sep 15, 2019']</review_date></doc>