<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_201</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/sas-programming-advanced</course_url><course_name>Doing More with SAS Programming</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Stacey Syphus</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is for business analysts and SAS programmers who want to learn data manipulation techniques using the SAS DATA step and procedures to access, transform, and summarize data. The course builds on the concepts that are presented in the Getting Started with SAS Programming course and is not recommended for beginning SAS software users.

In this course you learn how to understand and control DATA step processing, create an accumulating column and process data in groups, manipulate data with functions, convert column type, create custom formats, concatenate and merge tables, process repetitive code, and restructure tables. This course addresses Base SAS software.

Before attending this course, you should be able to write DATA step code to access data, subset rows and columns, compute new columns, and process data conditionally. You should also be able to sort tables using the SORT procedure and
apply SAS formats.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>SAS</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview and Data Setup//Controlling DATA Step Processing//Summarizing Data//Manipulating Data with Functions//Creating and Using Custom Formats//Combining Tables//Processing Repetitive Code//Restructuring Tables</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course!', 'Practicing in This Course'], ['Overview', 'DATA Step Review', 'DATA Step Processing', 'DATA Step Processing: Compilation', 'DATA Step Processing: Execution', 'Demo: DATA Step Processing in Action', 'Viewing Execution in the Log', 'Controlling DATA Step Processing', 'Implicit and Explicit Output', 'Sending Output to Multiple Tables', 'Demo: Directing Row Output', 'Controlling Column Output', 'Demo: Directing Column Output', 'Columns in the PDV'], ['Overview', 'Demo: Creating an Accumulating Column', 'Retaining Values in the PDV', 'Using the Sum Statement', 'Answering Questions about Groups', 'Processing Sorted Data in Groups', 'Demo: Identifying the First and Last Row in Each Group', 'Subsetting Rows in the Execution Phase', 'Demo: Creating an Accumulating Column within Groups', 'Using Multiple BY Columns'], ['Overview', 'Review of Functions', 'Specifying Columns Lists', 'Using a CALL Routine to Modify Data', 'Using Numeric Functions', 'Demo: Using Numeric Functions', 'SAS Date, Datetime, and Time Values', 'Extracting Data from a Datetime Value', 'Calculating Date Intervals', 'Shifting Date Values', 'Demo: Shifting Date Values Based on an Interval', 'Useful Character Functions', 'Extracting Words from a String', 'Demo: Using Character Functions to Extract Words from a String', 'Searching for Character Strings', 'Replacing Character Strings', 'Handling Column Type', 'Converting Column Type', 'Converting Character Values to Numeric Values', 'Using a Generic Informat to Read Dates', 'Converting the Type of an Existing Column', 'Converting Numeric Values to Character Values', 'Demo: Using the INPUT Function to Convert Column Types', 'Demo: Using the PUT Function to Convert Column Types'], ['Overview', 'Formatting Data Values', 'Creating and Applying a Custom Format', 'Using Ranges', 'Demo: Creating and Using Custom Formats', 'Reading a Table of Values for a Format', 'Demo: Creating Custom Formats from Tables', 'Storing Custom Formats'], ['Overview', 'Concatenating Tables with Matching Columns', 'Demo: Concatenating Tables', 'Handling Column Attributes', 'What is a Merge?', 'Processing a One-to-One Merge', 'Processing a One-To-Many Merge', 'Demo: Merging Tables', 'Merging Tables with Nonmatching Rows', 'Identifying Matches and Nonmatches', 'Demo: Merging Tables with Nonmatching Rows', 'Merging Tables with Matching Column Names', 'Merging Tables without a Common Column', 'DATA Step Merge and PROC SQL Join'], ['Overview', 'Processing Repetitive Code', 'Iterative DO Loops', 'Demo: Executing an Iterative DO Loop', 'Output Inside and Outside the DO Loop', 'Demo: Using Iterative DO Loops', 'Conditional DO Loops', 'Checking the Condition', 'Demo: Using Conditional DO Loops', 'Combining Iterative and Conditional DO Loops', 'Demo: Combining Iterative and Conditional DO Loops'], ['Overview', 'Understanding Table Structure', 'Restructuring Data', 'Demo: Creating a Narrow Table with the DATA Step', 'Creating a Wide Table with the DATA Step', 'The Transpose Procedure', 'Transposing Values within Groups', 'Demo: Creating a Wide Table with PROC TRANSPOSE', 'Creating a Narrow Table with PROC TRANSPOSE', 'Changing Column Names']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 25 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Level 2 of great introduction to SAS. The course offers a lot of interactive coding experience with SAS Studio platform through many activities and code-based quizes. It leads from easier to more complicated examples, starting from scripts missing single statements, ending on code to be written from scratch to achieve a specific result. Hard to imagine better way to design such a course. Great learning experience.', 'excellent course', 'Great Course, even better than the first one!', 'I like it very much... I enjoyed this nodule much', 'm', 'e', 'One of the best courses ', 'This opened my perspective as to how data analytics can really shape the world. This program equipped me not just with more advanced technical skills, but also, with brand new eyes for data validation. SAS makes it looks so appealing to crunch numbers, which just goes to prove how sophisticated the software is.', 'My personal opinion is that SAS institute must understand that they need to make such courses affordable for individuals to practice and experiment. I for one cannot afford, as an individual, to pay thousands of euros for SAS courses and these days neither can companies afford to train their employees because of the huge costs involved.  ', 'Terrific course!', 'Great presentation of complex material; exercises and quizzes really help with understanding and applying concepts.', "A very useful course if you're interested in SAS programming. The platform is also easy to use, it's not necessary to have SAS installed on your laptop in order to take this class.", 'Very comprehensive course that is broken down into simple steps which are easy to follow. Admins provide helpful answers to questions.', 'Great second part of the 3 part SAS course.  TIP: Print the syntax notes at the end of each week. They will help you take notes and keep track of what you are learning.', 'Whoa.  It was an incredible course and covered almost everything one will ever need to succeed as a SAS analyst.  Stacy did an incredible job in her presentation and explaining everything through hands-on.  Condensing it in only 7 weeks seems a bit much though', 'happy', 'A well structured course. It has all the information along with a good set of practice problems.', 'This course provided me with the know how needed to write SAS programs. I would definitely recommend this course for folks looking to get an insight on writing or understanding SAS codes.', 'I love the way the course content builds on itself in such a systematic way, and welcome the variety of exercises and practices.', ' Amazing extended introduction to the SAS analytic tool kit. Well designed courses with segmented and modulated videos and hands-on practice. Completing all the practice exercise will give you the edge to fully familiarize with the materials covered!  ', 'Perfect course which gives much more understanding and practice in SAS programming. Highly recommended!', 'Very clear', 'great, good info..', 'There is a lot to unpack in this course, and at times I fear my memory might let it slip.  It would be nice, if there were exercises, which combined skills learned in previous weeks.', 'Great class! Definitely would recommend if one does not know how to manipulate data in SAS']</reviews><reviewers>['By Krzysztof P', 'By Anitha t', 'By Daniel W', 'By Mohamed A', 'By Xinkai Z', 'By Mohsin M', 'By Lokesh H', 'By Patricia V', 'By Neville A', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Michael W', 'By Eva K E', 'By Eugene L', 'By Hannah R', 'By PATRICK M', 'By YUXI L', 'By Roopal J', 'By Rajesh S', 'By Val', 'By Victor(JingFeng) X', 'By Oleksandr L', 'By Bowen Z', 'By liz a', 'By Michael K', 'By Dagoberto R']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 09, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'May 11, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'May 29, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jul 10, 2019', 'Jul 11, 2019', 'Jul 16, 2019', 'Jul 28, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Apr 25, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019', 'Sep 03, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Jul 16, 2019']</review_date></doc>