<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_129</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/summary-statistics</course_url><course_name>Summary Statistics in Public Health</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>John McGready, PhD, MS</course_instructor><course_introduction>Biostatistics is the application of statistical reasoning to the life sciences, and it is the key to unlocking the data gathered by researchers and the evidence presented in the scientific literature. In this course, we'll focus on the use of statistical measurement methods within the world of public health research. Along the way, you'll be introduced to a variety of methods and measures, and you'll practice interpreting data and performing calculations on real data from published studies.  Topics include summary measures, visual displays, continuous data, sample size, the normal distribution, binary data, the element of time, and the Kaplan-Meir curve.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Normal Distribution//summary measures//binary data</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Role of Statistics in Public Health Research//Continuous Data Measures//The Normal Distribution//Binary Data//Dealing with the Element of Time//Course Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Introduction and Overview', 'Samples Versus Population', 'Considerations with Regard to Study Design', 'Data Types and Summarization', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'Useful Summary Statistics', 'Visual Displays', 'The Role of Sample Size on Sample Based Estimates', 'Comparing Distributions of Continuous Data', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'The Standard Normal Distribution Defined', 'Applying the Principles of the Normal Distribution to Sample Data to Estimate Characteristics of Population Data', 'What Happens When We Apply the Properties of the Normal Distribution to Data Not Approximately Normal: A Warning', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'Binary Data: Definition and Summarization (Binomial Distribution, P-Hat, SD)', 'Comparing Distributions of Binary Data: Risk Difference and Relative Risk', 'Comparing Distributions of Binary Data: Odds Ratios', 'A Brief Note About Ratios (Will Also Be Revisited Later in the Course)', 'Additional Examples'], ['Introduction', 'Time to Event Data: Definition (Censoring) and Numerical Summary Measures (Incidence Rates)', 'Numerically Comparing Groups on Time to Event Outcomes', 'Summarizing Time-to-Event Data, Graphically', 'Graphically Comparing Groups on Time to Event Outcomes', 'Additional Examples'], ['Biostatistical Consulting Project']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent course, very succinct and easy to understand, the professor is fantastic! I was going to just take this class and now I am enrolled in the specialization, some professors are so good that make you wanna learn more, thank you. ', 'Excellent teaching and good examples which help in manipulating and visualizing  huge data samples . Good course which i recommend for everyone.', 'Great course for an introduction into the literally limitless possibilities of interpretation of population data.', 'This is a well structured content. The course is presented in the most simplest form to accommodate complete novices. I found it very educative, practical and lucidly intense.', 'Easy to understand, explains normally difficult concepts very well, engaging project quizzes', 'Este primer curso del programa especializado me parece simplemente fundamental en la formaci칩n de todo profesional de salud, teniendo en cuenta que el 90% o m치s del material que se utiliza en la pr치ctica diaria est치 relacionado con el proceso de Medicina Basada en Evidencias. Realmente recomiendo este curso.', 'I appreciated the content of this course. It is presently appropriately, at a good pace, with useful explanations. I like being able to pause the video to take notes about the slides and then restart the video listen to the professor explain them. Everything is not flawless (there are a few typos in the quizzes and occasional errors in the slides), but it is on par to what would be experienced in a classroom setting. Being able to understand differences regarding numbers of standard deviations, odds ratios, relative risks, incidence rates, and incidence rate ratios is very useful in my work --- and this course fit the bill for presenting the information straightforwardly and clearly without the professor making assumptions about my previous knowledge. The use of the Additional Examples videos helps to solidify the application of the concepts. Highly recommended!', 'Dr. McGready did an excellent job putting abstract statistical terms and methods in plain languages (with good examples). I find this course very helpful! ', "Instructor is dry, audio recordings are poor.  The instructor reads off the power point way too much, doesn't simplify in a way that encourages creativity or out of the box thinking.   For JHU I am very surprised - it didn't feel any different from stats work I have done in class at Purdue.  ", 'Absolutely fantastic explanation of some basic concepts in statistics that I thought previously that I had a solid understanding of. I will definitely look for additional classes taught by Dr. McGready.', 'Not only informative, this course is very useful in routine clinical practice. ', 'Indeed an eye opening experience', "Excellent course. Dr. McGready is so clear and concise. Can't wait to get to the next module.", "Excellent!!! I'm thrilled to have taken it!!!", 'It is a great course to enroll with basic skills in statistics.', 'Quite informative and engaging. I enjoyed every bit of it', 'Friendly intro, with excellent examples.', 'This was an AMAZING course, largely due to Dr. McGready!  You made a sometimes difficult subject make perfect sense.  I actually loved learning how to interpret different statistical measures.  Thank you for the awesome instructional lectures and examples.', 'one of the best course to start with statistics, the quiz is tricky ', 'EXCELLENT COURSE FOR BEGINNER', 'Excellent course ', 'Great information, organized, and well presented.  I would like to review why some answers were incorrect.  Thank you!  ', 'I enjoyed this course, great professor, easy to understand.', 'Great course. The lecturer makes things so easy to understand. I love that there are additional examples available. I will definitely recommend this course to everyone in healthcare ', 'This is an excellent course. Professor McGready is an excellent teacher. He has real passion for the subject and that kept me engrossed throughout the course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nancy Z', 'By Ayush B ', 'By Konstantin G', 'By Anyanwu R', 'By Daniel Y T Y', 'By Francisco C', 'By Elizabeth L', 'By huaqin p', 'By Anthony C', 'By Mark S', 'By Hoon L C', 'By OLATUNDE O', 'By James M', 'By Mavroudis I', 'By Andrea G', 'By Ezeobi O', 'By Thomas J H', 'By Tammy P', 'By Sandeep K', 'By Dr. A S', 'By kelvin o ', 'By Cassandra N', 'By Elena L', 'By Ulrick S K K', 'By Nachiket M']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 26, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Apr 28, 2019', 'Apr 28, 2019', 'Apr 12, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'May 02, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Jun 11, 2019', 'Jun 21, 2019', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Jul 14, 2019']</review_date></doc>