<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_20</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-science-methodology</course_url><course_name>Data Science Methodology</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Aklson</course_instructor><course_introduction>Despite the recent increase in computing power and access to data over the last couple of decades, our ability to use the data within the decision making process is either lost or not maximized at all too often, we don't have a solid understanding of the questions being asked and how to apply the data correctly to the problem at hand.

This course has one purpose, and that is to share a methodology that can be used within data science, to ensure that the data used in problem solving is relevant and properly manipulated to address the question at hand.

Accordingly, in this course, you will learn:
    - The major steps involved in tackling a data science problem.
    - The major steps involved in practicing data science, from forming a concrete business or research problem, to collecting and analyzing data, to building a model, and understanding the feedback after model deployment.
    - How data scientists think!

LIMITED TIME OFFER: Subscription is only $39 USD per month for access to graded materials and a certificate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>From Problem to Approach and From Requirements to Collection//From Understanding to Preparation and From Modeling to Evaluation//From Deployment to Feedback</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Business Understanding', 'Analytic Approach', 'Data Requirements', 'Data Collection'], ['Data Understanding', 'Data Preparation - Concepts', 'Data Preparation - Case Study', 'Modeling - Concepts', 'Modeling - Case Study', 'Evaluation'], ['Deployment', 'Feedback', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This one is fairly painful to sit through and needlessly complex.  Other sites have explained this much simpler and clearer than here', 'Instead of CHF the case study should be change to something which everyone can understand.', '1) This descriptions in this course are very dull. They need to be supported by better examples which do not include a lot of terminology specific to the topic. ', "Nothing is discussed in details. For people know nothing about data science, many topics are not explained and they won't understand anything valuable; for people already have a background in data science, the topics are useless and too shallow.", 'The example should change to a easier one. This example is hard to understand.', 'Quizzes quiz on material not covered in the course or directed to externally. Most of the quizzes are word games and do not apply concepts covered in the material. Everything from how disconnected the quiz questions are compared to available information provided in the course to the peer-graded final assignment show little or now effort was put into composing this course.', 'This Course is pretty good and concepts are so nice but the example taken to describe the Data Science Methodology is not so good. Could have been taken a better example with far better presentation skills.', 'Really difficult content to digest without much written information. This course needs to provide more readings and the videos need to provide more text, as opposed to relying on voice instruction.', 'This was a good course. It was an overview of the entire data science process, which was helpful for me since I didn\'t really have a good understanding of what data science meant before this class. Now I have a much better understanding of what people mean when they say data science. Also, this class gives a good orientation for other courses; for example, I would see "data mining" courses on Coursera and not understand how that fit in with data science. Now I do. I would recommend this course for people very new at programming and data science, like me.', 'The base concept for every Data Scientist and taught excellent here in Coursera.', 'The example should be easier than CHF in the videos like the example of cuisines was. The CHF example was good but it was not self explanatory and it might be hard for some people.', 'this course should be a little later in the IBM sylalbis', 'Fine for an introductory course', 'Was a bit hard to understand for a complete beginner without a statistical background. Hospital example was a bit difficult to follow as well. ', 'Too complex of a case study to understand stuff. Also, too boring and theoretical and very less interactive. ', 'excellent training with hands-on exercises', 'Very well structured course which gives us good insights on data science methodology. ', 'Excellent course and practice. Very complete for those who start in data science. ', 'The Final Assignment was not so easy to understand how to do it.', 'Excellent description of the processs', 'Very well explained !!!', 'The topics covered in this course are really good. Without this course, the training in data science is incomplete', 'the course should include more hands on tutorial', 'Case study throughout the course was great idea, i loved it', 'Wasnt so easy peasy,I appreciated the challenge.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Clayton S', 'By Husain B', 'By Ozge I', 'By Jianfei Z', 'By Jiayang Z', 'By Kristoffer H', 'By Kameshwara N S B', 'By Sasha M', 'By Lauren J', 'By VIJAY K N', 'By Huzaifah S', 'By Johannes', 'By Ponciano R', 'By ALINA R', 'By Sayak C', 'By Jeffrey B', 'By Swaraj B', 'By Jose A M A', 'By Elise Y T', 'By Jim C', 'By Venkata R S', 'By Avinash S', 'By Akshay j', 'By Afanasev A', 'By Rosanna B']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 02, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Jul 20, 2019', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018']</review_date></doc>