<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_68</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-essentials</course_url><course_name>Big Data Essentials: HDFS, MapReduce and Spark RDD</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ivan Puzyrevskiy</course_instructor><course_introduction>Have you ever heard about such technologies as HDFS, MapReduce, Spark? Always wanted to learn these new tools but missed concise starting material? Don’t miss this course either!
 
In this 6-week course you will:
- learn some basic technologies of the modern Big Data landscape, namely: HDFS, MapReduce and Spark;
- be guided both through systems internals and their applications;
- learn about distributed file systems, why they exist and what function they serve;
- grasp the MapReduce framework, a workhorse for many modern Big Data applications;
- apply the framework to process texts and solve sample business cases;
- learn about Spark, the next-generation computational framework;
- build a strong understanding of Spark basic concepts;
- develop skills to apply these tools to creating solutions in finance, social networks, telecommunications and many other fields.

Your learning experience will be as close to real life as possible with the chance to evaluate your practical assignments on a real cluster. No mocking, a friendly considerate atmosphere to make the process of your learning smooth and enjoyable.
 
Get ready to work with real datasets alongside with real masters!

Special thanks to:
- Prof. Mikhail Roytberg, APT dept., MIPT, who was the initial reviewer of the project, the supervisor and mentor of half of the BigData team. He was the one, who helped to get this show on the road.
- Oleg Sukhoroslov (PhD, Senior Researcher at IITP RAS), who has been teaching  MapReduce, Hadoop  and friends since 2008. Now he is leading the infrastructure team.
- Oleg Ivchenko (PhD student APT dept., MIPT), Pavel Akhtyamov (MSc. student at APT dept., MIPT) and Vladimir Kuznetsov (Assistant at P.G. Demidov Yaroslavl State University), superbrains who have developed and now maintain the infrastructure used for practical assignments in this course.
- Asya Roitberg, Eugene Baulin, Marina Sudarikova. These people never sleep to babysit this course day and night, to make your learning experience productive, smooth and exciting.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Apache Hadoop//Mapreduce//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Yandex</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome//What are BigData and distributed file systems (e.g. HDFS)?//Solving Problems with MapReduce//Solving Problems with MapReduce (practice week)// Introduction to Apache Spark//Introduction to Apache Spark (practice week)//Real-World Applications</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Why BigData?', 'Issues BigData can solve', 'BigData Applications', 'What is BigData Essentials?', 'Course Structure', 'Meet Emeli', 'Meet Alexey', 'Meet Ivan'], ['File system exploration', 'File system managing', 'File content exploration 1', 'File content exploration 2', 'Processes', 'Scaling Distributed File System', 'Block and Replica States, Recovery Process 1', 'Block and Replica States, Recovery Process 2', 'HDFS Client', 'Web UI, REST API', 'Namenode Architecture', 'Introduction', 'Text formats', 'Binary formats 1', 'Binary formats 2', 'Compression', 'How to submit your first assignment', 'How to Install Docker on Windows 7, 8, 10'], ['Unreliable Components 1', 'Unreliable Components 2', 'MapReduce', 'Distributed Shell', 'Fault Tolerance', 'Fault Tolerance. Live Demo', 'Streaming', 'Streaming in Python', 'WordCount in Python', 'Distributed Cache', 'Environment, Counters', 'Testing', 'Combiner', 'Partitioner', 'Comparator', 'Speculative Execution / Backup Tasks', 'Compression'], ['How to submit your first Hadoop assignment'], ['Welcome', 'RDDs', 'Transformations 1', 'Transformations 2', 'Actions', 'Resiliency', 'Execution &amp; Scheduling', 'Caching &amp; Persistence', 'Broadcast variables', 'Accumulator variables', 'Getting started with Spark &amp; Python', 'Working with text files', 'Joins', 'Broadcast &amp; Accumulator variables', 'Spark UI', 'Cluster mode'], ['Spark assignments Intro', 'Building an intuition behind the PMI definition'], ['Sampling', 'Estimating proportions', 'Means', 'Medians', 'Map and Reduce Side Joins', 'Tabular Data, KeyFieldSelection', 'Data Skew, Salting', 'Twitter graph case study', 'Shortest path']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 45 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Tools provided in the course to submit the assignment doesn't work and there is no response from the team on how to resolve this issue. All the users in this course are facing the same issue.", 'I am unable to understand what the tutors have been talking. I am scared after seeing them talking in the very first video.', "The tools provide to complete the course doesn't work.", 'I appreciate that practical assignments exist and were definitely helpful for really understanding how to use MapReduce and Spark.', 'Difficult to understand, poorly cut and buggy', 'I audited this course, because I was interested to complete the specialization. I finished the course and all of the assignments. After finishing this course, I will not continue the specialization.', 'This is the most awful course I have ever had in Coursera', 'The course is advertised as a practical one. But the majority of time is spent on outdated technologies like Map/Reduce. It would be more productive to go deeper into Spark. Assignments are not difficult but it takes a lot of time and attempts to figure out what exactly the authors wanted. The worst part is the grader and how it organized. Nevertheless you can learn a few things even if you are working in this industry.', 'Too few learning materials. Unreliable grader. Also unclear yarn mapReduce assignments. For example in the final assignment after submition one  test said "... this task must be done in less than 3 jobs" Ok, why don\'t write it in the assignment text? And so on..\n', 'Accent is horrible, it is hard to listen, a lot of mistakes in the words pronunciation. But the idea of course is good.', 'The course is not elaborated. Actually it is a FAIL. Bad accent, inappropriate jokes (Hello, Alexey!), not so good topics (for introductory course), paranoid grading system. ', 'Not very happy with the course. Submissions had lot of issues.I could not figure out and left the course in the middle(even the demo assignment was not working).The instructors were great but somehow I thought they were not very involved.Too much information (stated fast) out of which you may not be caring a lot. Lot of slides/presentation but somewhere they were too fast or were  not able to connect the exact points. ', 'Non existent instructor support', 'The topics and the content of the course were good but that is the only thing that was good. The presentation is done in English with a heavy Russian accent with wrongly translated subtitles. The assignments are described minimalistically, passing the automatic checking of the assignments cost more time than actually getting the right answer for the assignment and often the external assignment environment is down or not functioning correctly. When this happens the staff support on the discussion board is really slow (think in days or weeks) or non-existing.', 'The lectures are good, but the assignments seem to rely on a Jupyter setup that is different than the one usually provided through Coursera.  So far, I have spent more time dealing with these troubleshooting issues than actually focusing on the content.', 'Awesome content...great learning ...:)', 'There were no such other course online as far as I know. You can find many courses on machine learning or other topics of data analysis, but on the side of engineering you were along so far. With this course you will learn basics of Hadoop, HDFS, MapReduce and Spark. You will work on many practical assignments that will let you understand those technologies. If you are willing to move into direction of data engineering being software developer, or if you want to learn some engineering topics being a data analyst, this course is for you!', 'Absolutely essential for everyone who wants a proper introduction to HDFS, MapReduce and Spark. Brought to you by a great team of geniuses of their time ;)', 'Quite challenging course for me (I was starting almost from scratch). Lots of information, lots of practice, additional practices for those eager to do more, Slack channels to communicate, you name it. Kudos to the Yandex team, and to the mentors community!', 'Excellent class to learn the basics of MapReduce, Hadoop, and PySpark. The lectures are very informative. They move at a strong pace, making this class more like a graduate level class in lecture style. ', 'This course has been well structured and I liked the assignments a lot. One area of improvement is to make the grading environment stable. This will save a lot of time! ', 'Home Assignments and their checker could be more transparent :)', "The course fills an important gap between software engineering and data engineering. The course content is good and the presentation is quite good as well. There are occasional issues with submitting assignments. It seems like the grading infrastructure has not been perfected just yet. This is definitely not a course for beginners. There's just too many things that can go wrong that are hard to understand unless you're already a somewhat experienced programmer and comfortable with the CLI. ", 'Difficult for newbies, but good for intermediate', 'Task is easy, but takes a lot of time for debbuging on hdfs and understending whats wrong with submission.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mayur T', 'By Suman K S', 'By Ferran G P', 'By Sock, H', 'By Vinokurov A', 'By Scott S', 'By Ehsan F', 'By Leonid M', 'By Evgeny F', 'By Maryna D', 'By Mikhail M', 'By Ejaj A', 'By pete_ch', 'By Pieter M', 'By Bryce C F', 'By navneet k', 'By Viacheslav I', 'By STEVEN V D', 'By Benjamin R', 'By Sanjay M', 'By Raja H', 'By Alexander P', 'By Sergejs P', 'By Kassymzhomart K', 'By Antonov A E']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 08, 2019', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Mar 08, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Sep 18, 2018', 'Apr 05, 2019', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Oct 19, 2018', 'Oct 17, 2018', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Jan 25, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2018', 'Oct 18, 2017', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Oct 24, 2017', 'Jun 28, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Feb 26, 2018', 'Jul 21, 2018', 'Oct 29, 2017', 'May 13, 2018', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2018']</review_date></doc>