<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_122</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/statistical-inferences</course_url><course_name>Improving your statistical inferences</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Lakens</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course aims to help you to draw better statistical inferences from empirical research. First, we will discuss how to correctly interpret p-values, effect sizes, confidence intervals, Bayes Factors, and likelihood ratios, and how these statistics answer different questions you might be interested in. Then, you will learn how to design experiments where the false positive rate is controlled, and how to decide upon the sample size for your study, for example in order to achieve high statistical power. Subsequently, you will learn how to interpret evidence in the scientific literature given widespread publication bias, for example by learning about p-curve analysis. Finally, we will talk about how to do philosophy of science, theory construction, and cumulative science, including how to perform replication studies, why and how to pre-register your experiment, and how to share your results following Open Science principles. 

In practical, hands on assignments, you will learn how to simulate t-tests to learn which p-values you can expect, calculate likelihood ratio's and get an introduction the binomial Bayesian statistics, and learn about the positive predictive value which expresses the probability published research findings are true. We will experience the problems with optional stopping and learn how to prevent these problems by using sequential analyses. You will calculate effect sizes, see how confidence intervals work through simulations, and practice doing a-priori power analyses. Finally, you will learn how to examine whether the null hypothesis is true using equivalence testing and Bayesian statistics, and how to pre-register a study, and share your data on the Open Science Framework.

All videos now have Chinese subtitles. More than 10.000 learners have enrolled so far!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Likelihood Function//Bayesian Statistics//P-Value//Statistical Inference</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>Eindhoven University of Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction + Frequentist Statistics//Likelihoods &amp; Bayesian Statistics//Multiple Comparisons, Statistical Power, Pre-Registration//Effect Sizes//Confidence Intervals, Sample Size Justification, P-Curve analysis//Philosophy of Science &amp; Theory//Open Science//Final Exam</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Frequentism, Likelihoods, Bayesian statistics', 'What is a p-value', 'Type 1 and Type 2 errors'], ['Interview: Zoltan Dienes', 'Likelihoods', 'Binomial Bayesian Inference', 'Bayesian Thinking'], ['Type 1 error control', 'Type 2 error control', 'Interview Professor Dan Simons', 'Pre-registration'], ['Effect Sizes', "Cohen's d", 'Correlations'], ['Confidence Intervals', 'Sample Size Justification', 'P-Curve Analysis'], ['Philosophy of Science', 'The Null is Always False', 'Theory Construction'], ['Replications', 'Publication Bias', 'Open Science'], ['Pop Quiz 6!', 'Practice Exam', 'Graded Final Exam']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This courses uses R', 'Amazing course! Tons of insights and original thinking!', 'The explanations from Daniel are awesome... I am understanding p values in a manner I never did before.', "As an early career scientist, this course helped me get a solid foundation on statistical inferences. After years of accumulating vaguely-organised statistical concepts and procedures, now I am confident I have mastered the basics. Definitely the best course I've had in a long time!", "Amazing course! Many thanks to Daniel Lakens for the time spent on this. It's really useful and I've learned so many things I will use to make better research. ", 'This course is amazing, dynamic and entertaining. Daniel Lakens is brilliant. ', 'excellent refresher and expansion on frequentists stats (interpretation) and  nice intro to bayesian stats. highly recommended.', 'I really enjoyed the course and found it challenging at times. Its definitely worth the time and effort as my knowledge has improved dramatically. I have gained knowledge which will be really helpful in the future for correctly interpreting current literature as well as future reporting of data and building research ideas. I also appreciate all the effort put into this course and the tools provided which will be beneficial to me in the future. I have saved a lot of the webpages and tools for future reference and will definitely use them when beginning research as well as examining current literature. Excellent', 'Great overview of statistics and philosophy of science. Now I know what to tell my students when they ask me about p-values. At last !', 'Great course.  A lot of topics introduced and explored.  Well worth the time.', 'It was truly an awesome course! I learned a lot from the very well done videos, and well thought-through assignment. Would recommend to anyone trying to marry theory and application in ways that are actually helpful! BRAVO!', 'Thank you daniel, very educational, I learned a lot', 'Practico sin hacer a un lado lo teorico, te dan un marco mucho mas amplio para la interpretacion y planteamiento de hipotesis', 'Excellent course. I learned a lot about inference.', 'Great course!', 'The best MOOC in statistis ever!', 'Excellent course that changed my views on interpreting  p-values, confidence intervals, etc. and will surely make my statistical inferences much better. ', 'Thank you Daniel Lakens for creating and sharing this course in the way you have done. The content is very appropriate for any one anyone who is looking to work with Inferential Statistics. Many thanks ', 'A great course to learn or refresh theoretical concepts behind statistical inferences. There is also a lot of hands-on material and additional content. I think I will come back to the videos and slides when I want to refresh some concepts.', 'Nicely packed body of information necessary to understand your data and to infer any judgements about real world impact of scientific research. The course led me to question my way of creating inferences about my research and conclusions of others. Now, I can be more precise in formulating hypotheses and interpreting results in the way that is closer to truth. Thank you.', 'One of the best online courses I\'ve ever taken! (completed it just now). Great lectures, great materials, great assignments. Links and information for anyone wanting to go deeper on any topic. Brilliant and engaing lecturer who provides the information with so much passion and interest that it "catches on" to you. I especially liked how actual studies are used as examples for learning/assignments. Bottom line - in my opinion it\'s a must do course to anyone who is interested in inferential statistics. ', "This is a top-notch course.  The ground (especially pitfalls) is very well covered, and useful free tools are engaged (R, G*Power, prof's own spreadsheets for calculating effect size).", 'A real pleasure to take this course ! The videos are extremely pleasant to watch and give away a lot of knowledge, without ever having this feeling of getting lost ! The assignments are fair and extremely useful as well as the exams ! Will definitely recommend (and actually already have ! =P)', "An excellent course!  I've taught undergraduate statistics in psychology and consider myself reasonably well-versed in statistics and this was a very helpful expansion.  ", 'Great course with practical examples and exercises! Clearly explains typical statistical misunderstandings and provides tips for a responsible and honest scientific practice. I really enjoyed it and already recommended it to all of my colleagues. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Shan G', 'By Yonathan M P', 'By Pepe V C', 'By Daniel A L', 'By Julien B', 'By Bertin ', 'By Dennis H', 'By Jason L', 'By Romain R', 'By Richard M', 'By Esthelle E', 'By Bruno V', 'By César A Y B', 'By Peter K', 'By Nareg K', 'By Maureen M', 'By Ernesto M', 'By Aishwar D', 'By Jose J P N', 'By Jan N', 'By Yoel S', 'By Bob H', 'By Emmanuel D', 'By Tyson W B', 'By Anna S K']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 25, 2018', 'Jun 08, 2019', 'Jun 01, 2019', 'May 25, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Aug 25, 2018', 'Oct 09, 2018', 'Oct 11, 2018', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Oct 06, 2017', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Feb 23, 2018', 'Mar 22, 2018']</review_date></doc>