<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_405</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/bd2k-lincs</course_url><course_name>Big Data Science with the BD2K-LINCS Data Coordination and Integration Center</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Avi Ma’ayan, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>The Library of Integrative Network-based Cellular Signatures (LINCS) is an NIH Common Fund program. The idea is to perturb different types of human cells with many different types of perturbations such as: drugs and other small molecules; genetic manipulations such as knockdown or overexpression of single genes; manipulation of the extracellular microenvironment conditions, for example, growing cells on different surfaces, and more. These perturbations are applied to various types of human cells including induced pluripotent stem cells from patients, differentiated into various lineages such as neurons or cardiomyocytes. Then, to better understand the molecular networks that are affected by these perturbations, changes in level of many different variables are measured including: mRNAs, proteins, and metabolites, as well as cellular phenotypic changes such as changes in cell morphology. The BD2K-LINCS Data Coordination and Integration Center (DCIC) is commissioned to organize, analyze, visualize and integrate this data with other publicly available relevant resources. In this course we briefly introduce the DCIC and the various Centers that collect data for LINCS. We then cover metadata and how metadata is linked to ontologies. We then present data processing and normalization methods to clean and harmonize LINCS data. This follow discussions about how data is served as RESTful APIs. Most importantly, the course covers computational methods including: data clustering, gene-set enrichment analysis, interactive data visualization, and supervised learning. Finally, we introduce crowdsourcing/citizen-science projects where students can work together in teams to extract expression signatures from public databases and then query such collections of signatures against LINCS data for predicting small molecules as potential therapeutics.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Health Informatics</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Library of Integrated Network-based Cellular Signatures (LINCS) Program Overview//Metadata and Ontologies//Serving Data with APIs//Bioinformatics Pipelines//The Harmonizome//Data Normalization//Data Clustering//Midterm Exam//Enrichment Analysis//Machine Learning//Benchmarking//Interactive Data Visualization//Crowdsourcing Projects//Final Exam</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Layers of Cellular Regulation and Omics Technologies', 'The Connectivity Map', 'Geometrical View of the Connectivity Map Concept', 'LINCS Data and Signature Generation Centers', 'BD2K-LINCS Data Coordination and Integration Center', 'Induced Pluripotent Stem Cells (iPSCs)', 'Introduction to LINCS L1000 Data', 'L1000 Characteristic Direction Signature Search Engine (L1000CDS2) Demo'], ['Introduction to Metadata and Ontologies | Part 1', 'Introduction to Metadata and Ontologies | Part 2'], ['Accessing and Serving Data through RESTful APIs | Part 1', 'Accessing and Serving Data through RESTful APIs | Part 2'], ['Analyzing Big Data with Computational Pipelines'], ['The Harmonizome Concept', 'Processing Datasets | Part 1', 'Processing Datasets | Part 2', 'Processing Datasets | Part 3'], ['Data Normalization | Part 1', 'Data Normalization | Part 2'], ['Data Clustering | Part 1 | Introduction', 'Data Clustering | Part 2 | Distance Functions ', 'Data Clustering | Part 3 | Algorithms and Evaluation'], ['Midterm Exam'], ['Enrichment Analysis | Part 1', 'Enrichment Analysis | Part 2', 'Enrichr Demo'], ['Introduction to Machine Learning | Part 1', 'Introduction to Machine Learning | Part 2 ', 'Introduction to Machine Learning | Part 3'], ['Benchmarking | Part 1', 'Benchmarking | Part 2'], ['Interactive Data Visualization with E-Charts', 'Visualizing Data using Interactive Clustergrams Built with D3.js | Part 1', 'Visualizing Data using Interactive Clustergrams Built with D3.js | Part 2', 'Visualizing Data using Interactive Clustergrams Built with D3.js | Part 3'], ['Microtasks and GEO2Enrichr Demo', 'L1000-2-P100 Megatask Challenge'], ['Final Exam']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['excellent oppurtunity for the data science learners', 'Fun, fascinating, and informative! ', 'A very practical courses. Very good introduction to Big Data sources and Computational Analysis tool. ', 'I recommend it, good materials, very instructive and a good level. Very interesting course. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Hemasree', 'By Ezra L', 'By Musalula S', 'By Jose M V']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 19, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2018', 'Jan 21, 2017', 'Jul 29, 2017']</review_date></doc>