<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_161</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/dataviz-visual-analytics</course_url><course_name>Visual Analytics with Tableau</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Suk S. Brar, M.B.A.</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this third course of the specialization, we’ll drill deeper into the tools Tableau offers in the areas of charting, dates, table calculations and mapping. We’ll explore the best choices for charts, based on the type of data you are using. We’ll look at specific types of charts including scatter plots, Gantt charts, histograms, bullet charts and several others, and we’ll address charting guidelines. We’ll define discrete and continuous dates, and examine when to use each one to explain your data.  You’ll learn how to create custom and quick table calculations and how to create parameters. We’ll also introduce mapping and explore how Tableau can use different types of geographic data, how to connect to multiple data sources and how to create custom maps.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Visual Analytics//Map//Tableau Software//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started and Charting//Dates//Table Calculations//Mapping</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Visual Analytics with Tableau Introduction', 'Introduction to Charting', 'Tableau Charts', 'Colors, Shapes, and Sizes', 'Dual Line Charts', 'Tableau Tooltip', 'Charting Guidelines: Bar Charts, Line Graphs, Pie Charts', 'Charting Guidelines: Maps, Scatter Plots, Gantt Charts, Bubble Charts', 'Charting Guidelines: Histograms, Bullet Charts, Heat Maps and Highlight Tables', 'Charting Guidelines: Treemaps and Box-and-Whisker Plots'], ['Introduction to Dates', 'Discrete vs. Continuous Dates', 'Date Hierarchies', 'Converting Discrete and Continuous Dates', 'Tableau Calculated Fields'], ['Introduction to Table Calculations', 'Calculated Fields', 'Quick Table Calculations', 'Custom Table Calculations', 'Filters', 'Parameters'], ['Introduction to Mapping', 'Working with Geographic Data', 'Shapes, Colors, and Sizes', 'Custom Mapping Techniques', 'Custom Geocoding', 'Dual Layer Mapping', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Disappointing. Very disappointing. Here is why:', "The content is essentially a subset of the information available in the free tutorials on Tableau's website. And a pretty small subset with that; the total length of the course is less than most of the MOOCs I have taken have for one week. ", 'This course is at best OK. Only covers the bare minimum. But what is very frustrating is that the assignment instructions are very poorly worded. It is confusing and the expectations are not clearly led out. This results in the students have to interpret what the author wants. Overall this left a very bad taste. It does not meet Coursera standard or what is the standard in other courses.', "Assignment exercises have missing instructions and even after so many threads about it, no actions have been taken by instructors. Moreover, less emphasis is on teaching practical applications of the tableau. Overall I think it's a very basic course with bad assignments.", 'Tests material it did not teach. Has assignments that require knowledge of business and sales. ', 'The videos for this course seemed to be 30% recap of the prior lesson, and 20% restatement of what was learned.  Some even duplicated their own content in the restatement.  The material covered was simply running through each of the menus in Tableau.  Again, this material may be of use, but would be better as a primer for the class rather than presented as useful, paid content.  Terribly disappointed.', 'Thumbs Up!', 'Excelente curso, muy bien impartido, muy didáctico.', 'simply the best', 'all your technical expectation of Tableau for beginner is here', 'That is excellent course ', 'Great course for the beginners!', 'It was a very good course', 'Great course', 'Very good explanation of the different visual techniques within Tableau.', 'Good info with great Quality', 'I liked how this course really got to the point quickly and then moved on.  Well done.', 'I liked it', 'Excellent course !, I learned a lot', 'So Far, This is a Very Good course design. However, if it is possible, more practice assignment will be much better for learning and improving the skill.', "Good intro to Tableau. The instructor is crystal clear. The case study is pretty good, it's very satisfactory to understand at the end what is wrong with this company.", None, 'Amazing :) ', 'Great Course', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Luca N', 'By Florent B', 'By Saptarshi B', 'By kartikey d', 'By Lydia D', 'By Larry C', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By José E B C', 'By Snehal B', 'By Trisya K S S', 'By hoda', 'By Xianhui W', 'By Kingsley', 'By René G B', 'By Khalid S', 'By Ajith K', 'By Patrick W', 'By Anastasiia T', 'By Karina S', 'By Sy Y W', 'By Florian B', 'By PRABHU N S', 'By Ahmed T', 'By Irvin Y D M', 'By Troy G']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 17, 2017', 'Jan 20, 2017', 'Sep 11, 2017', 'Jul 02, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2018', 'Mar 13, 2017', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Jul 12, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2017', 'Oct 16, 2017', 'Jan 03, 2018', 'Apr 12, 2018', 'Apr 19, 2017', 'Jun 12, 2017', 'May 08, 2018', 'Aug 31, 2017']</review_date></doc>