<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_175</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/managing-data-analysis</course_url><course_name>Managing Data Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>This one-week course describes the process of analyzing data and how to manage that process. We describe the iterative nature of data analysis and the role of stating a sharp question, exploratory data analysis, inference, formal statistical modeling, interpretation, and communication. In addition, we will describe how to direct analytic activities within a team and to drive the data analysis process towards coherent and useful results. 

This is a focused course designed to rapidly get you up to speed on the process of data analysis and how it can be managed. Our goal was to make this as convenient as possible for you without sacrificing any essential content. We've left the technical information aside so that you can focus on managing your team and moving it forward.

After completing this course you will know how to….

1. Describe the basic data analysis iteration
2. Identify different types of questions and translate them to specific datasets
3. Describe different types of data pulls
4. Explore datasets to determine if data are appropriate for a given question
5. Direct model building efforts in common data analyses
6. Interpret the results from common data analyses
7. Integrate statistical findings to form coherent data analysis presentations

Commitment: 1 week of study, 4-6 hours

Course cover image by fdecomite. Creative Commons BY https://flic.kr/p/4HjmvD</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Leadership and Management</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Communication//Interpretation//Exploratory Data Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Managing Data Analysis</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['What this Course is About', 'Data Analysis Iteration', 'Stages of Data Analysis', 'Six Types of Questions', 'Characteristics of a Good Question', 'Exploratory Data Analysis Goals &amp; Expectations', 'Using Statistical Models to Explore Your Data (Part 1)', 'Using Statistical Models to Explore Your Data (Part 2)', 'Exploratory Data Analysis: When to Stop', 'Making Inferences from Data: Introduction', 'Populations Come in Many Forms', 'Inference: What Can Go Wrong', 'General Framework', 'Associational Analyses', 'Prediction Analyses', 'Inference vs. Prediction', 'Interpreting Your Results', 'Routine Communication in Data Analysis', 'Making a Data Analysis Presentation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course gives me a general understanding of the whole process of data analyses. Pretty good! ', 'Very good online  learning course regarding Data Analysis', 'A', "I've taken the first three courses at this point and this has easily been my favourite. I particularly enjoy the focus on practical examples. Breaking down the analysis conceptually first then highlighting how this can be applied with a more complex and practical context. ", 'Very well conceived course and excellently delivered...clear and concise ', 'Awesome ', 'Não encontrei onde baixar o certificado ...', 'this is a very deep reflection in Data Managing. Amazing course', 'Very valuable and interesting info. ', 'thank you!', 'An awesome course completed', '  Interesting for a Non-Data Science Executive despite some minor spelling errors in video transcripts.  ', 'Material is explained really good and is focused on practical issues.', 'Superb!!!', "This course provided me with a lot of direction for some data I'm trying to understand at work. It also made me aware of some important considerations I need to make and structure I should follow when looking at the data, so that my results will be more meaningful. I honestly thought the last section about presentation wouldn't be useful at all, but even that section provided some important insight that I hadn't previously considered, and made me feel excited about eventually presenting the results of my data analysis to my organization.", "This was the best part of Specialization until now. As Product Manager I do think it's was great to understand concepts about data analysis and how to manage a team.", 'Teachers, Content and knowledge is amazing valuable for my professional development. Highly recommended ', "Really liked Roger's enthusiasm for the topic!", 'Great course and the materials and the tutors are great', 'Overall, the sharpness and clarity of the course is quite remarkable', 'Short yet nice :)', "It's a good course, and the professor is good too. I highly recommend it. = Es un buen curso, y el profesor es bueno también. Lo recomiendo completamente.", 'My name is Jose Antonio. I am looking for a new Data Scientist career (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseantonio11)', 'Good course. ', 'Great, most useful of the slew of courses']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ying C', 'By Kalvin L', 'By Kim K R', 'By Jason C', 'By HARI M', 'By Ajayi I M', 'By WILLIAM E A', 'By Dago', 'By Alberto M B', 'By Hector R C C', 'By Alzum S M', 'By Elton K', 'By Zheleznov K', 'By Prasenjit P', 'By Rebecca T', 'By Alexander I F', 'By Wladimir R', 'By Kristin C', 'By Muhire I', 'By Theodore K', 'By Vijai K S', 'By Sebastián A P R', 'By Jose A R N', 'By Parkash B', 'By Kevin M']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 28, 2015', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Aug 03, 2018', 'Aug 08, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'Aug 25, 2018', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Sep 01, 2017', 'Feb 10, 2016', 'Sep 11, 2016', 'Jul 09, 2017', 'Feb 05, 2017', 'Jul 03, 2017']</review_date></doc>