<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_361</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/digital-footprint</course_url><course_name>Digital Footprint</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Louise Connelly</course_instructor><course_introduction>If I Googled you, what would I find?

As we move around the online world we leave tracks and traces of our activity all the time: social media accounts, tagged images, professional presences, scraps of text, but also many artefacts we don't always realise we are leaving behind, or that others leave about us.  

In this course you will hear from a range of experts and you will have an opportunity to explore and reflect on your own online tracks and traces, to understand why your digital footprint is important. We will introduce you to some of the tools and approaches to effectively manage your online presence (or digital footprint).  

The course will focus on the different dimensions of a digital footprint, including developing an effective online presence, managing your privacy, creating opportunities for networking, balancing and managing professional and personal presences (eprofessionalism). By the end of this course (MOOC) you should be equipped to ensure that your digital footprint works for you, whether you want to be more private online, or are looking to create a more effective and impactful presence.  

You can also join the conversation on Twitter using the hashtag #DFMOOC and follow us @DFMOOC

We hope you enjoy the course!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Personal Development.Personal Development</course_category><course_tag>Digital Footprint//E-Professional//Social Media//Privacy</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>The University of Edinburgh</course_orgnization><course_chapter>What makes an online presence effective?//Why does your digital footprint matter?//What does it mean to be an effective online professional?</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the course and week 1 (Nicola Osborne)', 'What is a digital footprint?', 'The Uncontainable Self - Part 1 (Nicola Osborne)', 'The Uncontainable Self and Professional Identity - Part 2 (Nicola Osborne)', 'Taking Gaming Into Adulthood (Dr Jill MacKay)', 'Who owns your data? - Part 1 (Nicola Osborne)', 'Who Owns Your Data? - Part 2 (Nicola Osborne)', 'Who Owns Your Data? - Part 3 (Nicola Osborne)'], ['Introduction to week 2 (Dr Louise Connelly)', 'Step 2: Zeemap Activity - Review (Dr Louise Connelly)', 'Creating an effective online presence (Dr Louise Connelly)', 'Digital Footprints (Dr Rachel Buchanan)', 'Managing your online presence (Interview with Dr Ben Marder)', 'Tag Review Function, Taking Control Back (Dr Ben Marder)', 'Our Data, Our Rights (Interview with Prof. Lilian Edwards)', 'Death and Privacy (Interview  with Prof. Lilian Edwards)', 'Data after death (Interview with Prof. Lilian Edwards)', 'Privacy Tips 1-6 (Nicola Osborne)', 'Privacy Tips 7-12 (Nicola Osborne)', 'Audience online, time/longevity of data, visibility  (Interview with David Brake)', 'Audience (Interview with David Brake)', 'Time (Interview with David Brake)', 'One piece of advice about managing your digital footprint'], ['Welcome to week 3 (Dr Louise Connelly)', 'Professional networking online (Rebecca Valentine)', 'Recruitment &amp; business (Copil Yanez)', 'Student leaders and online presence (Tanya Lubicz-Nawrocka)', 'Professional bodies (Dr Louise Connelly)', 'E-professionalism &amp; Nursing - Part 1 (Interview with Sharon Levy)', 'E-Professionalism &amp; Nursing - Part 2 (Interview with Sharon Levy)', 'The E-Nurse (Interview with Sharon Levy)', 'Online Academic Presence (Dr Jill MacKay)', 'Academic presence: social sciences - part 1 (Interview with Dr Karen Gregory)', 'Academic presence: social sciences - Part 2 (Interview with Dr Karen Gregory)', 'How social media has been beneficial', 'One piece of advice about creating a professional online presence']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 5 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Easy clear valuable course to know about how online presence is important, and how to manage it.', 'Great course, I am refreshing my existing knowledge and learn new things at the same time.', 'The course is very crispy and creative, loved it!!!', None, 'This course make me update for knowledge', 'I thoroughly enjoyed this course, my objectives were met and the course creators put a lot of thought into ensuring that various options were available to suit different learning styles. Thank you', 'I loved it', "The course is excellent! But should if you feel confident about the way you manage your digital footprint, you won't really learn that much. ", 'This course is wonderful. It was very useful and interesting! ', 'Superb Learning Experience, highly recommend this course.', 'Outstanding experience!', 'Very information course. One must go through this vital course for up-gradation.', 'Really useful, efficient use of my time, very practical.', 'Very very cool!!!', 'It was really interesting to find out more about this topic, thank you!', 'nice course, thank coursera', "Thoughtful, and thought-provoking course on what it means to have a presence online and to be active on social media, in personal and professional capacities. I've been using social media for years, and this helped me to think more about how the landscape has changed, how my needs and wants for social media have changed, and how I can be more proactive in making sure it works for me. ", 'Solid information. Useful for students.', 'What I learned: Proactively shape your own digital identity to reflect your professional and personal views. The section on the legacy of my digital footprint was something I had not considered. ', 'It was a very good introductory course to raise awareness of the topic, but it can go a bit deeper into privacy topics. It has the time, potential and the teachers are very good as well. ', 'Its a nice and informative course letting now know about the various risks and opportunities that one has when they go online . It shows us how to be aware of all things we do online and what precautions to take. ', 'This course is a must for anyone who uses social media or the internet in general...which means everyone!', 'a very good course helped me a lot', 'Interesting and fun way of learning', 'I really wanted to know some more interesting and unusual facts about footstep of famous people. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Abdullah S M', 'By Edyta S', 'By I C S V ', 'By Pierre S', 'By Apichart T', 'By TOLULOPE M ', 'By Sylwia K', 'By Eunice S G', 'By Iryna K', 'By Arushi M', 'By Голубев И Ф', 'By Dr T P J', 'By Claire P', 'By Giuseppe ', 'By Загрядский Г В', 'By manhar', 'By Scott K', 'By Kevin M', 'By Madeline L', 'By Maria J A', 'By Varun A', 'By Kantesh G', 'By Marshall P', 'By Mawsamee D B', 'By Геворгян А С']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 24, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2017', 'Jun 21, 2017', 'May 19, 2017', 'Jul 24, 2017', 'Aug 14, 2017', 'Feb 02, 2018', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Aug 11, 2017', 'Apr 21, 2018', 'Mar 06, 2018', 'May 13, 2017', 'Dec 30, 2017', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'Mar 11, 2018', 'Aug 17, 2018', 'May 23, 2019', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Oct 06, 2017', 'Oct 16, 2017', 'Jun 27, 2017', 'Jan 14, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2017', 'Oct 08, 2017', 'Jun 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>