<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_166</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/text-mining</course_url><course_name>Text Mining and Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>ChengXiang Zhai</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will cover the major techniques for mining and analyzing text data to discover interesting patterns, extract useful knowledge, and support decision making, with an emphasis on statistical approaches that can be generally applied to arbitrary text data in any natural language with no or minimum human effort. 

Detailed analysis of text data requires understanding of natural language text, which is known to be a difficult task for computers. However, a number of statistical approaches have been shown to work well for the "shallow" but robust analysis of text data for pattern finding and knowledge discovery. You will learn the basic concepts, principles, and major algorithms in text mining and their potential applications.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Clustering Algorithms//Text Mining//Probabilistic Models//Sentiment Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Orientation//Week 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4//Week 5//Week 6</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Text Mining and Analytics', 'Course Prerequisites &amp; Completion'], ['1.1 Overview Text Mining and Analytics: Part 1', '1.2 Overview Text Mining and Analytics: Part 2', '1.3 Natural Language Content Analysis: Part 1', '1.4 Natural Language Content Analysis: Part 2', '1.5 Text Representation: Part 1', '1.6 Text Representation: Part 2', '1.7 Word Association Mining and Analysis', '1.8 Paradigmatic Relation Discovery Part 1', '1.9 Paradigmatic Relation Discovery Part 2'], ['2.1 Syntagmatic Relation Discovery: Entropy', '2.2 Syntagmatic Relation Discovery: Conditional Entropy', '2.3 Syntagmatic Relation Discovery: Mutual Information: Part 1', '2.4 Syntagmatic Relation Discovery: Mutual Information: Part 2', '2.5 Topic Mining and Analysis: Motivation and Task Definition', '2.6 Topic Mining and Analysis: Term as Topic', '2.7 Topic Mining and Analysis: Probabilistic Topic Models', '2.8 Probabilistic Topic Models: Overview of Statistical Language Models: Part 1', '2.9 Probabilistic Topic Models: Overview of Statistical Language Models: Part 2', '2.10 Probabilistic Topic Models: Mining One Topic'], ['3.1 Probabilistic Topic Models: Mixture of Unigram Language Models', '3.2 Probabilistic Topic Models: Mixture Model Estimation: Part 1', '3.3 Probabilistic Topic Models: Mixture Model Estimation: Part 2', '3.4 Probabilistic Topic Models: Expectation-Maximization Algorithm: Part 1', '3.5 Probabilistic Topic Models: Expectation-Maximization Algorithm: Part 2', '3.6 Probabilistic Topic Models: Expectation-Maximization Algorithm: Part 3', '3.7 Probabilistic Latent Semantic Analysis (PLSA): Part 1', '3.8 Probabilistic Latent Semantic Analysis (PLSA): Part 2', '3.9 Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA): Part 1', '3.10 Latent Dirichlet Allocation (LDA): Part 2'], ['4.1 Text Clustering: Motivation', '4.2 Text Clustering: Generative Probabilistic Models Part 1', '4.3 Text Clustering: Generative Probabilistic Models Part 2', '4.4 Text Clustering: Generative Probabilistic Models Part 3', '4.5 Text Clustering: Similarity-based Approaches', '4.6 Text Clustering: Evaluation', '4.7 Text Categorization: Motivation', '4.8 Text Categorization: Methods', '4.9 Text Categorization: Generative Probabilistic Models'], ['5.1 Text Categorization: Discriminative Classifier Part 1', '5.2 Text Categorization: Discriminative Classifier Part 2', '5.3 Text Categorization: Evaluation Part 1', '5.4 Text Categorization: Evaluation Part 2', '5.5 Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis: Motivation', '5.6 Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis: Sentiment Classification', '5.7 Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis: Ordinal Logistic Regression'], ['6.1 Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis: Latent Aspect Rating Analysis Part 1', '6.2 Opinion Mining and Sentiment Analysis: Latent Aspect Rating Analysis Part 2', '6.3 Text-Based Prediction', '6.4 Contextual Text Mining: Motivation', '6.5 Contextual Text Mining: Contextual Probabilistic Latent Semantic Analysis', '6.6 Contextual Text Mining: Mining Topics with Social Network Context', '6.7 Contextual Text Mining: Mining Casual Topics with Time Series Supervision', '6.8 Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 20 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Annoyingly, the specific pre-requisites can't be determined until AFTER enrolling.  This course is in C++, so if you're not a C++ programmer, it's probably not a good idea to purchase this.", 'I got the sense that this course needs to be updated. Some of the quizzes covered work that had not been treated up to that point and the programming assignment did not work with the most recent version of the MeTA toolkit. For a course of this stature I would have expected a lot more attention to such detail. It would also appear as though the owners of the course material are not present on the forums with students left to their own devices.This course as well as the Text Retrieval one does not compare well with the Machine Learning course from Stanford offered on Coursera when considering the above issues.Some work is required I believe', 'The course focuses more on the theoretical side with no practical examples. It also does not explain these theoretical concepts in detail enough. It was difficult for me as a new learner in the text analytics field to follow such dense theoretical concepts.', 'The content of the course is quite good. Professor Cheng explains the concepts well and I did learn quite a bit. However I feel that these courses have been all but abandoned by any support personnel. So far this is not a series I would recommend for anything but watching video lectures.', 'This course is a pretty good resource for full-time graduates who are doing research in Natural Language Processing, but not for other people who want to learn in part-time some concrete skills to resolve specific text mining problems.', 'The topics were interesting and Cheng was very motivated.', 'I didnt feel like continuing, I had problem at job for which i enrolled in course,to do efficient text mining..Its all theoretical..Too much information at one short and no examples relating to it', "This is a great course for data science.  I hope to use many of the techniques that were explained.  There is plenty of cutting edge material here.  It is essential for modern data science practice in my opinion. It's fairly advanced level.  Students of this course will do just fine though, if they already have the ability to pass university level undergraduate computer science courses.", 'Very good course thank you', 'I think the course has very limited practical problems; so for beginners in NLP and text analytics, it is very difficult to grasp all the theoretical concepts presented in the course.', '\n', 'Presentation has a lot of room for improvement to present the information where other people can comprehend the topic.', 'Excellent course the provides comprehensive knowledge on Text Mining and Ananlytics in all its dimensions.', 'It is rare to find an online course that explains the statistics and intuition behind text mining and machine learning algorithm! ', 'The course was very challenging and i learn a lot of new things from the course, this will help to complete  my project.', 'Great..Clear. Thanks', 'Excellent course.', 'Useful course to build foundation for text mining and NLP especially for beginners.', 'The content was very useful, and the preparation of the course denoted much care and preparation by the teacher. I would love to see some modern topics like word embeddings covered in the course!', "The content layout of this course is very good. It gives a big picture about text mining. It's very hard to explain text mining just in 6 weeks course. But Professor did it. I hope professor can provide further class of text mining, provide more detail case to explain some algorithm not covering in this class and cover more new topic like knowledge graph etc.", None, 'As a former compute science undergrad who wanted to get more knowledge into ML and NLP, I found this course to be both a very nice introduction and a progressive dive into more recent and advanced techniques. The structure suited my needs very well and was easy to follow along.', 'The content of Text Mining and Analytics is very comprehensive and deep. More practise about how formula works would be better. Quiz could be not tough to be completed after attending every lectures.', None, 'E']</reviews><reviewers>['By David C B', 'By Paul N', 'By Essam D', 'By Gary C', 'By 象道', 'By John', 'By Shreya P', 'By geoffrey a', 'By Samir A G', 'By Sawal M', 'By Lee X A', 'By Scott C', 'By Yugandhar D', 'By Yaoyao D', 'By YASH L', 'By Luis F Y B', 'By Gourav A', 'By Julie W', 'By Javier S', 'By GANG L', 'By Hernan C V', 'By Julien P', 'By David C', 'By Jose A E H', 'By Deepak S']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 10, 2017', 'Jun 08, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2016', 'Jul 24, 2017', 'Dec 31, 2016', 'Feb 07, 2018', 'Jul 04, 2017', 'Sep 06, 2017', 'Feb 25, 2017', 'Apr 18, 2017', 'Jul 18, 2016', 'Jul 06, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Sep 29, 2018', 'Oct 26, 2018', 'Jan 22, 2018', 'Jun 07, 2017', 'Jan 15, 2018', 'May 04, 2017', 'Jul 06, 2017', 'Mar 25, 2018', 'Feb 10, 2017', 'Aug 11, 2016']</review_date></doc>