<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_9</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/sql-for-data-science</course_url><course_name>SQL for Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sadie St. Lawrence</course_instructor><course_introduction>As data collection has increased exponentially, so has the need for people skilled at using and interacting with data; to be able to think critically, and provide insights to make better decisions and optimize their businesses. This is a data scientist, “part mathematician, part computer scientist, and part trend spotter” (SAS Institute, Inc.). According to Glassdoor, being a data scientist is the best job in America; with a median base salary of $110,000 and thousands of job openings at a time. The skills necessary to be a good data scientist include being able to retrieve and work with data, and to do that you need to be well versed in SQL, the standard language for communicating with database systems.

This course is designed to give you a primer in the fundamentals of SQL and working with data so that you can begin analyzing it for data science purposes. You will begin to ask the right questions and come up with good answers to deliver valuable insights for your organization. This course starts with the basics and assumes you do not have any knowledge or skills in SQL. It will build on that foundation and gradually have you write both simple and complex queries to help you select data from tables.  You'll start to work with different types of data like strings and numbers and discuss methods to filter and pare down your results. 

You will create new tables and be able to move data into them. You will learn common operators and how to combine the data. You will use case statements and concepts like data governance and profiling. You will discuss topics on data, and practice using real-world programming assignments. You will interpret the structure, meaning, and relationships in source data and use SQL as a professional to shape your data for targeted analysis purposes. 

Although we do not have any specific prerequisites or software requirements to take this course, a simple text editor is recommended for the final project. So what are you waiting for? This is your first step in landing a job in the best occupation in the US and soon the world!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Data Analysis//Sqlite//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started and Selecting &amp; Retrieving Data with SQL//Filtering, Sorting, and Calculating Data with SQL//Subqueries and Joins in SQL//Modifying and Analyzing Data with SQL</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Module Introduction', 'What is SQL Anyway?', 'Data Models, Part 1: Thinking About Your Data', 'Data Models, Part 2: The Evolution of Data Models', 'Data Models, Part 3: Relational vs. Transactional Models', 'Retrieving Data with a SELECT Statement', 'Creating Tables', 'Creating Temporary Tables', 'Adding Comments to SQL', 'Summary'], ['Module Introduction', 'Basics of Filtering with SQL', 'Advanced Filtering: IN, OR, and NOT', 'Using Wildcards in SQL', 'Sorting with ORDER BY', 'Math Operations', 'Aggregate Functions', 'Grouping Data with SQL', 'Putting it All Together'], ['Module Introduction', 'Using Subqueries', 'Subquery Best Practices and Considerations', 'Joining Tables: An Introduction', 'Cartesian (Cross) Joins', 'Inner Joins', 'Aliases and Self Joins', 'Advanced Joins: Left, Right, and Full Outer Joins', 'Unions', 'Summary'], ['Module Introduction', 'Working with Text Strings', 'Working with Date and Time Strings', 'Date and Time Strings Examples', 'Case Statements', 'Views', 'Data Governance and Profiling', 'Using SQL for Data Science, Part 1', 'Using SQL for Data Science, Part 2', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 20 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I come from a background of teaching for 18 years, and not in SQL. My biggest criticism for this course is the lack of preparation for the culminating activities. The course saves all the challenging work for the last 2% of the course. Even that would be okay, if you were prepared via practice early on for the rigor at the end. All the assistants and fellow students try their best to help each other in the forums without cheating, but it shouldn't be this way. If so many students are needing so much help in the final part of the course, then that speaks to ineffective and inadequate instruction early in the course. ", 'Great for complete beginners. ', 'Poorly designed quiz and final project questions combined with a SQL interface which cannot use some of the commands introduced in the lessons leads to tedious parsing of the questions.  But it is short and there appears to be enough students to make the peer review of the final project possible in April 2019.  Not recommended.', 'The videos contain the material necessary to get a basic understanding for relational databases and sql. ', 'This is not a course. It is a presentation of material. The version of SQLite that is provided does not support the important and flexible functions that SQLite normally supports.', 'Instructor seems not to have written or read the script prior to recording - stumbling over her words is distracting and reduces learner comprehension. No way to practice coding with feedback in the module. Practice exercises at the end of the module include no feedback, hints, or examples - it may as well be a test. I stopped after two weeks - I was wasting my time. ', 'Pretty decent introductory course to SQL.', "The lectures are littered with sloppy errors that haven't been fixed or acknowledged even after multiple people have pointed them out more than a year ago. Some of these errors seriously impede understanding and progress.", 'Well the examples were very accurate for the course. I liked the final assessment specially it was a very good practice', 'The course met my expectations as someone with no real prior knowledge. I now feel much more confident. ', 'I dislike being negative about courses, but I really struggled on this one.  The lecture videos felt disconnected from the coursework, and it was often unclear what the lectures were supposed to be teaching me.  There was very little detail in the lectures themselves, but rather vague bulletpointed lists that the lecturer just read out verbatim.  ', "Course was informative and a decent foundation, but the lecture delivery was incredibly frustrating. Some concepts were explained very poorly, and I'll have to supplement how parts of the basics are used (e.g. Views, Self Joins, Having, European Date treatment). Often the lecturer tripped over sentences inserting phrases that made no sense, couldn't read words on the screen correctly etc. Also, needed FAR more examples for a couple of the more involved commands. Syntax of code writing changed mid lecture series for one of the weeks, and the practice questions in W2 had completely inconsistent code with what was provided in lectures. This course has potential, but the delivery must be *vastly* improved", 'The course is basically theoretical. There is not any practice during the course except for the quizes and the final project. I had to complement the theory I learned here with another online course that focuses on the practice. ', 'many of the quiz problems are poorly constructed!   We are told after the fact "ohh... we forgot to tell you the value is a string, so you need to fix that field before attempting the min/max we are asking for." Design a better course!!!!  Going to EdX SQL class instead which uses the DataCamp back end!  ', 'Very clear and useful class! The outline of each module is easy to understand and follow, and the assignment is helpful to strengthen SQL skills.', 'So helpful! Really helped me learn SQL on a level that I am confident enough to add it to my resume. ', 'Good course.  The peer assignments was a bit challenging hence most interesting as well.', 'Great course i had a very good learning experience from this course and what i was expecting from this course i got that knowledge and i am very happy to take this course. thank you so much.', 'This was an amazing course. I learned so much practical and application skills from the course. The lectures are great, as our the assignments and tests.', 'A nice course to get introduced to writing SQL queries in Data science. Provides hands on exercises that boost confidence. Genuinely appreciate the ease with which SQL topics are covered', 'This course is designed with beginners in mind, and it is an excellent introduction to SQL. I intend to further my knowledge of SQL after taking this course. The instructor did a terrific job.', '=)  Very clear walkthrough of important concepts in SQL and why use certain functions for certain tasks.', "The Content of the course is good, quizzes are fine, but the final project is a total mess up, inconsistent and don't contain the course potential, so you won't be able to apply the knowledge by doing it", 'Great course with great learning and an opportunity to apply that learning', 'While I did learn some useful bits, I found the course lacking. I think it could have been much improved if certain conditions would have been met:A. More practice! You don\'t learn a computer language by hearing about it, you learn by using it. The only practice this course had were the quizzes, and they were far from sufficient. I would expect each lesson to be followed by at least some practice. I often found myself venturing to different websites in order to practice what I had learned, and learned more from that than I did from the actual course.B. Better explanations. I found the explanations short and sometimes lacking. Moreover, at times there was no synchronization between what the instructor was saying and what was presented on screen (e.g. she was talking about products when the example presented data of employess). It\'s a small thing but can be very confusing. It is very important to be precise here. Again, I found myself reading elsewhere in order to better understand certain concepts, which I might as well have learned elsewhere altogether.C. Examples! Again, you don\'t learn a computer language by hearing about it. You learn by using it or by seeing how it is used. Whenever I\'m taught something, I want to be shown examples of possible ways to use it. Examples were scarce and incomprehensive.D. Applicability. The course is called "SQL for Data Science", yet I found very little in the way of applying SQL to data science. I would expect a lot more tips and tricks and examples of real-life problems and how an actual data scientist would tackle them. There was almost none of that. There were positives as well. The instructor was pleasant, the course was pretty well structured and did provide an introduction (although not much more) to SQL. But I did not get what I was hoping for.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Luke F', 'By Leo U', 'By Finn O', 'By Luca T', 'By Gary B', 'By Laura W', 'By Chutian Z', 'By Marwan D', 'By Andres H', 'By Alexandra R', 'By André A', 'By Conor M', 'By Veronica G S', 'By Miguel M', 'By Maxine L', 'By Megan H', 'By Manish R', 'By Manas S', 'By Gary L', 'By Nikhil N P', 'By Avinash M', 'By Chloe W', 'By Sergii S', 'By Nikhil K s', 'By Omer G']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 30, 2019', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Apr 30, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'May 16, 2019', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'May 25, 2019', 'May 01, 2019', 'Jul 09, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2018', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'May 03, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2018', 'Jul 17, 2019', 'Oct 31, 2018', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jul 02, 2018']</review_date></doc>