<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_423</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/roadmap-success-digital-manufacturing-design</course_url><course_name>Roadmap to Success in Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Amy Moore</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learners will create a roadmap to achieve their own personal goals related to the digital manufacturing and design (DM&amp;D) profession, which will help them leverage relevant opportunities. The culminating project provides a tangible element to include in their professional portfolios that showcases their knowledge of Industry 4.0.

This project is part of the Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology specialization that explores the many facets of manufacturing’s “Fourth Revolution,”  aka Industry 4.0. To learn more about the specialization and its courses, please watch the overview video by copying and pasting the following link into your web browser: https://youtu.be/wETK1O9c-CA</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Mechanical Engineering</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Project Definition//Self-Assessment//Network Exploration//Roadmap Execution//Final Project Submission and Peer Review Evaluation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction: Roadmap to Success in Digital Manufacturing and Design', 'Project Definition', 'Industry Opportunities', 'Traditional vs. Digital Manufacturing Roles', 'Next Generation', 'Project Charter'], ['Self-Assessment: Strength, Weaknesses, Opportunities, and Threats (SWOT) Analysis', 'A Business Case for Digital Implementation', 'Your Future in Digital Manufacturing and Design', 'Self-Marketing Tools'], ['Finding a Mentor', 'Network Expansion', 'Safeguard Your Online Image', 'Creating an Elevator Pitch'], ['Roadmap to Success in Digital Manufacturing and Design Execution Plan'], ['Final Project Submission and Evaluation: Congratulations!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 5 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['thank you', 'Really enjoyed this course and the entire specialization. I got a lot of useful information from it.', 'It was a great experience and everyone interested in Industry 4.0 should take this specialization. Especially, mechanical engineers and industrial engineers as well as engineering technicians.', 'Great Course', 'wonderfull space for learning', 'Good information and resources for creating a professional roadmap.', "it's ok"]</reviews><reviewers>['By Tejash y T G', 'By Scott C', 'By Vancho D', 'By yashar k s', 'By CATHERINE A A V', 'By David C', 'By Eric E B T A']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 07, 2018', 'Oct 15, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2018', 'Jun 02, 2018', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2018', 'Jun 13, 2019']</review_date></doc>