<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_39</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-plotting</course_url><course_name>Applied Plotting, Charting &amp; Data Representation in Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Christopher Brooks</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce the learner to information visualization basics, with a focus on reporting and charting using the matplotlib library. The course will start with a design and information literacy perspective, touching on what makes a good and bad visualization, and what statistical measures translate into in terms of visualizations. The second week will focus on the technology used to make visualizations in python, matplotlib, and introduce users to best practices when creating basic charts and how to realize design decisions in the framework. The third week will be a tutorial of functionality available in matplotlib, and demonstrate a variety of basic statistical charts helping learners to identify when a particular method is good for a particular problem. The course will end with a discussion of other forms of structuring and visualizing data. 

This course should be taken after Introduction to Data Science in Python and before the remainder of the Applied Data Science with Python courses: Applied Machine Learning in Python, Applied Text Mining in Python, and Applied Social Network Analysis in Python.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Matplotlib</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Principles of Information Visualization//Module 2: Basic Charting//Module 3: Charting Fundamentals//Module 4: Applied Visualizations</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'About the Professor: Christopher Brooks', 'Tools for Thinking about Design (Alberto Cairo)', 'Graphical heuristics: Data-ink ratio (Edward Tufte)', 'Graphical heuristics: Chart junk (Edward Tufte)', 'Graphical heuristics: Lie Factor and Spark Lines (Edward Tufte)', 'The Truthful Art (Alberto Cairo)'], ['Introduction', 'Matplotlib Architecture', 'Basic Plotting with Matplotlib', 'Scatterplots', 'Line Plots', 'Bar Charts', 'Dejunkifying a Plot'], ['Subplots', 'Histograms', 'Box Plots', 'Heatmaps', 'Animation', 'Interactivity'], ['Plotting with Pandas', 'Seaborn', 'Becoming an Independent Data Scientist']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course can be summarized as: "OK, here are some tools that can be used: now read the documentation, Stack Overflow and some papers that we give you links to". Each week there are just few videos. What I expect from a Course are baby steps and clear guidance about good practices. Of course you can learn it all from the Internet - I am taking a Course to get something I will not easily find elsewhere: a good teacher who will guide me through optimal approaches. ', "The grading by peers system coupled with the unlocking next week lesson is really aweful. I can't change to previous session event though I worked through the first lesson fast. Everyone has the same issue on the forum but nobody dares to reply. We get no help nor assitance from the platform. This course is purely money stealing. Run away from this course as soon as possible.", "I don't think the tutorials walk us through what we are supposed to do. I find myself on youtube watching free tutorials on the very subjects I am paying to learn. ", 'The lectures are overloaded with too much information, and the concepts are presented in a complicated way. I wish the courses in this specialization were self sufficient. It just does not feel like I am getting proficient at any of this even though I can get the assignments done on my own. there should be ample practice exercises with the aim of burning the syntaxes and concepts to memory which is usually not the case. This eventually leads to half hearted learning where students are expected to do every thing on there own. I am disappointed.  The course can be improved by going deep into the concepts and providing additional resources for students to explore.', 'This is an interesting course, but the professor really does not spend enough time teaching the topic. It\'s like as if he expects that giving us a very high level overview on a subject (e.g., "These are the principles of beauty to follow when making a chart!"), followed by 1-2 very specific cases ("here\'s how to build a scatterplot!") is enough. We\'re then expected to teach ourselves in order to be able to turn in assignments. I understand that a core skill of any programmer is the capacity to search for code snippets online as well as ask questions to the community, but for an introductory course on Matplotlib, I\'d expect more teaching of the subject matter. ', 'assignments are unclear and provide few explicit resources for users less familiar with statistics. crucial topics are not discussed and we are instead told to go google them for ourselves, which i could have done without paying for a course.', 'Not very good instructions. The Assignments required just self learning online via other video tutorials/documentation....which defeats the purpose of taking an online course', 'The instructor just read a text without any interest and passion.', 'Cant submit for two weeks but billed monthly, this is bogus.', 'Very helpful to understand what it takes to make a scientific and sensible visual. Recommended for someone who is interested in learning data visualization and does not have a background. ', "Didn't like peer grading as it introduces delays in grade and peers don't have competency to judge my work.", 'Very unresponsible professor. No passion at all!!!!! Did not explain the fundamental concept well. As a result, I do not think I have a deep understangin at all. I spend most my time google in order to finish my assignments.', "instructor advice is primarily to 'use stack overflow'.", "This course was not nearly as valuable to me as the first course in the series.  It breezed through a bunch of different plot types without explaining in enough detail what they would be used for or when you should choose to use them.  At the same time, it also didn't provide enough clear examples of how to do basic things in matplotlib, which seems to me to be a very non-intuitive thing with poor documentation.  I found the first assignment to be very difficult.", 'The only advantage are the assignments and the certificate. But there are better alternatives for information and learning matierals for pandas or matplotlib on youtube or so one. But this course isnt 50 bucks worth it.', 'very much disappointed.so much less content than the first one and it is not self-contained. A lot of things left unexplained and kind of assumed that you knew a lot about python already. I literally took another course in python before finishing up this one.  ', "Peer review of assignment is very time sensitive. I don't feel it useful.", 'This course makes you give up on data science and MOOCs. ', 'Too few lectures with detailed explanations of the functionality of matplotlib. ', 'I feel like this course is bad. Since it basically tell us to search google for everything.', 'Well to be honest youtube videos are quite informative than this.  Opting out from this course.', 'I registered to the whole specialization mainly to take the first three courses. I got stuck in the second (this one about data visualisation) because a file I need for assignment in week 2 is missing. There are many complaints in the forum from those affected (the file is supposed to contain weather data around your location, and it seems to affect some of us in Europe). I jumped to course 3.', "The course takes into account the theoretical approach when creating charts which is something I have never thought of! And I don't think you'll find instructors that will go that deep into theory instead of programming. ", 'Great course, great instructor! I think for me the more difficult was lack of simple practice tasks during course - it will much improve to understand material. Regards, and thanks!', 'Amazing source ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Jan', 'By Huang L', 'By scott m', 'By Sourav P', 'By Alexandre M', 'By David S', 'By William T', 'By Farhad S', 'By John R', 'By Abu S ', 'By Valeriya P', 'By cheting c', 'By George N', 'By Melinda M', 'By Maxim P', 'By Vivian Y Q', 'By Josh C', 'By Eklavya s', 'By Jakob P', 'By Yifei Z', 'By Naveen P', 'By Nicolau G', 'By Yousef A S A', 'By Karol S', 'By Ahmad H S']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 04, 2017', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Sep 15, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2018', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Mar 06, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2017', 'Mar 02, 2018', 'Apr 24, 2017', 'Mar 26, 2017', 'Jul 14, 2018', 'May 05, 2018', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Jun 19, 2017', 'Oct 07, 2017', 'May 15, 2018', 'May 25, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2017', 'Jul 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>