<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_148</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/dataviz-dashboards</course_url><course_name>Creating Dashboards and Storytelling with Tableau</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Govind Acharya</course_instructor><course_introduction>Leveraging the visualizations you created in the previous course, Visual Analytics with Tableau, you will create dashboards that help you identify the story within your data, and you will discover how to use Storypoints to create a powerful story to leave a lasting impression with your audience.

You will balance the goals of your stakeholders with the needs of your end-users, and be able to structure and organize your story for maximum impact. Throughout the course you will apply more advanced functions within Tableau, such as hierarchies, actions and parameters to guide user interactions.  For your final project, you will create a compelling narrative to be delivered in a meeting, as a static report, or in an interactive display online.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Storyboarding//Tableau Software//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Planning and Preproduction: Aligning your Audience, Stakeholders, and Data//Key Metrics, Indicators, and Decision Triggers//Dashboard and Storytelling with Data//Tell the Story of Your Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'What is a Story?', 'Introduction to Planning and Preproduction for Visualizations', 'A Design Checklist of the Who, What, Why, and How', 'Start with Your Stakeholders', 'Addressing Your Audience and Their Context', 'Finding the Story', 'Prioritizing, Optimizing, and Designing the Data Story', 'Case Study - "The Tale of 100 Entrepreneurs" (Part 1)', 'Case Study - "The Tale of 100 Entrepreneurs" (Part 2)', 'Case Study - "The Tale of 100 Entrepreneurs" (Part 3)'], ['Introduction to Key Metrics, Indicators, and Decision Triggers', 'Key Performance Indicators (KPIs)', 'Tableau Calculated Fields and KPIs', 'Creating Complex KPIs Using Tableau', 'Thresholds and Alerts', 'Data Quality'], ['Best Practices for Dashboard Design', 'Dashboard Design Principles 1, 2, &amp; 3', 'Dashboard Design Principles 4, 5, &amp; 6', 'Hierarchies, Actions, Filters, and Parameters (Parts 1&amp;2)', 'Hierarchies, Actions, Filters, and Parameters (Part 3)', 'Hierarchies, Actions, Filters, and Parameters (Part 4)', 'Important Considerations for Creating Dashboards'], ['Tell the Story of Your Data Introduction', 'The Art of Storytelling (Past, Present, and Future)', 'Storytelling and the Human Brain', 'Bringing Data to Life: Emotions and Data Storytelling', 'Emotion Modulators: Color, Language, and Other Design Elements', 'Framing and Format', 'Framing, Conventions, and Priming', 'False Narratives and Data Storytelling', 'Telling the Stories within the Story (Part 1)', 'Telling the Stories within the Story (Part 2)', 'Story Considerations', 'Preparation of the Story Points', 'Setting Up the Story', 'Creating Points in the Story', 'Interactive Story', 'Create a Data Story in a Static Presentation', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 19 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Week 1 starts off where Course 1 &amp; 2 left off... more lectures without course-directed opportunity to apply the lessons.  Week 1 is lead by guest Instructor Hunter (who led some of the weeks in earlier courses).  He's an expert academic in his field, but without more practical application of principles, limited benefit.", 'Great course with amazing teachers and material! I especially liked the amount of technical tutorials that are given in this course. I would recommend this to anyone starting out in Tableau.', None, '  Needs better step-by-step in Tableau. if wanted to figure it out myself, i would not have taken this certification. Also, formatting is drastically different from my version of Tableau.  ', "I enjoyed the class; I didn't care for classmate assessments because it was subjective to their viewpoint, preference, and prior experience.", 'Thumbs Up!', 'Great course', 'Really good course', 'Creating Dashboards and Storytelling with Tableau is really a good Course for all the Business  ', 'Good learning and this will help me to Build dashboards and storyline In future proj', 'Best Course', 'Great Course', 'Excellent !, I learned a lot!! Thanks!', 'Great! I love it, thank you so such~', 'Very good!', 'Good Working Course', 'I am very thankful for this course. It really gave me a lot of explanation and understanding about the topic. And it forced me think hard about that level. ', 'The course is well done and thought, it is not exceptional though.', 'Lovely course and so interesting. I recommend', 'The best course of this specialization. Storytelling is a very important and current subject. Highly recommend.', 'Already commented that this was a great course... please see my previous review.', 'This was one of the most indepth tableau courses in the series. It got into details and usable examples, just the thing you need to get creating on your own. ', 'This course had the perfect balance between guiding you and challenging you. Totally recommended.', 'Hands on lessons are great.', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Mark A', 'By Maksym M', 'By Mesum R H', 'By Lindsay J', 'By Gina R R', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By René G B', 'By Tallal N', 'By Manjunatha G', 'By shubhangi P M', 'By Blaise S', 'By Aditya D', 'By Karina S', 'By YOYO', 'By Wu Z', 'By Abhishek A', 'By igor s', 'By Luca N', 'By Daouda T', 'By Luiz A M', 'By Jeremy C', 'By Justin D F', 'By Fernando E', 'By Tim C ', 'By Vivian Y Q']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 23, 2018', 'May 24, 2018', 'Mar 16, 2017', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Oct 04, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2017', 'Jun 01, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2017', 'Mar 04, 2018', 'Jul 07, 2017', 'Aug 06, 2017', 'Feb 10, 2018', 'May 18, 2018', 'Jul 14, 2017', 'Nov 29, 2017', 'Nov 10, 2017', 'Mar 26, 2018', 'May 19, 2017']</review_date></doc>