<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_308</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/uva-darden-understanding-data-tools</course_url><course_name>Understanding Your Data: Analytical Tools</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Cristiano Guarana</course_instructor><course_introduction>Are you trying to understand data from your research? Learn how and when to conduct mediation, moderation, and conditional indirect effects analyses? Or, perhaps, how to theorize and test your theoretical models? If so, this is the course for you! We will walk you through the steps of conducting multilevel analyses using a real dataset and provide articles and templates designed to facilitate your learning. You'll leave with the tools you need to analyze and interpret the results of the datasets you collect as a researcher. 

By the end of this course, you will understand the differences between mediation and moderation and between moderated mediation and mediated moderation models (conditional indirect effects), and the importance of multilevel analysis. Most important, you will be able to run mediation, moderation, conditional indirect effect and multilevel models and interpret the results.

This course is supported by the BRAD Lab at the Darden School of Business, which studies organizational behavior, marketing, business ethics, judgment and decision-making, behavioral operations, and entrepreneurship, among other areas. More: http://www.darden.virginia.edu/brad-lab/</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Mediation//Multilevel Model//Data Analysis//Data Model//Data Moderation</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Virginia</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Mediation and Moderation//Conditional Indirect Effects//Multilevel Analysis</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Overview', 'What Is Mediation?', 'Introduction to SPSS', 'Running a Mediation Model', 'Conducting a Parallel Mediation Analysis', 'Conducting Serial Mediation Analysis', 'Moderation Overview', 'Conducting Moderation Analysis: Understanding the Outputs', 'Conducting Moderation Analysis: Plotting Interactions'], ['Conditional Indirect Effects: Mediated Moderation Models', 'Testing Mediated Moderation Models: Steps 1-2', 'Testing Mediated Moderation Models: Steps 3-5', 'Moderated Mediation Models Overview', 'Testing First Stage Moderated Mediation Models', 'Second Stage Moderated Mediation Models Overview', 'Testing Second Stage Moderated Mediation Models', 'Dual Stage Moderated Mediation Models Overview', 'Testing Dual Stage Moderated Mediation Models'], ['Multilevel Models Overview', 'Multilevel Models Technical Elements', 'Conducting Multilevel Analysis and Centering', 'Conducting Multilevel Analysis and Interpreting Outputs']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very useful to learn and develop analytical skills of available data', 'I learned many useful concept related to regression and multilevel analysis of data.', 'good', 'Easy to understand complex concepts. Thank you!', 'Very easy to understand and explained with real examples', 'This is a wonderful course with a working example on the use of SPSS with the regression based approach in statistical analysis.', 'Very good and informative course', 'Excellent course! Content is very important for the improvement of statistical techniques that are widely used in scientific research. The professor has a great mastery of content and his teaching is very engaging. I hope there will be continuation with other approaches to related issues.', 'I would like to express my sincere gratitude to Cristiano Guarana (Ph.D.) and the whole team behind this course for the well informative course content and an excellent way of instruction. Being an early career researcher, this course has been of great help in building a strong foundation for my Ph.D. journey. And I am sure, like me, a lot of other enthusiastic students will also be looking forward to have more effective courses from this team. Thank You.', 'This course is giving a very detail and well structured insights into Data Analysis.', 'THIS COURSE IS TALKING ABOUT MEDIATION, MODERATION, NEW TESTS ON SPSS, NOT THE BASIC ONES.', 'Very Helpful &amp; knowledgeable course on analytical ', 'very useful learning', 'NA', 'Positive approach to learn new things in a different way. Thanks ', 'very nice and good information about data analysis and variable types', 'Completed the Course ', 'Explained most concepts clearly, and I love the details included in the slides.', 'Good for basic and practical understand of modelling. ', 'Thank you for a good course. However, a lot needs to be added that can fully justify the stated scope of the course. These were isolated topics in data analysis. Useful but isolated and limited. Still, thank you for the great effort.', 'The course was fine in general, with clear slides and step-by-step instructions.', 'Explanations need to be more clear, especially analysis of the outputs using HLM tool and IBM Statistical tool.', 'very hard to complete the course with the available time  production hours. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By SURESH B R S', 'By MUHAMMAD S', 'By Kan W', 'By Anurag P', 'By Ashutosh P', 'By Jaime A P J', 'By Kambiz A', 'By Luis H C P', 'By ATHIRA R V', 'By Haroon A', 'By gehad g', 'By gudiya r', 'By charit t', 'By Shikha S', 'By Abithlal T', 'By Muhammad i', 'By 115801', 'By Xiaolin P', 'By Snigdha D', 'By Muhammad T S', 'By Veerle O', 'By Kirthivasan A', 'By BHASKER B']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 18, 2019', 'Jun 06, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2017', 'Apr 22, 2018', 'Mar 31, 2018', 'Apr 30, 2018', 'Feb 02, 2018', 'Feb 13, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2018', 'Aug 20, 2018', 'Oct 14, 2018', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Apr 13, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Jun 11, 2018', 'Oct 26, 2017', 'Apr 01, 2018', 'Sep 04, 2018', 'Apr 24, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>