<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_321</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-intelligence-data-warehousing</course_url><course_name>Business intelligence and data warehousing</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>María del Pilar Ángeles</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to the specialization course Business Intelligence and Data Warehousing. This course will be completed on six weeks, it will be supported with videos and various documents that will allow you to learn in a very simple way how to identify, design and develop analytical information systems, such as Business Intelligence with a descriptive analysis on data warehouses. You will be able to understand the problem of integration and predictive analysis of high volume of unstructured data (big data) with data mining and the Hadoop framework.

After completing this course, a learner will be able to
●	Create a Star o Snowflake data model Diagram through the Multidimensional Design from analytical business requirements and OLTP system
●	Create a physical database system 
●	Extract, Transform and load data to a data-warehouse.
●	Program analytical queries with SQL using MySQL
●	Predictive analysis with RapidMiner
●	Load relational or unstructured data to Hortonworks HDFS
●	Execute Map-Reduce jobs to query data on HDFS for analytical purposes


Programming languages:
For course 2 you will use the MYSQL language.

Software to download:
Rapidminer
MYSQL
Excel
Hortonworks Hadoop framework

In case you have a Mac / IOS operating system you will need to use a virtual Machine (VirtualBox, Vmware).</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Business Intelligence as Analytical System//Designing a Data Warehouse//The ETL process and Analytical queries with SQL// Predictive Analytics with Data mining//The problem of integration and analysis of unstructured data //Big Data and Hadoop Framework</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to BI', 'How data is analyzed?'], ['Design and implement an analytical databases', 'Steps to Multidimensional model OLTP'], ['Extract, transform and load data', 'Typical OLAP operations'], ['The process of data mining', 'ID3 Algorithms'], ['Data types according to structure of data', 'Integrate, store and analyze unstructured data'], ['What Big Data is?', 'Analysis of unstructured data']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Awesome Lessons ,also to clear all the basics', 'The Course was great. Hoping others will learn great stuff']</reviews><reviewers>['By Sahil S', 'By James W']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 18, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>