<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_46</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/excel-data-analysis</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Data Analysis Using Excel</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sharad Borle</course_instructor><course_introduction>The use of Excel is widespread in the industry. It is a very powerful data analysis tool and almost all big and small businesses use Excel in their day to day functioning. This is an introductory course in the use of Excel and is designed to give you a working knowledge of Excel with the aim of getting to use it for more advance topics in Business Statistics later. The course is designed keeping in mind two kinds of learners -  those who have very little functional knowledge of Excel and those who use Excel regularly but at a peripheral level and wish to enhance their skills. The course takes you from basic operations such as reading data into excel using various data formats, organizing and manipulating data, to some of the more advanced functionality of Excel. All along, Excel functionality is introduced using easy to understand examples which are demonstrated in a way that learners can become comfortable in understanding and applying them.

To successfully complete course assignments, students must have access to a Windows version of Microsoft Excel 2010 or later. 
________________________________________
WEEK 1
Module 1: Introduction to Spreadsheets
In this module, you will be introduced to the use of Excel spreadsheets and various basic data functions of Excel.

Topics covered include:
•	Reading data into Excel using various formats
•	Basic functions in Excel, arithmetic as well as various logical functions
•	Formatting rows and columns
•	Using formulas in Excel and their copy and paste using absolute and relative referencing
________________________________________
WEEK 2
Module 2: Spreadsheet Functions to Organize Data
This module introduces various Excel functions to organize and query data. Learners are introduced to the IF, nested IF, VLOOKUP and the HLOOKUP functions of Excel. 

Topics covered include:
•	IF and the nested IF functions
•	VLOOKUP and HLOOKUP
•	The RANDBETWEEN function
________________________________________
WEEK 3
Module 3: Introduction to Filtering, Pivot Tables, and Charts
This module introduces various data filtering capabilities of Excel. You’ll learn how to set filters in data to selectively access data. A very powerful data summarizing tool, the Pivot Table, is also explained and we begin to introduce the charting feature of Excel.

Topics covered include:
•	VLOOKUP across worksheets
•	Data filtering in Excel
•	Use of Pivot tables with categorical as well as numerical data
•	Introduction to the charting capability of Excel
________________________________________
WEEK 4
Module 4: Advanced Graphing and Charting
This module explores various advanced graphing and charting techniques available in Excel. Starting with various line, bar and pie charts we introduce pivot charts, scatter plots and histograms. You will get to understand these various charts and get to build them on your own.

Topics covered include
•	Line, Bar and Pie charts
•	Pivot charts
•	Scatter plots
•	Histograms</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Lookup Table//Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Pivot Table</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Spreadsheets//Spreadsheet Functions to Organize Data//Introduction to Filtering, Pivot Tables, and Charts//Advanced Graphing and Charting</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Meet the Professor', 'Reading Data into Excel', 'Basic Data Manipulation in Excel', 'Arithmetic Manipulation in Excel', 'Basic Functions in Excel', 'Functions Using Absolute and Relative References', 'Functions Explained', 'Week 1 Recap'], ['The “IF” Command in Excel', 'The “IF” Command in Excel Using Numerical Data', 'The "Nested IF" Command in Excel', 'The "VLOOKUP" Function in Excel', 'Another "VLOOKUP" Example', 'The "HLOOKUP" Function in Excel', "Professor 'Know-it-all' Needs Help!", 'Week 2 Recap'], ['Using the “VLOOKUP” Function Across Worksheets', 'Data Filtering in Excel', 'Use of Pivot Tables in Excel', 'More Pivot Table Options', 'Application of Pivot Tables to Numeric Data', 'Introduction to Charts in Excel', 'Week 3 Recap'], ['Line Graphs', 'Bar Graphs and Pie Charts', 'Pivot Charts', 'Scatter Plots', 'Histograms Part 1', 'Histograms Part 2', 'Week 4 Recap']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Overall the course content and the way it is explained with right examples is making one to follow and understand the tools available in excel. It would be nice, if the course gives the option to choose the Excel version one has, so that it will be easy to quickly find the options being discussed', 'A good course for anyone looking for an introduction to using Excel for analysis. There is some help with navigation, but to be successful in this class it would be very helpful for a person to already be fairly familiar with the Excel ribbon and basic Excel navigation.', 'The course is very helpful to enter into Data Analysis starting Excel. I learned many new things to analyse data using excel and I am confident now to handle more data after this course. Whom so ever want to learn data analysis using excel must go for this course.', 'Excelente curso.', None, 'So useful!', 'An excellent introduction of industry standard Excel', 'It was a very well explained course, amazing learning experience. Thankyou', 'Good course for learning and practicing vlookup, pivot tables, and charts.', 'Fantastic', 'I really learnt a lot in this course, I was a newbie with excel spreadsheets, now I feel comfortable handling data files and extracting valuable information from raw data. ', "Introduction to Data Analysis Using Excel is a fun fast paced course that will teach you practical knowledge in a short amount of time. All exercises were useful and to the point. I have no doubt, I'll be using what I learned in no time at all. Many thanks to Professor Sharad Borle, Rice and Coursera!", None, "Great course if you're looking to understand the basic of Excel!", 'A great course! Would recommend this course to anyone who is willing to explore the field of Datascience or data analytics. All the topics in this course are covered very well.', 'Easy to understand and follow. ', 'Excellent course! Thanks to the instructor', 'REALLY NICE COURSE..QUIZZES ARE VERY WELL DESIGNED ', 'Good course provides a basic basis for data analysis! Excellent for beginners who have no idea how to use excel to systematically learn excellent files from each lecture is very helpful.', 'Excellent Course to explore', '...', 'The professor and the team has done a great job here!', 'A very detail and structure explanation by the lecturer. ', None, 'excellent!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Raju B', 'By Heather H', 'By Amit M', 'By Deleted A', 'By enrique a r', 'By Xiaolin P', 'By Samin U W', 'By Shreya G', 'By David B', 'By Ganapathi N K', 'By Deepak N', 'By José R H', 'By Matthew H', 'By Sunil C', 'By Saurabh P', 'By Daniel H', 'By Padmapriyadarshini', 'By lakshya b', 'By Vigneshwaran N', 'By Shittu I', 'By Khaldoon M A', 'By Kalyani', 'By Fiona N S L', 'By Albert C', 'By Paul J H']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 03, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019']</review_date></doc>