<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_334</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/advanced-manufacturing-process-analysis</course_url><course_name>Advanced Manufacturing Process Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rahul Rai</course_instructor><course_introduction>Variability is a fact of life in manufacturing environments, impacting product quality and yield. Through this course, students will learn why performing advanced analysis of manufacturing processes is integral for diagnosing and correcting operational flaws in order to improve yields and reduce costs.   

Gain insights into the best ways to collect, prepare and analyze data, as well as computational platforms that can be leveraged to collect and process data over sustained periods of time. Become better prepared to participate as a member of an advanced analysis team and share valuable inputs on effective implementation.    

Main concepts of this course will be delivered through lectures, readings, discussions and various videos. 

This is the fourth course in the Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design Technology specialization that explores the many facets of manufacturing’s “Fourth Revolution,”  aka Industry 4.0, and features a culminating project involving creation of a roadmap to achieve a self-established DMD-related professional goal.

To learn more about the Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology specialization, please watch the overview video by copying and pasting the following link into your web browser: https://youtu.be/wETK1O9c-CA</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Mechanical Engineering</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Advanced Manufacturing Process Analysis//Data Collection//Data Analysis: Computational Techniques and Platforms</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Advanced Manufacturing Process Analysis', 'The Data Analysis Process', 'Data Collection in Different Manufacturing Settings', 'DMD Dialogue 1: Discrete Part Manufacturing', 'DMD Dialogue 2: Continuous Manufacturing'], ['Big Data', 'Data Collection Considerations', 'Data Storage', 'Data Preprocessing'], ['Sensitivity Analysis', 'Anomaly Detection', 'The Computational Platform', 'HPC and Cloud Computing', 'Your 4.0 Roadmap to Success']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 4 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Mostly tells what happens and what might happen with Advanced Manufacturing Process Analysis application in the Industry, but very less about How it actually happens and what are the exact procedures.', 'Nothing advanced in this course', 'Most of the Links for further infromations to the topics are not working or leading to some product or software selling sites. bis scam!', 'Extremely basic one these quiz can be answered without studying videos in a single attempt this is an basic knowledge that an mechanical engineer has. pls improve quality of education', 'Learn Nothing specifically. just introductions', 'So elementary and monotone', 'Could have been better, concepts explained in the videos are mostly obvious. This course is mainly a collection of external links.', '  Good  ', 'Very good to learn', None, 'Course structure has been built in right manner for improving the method of data collection, storage, analysis, information and decision making.', 'Thank you for the training course.  This course will be very helpful in analyzing &amp; improving stamping process in Press shop, that will help us to deliver superior quality product to our customer.', 'good course to avail!', 'This 4 week course of Advance Manufacturing Process Analysis is wonderful and recommendable to all. Content is very good and easy to understand. It helps in my current role as well.', 'Good', 'The best online course with lots of videos and contents.', 'good', 'good', 'good learning', 'Very good way of teaching.', 'I really appreciate the hard work behind this course by faculty , for providing us a profound understanding on the topic Advanced Manufacturing Process Analysis. Thankyou !', 'very usefulll', 'Enjoyed the course.', 'Good course', 'Very interesting, and difficult!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Upamanyu R', 'By Кудинов А В', 'By Binu M', 'By Umang S M', 'By Muhammad U', 'By Alireza Z', 'By Johnson D', 'By Atichat P', 'By Khushyal S', 'By GODHAN S', 'By Surapaneni V', 'By KUNDAN S S', 'By Rifad H', 'By Yogesh S', 'By Kishan s', 'By LAKSHMAN S', 'By P k', 'By vikram s', 'By Jitendra K', 'By ABHIJITH A', 'By Shivoh C', 'By vishwas m a', 'By Scott C', 'By yashar k s', 'By Joaquin C']</reviewers><review_date>['May 26, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2018', 'May 29, 2018', 'Aug 27, 2018', 'May 22, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2018', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Oct 08, 2018', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Aug 07, 2018', 'May 28, 2018', 'May 14, 2017']</review_date></doc>