<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_326</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/recommender-metrics</course_url><course_name>Recommender Systems:  Evaluation and Metrics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Michael D. Ekstrand</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will learn how to evaluate recommender systems.  You will gain familiarity with several families of metrics, including ones to measure prediction accuracy, rank accuracy, decision-support, and other factors such as diversity, product coverage, and serendipity.  You will learn how different metrics relate to different user goals and business goals.  You will also learn how to rigorously conduct offline evaluations (i.e., how to prepare and sample data, and how to aggregate results).  And you will learn about online (experimental) evaluation.  At the completion of this course you will have the tools you need to compare different recommender system alternatives for a wide variety of uses.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Minnesota</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Preface//Basic Prediction and Recommendation Metrics//Advanced Metrics and Offline Evaluation//Online Evaluation//Evaluation Design</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Evaluation and Metrics', 'The Goals of Evaluation'], ['Hidden Data Evaluation', 'Prediction Accuracy Metrics', 'Decision Support Metrics', 'Rank-Aware Top-N Metrics', 'Assignment Intro Video'], ['Beyond Basic Evaluation', 'Additional Item and List-Based Metrics', 'Experimental Protocols', 'Unary Data Evaluation', 'Temporal Evaluation of Recommenders (Interview with Neal Lathia)', 'Programming Assignment Introduction'], ['Introduction to Online Evaluation and User Studies', 'Usage Logs and Analysis', 'A/B Studies (Field Experiments)', 'User-Centered Evaluation (Interview with Bart Knijnenburg)'], ['Matching Evaluation to the Problem/Challenge', 'Case Examples', 'Assignment Intro Video']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["If you are new to Recommender Systems evaluation, and would like to first know why we do what we do in evaluating a recommender system, go for this course! Each and every approach is explained in vivid details, stripped to the bare essentials so you can see the skeleton of that approach! The only shortcoming, in my opinion was that i felt the codes in honours content in Lenskit could've been further explained. But, all in all, a wonderful place to start!", 'That last assignment is great for a better understanding of the metrics.', 'The course presents the different metrics used for evaluating recommender systems. Moreover, they show many real-life applications where these metrics could be applied and the trade-offs of them. It also includes interviews with experts on the field.', 'nice to learn  excel statistic', 'My issues about the previous courses in this specialization seem to have been addressed in this one. The assignment in the end is a real good one. The creators of this course have done well to evolve a really thought-provoking and relevant assignment. The course itself helps one develop the appropriate thought process, which comes in handy while deciding upon a metric for a problem at hand.', 'It is not perfect but best of specialisation so far. It is a little bit philosophical rather than  technical and formal, but it was exactly meet my current personal needs. Can not be recommended as a first and only introduction to a topic of an evaluation and metrics of recommender systems. ', "I was working on a cross-domain recommendation system where i would recommend books to a user whose movie ratings have been given. I made the algorithm but didn't have any idea as to how to evaluate it but this course helped me through. Thanks", 'wonderful!!! They teach a lot what I did not expect!', 'the part of offline evaluation is really good and practical as well. However, although knowing online evaluation is a more complex subject, I felt it lacked a little bit how to put all this knowledge in practice.', 'not an easy course, specifically the honors track. the information is good, but not presented as well as in the previous two courses. Also there are errors in the honors assignment that make it unnecessarily difficult and you spend a lot of time on irrelevant things.', "The course is interesting because it makes you ask the right questions about recommender systems design. Overfall, there's no great theory behind recommend systems, it's mostly about understanding users' and business' needs, and lecturers do a great job to explain that!", 'Very good. But left out 1 star because one honors assignment did not have the material(base code) to download. Repeated questions were not answered in forum.', "Very Informative. Still, there isn't too much complete evaluation example invovled. It would be a great help if this course can provide some breakdown/design of a recommendaer evaluation system.", 'A lot of very in detail theories and metrics. I wish it could have more hands on experience. ', 'Loved the first part of the course where they introduced many relevant evaluation metrics (root mean square, Spearman, ROC, Precision/Recall, .etc). However, offline/online evaluations were vaguely explained and lacked depth. I really wish there were more concrete, written examples. The final quiz was abstract, weird, and difficult to understand.', 'The computer assignment is lack of explanation.', 'This course was very helpful for giving me a breadth of exposure to various ways to look at evaluating recommender systems.  Having faced a very similar problem evaluating a recommender system for a legal document search/suggestion engine (like Google News for lawyers), this gave me a proper "birds eye" perspective on that problem that I wish I had before. We faced exactly the same problem you describe of finding the proper tradeoff between precision and recall, or search vs. discovery.', 'Confused about some metrics.', 'The first two weeks are fantastic, up until evaluation metrics stop being covered. After that nothing concrete is said and very little is to be learned. Skip after that.', 'The content is good, interesting but too short for 4 weeks course. Too little new information. The honor assignment was so far the worse. The documentation contain a lot of errors, the description was incomplete.', '这么点内容撑起四周的课程。我不知道课程组织者是怎么想的。Honor assigment 的说明里充斥着巨量的错误。 怀疑其内容没有更新， 依旧是那个旧版本。 ', 'In addition to the normal number of small errors here and there, the course has too many big errors in the honors track assignments, and no help in the forums.  The course appears abandoned.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Anish S', 'By Joeri K', 'By Frederick A G', 'By zheng d', 'By Keshaw S', 'By Yury Z', 'By Dhruv M', 'By Light0617', 'By Caio H K M', 'By Chris C', 'By Antoine D', 'By srikalyan', 'By Zhenkun Z', 'By Chris S', 'By Gui M T', 'By llraphael', 'By Andrew W', 'By LU W', 'By Alex B', 'By Daniel P', 'By Siwei Y', "By Maxwell's D"]</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 23, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2017', 'Feb 09, 2018', 'Feb 22, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2018', 'Jun 15, 2018', 'Jul 19, 2017', 'May 18, 2018', 'Jul 03, 2018', 'May 14, 2017', 'Jun 13, 2017', 'Jun 16, 2017', 'Jul 16, 2017', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Jun 16, 2018', 'Feb 04, 2018', 'Aug 23, 2018', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2017', 'Jul 03, 2017', 'Jan 15, 2018']</review_date></doc>