<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_447</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/nursing-informatics-leaders</course_url><course_name>Nursing Informatics Leadership Theory and Practice</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel J. Pesut, Ph.D., RN, FAAN</course_instructor><course_introduction>“By the end of this Course, you will be able to…” 
•	Evaluate effective leadership styles for leadership in nursing informatics in clinical or academic contexts to improve leadership success.
•	Discover core values that support effective nursing informatics leadership in academic and clinical contexts to inform development of a personal leadership mission statement.
•	Discover competing values and polarities related to knowledge leadership and management to promote successful leadership collaboration.
•	Determine your personal informatics leadership style based on results from the Minnesota Informatics Leadership Inventory to inform successful leadership practice. 
•	Discuss the value and importance of foresight leadership in nursing informatics to anticipate trends and consequences that are likely to transform the learning health care system</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating /><course_orgnization>University of Minnesota</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Evaluate effective leadership styles for leadership in nursing informatics in clinical or academic contexts to improve your leadership success//Discover core values that support effective nursing informatics leadership in academic and clinical contexts to inform development of a personal leadership mission statement, and development plan//Discover competing values and polarities related to knowledge leadership and management to promote successful leadership collaboration//Reflect on results from the Minnesota Nursing Informatics Leadership Inventory (MNLI) to inform successful leadership development and practice//Discuss the value and importance of foresight leadership in nursing informatics to anticipate trends and consequences that are likely to transform the learning health care system</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome Video', 'Evaluate effective leadership styles for leadership in nursing informatics in clinical or academic contexts to improve your leadership success'], ['Discover core values that support effective nursing informatics leadership'], ['Discover competing values and polarities related to knowledge leadership and management to promote successful leadership collaboration'], ['Determine your personal informatics leadership style based on results from the Minnesota Nursing Informatics Leadership Inventory (MNLI) to inform successful leadership development and practice'], ['Discuss the value and importance of foresight leadership in nursing informatics to anticipate trends and consequences that are likely to transform the learning health care system']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>[]</reviews><reviewers>[]</reviewers><review_date>[]</review_date></doc>