<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_8</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/nlp-sequence-models</course_url><course_name>Sequence Models</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Andrew Ng</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will teach you how to build models for natural language, audio, and other sequence data. Thanks to deep learning, sequence algorithms are working far better than just two years ago, and this is enabling numerous exciting applications in speech recognition, music synthesis, chatbots, machine translation, natural language understanding, and many others. 

You will:
- Understand how to build and train Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs), and commonly-used variants such as GRUs and LSTMs.
- Be able to apply sequence models to natural language problems, including text synthesis. 
- Be able to apply sequence models to audio applications, including speech recognition and music synthesis.

This is the fifth and final course of the Deep Learning Specialization.

deeplearning.ai is also partnering with the NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute (DLI) in Course 5, Sequence Models, to provide a programming assignment on Machine Translation with deep learning. You will have the opportunity to build a deep learning project with cutting-edge, industry-relevant content.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Recurrent Neural Network//Artificial Neural Network//Deep Learning//Long Short-Term Memory (ISTM)</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>deeplearning.ai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Recurrent Neural Networks//Natural Language Processing &amp; Word Embeddings//Sequence models &amp; Attention mechanism</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Why sequence models', 'Notation', 'Recurrent Neural Network Model', 'Backpropagation through time', 'Different types of RNNs', 'Language model and sequence generation', 'Sampling novel sequences', 'Vanishing gradients with RNNs', 'Gated Recurrent Unit (GRU)', 'Long Short Term Memory (LSTM)', 'Bidirectional RNN', 'Deep RNNs'], ['Word Representation', 'Using word embeddings', 'Properties of word embeddings', 'Embedding matrix', 'Learning word embeddings', 'Word2Vec', 'Negative Sampling', 'GloVe word vectors', 'Sentiment Classification', 'Debiasing word embeddings'], ['Basic Models', 'Picking the most likely sentence', 'Beam Search', 'Refinements to Beam Search', 'Error analysis in beam search', 'Bleu Score (optional)', 'Attention Model Intuition', 'Attention Model', 'Speech recognition', 'Trigger Word Detection', 'Conclusion and thank you']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 17 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Full of appalling errors that have been present for over 1 year.  No one fixes it.  It is clear that since Ng was let go by Stanford and Baidu, he is trying to earn a living with deep learning_ai.  This apparently is not working as the small income from Coursera is not sufficient. As a result the prerecorded classes remain on Coursera to accrue some residual income.  But, Andrew Ng and the staff are apparently gone.', 'I really like the deeplearning.ai specialization. And also I like the Sequence Models course. However, I feel that I have learned less during this course comparing to the other ones in the specialization. First, I believe it was an extensive use of Keras. Whereas the framework is great, it would be much better for understanding if all the exercises were in numpy, whereas Keras tween-projects be optional.  Doing both numpy and Keras versions would allow to better understand the material and learn through repetition. Second, even though the course is great, I perceived the number of errors/typos was much higher than in other courses. Is that true? For example, the Jazz Improvisation exercise was a nightmare. Overall, thank you for the course. Despite those problems, I would still recommend it.', 'Tons of editing errors in lectures, and the programming problems rely more on knowledge of Keras (essentially untaught throughout the course) than they do on understanding of lecture material. A disgraceful end to an otherwise solid course sequence.', 'Keras is required to pass the assignments but no training provided for it. I can learn it myself of course but then the question is this - what am I paying for?', "I'm blown away by how quickly this series of courses brought me from thinking a neural network was a magic box full of fairy dust, to being able to understand even the (al)most complex of network architectures and what makes them tick at every level at a glance. A lot of time has obviously gone into structuring this course; not an ounce of fat present and the format of developing intuition before diving into the nitty gritty and optional further learning resonates with me on so many levels. Thank you Andrew Ng and the team at deepmind.ai and coursera!", 'I think it is the best courses designed so far. Gives you exactly the appropriate amount of information needed to understand basics behind sequence models. A must do course for all the students who want to pursue a career in this field.', 'If not Internet, I would not have been able to study a world-class Deep Learning course at an affordable price. Thanks Andrew and team.', 'Professor Andrew is really knowledgeable. I learn a lot from his lecture videos.', 'I want to thank Andrew Ng and his team for the amazing work. You definitely make the world a better place sharing this knowledge, and it is an inspiration.', 'Great module, I am lucky to have used this resources in learning sequence models, I can imagine running LSTM using one of the frameworks without ever implementing it myself, Andrew Ng/Deeplearning.ai  is the best!', 'The course is very good and has taught me the all the important concepts required to build a sequence model. The assignments are also very neatly and precisely designed for the real world application.', 'Could have been more thorough like previous courses', 'Great insights, helpful notebooks, good explanations.', 'Little bit math heavy. It was sometimes hard to understand the intuition, e.g. RNN, LSTM, GRU', 'Some coding assignments were too hard to follow what was required.', 'Poor submission system. Failed many times to upload and had to redo the assignments. I was using a 250Mbps high speed network. Also course materials are problematic. The instructors are not willing to fix the problems for many years.', 'Excellent course. Highly recommended! ', 'Excellent state of the art deep learning models made easy. Great job Andrew! And THANKS SO MUCH!!!', 'Auch der Letzte Kurs war sehr gut! Diese Spezialisierung hat sich sehr gelohnt. Der Stoff wurde gut erklärt und war sehr gut anwendbar.', '  cool  ', 'Thank you Andrew NG for teaching AI ', 'Awesome conclusion to deep learning. The 1 side trigger detection algorithm is good final touch. Thank you Andrew NG..', 'Very detailed hands-on assignment. Hard tho', 'This was an awesome sequence. I wanted to understand Deep Learning and the techniques and ideas that had advanced the state of the art beyond ordinary neural nets.  I was particularly interested in Sequence Models which are of interest in my line of work. ', 'Andrew Ng at it best.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Lewis C L', 'By Bogdan P', 'By Dylan R', 'By Alex R', 'By Nathan P', 'By khushal m', 'By Ng K W P', 'By Jizhou Y', 'By Andrés F R', 'By Ozioma N', 'By Abhijeet M', 'By Ravi K S', 'By Johannes J', 'By Beibit', 'By Jaime G', 'By Zhongyi T', 'By Bhaskar D', 'By Yoan S', 'By Daniel G', 'By Jhon S', 'By Veeresh S', 'By Srivathsan A', 'By zhiqing h', 'By Brian L', 'By Sushanta P']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 15, 2019', 'Nov 03, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Jun 15, 2018', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Jun 09, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'May 20, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jun 26, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jun 11, 2019', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 15, 2018']</review_date></doc>