<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_291</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-analytics</course_url><course_name>Business Analytics and Digital Media</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sudhir Voleti</course_instructor><course_introduction>The explosion in digital media - web, social and now mobile - represents a departure from how things were like in the last century. This proliferation of digital media is both a threat and an opportunity for many businesses. Business Analytics can be leveraged to process data, sentiment, buzz, contacts, context and other aspects of business interest in real time, for business performance and impact. The course picks and uses use-cases from a variety of industries and geographies, to showcase the potential and impact that business analytics done properly (or not) can have on business performance.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Digital Media//Data Analysis//Analytics//Business Analytics</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>Indian School of Business</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Business Analytics//Toolscape//Customer Analytics //Digital Media </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introductory Business Analytics and Digital Media', 'Conceptual Preliminaries', 'Framework for Problem Formulation', 'Transformative Problem Formulation', 'Data Types and Psychometric Scaling', 'Exploratory Vs Confirmatory Dichotomy', 'Revisiting Problem Formulation'], ['Toolscape for Business Analytics', 'A primer on Business Experimentation', 'Conceptual Preliminaries', 'Software for this Course', 'Training Machines A People-Analytics Use Case', 'The Exponential Learning Curve of the Machines', 'Toolscape Summary and Warp-up'], ['Motivating Customer Analytics', 'preliminaries for Customer Analytics', 'Factorizing Data', 'Clustering Data', 'Visualising Data'], ['Motivating Technology for Brands', 'Setting the Context: Digital Advertising', 'The App Era in Digital Social Media', 'Social Graphs and Hyper-Segmentation', 'Non-Social Digital Media for the Enterprise', 'Formulating and Analytics Problem']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The lectures were amazing but the text and the videos were not in sync in of the lectures', 'Some of the examples are confusing and not very clear. The transcripts are also not orderly placed. The course could be more better if author could give more examples apart from the readings to demonstrate the theory.', 'there were a number of technical challenges with the video that affect teaching and learning. the content by itself is great but resolving issues with missing readings, missing presentation slides, missing links etc will go a long way to help', 'Not very happy with the quality of this course.', 'Data &amp; Analytics in the context of any Organization is very critical and fundamentals were made strong through this course and caselets shared by professor. Thanks and I would recommend this to any such aspirant to get an intro to the Data world', "The course was of course very informative. Had given it 4.5 stars but couldn't manage to do that-not sure if that can be done. The only scope of improvement what i felt during the course is if the reading materials being referred to by Sudhir in between the videos were not made available. Thanks!", 'There are a lot of technical problems in the course. The visual aids are ', 'Great learning', 'This training was quite helpful in understanding the concepts of analytics. ', 'This is a very interesting course for the intellect who are always curious to learn more based on data points. Sudhir brings back the curiosity that every student wants to have on a gamut of topics this course covers. What better course than business analytics and digital media delivered by Sudhir can help us achieve that sense of curiosity. ', 'I need more training on how to formulate content for R ', 'Very good course for working professional. Thanks ISB &amp; Professor Sudhir. ', 'Very good beginning class covering the concepts needed.', 'Thank you for the wonderful session. It was very informative and helpful for me. And your YouTube videos are also really good to follow.', 'Insightful!', 'excellent content', 'Awesome experience learning. Thanks Sudhir sir for his teaching and Coursera for such a beautiful platform.', 'The importance of analytics and machine learning is well taught', 'E', 'very good', 'A great basic course that fueled my interest to learn more and deep dive into analytics ', 'Awesome course for beginners in business analytics and specially is provides good insight about social media marketing.', 'A very example oriented Course with real world applications.', 'Very interesting and gave a lot of Knowledge on Business Analytics.', "An interesting commentary about the Business Analytics and various toolscape and the diversity that Digital Media offers. Mr. Sudhir Voleti offers interesting examples to help us understand the concepts. The world is going 'mobile' and the essential know-how on analyzing and using 'data' is very well contained in this course. "]</reviews><reviewers>['By Venkata H B V', 'By puneet g', 'By daniel b', 'By Markus S', 'By Chandra K B', 'By Partha S M', 'By Carlos M F C', 'By Nikhil K S', 'By Jyothi P S B', 'By Reza K', 'By Siphiwe G B', 'By Deepak J', 'By David F', 'By Aparna C', 'By Imogie I', 'By Akhilesh K', 'By Sumit A', 'By VanajaKumari v', 'By Praveen S', 'By Krishna s k', 'By VIVEK K', 'By Nitin S M', 'By Subramaniam I', 'By SHARATH C A', 'By Bhavya C']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 19, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2018', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2018', 'Feb 16, 2018', 'May 10, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2019', 'Dec 15, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2017', 'Dec 05, 2017', 'Aug 06, 2017', 'Aug 07, 2017', 'May 15, 2018', 'Sep 29, 2017', 'Oct 27, 2017', 'Mar 18, 2018', 'Mar 05, 2018', 'Jul 08, 2018', 'Jun 19, 2017', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Jul 14, 2019', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Dec 09, 2018']</review_date></doc>