<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_371</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/understanding-china-history-part-1</course_url><course_name>Understanding China, 1700-2000: A Data Analytic Approach, Part 1</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>James Z. Lee</course_instructor><course_introduction>The purpose of this course is to summarize new directions in Chinese history and social science produced by the creation and analysis of big historical datasets based on newly opened Chinese archival holdings, and to organize this knowledge in a framework that encourages learning about China in comparative perspective.

Our course demonstrates how a new scholarship of discovery is redefining what is singular about modern China and modern Chinese history. Current understandings of human history and social theory are based largely on Western experience or on non-Western experience seen through a Western lens. This course offers alternative perspectives derived from Chinese experience over the last three centuries. We present specific case studies of this new scholarship of discovery divided into two stand-alone parts, which means that students can take any part without prior or subsequent attendance of the other part.

Part 1 (this course) focuses on comparative inequality and opportunity and addresses two related questions ‘Who rises to the top?’ and ‘Who gets what?’.

Part 2 (https://www.coursera.org/learn/understanding-china-history-part-2) turns to an arguably even more important question ‘Who are we?’ as seen through the framework of comparative population behavior - mortality, marriage, and reproduction – and their interaction with economic conditions and human values. We do so because mortality and reproduction are fundamental and universal, because they differ historically just as radically between China and the West as patterns of inequality and opportunity, and because these differences demonstrate the mutability of human behavior and values.

Course Overview video: https://youtu.be/dzUPRyJ4ETk</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Orientation and Module 1: Social Structure and Education in Late Imperial China//Module 2: Education and Social Mobility in Contemporary China//Module 3: Social Mobility and Wealth Distribution in Late Imperial and Contemporary China//Module 4: Wealth Distribution and Regime Change in Twentieth Century China//Final Exam and Farewell</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Overview', '1.1: Introduction', '1.2: Who Gets What and Why?', '1.3: Social Mobility and the Examination System in Late Imperial China', '1.4: Cultural Reproduction and Education in Late Imperial and Contemporary China'], ['2.1: Comparing Inequality in Education and Income between China and the West', '2.2: Student Diversity at Peking University 1950-1999 and Suzhou University 1950-2003', '2.3: China’s Silent Revolution’s Ladder of Success'], ['3.1: Wealth Distribution in the UK and US, 1700-2000', '3.2: Population Categories and Wealth Entitlements in China', '3.3: Land Distribution in Shuangcheng, 1870-1906', '3.4: Property Distribution in Contemporary China', '3.5: Comparative Wealth Distribution: Past/Present and East/West'], ['4.1: Wealth Distribution and Regime Change', '4.2: Wealth Distribution in Pre-Revolutionary China', '4.3: Political Processes and Institutions of Regime Change in Shuangcheng, 1946-1948', '4.4: Revolutionary Victims in Shuangcheng and Elsewhere', '4.5: Course Conclusion'], ['A Farewell Message from Professor James Lee', 'Rate this course']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The truth about China.  This is fact, by evidence, by statistics.  Very good to know.', 'It is a very short and concise course. ', 'I enjoyed this course tremendously, and discovered that there was a vast amount of information that I needed to learn about this SuperPower.  China is an amazing country with an enormous population and economy, a history of remarkable achievement, and yet still unknown in many ways.   Thanks for putting this course together.', None, 'good', 'Brilliant course. High quality information, comprehensive sources and interesting tests. Part 1 puts the revolution in a new perspective and connects imperial China with contemporary China. The course also throws a light on equality vs inequality globally and in China. The course is controversial in that it reflects duly and appropriately the complexity of Chinese social history and its development as opposed to the black-and-white view on China which still persists in the West. I also liked the very down-to-earth approach of Prof Lee.', 'Very interesting, I would recommend this course.', 'Informative, relevant, and unique. The focus on recent discoveries unearthed through original research is refreshing.', 'Well presented material, new and surprising insights. Rewarding experience.', 'I liked the data-driven, very analytic approach to understand Chines history better. Thank you for a great course. ', 'A little bit slow at first, amazing for people who just want to have some contact with the history and culture of china!', 'Very good', ' This course was boring as hell. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Joy S', 'By Nhat L', 'By JOHN Q', 'By Asir A', 'By lichuangye', 'By Jialin B', 'By Médéric D', 'By Matt M', 'By Sara T', 'By Fabian F', 'By Yasmin C', 'By Gabriel M R L', 'By Jonathan G']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 29, 2018', 'Sep 26, 2017', 'Nov 20, 2017', 'May 25, 2017', 'Apr 04, 2017', 'May 23, 2018', 'Jan 17, 2018', 'Oct 19, 2017', 'Oct 25, 2017', 'Jul 24, 2017', 'Jul 06, 2018', 'Aug 14, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2018']</review_date></doc>