<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_72</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/database-management</course_url><course_name>Database Management Essentials</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Michael Mannino</course_instructor><course_introduction>Database Management Essentials provides the foundation you need for a career in database development, data warehousing, or business intelligence, as well as for the entire Data Warehousing for Business Intelligence specialization. In this course, you will create relational databases, write SQL statements to extract information to satisfy business reporting requests, create entity relationship diagrams (ERDs) to design databases, and analyze table designs for excessive redundancy. As you develop these skills, you will use either Oracle or MySQL to execute SQL statements and a database diagramming tool such as the ER Assistant or Visual Paradigm to create ERDs. We’ve designed this course to ensure a common foundation for specialization learners. Everyone taking the course can jump right in with writing SQL statements in Oracle or MySQL.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Database (DB) Design//Entity–Relationship (E-R) Model//Database (DBMS)//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado System</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Introduction//Introduction to Databases and DBMSs//Relational Data Model and the CREATE TABLE Statement//Basic Query Formulation with SQL//Extended Query Formulation with SQL//Notation for Entity Relationship Diagrams//ERD Rules and Problem Solving//Developing Business Data Models//Data Modeling Problems and Completion of an ERD//Schema Conversion//Normalization Concepts and Practice</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Specialization Introduction video lesson', 'Course introduction video lecture', 'Course objectives video lecture', 'Topics and  assignments video lecture'], ['Database characteristics video lecture', 'Organizational Roles video lecture', 'DBMS overview and database definition feature video lecture', 'Non-procedural access video lecture', 'Transaction processing overview video lecture', 'Data warehouse processing overview video lecture', 'DBMS technology evolution video lecture'], ['Basics of relational databases video lecture', 'Integrity rules video lecture', 'Basic SQL CREATE TABLE statement video lecture', 'Integrity constraint syntax video lecture', 'Assignment 1 Notes video lecture'], ['SQL Overview video lecture', 'SELECT statement introduction video lecture', 'Join Operator video lecture', 'Using Join operations in SQL SELECT statements video lecture', 'GROUP BY clause video lecture'], ['Query formulation guidelines video lecture', 'Multiple table problems video lecture', 'Problems involving join and grouping operations video lecture', 'SQL set operators video lecture', 'SQL modification statements video lecture', 'Query formulation errors video lecture'], ['Database development goals video lecture', 'Basic ERD notation video lecture', 'Relationship variations I video lecture', 'Relationship variations II video lecture'], ['Basic diagram rules video lecture', 'Extended diagram rules video lecture', 'ERD problems I video lecture', 'ERD problems II video lecture', 'ER Assistant Demonstration video', 'Software demonstration video for Visual Paradigm'], ['Conceptual data modeling goals and challenges', 'Analyzing narrative problems', 'Design transformations I', 'Design transformations II video lecture'], ['Data modeling problems I video lecture', 'Data modeling problems II video lecture', 'Finalizing an ERD video lecture'], ['Goals and steps of logical database design video lecture', 'Conversion rules video lecture', 'Conversion problems video lecture'], ['Modification anomalies video lecture', 'Functional dependencies video lecture', 'Normal forms video lecture', 'Practical concerns video lecture', 'Normalization problems video lecture', 'Course Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 29 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Almost exclusively peer marked assessment and although you can learn from peer marking there is no incentive for other people to mark your work properly. Many people just appear to give everything full marks and the comment "great" or "nice" or even just a full stop to meet the comment requirement. When not giving full marks not one person put a comment to explain why they haven\'t given full marks and if the person marking your work doesn\'t fully understand the material they are just as likely to mark it correct when it is not as they are not sure about the material.  ', "This course provides the essential foundations that a rookie need to master partial SQL and the basic techniques for drawing entity relation diagrams. All in all, it's a good course to embark on your journey for exploring database. However, some part of the video is kind of redundant. There are three points that I would like to mention. First, The peer-evaluation system. In other CS course, a grading system is prepared to give marks on student's assignment, which is more objective; Second, this course provides a link to buy textbook, rather than providing student the access to free online resources; Third, week7 material, upon functional dependency and BCNF are not clearly elaborated.", 'The course is very intense, need a lot of practice. A little boring when I took this course, course the tutorial and the forms of the course if boring for me. But you can quiet a lot about basic sql syntax and ERD modeling. And the assignment is not well designed,  the classmate reviews take a lot of time , should be improved, like  each assignment just upload one file, should do some automatic tools for the assignment reviews.', 'Not enough implication from the instructors in the course. Students are left alone with the material, without any answers to there questions on the course.', 'Personally they should add a free textbook and a vocabulary list with clear examples.', "Avoid this course by all means. This is absolutely the worst course that I have ever enrolled and seriously I still can't understand how coursera allows such courses to exist. ", "excellent content. the forum is dead and there are some mistakes in the school solution that couldn't be address for that reason. 5 start for content, 1 star for staff participation and discussion forum.", 'Quite outdated', 'This course covered basic information. However, the organize about assignments is horrible. Tables format change from time to time, and the solution does not even match with questions. ', 'A very boring way to bring up the subject.', None, 'A lot of fluff is included, but taught the basics of SQL and entity relationship diagrams and normalisation, which to be pretty integral parts of understanding databases in a practical sense.', "I found the content was great but the style of lectures were a bit too robotic and not conversational. This didn't help the learning process. Also, the course admin might consider explaining 'On' 'And' 'Where' 'TIMESTAMP', 'DateDiff' more than what was provided. ", 'Assignments are very inaccurate. Mess with table and field names. Oracle VM is very heavy and slow to use on regular laptop.', 'The course is hardly intermediate level, I would put it at basic/beginner. Too much meta-discussions - probably 1-2 minutes of substance for each 6+ minute video. Very few examples for each concept (usually 1, rarely 2).', "Severe lack of support (zero) from the professor or TAs. Some wrong solutions were provided for assigments but were never addressed or acknowledged that it will be fixed. Some assignment files are not Mac friendly or is just not viewable by all students (I can't tell). Materials are quite good but grading is subject to broad interpretations and there is no human to provide guidance on what are the best practices. To think that I paid for the specialisation in order to take the graded assignment AND I have to do the grading BUT I do not receive support? This is ridiculous. I will have to think three times before I pay for a Coursera course in the future. Never again. I will not recommend this to others.", 'Most of the material I had to find outside of the course in order to complete the assignments. The professor just read from slides and did not show any hands on work like in other coursera classes. Weekly peer reviews were a disaster and not a reliable system if your grade depends on them. I submitted the same work twice, the first time I got a 66 and the second a 90. It seems that some people are not aware of what the rubric entails and you are penalized for it until someone else reviews your work again. Would suggest trying another database class offered.', 'In addition to outdated information in the query section, and some unnecessary focus on female genitalia in some assignments, the teaching is poor.', 'The course syllabus is well scoped out.  But the delivery is terrible - unclear or lack of explanation, boring presentation (sometimes uneven speech pace), poor slides content.  I use the syllabus content as a guide and refer to external material (youtube etc.) for the proper explanation of various topics.  ', "Presenter's style is way too boring. It felt like he was just reading a book. Every video contains more part of introduction and summary rather than actual content. Made me lose interest in online courses!", "Avoid this course like the plague. Terribly taught, no support, problems only vaguely related to the course material, and designed to force you to buy the manual for the course. The next classes in the specialization get even worse, with the student forums full of students who can't get any help though the grueling process of installing Oracle, Pentaho, etc.  on a personal laptop. I was fortunate to have experience with the tools, would have never managed to finish the course just based on the terribly taught material.", 'Was awesome. i loved the tutorials and how it was all broken down into modules and weeks', 'This course contains essential information and graded practice', 'Good course to understand SQL concept', 'Excellent']</reviews><reviewers>['By Judith G', 'By Zhu K', 'By Yong Y', 'By Sylvain L', 'By Quinten B', 'By Kostas A', 'By yoav z', 'By Shobana M a A', 'By Qin Q', 'By Julien L', 'By Eileene K G', 'By Elliott L', 'By John M', 'By Alexander S', 'By Kristiyan M', 'By Kwokmun L', 'By Kyle M', 'By Justin H', 'By kar a c', 'By Shubham P', 'By Serban T', 'By Banini P', 'By Daniel G', 'By Vivek S', 'By saumya']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'May 20, 2018', 'Mar 09, 2016', 'Jun 13, 2017', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Oct 31, 2017', 'Aug 23, 2018', 'May 13, 2016', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2016', 'Jan 03, 2016', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Jan 31, 2016', 'Sep 10, 2018', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'Feb 20, 2016', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>