<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_64</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/understanding-visualization-data</course_url><course_name>Understanding and Visualizing Data with Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brenda Gunderson</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, learners will be introduced to the field of statistics, including where data come from, study design, data management, and exploring and visualizing data. Learners will identify different types of data, and learn how to visualize, analyze, and interpret summaries for both univariate and multivariate data. Learners will also be introduced to the differences between probability and non-probability sampling from larger populations, the idea of how sample estimates vary, and how inferences can be made about larger populations based on probability sampling.

At the end of each week, learners will apply the statistical concepts they’ve learned using Python within the course environment. During these lab-based sessions, learners will discover the different uses of Python as a tool, including the Numpy, Pandas, Statsmodels, Matplotlib, and Seaborn libraries. Tutorial videos are provided to walk learners through the creation of visualizations and data management, all within Python. This course utilizes the Jupyter Notebook environment within Coursera.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Data Analysis//Python Programming//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>WEEK 1 - INTRODUCTION TO DATA//WEEK 2 - UNIVARIATE DATA//WEEK 3 - MULTIVARIATE DATA//WEEK 4 - POPULATIONS AND SAMPLES</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course!', 'What is Statistics?', 'Interview: Perspectives on Statistics in Real Life', '(Cool Stuff in) Data', 'Where Do Data Come From?', 'Variable Types', 'Study Design', 'Introduction to Jupyter Notebooks', 'Data Types in Python', 'Introduction to Libraries and Data Management'], ['Categorical Data: Tables, Bar Charts &amp; Pie Charts', 'Quantitative Data: Histograms', 'Quantitative Data: Numerical Summaries', 'Standard Score (Empirical Rule)', 'Quantitative Data: Boxplots', 'Demo: Interactive Histogram &amp; Boxplot', 'Important Python Libraries', 'Tables, Histograms, Boxplots in Python'], ['Looking at Associations with Multivariate Categorical Data', 'Looking at Associations with Multivariate Quantitative Data', 'Demo: Interactive Scatterplot', 'Introduction to Pizza Assignment', 'Multivariate Data Selection', 'Multivariate Distributions', 'Unit Testing'], ['Sampling from Well-Defined Populations', 'Probability Sampling: Part I', 'Probability Sampling: Part II', 'Non-Probability Sampling: Part I', 'Non-Probability Sampling: Part II', 'Sampling Variance &amp; Sampling Distributions: Part I', 'Sampling Variance &amp; Sampling Distributions: Part II', 'Demo: Interactive Sampling Distribution', 'Beyond Means: Sampling Distributions of Other Common Statistics', 'Making Population Inference Based on Only One Sample', 'Inference for Non-Probability Samples', 'Complex Samples', 'Sampling from a Biased Population', 'Randomness and Reproducibility', 'The Empirical Rule of Distribution']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Lectures are great but there's little practice material and the quizzes are terrible.  The quizzes are actually super easy but they don't cover much material from the course and sometimes introduce concepts and terms that were nowhere in the course materials. ", 'I love the U of M courses! I get so much out of them. Thank you again for helping me to advance my knowledge of Python and deepen my understanding of statistics.', "This course still has spelling mistakes in its quizzes, which in a programming focused course are big, and the instructors don't seem interested in fixing them. The result is you have to guess through their mistakes if code is suppose to not work in a quiz because of the error or the error is not supposed to be there in the first place and the code is valid.", 'This is the best course in this website in entry level', "I must say that this is a must take course for ones who are aspiring a career in Data Science. All the concepts were laid out so beautifully and it was explained very clearly with visualisations of each real-life-examples. I enrolled in this specialisation before starting my Machine Learning so that I have all the necessary  fundamentals of Statistics. Brady Sir &amp; Brendra Ma'am are simply phenomenal, the way they explain the concepts are incredible. The concepts gets etched in one's memory. The most exciting part of the course is Brenda Ma'am performing a cartwheel !! For all the ones who are enrolled, don't forget to watch it out.", 'More hands on assignments would be desirable.', '\nThe course contents are good to an introduction or refreshing in \nstatistics but the assigments are not really well prepared, and contains\n many unrepaired errors. This drops down the level an educational \npotential of this course (and the entire specialization) and converts it\n in a poor educational resource and a  waste of time, in my opinion\n\n\n\n', 'Very good course which covers both statistical concepts and python application.', 'Amazing course!', 'Nice!', 'I strongly recommend this course to those who want to begin python programming applied to statistics. It launches a very sound foundation for statistical inference theory.', 'Really enjoyed the different (yet all wonderful) teaching styles of the large instructor team!', 'Very good course instructors !  Excellent balance of basics of statistics and python programming oriented towards data analysis. Thoroughly enjoyed the course material. ', 'Great introduction', 'It was great setup for statistical analysis in python.', 'Thank you so much for this course. I loved it! :)', 'I loved this course! Thank you for sharing all your knowledge with us! ', 'A good introduction to visualizing data using the Python seaborn library', 'A good introduction on Statistics.', 'e', 'Excellent course for beginners from any subject related to engineering or science and who want to do research.', 'Excellent introductory course to statistics. Great use of NHANES dataset to demonstrate techniques on real dataset. I would appreciate a more demanding project at the course end. ', 'Really helpful to build a foundation for the basic Python and improve the understanding on basic but key concepts on statistics and visualizing techniques. Awesome!  ', 'Provides deep and systematic insight to the tits and bits of statistics using python.', 'A well paced stats refresher which covered the core material well and skillfully introduced current research.  The fourth week was a solid introduction to sampling methodologies and inference.  Looking forward to the next course in the sequence.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Daniel R', 'By David W', 'By Kristoffer H', 'By Md I', 'By Aayush G', 'By Jan T', 'By José A G P', 'By Marko P', 'By EDILSON S S O J', 'By Frank S Y R', 'By Jadson P A d S', 'By Jin S', 'By Rajesh R', 'By cameron g', 'By Varga I K', 'By Meghana K', 'By Patricia C G', 'By Yaron K', 'By Moid H', 'By Jorge A', 'By Saleem R', 'By Filip G', 'By Sangbaek P', 'By Arijit K G', 'By Richard R']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 22, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Apr 19, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2019', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Apr 16, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Apr 15, 2019']</review_date></doc>