<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_254</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/sas-programming-certification-review</course_url><course_name>Practical SAS Programming and Certification Review</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Stacey Syphus</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you have the opportunity to use the skills you acquired in the two SAS programming courses to solve realistic problems. This course is also designed to give you a thorough review of SAS programming concepts so you are prepared to take the SAS Certified Specialist: Base Programming Using SAS 9.4 Exam.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>SAS</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview and Data Setup//Review of Getting Started with SAS Programming, Part 1//Review of Getting Started with SAS Programming, Part 2//Case Study/Programming Assignment: Analyze TSA Claims Data//Review of Doing More with SAS Programming, Part 1//Review of Doing More with SAS Programming, Part 2//Case Study: Preparing World Tourism Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course', 'About the Certification Exam', 'How to Take This Course'], ['Program Structure and Syntax', 'Required SAS Column Attributes', 'Finding and Resolving Syntax Errors', 'Overview', 'Directly Accessing Structured Data', 'Importing Unstructured Data', 'Viewing Table Properties with PROC CONTENTS', 'Overview', 'Using SAS Procedures to Explore and Validate Data'], ['Overview', 'Using the DATA Step to Prepare Data', 'Using PROC SQL to Join Tables', 'Using PROC FREQ', 'Using PROC MEANS', 'Overview', 'Using PROC EXPORT', 'Using the Output Delivery System'], ['Case Study Overview', 'Accessing Data - Solution', 'Exploring Data - Solution', 'Preparing Data - Solution', 'Analyzing Data - Solution', 'Exporting Reports - Solution'], ['Understanding DATA Step Processing', 'Directing DATA Step Output', 'Summarizing Data', 'Using Numeric, Character, and Date Functions', 'Using the INTNX and INTCK Functions', 'Creating and Using Custom Formats'], ['Concatenating Tables', 'Merging Tables', 'Using Iterative and Conditional DO Loops', 'Using Nested DO Loops', 'Using the DATA Step to Restructure Tables', 'Using PROC TRANSPOSE to Restructure Tables'], ['Case Study Overview: Preparing World Tourism Data', 'View the Case Study Data', 'Create the Cleaned_Tourism Table, Part 1', 'Create the Cleaned_Tourism Table, Part 2', 'Create the Cleaned_Tourism Table, Part 3', 'Create the Final_Tourism Table', 'Create the NoCountryFound Table']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 27 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Just finished the whole specialization. I would say SAS programming specialization (and its courses) is the best one I've ever had on Coursera. It starts from simple concepts to complex tasks and projects. The best thing is the learner could get the hands dirty very quickly; usually a demo is followed with a practice task. Notice that the courses offered here are the same as those provided on SAS website (SAS itself has e-learning courses), but here you have more problems (and two projects in course 3) to practise. Highly recommend.", "This course was disappointing overall.  There is nothing you will learn, which wasn't covered in the previous two course.  Far worse, the review is done in the same sequence as the other two courses, so there really is never a chance to combine what was learned.  The challenges will be in the same order as the previous challenges, so don't expect any synthesis of skills you have developed.  There are two bigger problems, but it feels as if this course should have been a series of these.  If you are about to be billed again, there is no real reason to complete this third course.", 'This is an excellent course. I can highly recommend it. It does not only review the previous two courses but let\'s one use the acquired skills in two "real-world" assignments.', 'Excellent SAS overview, shows the strategies for data manipulation and then guides one through how to implement them.', 'Getting Harder but the Case Study are extremely helpful, thanks for all the materials.', 'Very interesting course. Learned a lot about SAS.', 'This is by far the best course I have come across in coursera. The structure of the program is excellent. The exercises are very good', 'hard but practically usefull', 'This is a wonderful course for beginners.', 'The wrap up and the exercises are very useful. I am still recommending to those who would like to take the SAS base examination.', 'Very good course. Taught how to apply concepts to real world problems. Excellent for certificate exam preparation.', 'Perfect course which gives opportunity to check knowledge and  apply it on real examples!', 'Good summary but there could be more exercises.', 'Amazing reviews for the SAS analytic tool kit. Well designed courses with segmented and modulated videos and hands-on practice. Completing all the practice exercise will give you the edge to fully familiarize with the materials covered! Aced the exam within 2 weeks of preparation. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Chutian Z', 'By Michael K', 'By Thomas N', 'By Gregg H', 'By Xinkai Z', 'By Fabrice L', 'By Abhishek R', 'By chenxiao x', 'By Rajesh S', 'By Lau T K', 'By Vidhi U', 'By Oleksandr L', 'By Elżbieta', 'By Victor(JingFeng) X']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 18, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Jun 17, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2019', 'Aug 18, 2019', 'Sep 05, 2019', 'Sep 13, 2019', 'Sep 16, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019']</review_date></doc>