<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_158</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/dwdesign</course_url><course_name>Data Warehouse Concepts, Design, and Data Integration</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Michael Mannino</course_instructor><course_introduction>This is the second course in the Data Warehousing for Business Intelligence specialization. Ideally, the courses should be taken in sequence.

In this course, you will learn exciting concepts and skills for designing data warehouses and creating data integration workflows. 
These are fundamental skills for data warehouse developers and administrators. You will have hands-on experience for data warehouse design and use open source products for manipulating pivot tables and creating data integration workflows.You will also gain conceptual background about maturity models, architectures, multidimensional models, and management practices, providing an organizational perspective about data warehouse development. If you are currently a business or information technology professional and want to become a data warehouse designer or administrator, this course will give you the knowledge and skills to do that. By the end of the course, you will have the design experience, software background, and organizational context that prepares you to succeed with data warehouse development projects.  

In this course, you will create data warehouse designs and data integration workflows that satisfy the business intelligence needs of organizations. When you’re done with this course, you’ll be able to:
   * Evaluate an organization for data warehouse maturity and business architecture alignment;
   * Create a data warehouse design and reflect on alternative design methodologies and design goals;
   * Create data integration workflows using prominent open source software;
   * Reflect on the role of change data, refresh constraints, refresh frequency trade-offs, and data quality goals in data integration process design; and
   * Perform operations on pivot tables to satisfy typical business analysis requests using prominent open source software</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Design and Product</course_category><course_tag>Extraction, Transformation And Loading (ETL)//Pentaho//Data Integration//Data Warehouse</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado System</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Data Warehouse Concepts and Architectures//Multidimensional Data Representation and Manipulation//Multidimensional Data Representation and Manipulation: Lesson Choices//Data Warehouse Design Practices and Methodologies//Data Integration Concepts, Processes,and Techniques //Architectures, Features, and Details of Data Integration Tools</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course introduction video lecture', 'Course objectives video lecture', 'Course topics and assignments video lecture', 'Motivation and characteristics video lecture', 'Learning effects for data warehouse development video lecture', 'Data warehouse architectures and maturity video lecture', 'Data Warehouse Examples video lecture', 'Employment opportunities video lecture'], ['Data cube representation video lecture', 'Data cube operators video lecture', 'Overview of Microsoft MDX video lecture', 'Microsoft MDX statements video lecture', 'Overview of Pivot4J video lecture', 'Overview of WebPivotTable video lecture', 'WebPivotTable software demonstration', 'Pivot4J software demonstration video lecture'], ['Quiz for module 2 assignment - WebPivotTable', 'Quiz for module 2 assignment - Pivot4J'], ['Relational database concepts for multidimensional data video lecture', 'Table design patterns video lecture', 'Summarizability patterns for dimension tables video lecture', 'Summarizability patterns for dimension-fact relationships video lecture', 'Mini case for data warehouse design video lecture', 'Data warehouse design methodologies video lecture'], ['Concepts of data integration processes video lecture', 'Change data concepts video lecture', 'Data cleaning tasks video lecture', 'Pattern matching with regular expressions video lecture', 'Matching and consolidation video lecture', 'Quasi identifiers and distance functions for entity matching video lecture'], ['Architectures and marketplace video lecture', 'Common features of data Integration tools video lecture', 'Talend Open Studio video lecture', 'Pentaho Data Integration video lecture', 'Software video demonstration for Pentaho Data Integration', 'Course conclusion video lecture']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The torture of having to identify which of the many combinations of Pentaho, Java and some freeware plugin actually works in the end has completely ruined this experience. I don't care if SOMEWHERE in the notes there is info I should install Version 5.0.2.3 instead of 5.0.whatever, this is just plain laziness in the course design by picking software which might have worked in the past and then not updating the instructions while pocketing the student's money for years to come. I have about had it with spending my nights installing and re-installing this junk of software nobody uses anyways in a real business setting only to advance in this class. ", 'The quality of assignments is awful', 'No guidance from instructors, and the assignments have nothing to do with the lectures. If I could get a refund, I would quit and get my money back. Not worth the frustration.', None, 'Pentaho does not work, hence I was not able to complete week 2 assignment and the course.', 'I just re-reviewed the 1 week and will re-review it within the day, prior to taking the exam.  overall the presentor is very capable and has mastery of the subject which is very very good. I love this course and i hope I could have this re-reviewed once I get to have the paid subscription.  ', 'very good', 'Extremely helpful course to learn regarding Data warehouse concepts', 'good course', 'Great lecture for DW/BI', 'Excellent', 'Excellent course, you will learn how to use data warehouse tools, you will gain design experience and have organisational context to work in data warehouse development projects.  My experience from this course is you need to be quite dedicated to pass.', 'Great Hands on experience!!', 'This Course has given new life to me', 'nice course very usefull', 'A very good course. It is challenging, especially the assignment in week 3, but extremely rewarding. Thanks to Coursera and the University of Colorado for creating this course. Really good to get an understanding of enterprise level data warehouses. ', 'I love both the theoretical and practical nature of this course. Enough content is provided to ensure a smooth introduction to data warehouses and proficiency in the important concepts of Extraction, transformation and loading. The progression of content across the weeks is excellent and Michael is definitely the best instructor in the subject.', 'Great course, includes data warehousing practices using Pentaho DI Studio.', 'T', 'Excellent course. Very logical sequence of presentation, accompanied by well designed exercises. ', 'Excelente curso', 'Thank you for all.', 'Excelente!!!!', 'Excellent course in the way of preparation to be a Expert in Business Intelligence and Data Warehouses.', 'Excellent course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nils K', 'By Александр К', 'By Rochelle H', 'By Sebastian G', 'By sujay b s', 'By Deleted A', 'By Maneesha R', 'By MOHIT K J', 'By Ashish G', 'By 백승원', 'By saumya', 'By Nasheena', 'By Revanth K', 'By SANJEEVE K G', 'By Francisco I S R', 'By Nelson F A', 'By Felix M', 'By Matheus Z', 'By Michael F', 'By Adam R', 'By Daniel G M P', 'By Alexander K', 'By Alejandro R', 'By Franklin P G', 'By William K']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 16, 2017', 'Nov 10, 2018', 'Aug 20, 2017', 'Jan 02, 2017', 'Jan 18, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Oct 14, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2018', 'Aug 02, 2017', 'Jun 06, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2015', 'Dec 22, 2015', 'Jan 04, 2016', 'Apr 23, 2017', 'Mar 20, 2016', 'Mar 26, 2016', 'Dec 14, 2015']</review_date></doc>