<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_397</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/r-packages</course_url><course_name>Building R Packages</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Roger D. Peng, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Writing good code for data science is only part of the job. In order to maximizing the usefulness and reusability of data science software, code must be organized and distributed in a manner that adheres to community-based standards and provides a good user experience. This course covers the primary means by which R software is organized and distributed to others. We cover R package development, writing good documentation and vignettes, writing robust software, cross-platform development, continuous integration tools, and distributing packages via CRAN and GitHub. Learners will produce R packages that satisfy the criteria for submission to CRAN.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Programming Tool//Github//Continuous Integration//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started with R Packages//Documentation and Testing//Licensing, Version Control, and Software Design//Continuous Integration and Cross Platform Development</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Building R Packages'], ['Documentation', "Vignette's and README Files", 'Knitr / Markdown', 'Common knitr Options', 'Help Files and roxygen2', 'Common roxygen2 Tags', 'Overview', 'Data for Demos', 'Internal Data', 'Data Packages', 'Summary', 'Introduction', 'The testthat Package', 'Passing CRAN Checks'], ['Overview', 'The General Public License', 'The MIT License', 'The CC0 License', 'Overview', 'Paying it Forward', 'Linus’s Law', 'Hiring', 'Summary', 'Introduction', 'git', 'Initializing a git repository', 'Committing', 'Browsing History', 'Linking local repo to GitHub repo', 'Syncing RStudio and GitHub', 'Issues', 'Pull Request', 'Merge Conflicts', 'Introduction', 'The Unix Philosophy', 'Default Values', 'Naming Things', 'Playing Well With Others', 'Summary'], ['Overview', 'Web Services for Continuous Integration', 'Using Travis', 'Using AppVeyor', 'Summary', 'Introduction', 'Handling Paths', 'Saving Files &amp; rappdirs', 'rappdirs', 'Options and Starting R', 'Package Installation', 'Environmental Attributes', 'Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['There is much I like about this course and also many areas for improvement. First, the online book that comes with the course presents an excellent overview of the steps required to build an R package. It will eventually get you where you need to go. However, some of the material is now out of date (e.g. functions moved from one package to another), there are no longer any mentors around, and the discussions boards are empty apart from people trying to get their assignments peer graded. Also, the content in the book, while good, is incomplete in many cases. I would highly suggest buying the "R Packages" book by Hadley Wickham as an additional reference since it fills many of the gaps and goes into much greater detail.', 'good but needs a little updating - several commands this teaches you to use are now depracated.', 'Poor course material made it difficult to complete the final assignment. The course has little to do with R and more to do with Software development methodologies.', 'There are not so mang classmates for peer reviewing. Please set other alternative ways for grading', 'Amazing course! Will explain every detail regarding R package creation.', 'Great course!', 'I finally started building R packages!!! Lots of useful bits', "It's one of better course for building packages!!!", 'Very good course for intermediate/advanced R users.  Sad that you are elegible to do assignments only if you pay.', 'very useful, especially the final practical exam', "This is a critical skill and it's barely covered anywhere else. Thanks for making this course!", 'R packages are essential learning. This class covers packages including documentation, vignettes, testing, building, and checking for compatibility with CRAN. It also gets you into git and travis (for continuous integration), with an entire side of open source philosophy and legal. If you can pass this, you *will* be able to create and maintain an R package. ', 'This course provides useful knowledge in building R packages, as well as opportunities to implement our knowledge. However, as the previous courses in the series, the last module (week) is extremely challenging compared to the previous ones.', 'The difficulty of the c ourse will depend on your background. If you have software development experience plus git, the course details the steps of releasing an R package to the community. If you have never worked with git or released software, this is a good way to tie those skills to your R skills.', '\n\nExcellent, but I would be grateful if you could translate all your courses of absolute quality into Spanish.  ', 'This was a great challenging course! Love it.', 'Good slow walk through of the process for creating and checking a package', 'Overall, this was a good course to learn the intricacies of building R packages. ', None, "This course really boosted my confidence in writing codes, functions and i look forward to someday writing my own package.  The course left me on such a high note that I made a couple of presentations using the plots in my vignette. I wanted to somehow show my appreciation to the authors of the course. The choice of a real life dataset made it really very interesting for me.  Here's the link to the presentations i made.  I'm not sure if it should be shared with your students, so i'll leave that up to you. Thanks again for making learning so much fun. BTW, it was a bit of a cliffhanger for me. I only got my package to pas travis at the last minute. Here are the links: ", 'Nice', '  Great course  ', "Fantastic course... Unfortunately, not too many people registered, it's tough to get your assignments graded. The program is the great continuation to the 10 course R data science specialization...", 'Good course, but very specialized programming knowledge in this particular course, which was not the case with other courses in the specialization. Would only recommend this course for those with the necessity to build R packages. ', 'I learned a lot in this course, was difficult at the begininng but enjoyable at the end!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Shawn M', 'By Matthew M', 'By Jonathan D', 'By Yi X', 'By Abhinav S', 'By Jorge L R Z', 'By Anthony S', 'By Gustavo B', 'By Moises E', 'By Francesco D Z', 'By Christopher B', 'By Jason S', 'By Youdinghuan C', 'By Jay B', 'By Gregorio A A P', 'By William G', 'By James M', 'By Cardy M I', 'By José E L', 'By Edmund J L O', 'By Ganapathi N K', 'By JEEWESH K J', 'By konstantin m', 'By Conner M', 'By Johans A A']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 16, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Jul 14, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Nov 16, 2018', 'Jul 07, 2017', 'Jan 16, 2017', 'Aug 01, 2017', 'Mar 30, 2017', 'Nov 28, 2017', 'Dec 25, 2017', 'Aug 05, 2017', 'Aug 26, 2017', 'Mar 01, 2017', 'Feb 08, 2018', 'Oct 07, 2017', 'May 29, 2017', 'Jan 21, 2018', 'May 29, 2018', 'Nov 01, 2017', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Mar 22, 2018']</review_date></doc>