<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_366</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/text-mining-analytics</course_url><course_name>Hands-on Text Mining and Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Min Song</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course provides an unique opportunity for you to learn key components of text mining and analytics aided by the real world datasets and the text mining toolkit written in Java. Hands-on experience in core text mining techniques including text preprocessing, sentiment analysis, and topic modeling help learners be trained to be a competent data scientists. 

Empowered by bringing lecture notes together with lab sessions based on the y-TextMiner toolkit developed for the class, learners will be able to develop interesting text mining applications.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Yonsei University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Logistics and the Text Mining Tool for the Course//Text Preprocessing//Text Analysis Techniques//Term Weighting and Document Classification//Sentiment Analysis//Topic Modeling</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.1 Description of the course including the objectives and outcomes', '1.2 Explanations of the y-TextMiner package and the datasets', '1.3 How-to-do: workspace installation and setup', '1.4 How-to-use: the y-TextMiner package (download it at http://informatics.yonsei.ac.kr/yTextMiner/yTextMiner1.2.zip)'], ['2.1 Description of possible project ideas', '2.2 What is text mining?', '2.3 Description of preprocessing techniques', '2.4 How-to-do: normalization including tokenization and lemmatization', '2.5 How-to-do: N-Grams'], ['3.1 Description of stopword removal, stemming, and POS tagging', '3.2 Explanations of named entity recognition', '3.3 Explanations of dependency parsing', '3.4 How-to-do: stopword removal and stemming', '3.5 How-to-do: NER and POS Tagging', '3.6 How-to-do: constituency and dependency parsing'], ['4.1 Explanations of TF*IDF', '4.2 Explanations of document classification', '4.3 Explanations of sentiment analysis', '4.4 How-to-do: computation of tf*idf weighting', '4.5 How-to-do: classification with Logistic Regression'], ['5.1 Explanations of sentiment analysis with supervised learning', '5.2 Explanations of sentiment analysis with unsupervised learning', '5.3 Explanations of sentiment analysis with CoreNLP, LingPipe and SentiWordNet', '5.4 How-to-do: sentiment analysis with CoreNLP', '5.5 How-to-do: sentiment analysis with LingPipe', '5.6 How-to-do: sentiment analysis with SentiWordNet'], ['6.1 Description of Topic Modeling', '6.2 Explanations of LDA and DMR', '6.3 Description of Topic Modeling with Mallet', '6.4 How-to-do: LDA', '6.5 How-to-do: DMR']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 24 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Excellent theory and hands-on lab codes. It'd be great if you could also cover how-to in other relevant programming languages using R or Python. ", None, 'Excellent course !!', 'Great &amp; Hot Topic. ', 'The presentation slides are not available for downloading and I did not like the evaluation method.  Good if you want to do text mining with Java and to know the libraries available for this.', 'The course is interesting and you learn things.', 'Does not explain how to download Workstation properly', 'The instructor in the course is very bad. The knowledge dissemination is also cursory. You might get familiar with few concepts but this is not an in-depth course on this subject. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Kyle A', 'By Alexander A S G', 'By el k W', 'By Dr. M H A J ', 'By Razan M', 'By Almudena A C', 'By Jake M', 'By Abhishek V']</reviewers><review_date>['May 31, 2017', 'Jun 06, 2017', 'May 05, 2017', 'Jan 26, 2018', 'Jun 02, 2017', 'Aug 25, 2018', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Apr 22, 2017']</review_date></doc>