<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_219</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-analytics-decision-making</course_url><course_name>Business Analytics for Decision Making</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Manuel Laguna</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will learn how to create models for decision making. We will start with cluster analysis, a technique for data reduction that is very useful in market segmentation. You will then learn the basics of Monte Carlo simulation that will help you model the uncertainty that is prevalent in many business decisions. A key element of decision making is to identify the best course of action. Since businesses problems often have too many alternative solutions, you will learn how optimization can help you identify the best option. What is really exciting about this course is that you won’t need to know a computer language or advanced statistics to learn about these predictive and prescriptive analytic models. The Analytic Solver Platform and basic knowledge of Excel is all you’ll need. Learners participating in assignments will be able to get free access to the Analytic Solver Platform.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Simulation//Business Analytics//Mathematical Optimization</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado Boulder</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Data Exploration and Reduction — Cluster Analysis//Dealing with Uncertainty and Analyzing Risk//Identifying the Best Options — Optimization//Decision Analytics</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the Course', '0. What is Cluster Analysis', '1. Data Reduction and Unsupervised Learning', '2. Preparing Data and Measuring Dissimilarities', '3. Hierarchical and k-Means Clustering', '4. Cluster Analysis with Excel', '5. Cluster Analysis with XLMiner'], ['0. Risk Analysis and Monte Carlo Simulation', '1. Adding Uncertainty to a Spreadsheet Model', '2. Defining Output Variables and Analyzing the Results', '3. Using Historical Data to Model Uncertainty', '4. Models with Correlated Uncertain Variables', '5. Creating and Interpreting Charts', '6. Using Average Values versus Simulation'], ['0. Optimization and Decision Making', '1. Formulating an Optimization Problem', '2. Developing a Spreadsheet Model', '3. Adding Optimization to a Spreadsheet Model', '4. What-if Analysis and the Sensitivity Report', '5. Evaluating Scenarios and Visualizing Results to Gain Practical Insights', '6. Digital Marketing Application of Optimization'], ['0. Advanced Models for Better Decisions', '1. Business Problems with Yes/No Decisions', '2. Formulation and Solution of Binary Optimization Problems', '3. Metaheuristic Optimization', '4. Chance Constraints and Value At Risk', '5. Simulation Optimization']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great learning opportunity Through Mr. Laguna its an outstanding way of bringing the classes for our business processes right at the desktop for our e', 'This course provides a brilliant overview of Business Analytics problems. Bit more details about the underlying mathematical techniques used would be helpful.', 'Although this course covers some useful techniques in data analysis it is largely a sales tool for the ASP (Analytics Solver Platform) which you only get a trial for. This course would be more useful if it taught the techniques using excel or basic mathematical solutions to understand the probability distributions and other items covered. If you are interested in learning general data analysis this is not the course for you.', 'Amazing course to learn a bunch of new aspects in a business organization', 'Great class', 'Very interesting, covered a lot of information very thoroughly for a 4-week course. Well-explained.', 'Great Teacher, Great Course. Love it', 'Great Course !', 'Very useful', 'I liked the way professor organized the course. Concept and example were clearly illustrated. ', None, 'Good introduction to the Analytic Solver Platform for Excel used for various prediction and prescriptive modeling. Could use better integration of slides and transcripts but that is a personal preference since I like my notes to read more like a textbook rather than spread across a simple text file, a video, a sparse PowerPoint deck, and some Excel workbooks. Too disjointed for easy review in my mind.', 'very useful and well explained', "Very interesting subject with a good instructor. I'd like to be able to cover the content in more detail, but it was a good introduction to optimization theory.", 'Really beneficial!', None, 'Very well presented and excellent content is provided.', None, 'Very enlightening two weeks.  Learned a lot', 'Wonderful course!', 'very well presented. best in the specialization so far', 'Very', None, 'A great course', 'Very good course in order to have an overview on mathematical tools that can be used to optimi']</reviews><reviewers>['By Manish B', 'By Subhajit G', 'By Anna R', 'By Pooja S D', 'By Ana T', 'By Jennifer Z', 'By Shiyu D', 'By PRALAY P', 'By Swaraj D', 'By Qi X', 'By Tinotenda M', 'By Michael L O', 'By Luciano E', 'By Dario A', 'By Rajat S ', 'By Malin A', 'By Shafi K', 'By Sreedhar R', 'By Richard F', 'By Md. A H B', 'By Lydia V', 'By Sunglak S', 'By Nedchanok H', 'By Jayashree', 'By JERRY S']</reviewers><review_date>['May 24, 2019', 'May 20, 2018', 'Sep 03, 2017', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2017', 'Jun 13, 2018', 'Jun 11, 2018', 'Apr 29, 2018', 'Apr 18, 2017', 'Aug 04, 2017', 'May 31, 2017', 'Nov 24, 2016', 'Nov 28, 2016', 'Mar 09, 2018', 'Jul 30, 2017', 'Feb 12, 2017', 'Feb 01, 2018', 'May 22, 2017', 'May 05, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2016', 'May 22, 2017', 'Jun 21, 2018', 'Jul 12, 2017', 'Dec 09, 2016', 'Oct 22, 2018']</review_date></doc>