<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_33</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-customer-analytics</course_url><course_name>Customer Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Eric Bradlow</course_instructor><course_introduction>Data about our browsing and buying patterns are everywhere.  From credit card transactions and online shopping carts, to customer loyalty programs and user-generated ratings/reviews, there is a staggering amount of data that can be used to describe our past buying behaviors, predict future ones, and prescribe new ways to influence future purchasing decisions. In this course, four of Wharton’s top marketing professors will provide an overview of key areas of customer analytics: descriptive analytics, predictive analytics, prescriptive analytics, and their application to real-world business practices including Amazon, Google, and Starbucks to name a few. This course provides an overview of the field of analytics so that you can make informed business decisions. It is an introduction to the theory of customer analytics, and is not intended to prepare learners to perform customer analytics. 

Course Learning Outcomes: 

After completing the course learners will be able to...

Describe the major methods of customer data collection used by companies and understand how this data can inform business decisions

Describe the main tools used to predict customer behavior and identify the appropriate uses for each tool 

Communicate key ideas about customer analytics and how the field informs business decisions

Communicate the history of customer analytics and latest best practices at top firms</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Strategy</course_category><course_tag>Predictive Analytics//Customer Analytics//Regression Analysis//Marketing Performance Measurement And Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Customer Analytics//Descriptive Analytics//Predictive Analytics//Prescriptive Analytics//Application/Case Studies</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction and Overview', 'Overview of the Business Analytics Specialization'], ['What is Descriptive Analytics?', 'Descriptive Data Collection: Survey Overview', 'Descriptive Data Collection: Net Promoter Score and Self-Reports', 'Descriptive Data Collection: Survey Design', 'Passive Data Collection', 'Media Planning', 'Causal Data Collection and Summary'], ['Introduction to Predictive Analytics', 'Asking Predictive Questions', 'Regression Analysis, Part 1: The Demand Curve', 'Regression Analysis, Part 2: Making Predictions', 'Beyond Period 2', 'Making Predictions Using a Data Set', 'Data Set Predictions: Mary, Sharmila, or Chris?', 'Probability Models', 'Implementation of the Model', 'Results and Predictions'], ['Introduction', 'What is Prescriptive Analytics?', 'Using the Data to Maximize Revenue', 'Parameters of the Model', 'Market Structure', 'Competition and Online Advertising Models', 'Conclusion(s)'], ['Introduction to Application to Analytics', 'The Future of Marketing is Business Analytics', 'The Golden Age of Marketing', 'Applications: ROI', 'Radically New Data Sets in Marketing', 'The Perils of Efficiency', "Analytics Applied: Kohl's, NetFlix, AmEx and more", 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course talks about various techniques and methodologies. But does not get into details. For example, churn analysis. They talk about churn analysis but does not get into the details on how to perform a churn analysis. ', 'Theoretical', "Good survey of the topic but only focused on B2C.  If that were my focus, I'd give it a higher rating.  I was hoping for insights on B2B as that is my field, even if only a short video to address differences/similarities/peculiarities.", 'Good as an introductory course for customer analytics.', 'Though I have worked on Customer Analytics with my previous work experiences and also on Surveys etc at George Brown College Canada, this module was more than insightful. Lots of learning to learn eh!', 'Insightful and a great introduction to a very complex topic. Probably would recommend having a grasp of statistical analysis before starting (not required) as it would help understand some of the concepts better. ', "Wow! This was so insightful into how our social media and daily habits are used. I don't like feeling like a sheep, so this awareness is appreciated. I'm still trying to design how I could apply this to my Trade.", 'Brilliant Course !! Loved going through all the materials and the lectures !!', 'Perfect Course for those who want to inquire insight and knowledge of how tons of data that we generate in our day to day life is being utilized by big organizations in optimizing their productivity. ', 'Amazing course for even beginners in the field of customer analytics. Highly recommend to do this course for enhancing the analytical skills. Examples and case studies explains the concept very well.', 'Very Detailed course on Customer Analytics. And it presented quite a few case studies too, to understand the concepts better. But I felt that a hands on experience of applying Customer Analytics to a problem in a step wise fashion would have cemented the knowledge gained by this course. ', "It was an amazing experience. Though the course won't provide much of a mathematical side to analytics but holds strong grounds in decision making and ways a person should think before landing upon the final decision.", 'Excellent knowledge about Customer Analysis', 'Very informative course,Well explained', 'Very interesting and useful. With this course you can learn in a few weeks the basics of Marketing Science, what it has became a must in business, specially for decision making.', 'Amazing course!Helped me a lot in improving my marketing analytics concepts. ', 'Super great class. The way that this course teaches me is interactive and stimilates a lot of personal thinking. Also the structure of the course is super lean and clear. ', 'Great course.', 'clarity knowledge delivery，helpful program，thanks for the platform!', 'Wonderful Course', "This is a great course for those who don't have any previous knowledge about analytics.  ", 'its a great course to start with', 'Excellent course with diverse knowledge gained.', 'very interesting and I learned a lot in which I hope to use professionally.  Thank you so much for the opportunity to take this course.', 'a very impressive course']</reviews><reviewers>['By Vinod D T', 'By Tariq H', 'By Raul', 'By Apoorv K', 'By Noel D', 'By Paulius P', 'By Tiffany T', 'By Suparno B', 'By ayush a', 'By Shruti S', 'By Akshay K', 'By Shivam K', 'By Shaharol N B M', 'By Shailesh P', 'By Joaquín C M', 'By Saurabh S', 'By Wenqi O', 'By Sonia W', 'By zanzhongyang', 'By Sourabh A K', 'By Prathamesh W', 'By Ashutosh', 'By Bhavya D', 'By Joseph F', 'By 阮心宇']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 29, 2018', 'Sep 05, 2017', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'May 11, 2018', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Jul 28, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2017', 'Nov 15, 2016', 'Oct 07, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018']</review_date></doc>