<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_114</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/dataviz-design</course_url><course_name>Essential Design Principles for Tableau</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Govind Acharya</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, you will analyze and apply essential design principles to your Tableau visualizations. This course assumes you understand the tools within Tableau and have some knowledge of the fundamental concepts of data visualization. You will define and examine the similarities and differences of exploratory and explanatory analysis as well as begin to ask the right questions about what’s needed in a visualization. You will assess how data and design work together, including how to choose the appropriate visual representation for your data, and the difference between effective and ineffective visuals. You will apply effective best practice design principles to your data visualizations and be able to illustrate examples of strategic use of contrast to highlight important elements. You will evaluate pre-attentive attributes and why they are important in visualizations. You will exam the importance of using the "right" amount of color and in the right place and be able to apply design principles to de-clutter your data visualization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Tableau Software//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started in Effective and Ineffective Visuals//Visual Perception and Cognitive Load//Design Best Practices and Exploratory Analysis//Design for Understanding</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'The Human Brain and Data Visualization', 'Cognitive vs Perceptual Design Distinction', 'Introduction of Effective and Ineffective Visuals', 'Types of Visualizations', 'Examples of the Types of Visualizations in Tableau', 'Practicing Good Ethics in Data Visualization', 'Ineffective Visuals and How to Improve Them'], ['Visual Perception and Cognitive Principles Introduction', 'Cognitive Load and Clutter', 'Principles of Visual Perception', 'Strategic Use of Contrast', 'Pre-Attentive Attributes of Visualizations', 'Color as a Pre-Attentive Attribute', 'De-Cluttering Exercise'], ['Design Best Practices Introduction', 'Gestalt Principle: Proximity', 'Leveraging Pre-Attentive Attributes', 'Accessible Visualizations', 'Aesthetics', 'Design and Exploratory Analysis Introduction', 'What is Exploratory and Explanatory Analysis?', "Case Study: Anscombe's Quartet", 'Identifying Outliers', 'Constructing a Control Chart'], ['Design For Understanding Introduction', 'Know Your Audience(s)', 'Design For Purpose', 'Data, Relationships, and Design', 'Static Versus Interactive Visualizations', 'Multiple, Connected View', 'Language, Labeling, and Scales', 'Visual Lies and Cognitive Bias', 'Final Thoughts']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['A really poor course.', "It was a exelent course for me, I was thinking just in technology, but the topics reviewed are exelent to know, how design a presentation. It's amazing, now I can apply this knowlodege in all aspect of my work. Thank you!!!", 'The course is not only focusing on the Tableau project, but also discussing key notes that need applying to make visualization become more effective. That is great course! Thanks!', 'good', 'This was a great course, it had lots of information on design principle which not only helps for people working on Tableau but any other presentation tools', 'Great course! I enjoyed it a lot. I think I will do all in this specialization.', 'The materials involving Tableau are simple and can be completed in a short time, so no need to spend a lot of hours on watching videos and submitting discussions. Some assignments are not quite related to operating Tableau.', "Not sure I would recommend this course. The course doesn't walk you through an example of how to meet and complete the requirements of the peer graded assignment. I got a notice that I needed to redo the peer assignment, but no feedback was given as to what I needed to be corrected in order to resubmit. I've also been looking for some sort of practical application video to show me how to actually use Tableau. Whenever I submit some feedback, I can never get a response from anybody. Is this course actually being facilitated by the instructor? HELP!!!!! I'm asking for help and assistance!!!", 'The material is not encapsuled on the course and the use of only peers evaluation on practical exercises.', "Mostly irrelevant theory and virtually no hands on use of Tableau. Curriculum is weak, doesn't walk you through how to do enough in Tableau.", 'Excellent course content, instructors and assignments.', 'Thumbs Up!', 'Great Course. Thank you Coursera', 'nice course', 'Govind and his team have designed a awesome course. Communicating the concepts in a effective manner ', 'Great course. Great Videos', 'Well taught course .. I highly recommend to enroll for this course 2 of the specialization if you want to build your path gradualy to creating very efficient and well communicating visualizaion. Happy Learning!', 'Learned a lot about knowing who the audience is (that I am designing a visualization for), also about use-of-color and de-cluttering my visualization.', 'Great course. As usual, the lecturers hit it out of the ballpark. ', 'I enjoyed the course, it helped me to understand design principles and design my visualizations based on them. Thank you !', 'Great course', None, 'Best course to learn about design principles.', 'Nice one', 'Wonderful course, very informative!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Víctor M C', 'By Claudia G G', 'By Nhan T N', 'By Anand L', 'By Prudha J', 'By Dumitru P', 'By Yichi Z', 'By Gil Y', 'By Bruno G d F e S', 'By David R', 'By Tushar K', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By Muhammad A Y', 'By Nitin K', 'By Abey', 'By Pravesh ', 'By Jamiil T A', 'By Tony - C A D', 'By Leonard N B', 'By mahnoush m', 'By Juan V', 'By Atchut S', 'By Aditya D', 'By Гарамжав', 'By E. M']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 08, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'May 20, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Aug 21, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'Jan 05, 2018', 'Jul 15, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Sep 04, 2018', 'Oct 19, 2018', 'Sep 20, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2018', 'Jun 01, 2018']</review_date></doc>