<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_74</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/probabilistic-graphical-models</course_url><course_name>Probabilistic Graphical Models 1: Representation</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daphne Koller</course_instructor><course_introduction>Probabilistic graphical models (PGMs) are a rich framework for encoding probability distributions over complex domains: joint (multivariate) distributions over large numbers of random variables that interact with each other. These representations sit at the intersection of statistics and computer science, relying on concepts from probability theory, graph algorithms, machine learning, and more. They are the basis for the state-of-the-art methods in a wide variety of applications, such as medical diagnosis, image understanding, speech recognition, natural language processing, and many, many more. They are also a foundational tool in formulating many machine learning problems. 

This course is the first in a sequence of three. It describes the two basic PGM representations: Bayesian Networks, which rely on a directed graph; and Markov networks, which use an undirected graph. The course discusses both the theoretical properties of these representations as well as their use in practice. The (highly recommended) honors track contains several hands-on assignments on how to represent some real-world problems. The course also presents some important extensions beyond the basic PGM representation, which allow more complex models to be encoded compactly.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Bayesian Network//Graphical Model//Markov Random Field</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Stanford University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction and Overview//Bayesian Network (Directed Models)//Template Models for Bayesian Networks//Structured CPDs for Bayesian Networks//Markov Networks (Undirected Models)//Decision Making//Knowledge Engineering &amp; Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome!', 'Overview and Motivation', 'Distributions', 'Factors'], ['Semantics &amp; Factorization', 'Reasoning Patterns', 'Flow of Probabilistic Influence', 'Conditional Independence', 'Independencies in Bayesian Networks', 'Naive Bayes', 'Application - Medical Diagnosis', 'Knowledge Engineering Example - SAMIAM', 'Basic Operations ', 'Moving Data Around ', 'Computing On Data ', 'Plotting Data ', 'Control Statements: for, while, if statements ', 'Vectorization ', 'Working on and Submitting Programming Exercises '], ['Overview of Template Models', 'Temporal Models - DBNs', 'Temporal Models - HMMs', 'Plate Models'], ['Overview: Structured CPDs', 'Tree-Structured CPDs', 'Independence of Causal Influence', 'Continuous Variables'], ['Pairwise Markov Networks', 'General Gibbs Distribution', 'Conditional Random Fields', 'Independencies in Markov Networks', 'I-maps and perfect maps', 'Log-Linear Models', 'Shared Features in Log-Linear Models'], ['Maximum Expected Utility', 'Utility Functions', 'Value of Perfect Information'], ['Knowledge Engineering']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 30 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Would be better if there are people monitoring the discussion board and actually answer student's questions.", "The content of the course is good but the assignments are in matlab which isn't as widely used as python and has the additional headache of licensing. it is the assignments where you really learn things so this is a serious negative point.", 'This course was solid overall but not excellent.  I learned the basics of different classes of probabilistic models including Bayesian networks and Markov networks and how to represent them.  Prof. Koller is knowledgeable and presented the materially logically.  With that said, this course could have been a lot better than it was.', 'This course seems to have been abandoned by Coursera. Mentors never reply to discussion forum posts (if there is any active mentor at all). Many assignments and tests are confusing and misleading. There are numerous materials you can find online to learn about Graphical Models than spending time &amp; money on this.', "This is not an easy course, so beware. The instruction is solid but you still need to reason through a lot on your own, and especially if you choose to complete the Honors programming section (which I highly recommend to prove to yourself that you really understand what you have learned and can apply it), you really need to plan on allocating sufficient number of hours to work through the programming assignments.  You'll likely need to re-watch several of the video segments several times for it to really sink in, as well as referencing the Discussion Forum when you are stuck and need inspiration.  Once you do complete this course (after many hours of work and thought) you will enjoy a deep sense of accomplishment, will look and think about decision-making in a fresh new way, and have learned many very useful skills.", 'In the video, a lot of knowledge point do not explain very clearly, we do not konw how to resolve the quizzes. Moreover, if buy the textbook, may acquire more detail about PGM, but the textbook do not explain very clear neither. Textbook is hard to read. Even so, this course is worthwile to learn. Because PGM is one of the basic theory of machine learning and widespread use. In the end, thank Koller and coursera! Thank you very much!', 'Dear Madam thanks a lot for the course.', '总体上很棒的课程，除了第四周的荣誉编程的体验有待提升。课程难度适中，不容易，但认真思考和理解后是没有问题的。很期待专项课程中剩余的课程。 ', 'I have Actually Earned Three Years of my life (at least) and one possible patent because of this course.', "Sometimes the questions weren't clear. But in general, I really like the course and the things I've learnt I am sure they are useful.", 'I really enjoyed the content of this course.  Having been inspired by reading The Book of Why, I was looking for some formal language around Bayesian Networks and this course really fit the bill.  My biggest piece of feedback is on the programming assignments.  These really should be in Python.  Octave is an okay choice, and I suspect might have to do with Andrew Ng original choice to use it for his own machine learning course. However, the data science community writ large uses Python and R, which is why Andrew switched to Python for his deep learning courses.  I would recommend the programming assignment be updated so that they are more accessible to the data science community. ', "The material is really important and helpful for many concepts of Machine Learning. Daphne Koller is very good at explaining complicated ideas in an intuitive way. The programming assignments are very relevant and cover many real-world application scenarios in medical diagnosis and testing. Unfortunately, programming assignments have many flaws. First, some scripts do not work and therefore it is necessary to manually adjust these in order to submit your assignment part by part. Second, the forum is almost dead, which means that is is difficult to get help once you are stuck at a problem. Most of the helpful posts are almost two years old. Third, often times questions in the quiz are very vague and not clearly formed which makes it difficult to answer the instructor's question. All in all, I think, that the course is worthwhile but nonetheless the course definitely needs some refurbishing and bugs in scripts need to be fixed.  ", "Good course, with actual university level content and depth (albeit in a multiple choice format). The explanations of the material were clear, however if you don't have at least a surface level familiarity with Bayesian probability and first year university level math, you'll find yourself spending a lot of time looking up random jargon on Wikipedia. ", "The course contents are presented very clearly. Difficult ideas are conveyed in a precise and convincing way. Despite this, the global structure is not presented very clearly, and the quality of some course material is not excellent. In particular, I didn't find the optional programming assignments particularly interesting, and the code/questions contained more than one bug. Also, the quality of video/sound is quite poor, and varies a lot from course to course.", 'maza aa gaya', 'Absolutely love it!!!! ', 'funny！！', 'Great course. Interesting concepts to learn, but some of them are too quickly and poorly explained.', 'Great course. Recommended to everyone who have interest on bayesian networks and markov models.', 'A great course!  The provided training clarifies all key concepts', 'Very good explanation and excellent assignments', 'A very nice-designed course', '不错的一门课', 'Great course ', 'Outstanding teaching and the assignments are quite useful!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ben L', 'By Sandeep M', 'By Michael S E', 'By Deleted A', 'By Alex L', 'By StudyExchange', 'By Santosh K S', 'By Shi Y', 'By Dhruv P', 'By Phillip W', 'By Alexander P', 'By Amine M', 'By M', 'By Lorenzo B', 'By Utkarsh A', 'By Marno B', 'By 张浩悦', 'By Alexandru I', 'By BOnur b', 'By Lik M C', 'By Mahmoud S', 'By Shengding H', 'By 刘仕琪', 'By Musalula S', 'By Pablo G M D']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 13, 2019', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Feb 14, 2017', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Apr 09, 2018', 'Mar 13, 2018', 'Jul 28, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jun 18, 2017', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Apr 02, 2019', 'Apr 30, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2018', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Dec 30, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Oct 31, 2016', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2018']</review_date></doc>