<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_186</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/social-media-data-analytics</course_url><course_name>Social Media Data Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Chirag Shah</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learner Outcomes: After taking this course, you will be able to:
- Utilize various Application Programming Interface (API) services to collect data from different social media sources such as YouTube, Twitter, and Flickr.
- Process the collected data - primarily structured - using methods involving correlation, regression, and classification to derive insights about the sources and people who generated that data.
- Analyze unstructured data - primarily textual comments - for sentiments expressed in them.
- Use different tools for collecting, analyzing, and exploring social media data for research and development purposes.

Sample Learner Story: Data analyst wanting to leverage social media data.
Isabella is a Data Analyst working as a consultant for a multinational corporation. She has experience working with Web analysis tools as well as marketing data. She wants to now expand into social media arena, trying to leverage the vast amounts of data available through various social media channels. Specifically, she wants to see how their clients, partners, and competitors view their products/services and talk about them. She hopes to build a new workflow of data analytics that incorporates traditional data processing using Web and marketing tools, as well as newer methods of using social media data.

Sample Job Roles requiring these skills: 
- Social Media Analyst
- Web Analyst
- Data Analyst
- Marketing and Public Relations 

Final Project Deliverable/ Artifact: The course will have a series of small assignments or mini-projects that involve data collection, analysis, and presentation involving various social media sources using the techniques learned in the class.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Statistical Analysis//Sentiment Analysis//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.1</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rutgers the State University of New Jersey</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Data Analytics//Collecting and Extracting Social Media Data//Data Analysis, Visualization, and Exploration//Case Studies</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Video-1: Introduction', 'Video-2: Structured vs. Unstructured Data', 'Video-3: Analyzing Structured Data', 'Video-4: Visualization of Data'], ['Video-1: Introduction', 'Video-2: Introduction to Python Programming', 'Video-3: Using Python to Extract Data from Twitter', 'Video-4: Using Python to Extract Data from YouTube'], ['Video-1: Introduction', 'Video-2: Analyzing Social Media Data Using Python', 'Video-3: Introduction to R', 'Video-4: Social Media Data Analysis with R'], ['Video-1: Introduction', 'Video-2: Sentiment Analysis with Twitter Data', 'Video-3: Text Mining of Twitter Data', 'Video-4: Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['very nice couse but peer assignment is very difficult taks', 'Excellent course !', "One of the best courses I've came across in Coursera. Chirag Sir is simply awesome, the way he describes things is just amazing! I would like to work under him or his connections if given a chance! This course boosted my confidence also.", 'very good', 'Very useful to learn the basics of social media analysis (twitter and youtube) with python and R.', 'excellent course ... gave me a lot of learning.', 'Very good course for overall picture of this field', None, 'Instructor was great, deliver lectures really nice. Looking for some more stuff from Dr. Shah', 'Good.', 'Tips you into the direction of great resources, but sometimes lacks in the explanations, leaving most code not explained. Not a deal breaker, and a worthy introduction but a more detailed explanation at times would help.', 'Interesting course, could have added a bit more on how to write basic scripts or more ways of social media analytics', 'This is an inroductory cousre tou', 'En general esta muy bien para empezar, aunque, algunos codigos no estan completos, sirve de incentivo para la autodidactica.', 'The course material should be provided on coursera itself. Instead of having to download a 1.8GB dataset from yelp, the two files could have been shared here. ', 'The course gives an overall exposure about the subject. The focus could be tighten into one program, and there could be more readings/videos about the idea how social media data should be analyzed or interpreted. Yet, the course has too much attention to tools (R and Python).', 'There should be an option that allows you to pass peer assignment reviews if there are no more submitted assignments. Maybe let us review past submissions instead?', 'Good overview, could be more robust and thorough!', None, None, 'A good, basic introduction to Social Media Data Analytics', "Well. this course could improve a lot. Some of the videos are bad edited and a few of the exercise files supplied by the instructor didn't work as the example at the video so I had to google a fix for the exercise so I could finish it on time.", 'This course did not go into the depth I had expected', 'Really beginner course. No in deep explanations. Just scratching the surface of the topics. There are several links for more informations that are not working. I needed a lot of time to fix the scripts that were provided by the tutor. Too much money for this very short course. One can  do it in 3 days instead of 4 weeks. However it gave me a start in APIs... someone who has zero experience in programming in R or Python can even make this course.', 'Very little appreciation of the codes provided']</reviews><reviewers>['By Muhammad i', 'By Javit A', 'By Rajat K', 'By Alexander A S G', 'By Juan F', 'By Barnava N', 'By Zhassulan S', 'By Sanjay F', 'By Abdul B M', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Fermin Q', 'By Vaibhav S', 'By Imre F', 'By Yeifer R C', 'By Petra', 'By Metin Y', 'By Cheng H K', 'By Arnav D', 'By naveen b', 'By Dr S M', 'By Agata F', 'By Johnnatan L', 'By Ardysatrio F H', 'By Tronje P K', 'By faiezy']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 07, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2017', 'Dec 04, 2017', 'Apr 17, 2017', 'Jul 11, 2017', 'Dec 17, 2017', 'May 30, 2017', 'May 10, 2018', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Nov 07, 2016', 'Nov 17, 2016', 'Nov 28, 2016', 'Jun 25, 2018', 'Apr 16, 2017', 'Jul 10, 2017', 'May 24, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2016', 'Nov 22, 2016', 'May 23, 2017', 'Jan 31, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2017', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'May 14, 2019', 'Aug 21, 2017']</review_date></doc>