<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_324</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/mobile-health-monitoring-systems</course_url><course_name>The Development of Mobile Health Monitoring Systems</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Evgenii Pustozerov</course_instructor><course_introduction>This join course created by SPSU and ETU  includes 5 modules dedicated to different stages of the system development. Its modules represent several widely separated fields of biomedical engineering. We interconnect them by applying the knowledge from them all to a common task – the development of a prototype of an mHealth ECG system with built-in data-driven signal processing and analysis. Working on this task throughout the course, you will acquire a knowledge on how these branches of science, including electronics, mathematics, data science and programming are applied together in a real project. Pieces of hardware and software, as well as the data sets that we utilize in this course are the same components that we use in our work developing prototypes of devices and algorithms for our tasks in science and engineering.
The course is a joint work of Saint Petersburg State University and Saint Petersburg Electrotechnical University ETU ("LETI").
Note that the goal of the course is not to provide you with fundamental knowledge on any of the topics highlighted in the modules, but to give you some useful skills on implementing them in practical tasks.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Design and Product</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>Saint Petersburg State University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Remote health monitoring system hardware//Data Exchange Between Device And Personal Computer//Preprocessing of Biomedical Signals//Event Detection in Biomedical Signals//Developing Data-Driven Recommendation System</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'The Structure of Remote Health Monitoring Systems', 'Problems Related to Hardware Development', 'Typical Scheme of an ECG Recording Channel', 'The Basics of Analog-to-Digital Conversion. Types of ADC', 'AFE Implementation for ECG Registration', 'Implementation of an AFE Evaluation Board', 'Basics of Arduino Platform Programming', 'A Simple Program for the Arduino Board', 'Arduino Peripheral Devices (UART, ADC, GPIO)', 'Programming an Arduino ADC'], ['Serial Interface', 'COM-Port Setup in MATLAB', 'Package Data Transferring', 'Connecting Arduino Via Virtual COM-Port', 'Working with Arduino Hardware Support Package for MATLAB', 'Plotting Real-Time Data with Arduino Hardware Package', 'Saving Data from Arduino Virtual COM-Port'], ['Measurement System Chain', 'Noise in Biomedical Signals', 'Spectral Analysis Basics. The Fourier Transform', 'Alternative Spectral Estimation', 'Spectral Analysis in MATLAB', 'Digital Filters', 'Transfer Function', 'Filter Design Using MATLAB'], ['Problem Statement', 'Feature Extraction Based on Signal Spectral Characteristics', 'Statistical Signal Processing Methods', 'Feature Extraction Using MATLAB', 'Peak Detection Algorithms', 'Simple Derivative-Based Algorithm for QRS Detection', 'Peak Detector in MATLAB', 'Feature Engineering in Accordance with the Task', 'Feature Engineering Example for an ECG Signal', 'Results Visualization and Analysis'], ['Exploration of Data Sample', 'Statistical Metrics and Sample Data Visualization', 'Analysis of Variance', 'Creating Data-Driven Models', 'Logistic Regression', 'Model Performance Evaluation', 'Improving Model Performance', 'Real-Time Data Flow Simulation', 'Practical Implementation of a Data-Driven Recommendation System']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent', 'more practical training is needed in this area :) ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Sasikumar G ', 'By Çağın Ç']</reviewers><review_date>['May 23, 2019', 'Aug 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>