<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_271</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-analytics-accountancy-1</course_url><course_name>Data Analytics Foundations for Accountancy I</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Robert Brunner</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Data Analytics Foundations for Accountancy I! You’re joining thousands of learners currently enrolled in the course. I'm excited to have you in the class and look forward to your contributions to the learning community.

To begin, I recommend taking a few minutes to explore the course site. Review the material we’ll cover each week, and preview the assignments you’ll need to complete to pass the course. Click Discussions to see forums where you can discuss the course material with fellow students taking the class.

If you have questions about course content, please post them in the forums to get help from others in the course community. For technical problems with the Coursera platform, visit the Learner Help Center.

Good luck as you get started, and I hope you enjoy the course!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Orientation//Module 1: Foundations//Module 2: Introduction to Python//Module 3: Introduction to Data Analysis//Module 4: Statistical Data Analysis//Module 5: Introduction to Visualization//Module 6: Introduction to Probability//Module 7: Exploring Two-Dimensional Data//Module 8: Introduction to Density Estimation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Data Analytics Foundations for Accountancy I', 'Meet Professor Brunner'], ['Introduction to Module 1', 'The Importance of Data Analytics in Modern Accountancy', 'Introduction to the Course JupyterHub Server', 'Introduction to Markdown', 'Introduction to Python'], ['Introduction to Module 2', 'Why Accounting Students Should Learn to Code', 'Python Data Structures', 'Introduction to Python Functions', 'Python Programming Concepts'], ['Introduction to Module 3', 'Why Use Python Instead of Excel?', 'Introduction to Unix', 'Python File I/O', 'Introduction to Pandas'], ['Introduction to Module 4', 'How the Pandas Module Can Support Standard Business Analytics', 'Introduction to Numpy', 'Introduction to Descriptive Statistics', 'Advanced Pandas'], ['Introduction to Module 5', 'Creating Clear and Powerful Visualizations', 'Visualization of Quantitative Data', 'Introduction to Plotting', 'Introduction to Data Visualization'], ['Introduction to Module 6', 'Introduction to Probability', 'Introduction to Bayes Theorem', 'Calculating Probabilities in Python', 'Introduction to Distributions'], ['Introduction to Module 7', 'Introduction to Scatter Plots', 'Introduction to Numpy Matrices', 'Statistical Issues When Exploring Multi-Dimensional Data', 'Introduction to Ordinary Linear Regression'], ['Introduction to Module 8', 'Why Do Accounting Students Need Data Analytics Skills?', 'Introduction to Density Estimation', 'Advanced Density Estimation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 52 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Little instruction occurs during this course - basically you will teach yourself from an intermediate-level smattering of lessons, the quizzes cover topics not covered in the materials, assignments appear to contain errors, and there is effectively no support from the teacher or assistants.. the vast majority of questions are unanswered.  ', 'Amazing course in terms of design, content. I was badly searching for a course in Data Analytics for Accounting Professionals. This course fits the right content needed to start of ones basics in learning Python and then seamlessly integrates into Accounting Profession. Thanks to amazing professor, he makes the solid content look easy to grasp.', "This is a great course to expose you to a lot of different topics. I've gotten more comfortable with Python, and have a number of topics to draw from when thinking through how to analyze financial data. This is a must if you want to become a better analyst."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Kevin M', 'By Vijay G K', 'By Paul V']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 06, 2019', 'Apr 07, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>