<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_385</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/geodesign</course_url><course_name>Geodesign: Change Your World</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Prof. Kelleann Foster</course_instructor><course_introduction>What happens when creativity and science come together?  The power to design our world is unleashed, providing tools to inform choices about how we live!  Geodesign is the glue—it’s a process that deploys creativity to connect information to people, using collaboration to better inform how we design our world.

This course includes well-illustrated lectures by the instructor, but also guest lectures each week to ensure you are hearing a variety of viewpoints.  Each week you will also be able to examine what geodesign is through interactive mapping that showcases real-word Case Study examples of geodesign from around the globe.  As you move along in the course, you will discover the interrelationships of both the physical and human aspects that contribute to how geodesign strategies are composed.  The course concludes with you outlining your own Geodesign Challenge, and receiving feedback about that from your peers.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Environmental Science and Sustainability</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Pennsylvania State University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1: Shared Languages//Week 2: The Three D's of Geodesign//Week 3: The Three C's of Geodesign//Week 4: The Influence of Context//Week 5: Process and Framework</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction Video', 'Main Lecture: Week 1', 'Guest Lecture 1: Week 1', 'Guest Lecture 2: Week 1'], ['Main Lecture: Week 2', 'Guest Lecture 1: Week 2', 'Guest Lecture 2: Week 2'], ['Main Lecture Week 3', 'Guest Lecture 1: Week 3', 'Guest Lecture 3: Week 3'], ['Main Lecture Week 4', 'Guest Lecture 1: Week 4', 'Guest Lecture 2: Week 4'], ['Main Lecture Week 5', 'Guest Lecture 1: Week 5', 'Guest Lecture 2: Week 5']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very nice course', 'I love it!', 'Its agreat introduction if you want to get new knoledge', "This course is so well presented that it seems unlikely that even the most casual student won't learn essential principles of geodesign and be able to apply them to real life situations.", 'Excelent! A wide view about geodesign...', 'Very interesting! Is a basic geodesign course but introduce professions in a different and very important way of thinking: shows the importance on plane urban landscapes with more environmental respect.', "Liked the guest lectures and the examples. Very apt case studies to help understand and learn from every week's main lecture. ", 'Great basic course. I hope it give more detailed answer about cases study']</reviews><reviewers>['By nken j b', 'By Marcos G', 'By Roberto M H', 'By Judith V', 'By Ricardo C M', 'By Eliana A', 'By Archanaa P', 'By Muhammad I']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 19, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2017', 'Aug 07, 2017', 'Sep 28, 2018', 'Jun 17, 2018', 'Mar 03, 2017', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'Apr 05, 2017']</review_date></doc>