<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_273</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/logistic-regression-r-public-health</course_url><course_name>Logistic Regression in R for Public Health</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Bottle</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Logistic Regression in R for Public Health! 

Why logistic regression for public health rather than just logistic regression? Well, there are some particular considerations for every data set, and public health data sets have particular features that need special attention. In a word, they're messy. Like the others in the series, this is a hands-on course, giving you plenty of practice with R on real-life, messy data, with predicting who has diabetes from a set of patient characteristics as the worked example for this course. Additionally, the interpretation of the outputs from the regression model can differ depending on the perspective that you take, and public health doesn’t just take the perspective of an individual patient but must also consider the population angle. That said, much of what is covered in this course is true for logistic regression when applied to any data set, so you will be able to apply the principles of this course to logistic regression more broadly too. 

By the end of this course, you will be able to: 
Explain when it is valid to use logistic regression 
Define odds and odds ratios 
Run simple and multiple logistic regression analysis in R and interpret the output 
Evaluate the model assumptions for multiple logistic regression in R 
Describe and compare some common ways to choose a multiple regression model 

This course builds on skills such as hypothesis testing, p values, and how to use R, which are covered in the first two courses of the Statistics for Public Health specialisation. If you are unfamiliar with these skills, we suggest you review Statistical Thinking for Public Health and Linear Regression for Public Health before beginning this course. If you are already familiar with these skills, we are confident that you will enjoy furthering your knowledge and skills in Statistics for Public Health: Logistic Regression for Public Health. 

We hope you enjoy the course!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>Logistic Regression//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Logistic Regression//Logistic Regression in R//Running Multiple Logistic Regression in R//Assessing Model Fit</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course', 'Introduction to Logistic Regression', 'Odds and Odds Ratios'], ['Preparing the Data For Logistic Regression', 'Logistic Regression in R'], ['How to Run Multiple Logistic Regression in R'], ['Choosing a Logistic Regression Model', 'Overfitting and Non-convergence', 'Summary of the Course']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This is one of the best courses. Dr. Alex is amazing and delivers the content quite well.', 'very good course!! highly recommend!! Although I am not major in public health, I learned a lot about logistic regression and basic ideas for data science', 'Excellent course! Highly recommended for people who want an introduction to Logistic Regression. I hope the instructor offers another version of the course with little more advanced material (for example, ordinal and multinomial logit models). ', 'Course is very easy to follow', 'very recommendable course', 'Excellent and very complete course on R. Specially for those working in public health and with an interest in understanding models of clinical trials, etc.', 'would have helped if there were even a glance about logistic with multiple outcomes']</reviews><reviewers>['By Moses C B A', 'By ji t', 'By Vivekananda D', 'By Shova P', 'By Ning D', 'By Tommys J G G', 'By Ahmed M Y O']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 01, 2019', 'Apr 05, 2019', 'Jun 19, 2019', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2019', 'Sep 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>