<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_322</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning-applications-big-data</course_url><course_name>Big Data Applications: Machine Learning at Scale</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Vladimir Lesnichenko</course_instructor><course_introduction>Machine learning is transforming the world around us. To become successful, you’d better know what kinds of problems can be solved with machine learning, and how they can be solved. Don’t know where to start? The answer is one button away.
 
During this course you will:
- Identify practical problems which can be solved with machine learning
- Build, tune and apply linear models with Spark MLLib
- Understand methods of text processing
- Fit decision trees and boost them with ensemble learning
- Construct your own recommender system.
 
As a practical assignment, you will 
- build and apply linear models for classification and regression tasks; 
- learn how to work with texts; 
- automatically construct decision trees and improve their performance with ensemble learning; 
- finally, you will build your own recommender system!

With these skills, you will be able to tackle many practical machine learning tasks.
 
We provide the tools, you choose the place of application to make this world of machines more intelligent.

Special thanks to:
- Prof. Mikhail Roytberg, APT dept., MIPT, who was the initial reviewer of the project, the supervisor and mentor of half of the BigData team. He was the one, who helped to get this show on the road.
- Oleg Sukhoroslov (PhD, Senior Researcher at IITP RAS), who has been teaching  MapReduce, Hadoop and friends since 2008. Now he is leading the infrastructure team.
- Oleg Ivchenko (PhD student APT dept., MIPT), Pavel Akhtyamov (MSc. student at APT dept., MIPT) and Vladimir Kuznetsov (Assistant at P.G. Demidov Yaroslavl State University), superbrains who have developed and now maintain the infrastructure used for practical assignments in this course.
- Asya Roitberg, Eugene Baulin, Marina Sudarikova. These people never sleep to babysit this course day and night, to make your learning experience productive, smooth and exciting.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Yandex</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome//(Optional) Machine Learning: Introduction//Spark MLLib and Linear Models//Machine Learning with Texts &amp; Feature Engineering//Decision Trees &amp; Ensemble Learning//Recommender Systems//Recommender Systems (practice week)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Machine Learning Applications for BigData', 'Course Structure', 'Meet Alexey', 'Meet Pavel', 'Meet Ilya'], ['(Optional) Intuition', '(Optional) Basic concepts', '(Optional) Types of problems and tasks', '(Optional) Supervised learning', '(Optional) Unsupervised learning', '(Optional) Business applications of the machine learning'], ['Introduction to large scale machine learning', 'First example. Linear regression', 'How MLlib library is arranged', 'How to train algorithms. Gradient descent method', 'How to train algorithms. Second order methods', 'Large scale classification. Logistic regression', 'Regularization', 'PCA decomposition', 'K-means clustering', 'How to submit your first assignment', 'How to Install Docker on Windows 7, 8, 10'], ['Welcome', 'Feature Engineering for Texts, part 1', 'Feature Engineering for Texts, part 2', 'N-grams', 'Hashing trick', 'Categorical Features', 'Feature Interactions', 'Spark ML. Feature Engineering for Texts, part 1', 'Spark ML. Feature Engineering for Texts, part 2', 'Spark ML. Categorical Features', 'Topic Modeling. LDA.', 'Word2Vec'], ['Welcome', 'Decision Trees Basics', 'Decision Trees for Regression', 'Decision Trees for Classification', 'Decision Trees: Summary', 'Bootstrap &amp; Bagging', 'Random Forest', 'Gradient Boosted Decision Trees: Intro &amp; Regression', 'Gradient Boosted Decision Trees: Classification', 'Stochastic Boosting', 'Gradient Boosted Decision Trees: Usage Tips &amp; Summary', 'Spark ML. Decision Trees &amp; Ensembles', 'Spark ML. Cross-validation'], ['Recommender Systems, Introduction. Part I', 'Recommender Systems, Introduction. Part II', 'Non-Personalized Recommender Systems', 'Content-Based Recommender Systems', 'Recommender System Evaluation', 'Collaborative Filtering RecSys: User-User and Item-Item', 'RecSys: SVD I', 'RecSys: SVD II', 'RecSys: SVD III', 'RecSys: MF I', 'RecSys: MF II', 'RecSys: iALS I', 'RecSys: iALS II', 'RecSys: Hybrid I', 'RecSys: Hybrid II'], ['Recommender Systems. Spark Assignment']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 77 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['many things was impressive', 'Excellent course', 'It was good. People made lot of work on it... ', 'need more simple examples and literature links', 'Needs more examples and to reduce the speed in many subjects.', 'Course contained lots of new information for me, but exercises were too simple in comparison with other courses of specialization.', 'Oh, that lovely accent', 'Lack of clarity on how to answer questions both in quiz and programming', 'Nice course, but the impression about practical tasks is really awful. The tasks are ok, but grading system is too buggy', 'I wish there were more practice', "The videos are good, it's just the assignments that are frustrating.", 'The assignments are not clear and the teacher support is poor (despit the slack channel being a welcome improvement!).', 'The course is interesting and challenging. Some work is needed on how to best transfer the right message to the students. Some videos are going way to deep into technical details and not focusing enough on the end goal. Overall interesting and mind-engaging course.', 'Unexistant support, failing notebooks', 'Just a highlevel introduction to machine learning with comments like "you can also do it on spark". No details about the parallel learning process (parameter server, etc)', 'The autograders are broken and team support is lacking. Decent lecture content however.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Pramod W', 'By sekhar', 'By Rami', 'By Evgeniy C', 'By Alberto B', 'By Сергей Б', 'By Egor M', 'By Paulo H C', 'By Kiselyov A', 'By Mykola K', 'By Marco G', 'By Martin T', 'By Papadopoulos K', 'By Ángel M R', 'By Alexander C', 'By Kirk B']</reviewers><review_date>['May 24, 2018', 'Mar 27, 2018', 'Aug 01, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'Sep 17, 2018', 'Jul 08, 2018', 'Nov 03, 2017', 'Jul 13, 2019', 'May 23, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Sep 20, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019']</review_date></doc>