<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_335</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-statistics-analysis-capstone</course_url><course_name>Business Statistics and Analysis Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sharad Borle</course_instructor><course_introduction>The Business Statistics and Analysis Capstone is an opportunity to apply various skills developed across the four courses in the specialization to a real life data. The Capstone, in collaboration with an industry partner uses publicly available ‘Housing Data’ to pose various questions typically a client would pose to a data analyst.
Your job is to do the relevant statistical analysis and report your findings in response to the questions in a way that anyone can understand.
Please remember that this is a Capstone, and has a degree of difficulty/ambiguity higher than the previous four courses. The aim being to mimic a real life application as close as possible.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Predictive Analytics//Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Business Statistics and Analysis Capstone: An Introduction//Business Statistics and Analysis Capstone: Assessments 1 &amp; 2//Business Statistics and Analysis Capstone: Assessment 3//Business Statistics and Analysis Capstone: Assessment 4</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['A Summary of the Four Courses in the Specialization', 'Introducing the Capstone', 'A Conversation with Garfield Fisher, the industry partner for the Capstone', 'Q&amp;A with Garfield Fisher', 'Data for the Capstone Project', 'Merging and Cleaning Data for the Capstone'], ['Introducing Assignment 1: Differences in Market Value of Housing Units', 'Introducing Assignment 2: Fair Market Rent of Housing Units'], ['Introducing Assignment 3: A Model for Market Value of Housing Units'], ['Introducing Assignment 4: Building a Predictive Model for Market Value of Housing Units']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It's the capstone of the specialization where you apply all what you've learnt in the previous courses. I really liked the whole specialization. Thanks", 'The Capstone project gets ready to think in real-world scenarios and how you have to think and approach the data that you have to process it then transform it into the desired results. I was a bit nervous at the beginning but then I could get confident and could do all the assignments thanks to Capstone that help me think as a real Data Analyst that I feel I am from now on.', 'Very useful course for someone interested in the fundamentals of business predictions and regression models.', 'The course has really helped in developing a niche in the Excel which is essential for every engineers and professionals. Excel has been a widely used tools and almost all the organisation have got this platform to carry out their day to day business. Moreover, the examples and the problems described in the lectures were real life examples in a business setting. These has been quite helpful in understanding business problems and constraints. ', 'Great course to start learning business analysis using statistical inferences with Excel. Real actual business problems and solutions. ', '  Rigorous and rewarding when you put the work in.  ', 'n', 'Great opportunity to put in practice what was learned throughout the courses. Thanks!!', 'Professor Sharod is great. I learned a lot from this course ', 'great course, great instructor.  The entire series was very beneficial.', 'Excellent Course.  Thank you.  Very useful knowledge', 'Fun and challenging, I really appreciated having the chance to have a guided practice with real world data.', 'Challenging tasks but worth to cracking them!', 'excellent content. ', None, 'The Capstone was very interesting and challenging. It helped reinforce the concepts that we learned in the other courses within the Business Statistics and Analysis specialisation. I had great fun doing the various exercises, I have gained a better insight into statistics as a result of the 5 course specialization. The specialization is well designed and Professor Sharad Borle has been a great guide and instructor throughout this specialization. ', 'This course strikes a great balance between giving guidance &amp; giving freedom to the learner to self discover the solutions. The case study is also interesting!', 'Excellent Course, I have learnt a lot!', 'Nice Course', 'Good course. Excellent Instructor. thanks', 'Excellent course and instruction materials. Very engaging and carefully structured to allow all learners to succeed. ', 'Really solidified the previous subjects in the course. Using larger sets of real data was extremely helpful as it  taught small lessons, e.g. around data cleansing, that are implicit in data analysis but require a more experiential approach. Thank you Sharad.', 'Processing data can be very slow via Excel.', 'Good summary of the prior 4 courses with an emphasis on linear regression models. I learned how to leverage excel for descriptive and predictive data analysis. Thanks!', 'Not nearly as informative or straightforward as the previous 4 courses in the series.  ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Shady N S T', 'By Sofia L', 'By Andras F', 'By Sudhir K', 'By Andre N', 'By Kim K', 'By Muhammad Z M', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Nazmus S S', 'By John D I', 'By Mark H', 'By Marcos P', 'By Li Y', 'By Himanshu P', 'By Федор Е', 'By Siddharth S', 'By Edward S', 'By shaorong Z', 'By BHUPESH K', 'By jorge l', 'By Bell, M W', 'By Samantha B', 'By Sun', 'By Colin P', 'By Rohan G L']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 03, 2019', 'Aug 30, 2018', 'Feb 22, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2017', 'Aug 19, 2019', 'Aug 08, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Oct 16, 2018', 'May 23, 2018', 'Jun 20, 2018', 'Jul 13, 2017', 'Jul 13, 2017', 'May 07, 2017', 'Feb 10, 2018', 'Apr 03, 2018', 'Feb 13, 2018', 'Jul 13, 2017', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Sep 16, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2018', 'Jun 22, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2017']</review_date></doc>