<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_78</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-science-course</course_url><course_name>A Crash Course in Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>By now you have definitely heard about data science and big data. In this one-week class, we will provide a crash course in what these terms mean and how they play a role in successful organizations. This class is for anyone who wants to learn what all the data science action is about, including those who will eventually need to manage data scientists. The goal is to get you up to speed as quickly as possible on data science without all the fluff. We've designed this course to be as convenient as possible without sacrificing any of the essentials.

This is a focused course designed to rapidly get you up to speed on the field of data science. Our goal was to make this as convenient as possible for you without sacrificing any essential content. We've left the technical information aside so that you can focus on managing your team and moving it forward.

After completing this course you will know. 

1. How to describe the role data science plays in various contexts
2. How statistics, machine learning, and software engineering play a role in data science
3. How to describe the structure of a data science project
4. Know the key terms and tools used by data scientists
5. How to identify a successful and an unsuccessful data science project
3. The role of a data science manager


Course cover image by r2hox. Creative Commons BY-SA: https://flic.kr/p/gdMuhT</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Data Analysis//Machine Learning//Project</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>A Crash Course in Data Science</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About Your Instructors', 'What is Data Science?', 'Statistics by example activities', 'Machine learning, the basics', 'Machine learning further reading', 'What is Software Engineering for Data Science?', 'The Structure of a Data Science Project', 'The outputs of a data science experiment', 'The four secrets of a successful data science experiment', 'Data Scientist Toolbox', 'Separating Hype from Value']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 5 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great starting point for any experienced professional with no data science background to understand this growing in-demand field, its purpose, the various components that comprise data science, in addition to overall objectives and outcomes of data science.  Allows you to evaluate how much further one would like to dive into the field respective of your personal or professional objectives.  ', 'Very nice way to get introduced to the world of data science. Thanks a lot!', 'Nice and well taught .There is really alot to learn', 'A light overview about Data Science that can be really useful as a first time on this topic.', 'Executive Summary: Do not spend time on this course if you have minimal common sense and have read at least one article on Data Science.', 'good ', 'It was my first experience on an Online course, and was really good!', 'High level background on data science in 1 module is well covered !!', 'Excellent starting intro course', 'This is a good course for beginners to start thinking about data science. The quizzes are not trivial and make you think and research. ', 'Great Introduction to DataScience', 'Quick and big picture concepts explained', 'Amazing Course. ', 'Clear with easy to understand concepts. The course made great use of examples and video lectures to bring participants up to speed on Data Science basics.', 'Some of the quiz questions could be clearer. Other than that, I have learnt a lot ', 'Interesting for a Non-Data Science Executive despite some minor spelling errors in video transcripts.', 'The course is general enough for non-specialist, but rigorous enough to keep you challenged and interested. Highly recommend for anyone who deals with data and data analysts / engineers as part of their work, or who aspires to do so.', 'A very well designed course to begin the journey of (not-hyped) data science. Thank you!', 'Excellent course coverage and helpful to understand the difference between hype and value.', 'Fundamental for beginners.', 'Gives a very brief overview of data science. If you have some experience it might be a bit superficial, but it is nevertheless a clean introduction to data science from a management perspective. ', 'I have enjoyed while learning new things', "This is a great course if you just need to know what Data science is and it isn't. ", 'liked the course and real world contents', 'Thoroughly enjoyed working through this course in ONE day as a true "crash" course. Certainly helped get many ideas cemented in my mind about what DS is about and the structure and realities of running DS projects. Great materials, well laid out and structured.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Omar Z', 'By PRAVEEN K S', 'By ezechukwu', 'By Rafael H R', 'By Sven M', 'By kailas s', 'By Diego B', 'By Yogesh B C A S', 'By Marc C', 'By Santosh S', 'By Jay P', 'By Kevin P', 'By Nadeem S', 'By Kimberly K', 'By Fatih Y', 'By Elton K', 'By DB', 'By Victor B', 'By Raj R', 'By João C S', 'By Andreas O', 'By Alzum S M', 'By Mallon L', 'By TARUN C', 'By Matthew B L T']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 08, 2019', 'Jun 02, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Sep 18, 2016', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Jan 19, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>