<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_51</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/clinical-research</course_url><course_name>Understanding Clinical Research: Behind the Statistics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Juan H Klopper</course_instructor><course_introduction>If you’ve ever skipped over`the results section of a medical paper because terms like “confidence interval” or “p-value” go over your head, then you’re in the right place. You may be a clinical practitioner reading research articles to keep up-to-date with developments in your field or a medical student wondering how to approach your own research. Greater confidence in understanding statistical analysis and the results can benefit both working professionals and those undertaking research themselves. 

If you are simply interested in properly understanding the published literature or if you are embarking on conducting your own research, this course is your first step. It offers an easy entry into interpreting common statistical concepts without getting into nitty-gritty mathematical formulae. To be able to interpret and understand these concepts is the best way to start your journey into the world of clinical literature. That’s where this course comes in - so let’s get started!

The course is free to enroll and take. You will be offered the option of purchasing a certificate of completion which you become eligible for, if you successfully complete the course requirements. This can be an excellent way of staying motivated!  Financial Aid is also available.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Research</course_category><course_tag>Clinical Research//Statistics//Statistical Analysis//Statistical Hypothesis Testing</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Cape Town</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting things started by defining study types//Describing your data //Building an intuitive understanding of statistical analysis//The important first steps: Hypothesis testing and confidence levels//Which test should you use?//Categorical data and analyzing accuracy of results </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Understanding Clinical Research', 'About the course', 'Observing and intervening: Observational &amp; experimental studies', 'Observing and describing: Case series studies', 'Comparing groups: Case-control studies', 'Collecting data at one point in time: Cross-sectional studies', 'Studying a group with common traits: Cohort studies', "Let's intervene: Experimental studies", 'Working with existing research: Meta-analysis and Systematic Review', 'Doing a literature search: Part 1', 'Doing a literature search: Part 2'], ['Introduction', 'Some key concepts: Definitions', 'Data types', 'Arbitary classification: Nominal categorical data', 'Natural ordering of attributes: Ordinal categorical data', 'Measurements and numbers: Numerical data types', 'How to tell the difference: Discrete and continuous variables', 'Introduction', 'Measures of central tendency', 'Measures of dispersion', '(Optional) Setting up spreadsheet software to do your own analysis', '(Optional) Descriptive statistics using spreadsheet software', 'Making inferences: Sampling', 'Types of sampling', 'Case study 1'], ['P-values: P is for probability', 'Working out the probability: Rolling dice', 'Area under the curve: Continuous data types', 'Introduction to the central limit theorem: The heart of probability theory', 'Asymmetry and peakedness: Skewness and Kurtosis', 'Learning from the lotto: Combinations', 'Approximating a bell-shaped curve: The central limit theorem', 'Patterns in the data: Distributions', 'The bell-shaped curve: Normal distribution', 'Plotting a sample statistic: Sampling distribution', 'Standard normal distribution: Z distribution', 'Estimating population parameters: t-distribution', '(Optional) Generating random data point values using spreadsheet software', 'Case study 2'], ['Introduction to Hypothesis Testing', 'Testing assumptions: Null and alternative hypothesis', 'Is there a difference?: Alternative Hypothesis', 'Type I and II: Hypothesis testing errors', 'Introduction to confidence intervals', 'How confident are you?: Confidence levels', 'Interval estimation: Confidence intervals', '(Optional) Calculating confidence intervals using spreadsheet software'], ['Introduction to parametric tests', "Student's t-test", 'ANOVA', 'Linear Regression', "(Optional) Student's t-test in action", 'Introduction to nonparametric tests', 'Checking for normality', 'Thinking nonparametrically', 'Comparing paired observations: Signs', 'Ordering values: Ranking', 'Paired comparisons: Sign ranks', 'Summation of ranks: Rank sums', 'Comparing two populations: Mann-Whitney-U test', 'More nonparametric tests', 'Case study 3'], ['Introduction to comparing categorical data', 'Observed frequencies: Contingency tables', 'Comparing observed and expected values: Chi-square test', "Association between two variables: Fisher's exact test", '(Optional) Calculating chi-square test using spreadsheet software', 'Introduction to sensitivity and specificity', 'Measuring performance: Sensitivity and specificity', 'Proportions of results: Positive and negative predictive values']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 23 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I managed to understand very important concepts of statistics used in the writing of articles, my understanding in the reading of scientific texts has improved a lot', 'Great course!! it is gonna provide you a good foundation in clinical studies if you want to start your career in clinical research! Clear explanation and comprehensive case study! highly recommended!', 'Klopper MD is a great teacher. There are other courses from another top universities about this topic, but I think this is my favourite. This the shortest in duration and most comprehensive among all.', 'Very useful course for healthcare researches..', 'Excelente curso.', 'Good basic overview of the concepts behind statistics. Enjoyed this course. ', 'A concise and easily understable course for all intending clinical researcher.', 'Excellent introductory course to clinical research. Thank you!', 'Worth the money.', '/', 'This is one of the best Online Course I have ever joined fully until completion.I absolutely recommend this course to my friends and anyone else in the area of Public Health, Medicine even Veterinary Medicine.There is so much to learn for so little time but Dr Juan is absolutely amazing in his way of handling this course that made it look simple and he has truly made  it so much easier to comprehend. So much better than learning from Statistical textbooks', 'It was an excellent course!', 'Finally, I have an intuitive understanding of clinical research! ', "A fantastic intro to the statistics behind clinical research! I haven't done much of my own research, so I am not really familiar with data analysis yet, but the course gave me a great panorama of the basic key concepts and how to think about results more critically. Totally recommend!", 'This is one of the most interesting courses on biomedical statistics. The course was explained in a beautiful way, very simple and easy. Examples were related to the daily medical field and clinical research. Professor Juan H Klopper is an amazing mentor. I loved everything about this course. Really understanding what is behind statistics without going through the hassle of mathematics that every researcher obviously hates ! I highly recommend this course for everyone who is involved in clinical research.', 'wonderful lecture series, conscise and straight to the point for clinicians.', 'Thanks to the team for putting together this course. Dr. Klopper to was excellent in the delivery', "One of the best courses i've ever done! I really enjoyed it.", "Just an excellent refresher in biostatistics that put many things into perspective. I'll be looking more keenly  and with a more critical eye at research papers and now I have more ammunition for doing my own research and writing papers.", 'Excellent and enjoyable course. ', 'Muy buen curso. ', 'Fantastic course. Gave me a much better understanding of trial methodology and the underlying statistics. The lectures are well paced and interesting. The assessments and quizzes help to underpin the course.   ', 'I very much enjoyed Dr Kloppers course. He manages to teach\na wide range of statistical theory within a clinical framework – which is where the value\nadded was as far as I am concerned as I am not a clinician, but I do need to\nknow my way around reports and assessments etc.  Further, if the course leaves you wanting more\n(and it should) look at Dr Klopper’s YouTube page – the content is superb.  ', '很系统清晰的课程设置，可惜没能及时完成进度·下次一定要按时完成', 'I enjoyed and learned at the same time.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Juan B A', 'By Lee Y K', 'By Andres M', 'By rambo081', 'By RENE C M', 'By Judy-April O', 'By Dr. A A Y', 'By Jael E C', 'By Timotej V', 'By Marijana M', 'By Frans U D', 'By Mohamed G', 'By Mohammed Z', 'By Wagner S B', 'By Noha A G', 'By AGOMINAB A R', 'By JAMES B A', 'By Christmar D Q L', 'By John N T N', 'By Dr. R X K', 'By Stella A A', 'By David B', 'By Sean K', 'By Kelly A', 'By Nilay']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 02, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2017', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Nov 29, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 01, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2019']</review_date></doc>