<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_393</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/missing-data</course_url><course_name>Dealing With Missing Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Richard Valliant, Ph.D.</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will cover the steps used in weighting sample surveys, including methods for adjusting for nonresponse and using data external to the survey for calibration.  Among the techniques discussed are adjustments using estimated response propensities, poststratification, raking, and general regression estimation.  Alternative techniques for imputing values for missing items will be discussed.  For both weighting and imputation, the capabilities of different statistical software packages will be covered, including R®, Stata®, and SAS®.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Maryland, College Park</course_orgnization><course_chapter>General Steps in Weighting//Specific Steps//Implementing the Steps//Imputing for Missing Items//Summary of Course 5</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Quantities to Estimate', 'Goals of Estimation', 'Statistical Interpretation of Estimates', 'Coverage Problems', 'Improving Precision', 'Effects of Weighting on SEs'], ['Overview', 'Base Weights', 'Nonresponse Adjustments', 'Response Propensities', 'Tree algorithms', 'Calibration'], ['Software', 'Base Weights', 'More on Base Weights', 'Nonresponse Adjustments', 'Examples of Calibration', 'Software for Poststratification'], ['Reasons for Imputation', 'Means and hotdeck', 'Regression Imputation', 'Effect on Variances', 'mice R package', 'mice example'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The professor was not very explanatory and I just managed to finish the course out of my sheer strong will', 'The quality of the presentation is very low, and way below the quality in other courses.  The assignments are very poorly designed.  This is not a subjective personal experience.  This is based on discussions with other learners in the forum who have expressed disappointment and frustration.', "very idfficult to understand. The sound of the videio is so low that most of it is impossible to understand, I had to try 10 times some of the tests because couldn't find the answer and had to guess it!", 'This course quite help to get as much reliable data as possible for any survey. ', 'Prof. Richard Valliant, Ph.D. clearly enough explain all of these course materials.  I will use these materials to dealing missing data on our census or survey. I believe that these materials were very helpful for me and my agency.', 'it is very informative', 'Excellent review of relevant material. ', 'Good knowledge about Non-responses!', 'Great course!', 'interesting material, well taught, lots of short quizzes to enforce understanding.', 'This is a higher level course. Good for beginners. ', 'I was interested in the topic. The course itself seems like just a starting point with understanding dealing with missing data. I wanted to know more and see more examples than the videos offered. I also would have appreciated including examples from more than just R, though I did appreciate the minimal discussion of other statistical software that are available for statistical analysis when it did occur.', 'As others have stated before the audio is REALLY LOW.  It makes it very difficult to hear him without headphones for my phone.  The course was fine, overall.', 'The topic of this course is attractive as it is hard to get from elsewhere. However, the content of this course is actually quite barren, practices are easy and not closely refective of the corresponding videos. ', 'There is scope for a lot of improvement in terms of quality of content as well as videos. There also appeared to be technical issues in the quizzes wherein the correct responses were often returned as incorrect &amp; vice-versa, for a few quizzes. Without a moderator, queries are not addressed and nobody appears to be keeping track of the feedback. I was disappointed in the course since the previous courses in the specialization were far better designed and executed. ', "While this course seems to have potential, there are many aspects of it that don't result in a great learning experience.  The course resources comprise of videos and notes.  The videos are informative but the notes are fairly lacking.  Perhaps the biggest issue that I found with this course was the disconnect between the material covered in the videos and that which was tested on the quizzes.  Often times the quiz questions were either painfully easy or worded in such a way that was not verifiable in any of the class resources.  As a result, confusion occurred sometimes more often than true learning.  A topic such as missing data is naturally very complex and I wouldn't expect a short course on Coursera to be able to adequately cover it.  However, I do think that a lot more could be done to improve the value of this course even if that means changing the scope of the materials.  Also, the lack of responsiveness to issues raised on the forum and issue-reporting buttons was a disappointment.", 'The contents of this course could be interesting, but they end up being terribly boring. The course lacks examples to bring things to life. A pity!', "I wrote some indepth feedback, but par for the course, I can't save it - either here or on the discussion board.  Nothing obscene, but certainly some major frustration with format, inconsistencies in scoring and format, information not reviewed in the course on some of the quizzes, the fact that Coursera keeps trying to sell me the specialty, the lack of ANY moderator on the discussion board to provide assistance...and can go on with the technical issues to but I won't!", 'the course materials are of very low quality.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Martyns N', 'By Ahmed I', 'By marine h', 'By Mohammad M', 'By Reni A', 'By Neeraj K', 'By Carlos F P', 'By Tin K O', 'By Anna B R', 'By Zachary M', 'By Hussein E', 'By Zachary H', 'By Iyshia L', 'By Lingbing F', 'By Anandita G', 'By Evan', 'By Réjane F R', 'By Margie H', 'By Hiroki N']</reviewers><review_date>['May 17, 2019', 'Sep 01, 2016', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Jun 05, 2017', 'Apr 05, 2018', 'Oct 26, 2016', 'Apr 27, 2017', 'Jan 25, 2017', 'Jan 24, 2018', 'Aug 20, 2019', 'Dec 25, 2017', 'Aug 31, 2016', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Nov 03, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2016', 'Dec 22, 2016', 'Aug 30, 2016', 'Nov 17, 2017']</review_date></doc>