<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_105</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/hadoop</course_url><course_name>Hadoop Platform and Application Framework</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Natasha Balac, Ph.D.</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is for novice programmers or business people who would like to understand the core tools used to wrangle and analyze big data. With no prior experience, you will have the opportunity to walk through hands-on examples with Hadoop and Spark frameworks, two of the most common in the industry. You will be comfortable explaining the specific components and basic processes of the Hadoop architecture, software stack, and execution environment.   In the assignments you will be guided in how data scientists apply the important concepts and techniques such as Map-Reduce that are used to solve fundamental problems in big data.  You'll feel empowered to have conversations about big data and the data analysis process.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Apache Hadoop//Mapreduce//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>3.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Hadoop Basics//Introduction to the Hadoop Stack//Introduction to Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS)//Introduction to Map/Reduce//Spark</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Hadoop Stack Basics', 'The Apache Framework: Basic Modules', 'Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS)', 'The Hadoop "Zoo"', 'Hadoop Ecosystem Major Components', 'Exploring the Cloudera VM: Hands-On Part 1', 'Exploring the Cloudera VM: Hands-On Part 2'], ['Overview of the Hadoop Stack', 'The Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) and HDFS2', 'MapReduce Framework and YARN', 'The Hadoop Execution Environment', 'YARN, Tez, and Spark', 'Hadoop Resource Scheduling', 'Hadoop-Based Applications', 'Introduction to Apache Pig', 'Introduction to Apache HIVE', 'Introduction to Apache HBASE'], ['Overview of HDFS Architecture', 'The HDFS Performance Envelope', 'Read/Write Processes in HDFS', 'HDFS Tuning Parameters', 'HDFS Performance and Robustness', 'Overview of HDFS Access, APIs, and Applications', 'HDFS Commands', 'Native Java API for HDFS', 'REST API for HDFS'], ['Introduction to Map/Reduce', 'The Map/Reduce Framework', 'A MapReduce Example: Wordcount in detail', 'MapReduce: Intro to Examples and Principles', 'MapReduce Example: Trending Wordcount', 'MapReduce Example: Joining Data', 'MapReduce Example: Vector Multiplication', 'Computational Costs of Vector Multiplication', 'MapReduce Summary'], ['Introduction to Apache Spark', 'Architecture of Spark', 'Resilient Distributed Datasets', 'Spark Transformations', 'Wide Transformations', 'Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) Scheduler', 'Actions in Spark', 'Memory Caching in Spark', 'Broadcast Variables', 'Accumulators']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 20 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This is one of the most disappointing classes I ever took on Coursera. I am a Coursera believer and have taken so many classes here. But with all due respect, the instructor in week 2 and 3 was just mumbling to himself in front of the camera. I feel kind of disrespected. This course is not well prepared and should not be on Coursera.', 'This is a good introductory course. The content is good, but the presentation is not great. The presenters speak with a low, mumbling voice.', "The instructor in week 2 makes me want to kill myself. There are people who can teach, there are people who can't teach, and there is this guy who absolutely cannot be allowed to teach due to safety reasons. ", "A walk-through of Cloudera's tutorials. Way overrated and over-hyped. Not worth the money. ", "I was almost done with this course but I ended up finishing it. I have taken other courses on Coursera, and this one is the worst so far. You may get to know the basics of the Hadoop Platform but the lectures aren't much interesting and the lecturer reads the bullet points or a \nscript. I was disappointed, frankly.\n\n", 'A bit more explanation along the slides would be really appreciated. Also it was a bit disappointing was the fact that the hands-on exercises were every word read from Cloudera, no addition/ additional information or clarification.', 'This is a very bad course. The VM image provided is very buggy and does not work. ( It took me 4 hours to make it to the second part of the first tutorial just to find out that the second part is broken due to miss-configured HUE server ). Professors do not respond to questions in forums as well. PLEASE do not waste your money/time on this course. The main issue is that other courses in the same specialization are very good but without passing this course, you can not earn specialization.  ', 'Es un curso muy agradable, los temas son muy interesantes y de gran ayuda...', 'This is a very good course to clear your basics and all the assignments gives you a good practice.', 'Course is awesome. It has clear my idea about MapReduce , Spark jobs.', 'Gained the hadoop(Map reduce) spark framework in detailed', 'This course is very simple to understand and good know all the concepts.', 'It provide the basis of the Hadoop platform. It also provide with some command to do the real life work. Good course to recommend. ', 'Great course for starters', 'Course is very well planned. Starts from very basic and gets to very detail. Will appreciate if instead of cloudera VM or along with that, can be guided to set up the framework in local and complete the assignments.', 'Good explanations and hands-on.', "Really great for a beginner. It has all the basics and required hands on assignment. No other website can match coursera's quality of assignment/quiz. I am surely going to keep coming back to revisit this course.", None, 'All the labs were really helpful in building the understanding of different applications. One area I felt could be helpful for labs is example of what output would look like at key intermediate steps. Writing up code stepwise and comparing results against some sample example would help as it would re-affirm the solution works as expected all the way through the exercise.', 'very good', 'Great course on hadoop.', None, 'good point to start  learning about hadoop.', 'Very good overview to Hadoop platform .', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Mengfei W', 'By Leonel G', 'By Ryan H', 'By Pablo T', 'By Tiago L', 'By Oana M', 'By Omar K', 'By Daniel P M', 'By Abhilash R', 'By chintan p', 'By Vinoth', 'By Saravanan', 'By Huixin L', 'By Ramneek k', 'By Vikash K J', 'By André P Z', 'By Nikhil J', 'By OUKHOUYA', 'By Saad T', 'By savitri v v', 'By Miao J', 'By Towhidul I', 'By Ajay P', 'By Sreedharrao V R', 'By Gavin C']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 06, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2017', 'Oct 11, 2016', 'Oct 03, 2017', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Sep 29, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Oct 07, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Oct 12, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2015', 'Dec 16, 2015', 'Nov 29, 2016', 'Feb 06, 2016', 'Oct 25, 2015']</review_date></doc>