<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_229</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/hypothesis-testing-confidence-intervals</course_url><course_name>Business Applications of Hypothesis Testing and Confidence Interval Estimation</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sharad Borle</course_instructor><course_introduction>Confidence intervals and Hypothesis tests are very important tools in the Business Statistics toolbox. A mastery over these topics will help enhance your business decision making and allow you to understand and measure the extent of ‘risk’ or ‘uncertainty’ in various business processes. 
This is the third course in the specialization "Business Statistics and Analysis" and the course  advances your knowledge about Business Statistics by introducing you to Confidence Intervals and Hypothesis Testing. We first conceptually understand these tools and their business application. We then introduce various calculations to constructing confidence intervals and to conduct different kinds of Hypothesis Tests. These are done by easy to understand applications.

To successfully complete course assignments, students must have access to a Windows version of Microsoft Excel 2010 or later. Please note that earlier versions of Microsoft Excel (2007 and earlier) will not be compatible to some Excel functions covered in this course. 


WEEK 1
Module 1: Confidence Interval - Introduction
In this module you will get to conceptually understand what a confidence interval is and how is its constructed. We will introduce the various building blocks for the confidence interval such as the t-distribution, the t-statistic, the z-statistic and their various excel formulas. We will then use these building blocks to construct confidence intervals.

Topics covered include:
•	Introducing the t-distribution, the T.DIST and T.INV excel functions
•	Conceptual understanding of a Confidence Interval
•	The z-statistic and the t-statistic
•	Constructing a Confidence Interval using z-statistic and t-statistic 


WEEK 2
Module 2: Confidence Interval - Applications
This module presents various business applications of the confidence interval including an application where we use the confidence interval to calculate an appropriate sample size. We also introduce with an application, the confidence interval for a population proportion. Towards the close of module we start introducing the concept of Hypothesis Testing.

Topics covered include:
•	Applications of Confidence Interval
•	Confidence Interval for a Population Proportion
•	Sample Size Calculation
•	Hypothesis Testing, An Introduction


WEEK 3
Module 3: Hypothesis Testing
This module introduces Hypothesis Testing. You get to understand the logic behind hypothesis tests. The four steps for conducting a hypothesis test are introduced and you get to apply them for hypothesis tests for a population mean as well as population proportion. You will understand the difference between single tail hypothesis tests and two tail hypothesis tests and also the Type I and Type II errors associated with hypothesis tests and ways to reduce such errors. 

Topics covered include:
•	The Logic of Hypothesis Testing
•	The Four Steps for conducting a Hypothesis Test
•	Single Tail and Two Tail Hypothesis Tests
•	Guidelines, Formulas and an Application of Hypothesis Test
•	Hypothesis Test for a Population Proportion
•	Type I and Type II Errors in a Hypothesis 


WEEK 4
Module 4: Hypothesis Test - Differences in Mean
In this module, you'll apply Hypothesis Tests to test the difference between two different data, such hypothesis tests are called difference in means tests. We will introduce the three kinds of difference in means test and apply them to various business applications. We will also introduce the Excel dialog box to conduct such hypothesis tests.

Topics covered include:
•	Introducing the Difference-In-Means Hypothesis Test
•	Applications of the Difference-In-Means Hypothesis Test
•	The Equal &amp; Unequal Variance Assumption and the Paired t-test for difference in means.
•	Some more applications</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Statistical Hypothesis Testing</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Confidence Interval - Introduction//Confidence Interval - Applications//Hypothesis Testing//Hypothesis Test - Differences in Mean</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Meet the Professor', 'Introducing the t-distribution, the T.DIST Function', 't-distribution Continued, the T.INV Function', 'Introducing Confidence Interval', 'Introducing Confidence Interval (Continued)', 'The z-statistic and the t-statistic', 'Using z- and t- statistics to Construct Confidence Interval', 'Week 1 Recap'], ['Application of Confidence Interval', 'Confidence Interval for a Population Proportion', 'Sample Size Calculation', 'Sample Size Calculation (Continued)', 'Hypothesis Testing, An Introduction', 'Week 2 Recap'], ['The Logic of Hypothesis Testing', 'Conducting a Hypothesis Test, the Four Steps', 'Single Tail and Two Tail Hypothesis Tests', 'Guidelines, Formulas and an Application of Hypothesis Test', 'Hypothesis Test for a Population Proportion', 'Type I and Type II Errors in a Hypothesis Test', 'Week 3 Recap'], ['Introducing the Difference-In-Means Hypothesis Test', 'Application of the Difference-In-Means Hypothesis Test', 'Application (Continued) - Equal &amp; Unequal Variance Assumption', 'The Paired t-Test for Means', 'Some More Applications', 'Some More Applications (Continued)', 'Week 4 Recap']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The content was concise and easy to understand. However, in the hypothesis testing modules, the presenter conflates "being unable to reject a hypothesis" to "accept a hypothesis". This, I think, is a dangerous habit to learn, and undermines what is otherwise a well-prepared course. ', 'The course is very helpful to learn and understand some really important and useful concepts of statistics. The course not only teach the concept but also we can practice it side by side ourselves also from the course material given by Coursera. Instructor is very good, this is my third course under a specialization by the same instructor and I must say one must take this course if they are going to use these concepts in future. Good Luck.', 'Great course. Excellent Instructor. Absolutely worth the time and effort.', 'Great', 'Well designed and usefull. A good investment ', 'Loved the course; great materials, great pace, great practice', 'I am from Applied Statistics background, and I used to do these tests by hands. I really have enjoyed doing them on Excel as well. Thanks for this amazing course! :)', 'Thumbs Up!', 'Professor is very good. I love this course.', 'Good', 'Great instructor! Easy to follow along.', 'Probably the best course on confidence intervals and hypothesis testing. A must for all engineering and management students and managers.', 'Course is very well organized and the concepts are explained in a very simple and effective way.', 'it is really helpful class!!! ', 'Very nice and easy to follow course. I have had a great experience learning the Hypothesis Testing secrets in Excel.', 'I am completing the specialization so this is my 3rd class with this instructor. I am enjoying the classes and feel that each lesson and class builds on the last one. Everything is clearly explained and demonstrated. He provides most of the files he uses so you can try it yourself in Excel. The forum is helpful for the more challenging questions on the final quiz. Overall, I think the class is a good pace and the final quiz is representative of what the class covers. That is, not too hard and not too easy.', 'In depth course regarding hypothesis testing. Even better than the course I had in my degree.', 'very knowledgeable. ', 'concept was very nicely explained. The excel examples were very helpful', 'Anyone who want to understand the topic of confidence interval &amp; Hypothesis Testing this COURSE IS MUST. Topics are explained in simple manner &amp; with hands on exercise in Excel we can grasp topics thoroughly. Thank you so much for Rice University for such a wonderful course on CI &amp; Hypothesis. Special thanks to Prod. Sharad &amp; his team for coming with wonderful.simple yet effective course.', 'Fantastic course and teacher', 'This is the class where it really started to get interesting.', 'i like it, easy to understand', 'Great course to master inferential statistics. Learnt a lot in this course and will be applying the learnings in the future.', 'The quizzes for this course are very well-done, quite challenging and certainly very satisfying to get through.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Sabarish V', 'By Amit M', 'By Emil R', 'By Olga', 'By Aline C', 'By Gregory L', 'By Shady N S T', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By Nazmus S S', 'By Atis R', 'By Ernie R', 'By ARVIND K S', 'By DEEPTI C', 'By 原野', 'By Ernesto B P', 'By Karen S Z', 'By Wellington G S', 'By Viktoryia A', 'By Arushi S', 'By Akshay H', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Tim L', 'By Yixuan W', 'By Siddharth S', 'By Alex M']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 01, 2019', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2018', 'Sep 14, 2017', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Jun 23, 2017', 'May 03, 2017', 'May 31, 2018', 'May 27, 2018', 'Aug 23, 2017', 'Jan 22, 2018', 'Apr 14, 2018']</review_date></doc>