<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_337</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/regression-modeling-practice</course_url><course_name>Regression Modeling in Practice</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jen Rose</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course focuses on one of the most important tools in your data analysis arsenal: regression analysis. Using either SAS or Python, you will begin with linear regression and then learn how to adapt when two variables do not present a clear linear relationship. You will examine multiple predictors of your outcome and be able to identify confounding variables, which can tell a more compelling story about your results. You will learn the assumptions underlying regression analysis, how to interpret regression coefficients, and how to use regression diagnostic plots and other tools to evaluate the quality of your regression model. Throughout the course, you will share with others the regression models you have developed and the stories they tell you.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Logistic Regression//Data Analysis//Python Programming//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Wesleyan University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Regression//Basics of Linear Regression//Multiple Regression//Logistic Regression</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Lesson 1: Observational Data', 'Lesson 2: Experimental Data', 'Lesson 3: Confounding Variables', 'Lesson 4: Introduction to Multivariate Methods'], ['SAS Lesson 1: More on Confounding Variables', 'SAS Lesson 2: Testing a Basic Linear Regression Mode', 'SAS Lesson 3: Categorical Explanatory Variables', 'Python Lesson 1: More on Confounding Variables', 'Python Lesson 2: Testing a Basic Linear Regression Model', 'Python Lesson 3: Categorical Explanatory Variables', 'Lesson 4: Linear Regression Assumptions', 'Lesson 5: Centering Explanatory Variables'], ['SAS Lesson 1: Multiple Regression', 'SAS Lesson 2: Confidence Intervals', 'SAS Lesson 3: Polynomial Regression', 'SAS Lesson 4: Evaluating Model Fit, pt. 1', 'SAS Lesson 5: Evaluating Model Fit, pt. 2', 'Python Lesson 1: Multiple Regression', 'Python Lesson 2: Confidence Intervals', 'Python Lesson 3: Polynomial Regression', 'Python Lesson 4: Evaluating Model Fit, pt. 1', 'Python Lesson 5: Evaluating Model Fit, pt. 2'], ['SAS Lesson 1: Categorical Explanatory Variables with More Than Two Categories', 'Python Lesson 1: Categorical Explanatory Variables with More Than Two Categories', 'Lesson 2: A Few Things to Keep in Mind', 'SAS Lesson 3: Logistic Regression for a Binary Response Variable, pt 1', 'SAS Lesson 4: Logistic Regression for a Binary Response Variable, pt. 2', 'Python Lesson 3: Logistic Regression for a Binary Response Variable, pt. 1', 'Python Lesson 4: Logistic Regression for a Binary Response Variable, pt. 2']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is really an eye opener. I had no idea statistics would be this much fun! The way the course is set up is just beautiful. Concepts are clearly explained, and they give you such a good insight into the world of data science. Definitely gonna recommend this to a lot of people  ', None, None, 'This is the only course on SAS(structured) available for free till date', 'really enjoyed it', None, 'It needs hard work and a lot of practicing :)', 'Great but too much stock video footage of people smoking. ', 'v', 'Great classes. You need all of the content to manage data.', "I really like this training. It's good if you want a good view of applied regression.", "The course content is very well-designed and to be honest, it doesn't go very deep into the statistical details and i completed the whole course within just a week. Still, it lays a good groundwork for future studies. Don't expect to be a data specialist after this course, but it definitely teaches you all the basic knowledge(Multiple regression, Logistic regression, examine model fit using q-q plot, standardized residuals and multiple diagnostic plots) you can start to implement to analyze your own data. And of course, if you are interested in all these topics and want to expand your knowledge, this course prepares you to furthure your studies. Great course! And I will sure recommend it to my friends with or without a statistical back ground.", 'Background Sound is awesome haha', 'I would do it again, even if there was no tutor support in discussion forums it teaches the arguments very good.', 'I enjoy this course so far. I like how the course entirely depends on peer grading. It will help us to get some honest feedback on our research.', "I think you will get a lot out of this course/specialisation if you don't expect to be spoon-fed. I have seen comments here stating that only one dataset is used per course, not covering all the other options available. This is because you are supposed to understand the concepts presented to you and apply them to your own set and ideas.", 'Excelente curso!', 'Again, great job!', 'easy to follow', 'Very nice lecture videos and explanations! Totally worth it', "This was a great course. I've done a few in the area of stats, regression and machine learning now and the Wesleyan ones are the most well-rounded of all of them", 'I liked the course. I would recommend it to others. Do not have any complains. However, I recommend you to consider making the grading procedure more granular, and providing an example sketch of how the exercise reports may look. ', 'Good course with a lot of applicable techniques. Thanks for your time and teachings!', 'This is a great beginner level course for those have no programming experience. But I would suggest the content to be extended to 8 weeks instead of 4 weeks.', 'simple and useful']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mukkesh G', 'By bourges', 'By MANOJ K', 'By Rahul K', 'By Glenn B', 'By Gopisankar M G', 'By Dina I', 'By David W', 'By ngoduyvu', 'By Ruben D S P', 'By Sergio A G G', 'By 晏文丹', 'By kwangje.baeg', 'By Roland K', 'By Vijai K S', 'By Monika K', 'By Bruno R B', 'By Arnold A', 'By Jinbo C', 'By Zacharias P', 'By Paul C', 'By Robertas P', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Meigui Y', 'By Ali R']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 14, 2019', 'Mar 02, 2017', 'Feb 22, 2016', 'Nov 23, 2015', 'Jun 07, 2017', 'Apr 02, 2017', 'Nov 03, 2017', 'Mar 15, 2016', 'Feb 16, 2016', 'Jun 29, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2016', 'Oct 01, 2016', 'Jan 09, 2017', 'Feb 08, 2016', 'Dec 11, 2015', 'Apr 22, 2016', 'Nov 21, 2016', 'Jun 09, 2016', 'Jan 08, 2017', 'Jan 20, 2016', 'Nov 28, 2016', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Dec 05, 2016', 'Jul 30, 2016']</review_date></doc>