<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_195</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/the-socio-technical-health-informatics-context</course_url><course_name>The Social and Technical Context of Health Informatics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Harold P. Lehmann, MD, Ph.D.</course_instructor><course_introduction>Improving health and healthcare institutions requires understanding of data and creation of interventions at the many levels at which health IT interact and affect the institution. These levels range from the external “world” in which the institution operates down to the specific technologies. Data scientists find that, when they aim at implementing their models in practice, it is the “socio” components that are both novel to them and mission critical to success. At the end of this course, students will be able to make a quick assessment of a health informatics problem—or a proposed solution—and to determine what is missing and what more needs to be learned.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Health Informatics</course_category><course_tag>health//Digital Health//Health Informatics//Decision Analysis//Informatics</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Overview of Health Informatics//World, Organization, Roles, Function//Workflow, Information System, Modules//Data, Information, Knowledge, Technology</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Health Informatics Specialization', 'Health Information Technology for Patients', 'Health Information Technology for Doctors', 'Populations', 'Imperatives: Quality', 'Imperatives: Safety', 'Imperatives: Costs', 'Imperatives: Technology', 'Definitions', 'The Stack', 'Using the Stack'], ['World, Organization, Roles, Function', 'Policy: New Models', 'Policy: Other Models', 'Interoperability', 'Privacy, Confidentiality, Security', 'Evaluation'], ['Need and System Specification', 'Articulating Workflow', 'Information System Architecture', 'The Modules Comprising Clinical Information Systems', 'Developing Software', 'Harming Workflow'], ['Introduction: Data, Information, Knowledge, Technology', 'Many Types of Clinical Data', 'Information', 'Knowledge', 'Putting DIKW Together', 'Data Exchange', 'Interoperability Revisited: Text Data', 'Interoperability: Images', 'Making It Work Together', 'Technology: Hype Cycles', 'Careers']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 20 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I want a career in Informatics and to work at John Hopkins!! Here I come!!', 'For the beginners, the information is just right amount to start up.', 'great course , but there is no any reading material provided in it . ', 'WAS FANTASTIC, GOOD PARTICIPATING IN THIS COURSE AND GLAD TO BE PART O', 'Very good information and the teaching material is easy to process and understand. I think the stack is a brilliant method to assess and to learn it is one of the important aspects of informatics. ', 'This course is great for beginners in the field of Health Informatics. I really enjoyed it and learnt some new fundamentals concepts and models. Thanks for the effort put in this course', 'Its been an overwhelming subject for me to learn, coming from a clinical background. However, the course design has been increasingly helpful in breaking down the concept and later putting it all together to critically analyse and understand the bigger picture of health informatics. I am an absolute fan of the Stack Analysis concept taught by Dr Lehmann.', 'Very informative;highly recommended!', 'This course is a collection of leading thoughts for Health Informatics.', 'slides are differ from tutor explanation, content is not useful ']</reviews><reviewers>['By EDITH J', 'By Raveendra M', 'By Majid m j', 'By sameera o a s', 'By Samuel I', 'By Muhammad S E S', 'By NISHITA J', 'By Daniel E', 'By Mayank A', 'By Abdelrahman']</reviewers><review_date>['May 23, 2019', 'May 13, 2019', 'Jun 08, 2019', 'Jul 25, 2019', 'Jul 14, 2019', 'Jul 08, 2019', 'Apr 27, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019']</review_date></doc>