<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_10</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/excel-essentials</course_url><course_name>Excel Skills for Business: Essentials</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr Yvonne Breyer</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this first course of the specialization Excel Skills for Business you will learn the Essentials of Microsoft Excel. Within six weeks, you will learn to expertly navigate the Excel user interface, perform basic calculations with formulas and functions, professionally format spreadsheets, and create visualizations of data through charts and graphs.

Whether you are self-taught and want to fill in the gaps for better efficiency and productivity, or whether you have never used Excel before, this course will set you up with a solid foundation to become a confident user and develop more advanced skills in later courses. 

We have brought together a great teaching team that will be with you every step of the way. A broad range of practice quizzes and challenges will provide great opportunities to build up your skillset. Work through each new challenge with our team and in no time you will surprise yourself with how far you have come. 

Spreadsheet software is one of the most ubiquitous pieces of software used in workplaces across the world. Learning to confidently operate this software means adding a highly valuable asset to your employability portfolio. At a time when digital skills jobs are growing much faster than non-digital jobs, make sure to position yourself ahead of the rest by adding Excel skills to your employment portfolio.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Graphs//Microsoft Excel//Chart//Sorting</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>Macquarie University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Critical Core of Excel//Performing calculations//Formatting//Working with Data//Printing//Charts//Final Assessment</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Week 1 Introduction', 'Week 1 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Taking Charge of Excel', 'Practice Video: Navigating and Selecting', 'Practice Video: View Options', 'Practice Video: Data Entry, Data Types, Editing and Deleting', 'Practice Video: Fill Handle', 'Week 1  Wrap-up', 'Copy and Paste', 'Templates'], ['Week 2 Introduction', 'Week 2 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Formulas', 'Practice Video: Formulas in Context', 'Practice Video: Functions I: SUM and AUTOSUM', 'Practice Video: Functions II: AVERAGE, MIN and MAX', 'Discussion: Absolute Cell References', 'Practice Video: Absolute Cell References', 'Practice Video: Calculations across sheets', 'Week 2  Wrap-up', 'Excel Options'], ['Week 3 Introduction', 'Week 3 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Formatting', 'Practice Video: Borders', 'Practice Video: Alignment Tools', 'Practice Video: Format Painter', 'Practice Video: Number Formats', 'Practice Video: Styles and Themes', 'Week 3 Wrap-up', 'Graphics'], ['Week 4 Introduction', 'Week 4 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Managing Rows and Columns', 'Practice Video: Find and Replace', 'Practice Video: Filtering', 'Practice Video: Sorting', 'Practice Video: Conditional Formatting', 'Week 4 Wrap-up', 'Accessibility'], ['Week 5 Introduction', 'Week 5 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Print Preview', 'Practice Video: Orientation, Margins and Scale', 'Practice Video: Page Breaks', 'Practice Video: Print Titles', 'Practice Video: Headers and Footers', 'Week 5 Wrap-up', 'Save Options'], ['Week 6 Introduction', 'Week 6 Discussion', 'Practice Video: Basic Chart Types: Pie, Column and Line Charts', 'Practice Video: Move and Resize Charts', 'Practice Video: Change Chart Style &amp; Type', 'Practice Video: Modify Chart Elements', 'Week 6 Wrap-up', 'Sharing Charts'], ['Course 1 Final Assessment']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I have working experience with Excel for many years and am a Mac user. I signed up for this to get more tips and a refresher on how to best use Excel. I initially learned using Excel in Windows, have been a Mac user for years. Most excel sheets I worked on would be revenue forecasts, pipeline etc.', 'This course demonstrated a solid overview of the core skills necessary to use Excel productively. I would recommend it to anyone looking to start using Excel effectively for data management tasks.', 'this course is amazing, the way of teaching, step by step, no complicated information at once, great knowledge for the learner different backgrounds. it suits me very well. Like it.', 'Very well narrated', "Great course, but only for those that Don't have any skills and experience with Excel, it might be a little to easy for those who have already worked with it.", '  I advise anyone who wants to learn Excel to get this course, it has been useful for me, thanks to all instructors.  ', "This course provides a good foundation of skills for Excel, additionally it can fill in a few gaps in your knowledge if you're a self taught Excel user already. ", 'I had really good time doing this course. This was the first time i was doing any online course and i found this course very interesting and easy to work with. The animation and videos were very helpful.', 'good for start', 'Good Course', "Great first course, thanks a lot for such a great preparation work ! It's interactive, clear, user-friendly and fun. I have learnt a lot, even though I am not a beginner with Excel. I'm looking forward to following the 3 other courses. ", 'Very helpful course', "It's really a good learning experience with hand on practice section", 'The course was excellent and taught a lot of basic excel tools.', 'It is hard to think that there is a better teacher that Dr. Breyer, she is a natural born teacher and I am impressed by her loving and articulate style of instruction. She is also very cute :)', 'I loved this course. It was easy and fun. It covered the basics of Excel.', 'It was very thorough and educational and it was a great course for helping me to become familiar with excel and a great platform for building confidence using excel with large data spreadsheets.', 'Very comprehensive. Taught in a friendly and easy way. I was sure I retained skills with the final exam.', "Very well structured course. Straight to the point tutorials. The challenges given at the end of each week reinforce the concepts learnt through the week! In a nutshell, it's simply amazing!", 'Nice bite size lessons help in learning quickly.', 'The best online course.', "The course was excellent. I came into it with an embarrassingly low level of ability and now I'm comfortable and quick producing useful and attractive spreadsheets for work. I'm dyslexic and yet I found the layout of the course very easy to follow and understand. My favourite thing was being able to save useful parts of the video's throughout the course, then review just those points before taking the exam. Thanks!", "This course is fun and very informative with some details that I didn't know about!  I am glad that I took this course.  I am now into Course 2!", 'Learned a few tricks I never knew before.', 'Excellent Cours for beginners! ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Cornelia R', 'By Alexander V', 'By Sayid N', 'By Steven A', 'By Théophile F', 'By Seyfullali C İ', 'By Anthony R', 'By Ali A T', 'By Svetlana S', 'By Vinod N', 'By Maëlanne B', 'By Abhipriya', 'By Mouneshwari R', 'By Parth P', 'By Efren M', 'By Nishant K S', 'By Scott M D', 'By Lauren A', 'By Ganesh S H', 'By Venkatesh R', 'By Nasim-Uz-Zaman', 'By Ms G J B', 'By Jacinta B', 'By Brynlee T', 'By Ferdally J']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 01, 2017', 'Feb 24, 2018', 'Jun 01, 2019', 'Jun 25, 2019', 'Jun 16, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jun 29, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2018', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jun 25, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jun 23, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jun 24, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2018']</review_date></doc>