<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_183</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/importance-of-listening</course_url><course_name>The Importance of Listening</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Randy Hlavac</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this second MOOC in the Social Marketing Specialization - "The Importance of Listening" - you will go deep into the Big Data of social and gain a more complete picture of what can be learned from interactions on social sites. You will be amazed at just how much information can be extracted from a single post, picture, or video. In this MOOC, guest speakers from Social Gist, BroadReader, Lexalytics, Semantria, Radian6, and IBM's Bluemix and Social Media Analytics Tools (SMA) will join Professor Hlavac to take you through the full range of analytics tools and options available to you and how to get the most from them. The best part, most of them will be available to you through the MOOC for free! Those purchasing the MOOC will receive special tools, templates, and videos to enhance your learning experience. In completing this course you will develop a fuller understanding of the data and will be able to increase the effectiveness of your content strategy by making better decisions and spotting crises before they happen! MOOC 2 bonus content in the paid toolkit includes access to Semantria's analytics engine to extract some data on the markets you are developing and have it analyzed. 

As a student in this course, you are being provided the opportunity to access IBM Bluemix® platform-as-a-service trial for up to six months at no-charge with no credit card (up to a $1500 value).

NOTE: By enrolling in this course, given access to IBM's Bluemix technology for one month for free as well as Lexalytics' Semantria tool. For those earning a Course Certificate, you will be given an additional five months of Bluemix and three months of Semantria at no cost with a special key code. By enrolling for a Course Certificate for this MOOC, you are acknowledging that your email will be shared with Lexalytics for the sole and express purpose of generating your individual key code. After the key code has been generated, Lexalytics will delete your email from its records. 

Additional MOOC 2 faculty include: 
* Steve Dodd (SVP Business Development, Effyis - dba BoardReader and Socialgist - Global Social Media Content Access) 
* Seth Redmore (CMO, Lexalytics, Inc.)
* Chris Gruber (Social Media Analytics Solution Architect, IBM)
* Russell Beardall (Cloud Architect, IBM) 
* Tom Collinger (Executive Director Spiegel Research Center and Senior Director Distance Learning, Medill Integrated Marketing Communications, Northwestern)
* Tressie Lieberman (VP Digital Innovation, Taco Bell)</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Marketing</course_category><course_tag>Social Marketing//Social Media Marketing//Social Media//Influencer Marketing</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Northwestern University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Big Data//Big Information//Big Insights//Real-Time in Action</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Using Social Data', 'Social Data Flows from a Single Source', 'Data Extraction from Social Documents', 'Accuracy of Text Analysis', 'Data Extraction from Photos and Videos', 'Accessing and Using the IBM Cloud System [for free!]', 'Sign up for Lexalytics Semantria'], ['Social Media Analytics Overview 2018', 'Free Influencer Analytics Tools 2018 - Followerwonk, Buzzsumo &amp; Instagram Search', 'Free Keyword &amp; Pay Per Click Analytics Tools 2018 - KWFinder, Socialert &amp; Google Adwords', 'Free Hashtag Analytics Tools 2018 - Ritetag, Hashtagify.me &amp; Keyhole.co', 'Free Search Analytics Tools 2018 - Google Trends, Answer the Public &amp; BoardReader', 'Free Content Analytics Tools 2018 - Buzzsumo, Mashable, Alltop, Channel Crawler &amp; ListenNotes', 'Bonus - IBM Institute for Business Value - Free Resource for Technology Information', 'Social Monitoring', 'Salesforce Social Studio - formerly Radian6', 'Social Marketing Toolkit Pt. 1b - Lexalytics Worksheets', 'Social Marketing Toolkit Pt. 1c - Analyzing Content'], ['Social Analytics', 'Transforming Data to Information', 'IBM Cloud - Assessing your Personality based on your Twitter activities - See Resources for Links to this System', 'New Bitly Instructions', 'IBM Cloud Visual Recognition System', 'IBM Cloud Tone Analyzer', 'Peer Review Assignment Step by Step'], ['How Are Big Insights Being Used Today?', 'Engagement Strategies', 'Building Social Relationships', 'Taco Bell War Room', 'Crisis Management', 'Social Insights for Content Strategies']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is great because you get hands on experience with social listening tools. If you work in social media marketing and want to know more about listening, this class is worth the time. ', 'one of the best courses for hands in platforms to use and understand. ', 'This course has opened my minds! The tools and the paid access to tools like IBM BlueMix and Semantria, are mindblowing. It has not only helped me advance in my career but it has also opened my perspective towards building a holistic social media plan for my target market.', 'Insightful. Useful application to real business. ', 'Amazing!', 'Great, is better than the first. ', '\nvery cool\n\n', 'i am very thanks to coursera and my beloved Randy Hlavac really good content of this course . ', 'The tools, insights and growth I got from this section was fantastic and has actually changed the way I approach my social media marketing for my business.', 'Great for doing consumer and customer research. ', "Great course and great tools. I can't wait for the next course", 'Great course, great material, great tools, great instructors!  This is a great course in every level possible.', 'Great learning and very well researched course. A must do for any marketer who want to stay contemporary and learn the nuances of social listening by understanding its applicability in formulation of marketing strategy', None, 'The Importance of Listening is a great course providing hands-on tools on how to track the social impact. Very useful tools.', 'I learned A LOT! ', 'Thoroughly enjoyable!', 'A very comprehensive look at understanding target markets and analyzing your influence. Excellent course!', 'Excellent course!', 'Excellent ! I recommend.', 'Practical, engaging and extremely informative', 'an excellent one ', 'Really enjoyed learning much more about how to understand what target market searches for and connecting with top influences of target market. ', 'Great Material, so far.', 'Excellent information , brilliant material and entertaining discussions. Highly recommend for anyone looking to build essential skills revolving around social media.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Anthony L F', 'By Daniel E T M', 'By Ambika R K', 'By samira m', 'By Lilia M A C', 'By Irma A H A', 'By Mahmoud R', 'By Muhammad A Y', 'By Megan N', 'By Chad W', 'By Vaylyn R', 'By Cathy C d D C', 'By sushant p', 'By Walfredo d F', 'By Ting J', 'By Ana D P', 'By Carlene B', 'By Katie D', 'By Eva R', 'By Sergio L F d M', 'By nikolaos a', 'By Arindam B', 'By Candice S', 'By Mauricio J V', 'By RAZA I']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 05, 2017', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Apr 13, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2018', 'Sep 14, 2016', 'Dec 05, 2016', 'Nov 14, 2015', 'Jan 25, 2016', 'Jan 06, 2017', 'Feb 14, 2016', 'Feb 12, 2016', 'Apr 15, 2016', 'Jul 17, 2017', 'Mar 17, 2016', 'Mar 07, 2016', 'Jun 19, 2016', 'Jun 30, 2017', 'Aug 11, 2016', 'Jun 12, 2016', 'Apr 08, 2017']</review_date></doc>