<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_357</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/health-informatics-professional</course_url><course_name>Interprofessional Healthcare Informatics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Karen  Monsen, Ph.D., RN, FAAN</course_instructor><course_introduction>Interprofessional Healthcare Informatics is a graduate-level, hands-on interactive exploration of real informatics tools and techniques offered by the University of Minnesota and the University of Minnesota's National Center for Interprofessional Practice and Education. We will be incorporating technology-enabled educational innovations to bring the subject matter to life. Over the 10 modules, we will create a vital online learning community and a working healthcare informatics network. 

We will explore perspectives of clinicians like dentists, physical therapists, nurses, and physicians in all sorts of practice settings worldwide. Emerging technologies, telehealth, gaming, simulations, and eScience are just some of the topics that we will consider. 

Throughout the course, we’ll focus on creativity, controversy, and collaboration - as we collectively imagine and create the future within the rapidly evolving healthcare informatics milieu. All healthcare professionals and IT geeks are welcome!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Graph Theory//Information Theory//Data Virtualization//Health Informatics//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Minnesota</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Informatics Theory//Data, Information, and Knowledge//Electronic Health Record (EHR) Components, Evidence-Based Practice//Quality Improvement/ Workflow Analysis/ Redesign//Telehealth/ Consumer Health/ Mobile Technology//Community/ Population Health//Informatics, Gaming, and Simulation//Informatics and Ethics//Data Exchange and Interoperability//Informatics and the Foundation of Knowledge</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction and Overview'], ['Informatics Theory Part 1', 'Informatics Theory Part 2'], ['Data, Information, and Knowledge', 'Introduction to the Omaha System', 'An Omaha System Journey: Diane Thorson'], ['Electronic Health Records ', 'Evidence Based Practice'], ['Quality Improvement ', 'Workflow Processes '], ['Informatics and Telehealth ', 'Telehealth ', 'Consumer Health Informatics '], ['Informatics and Population Health '], ['Informatics, Gaming, and Simulations', 'Game Based Teaching and Computer Simulation ', 'Computational Modeling and Simulation'], ['Informatics and Ethics '], ['Health Information Exchange ', 'Standardization - Part 1 ', 'Standardization - Part 2 ', 'Standardization - Part 3 '], ['Informatics and the Foundation of Knowledge ', 'Data Visualization Part 1', 'Data Visualization Part 2 ', 'Synthesis ']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great content, but many of the links our out-of-date, so they definitely need to be updated.', None, 'The course was very informative to expand upon. It would have been very nice to have the presentation material made available in the form of slides or a readable PDF document...', 'This was a powerful course, sincerely it has improved my teaching-Health informatics is at it is infancy here in Kenya, yet we are suppose to teach it, with your awesome explanation and examples, things get better.', "I'm about half way through this course. It's a great accompaniment to the Health Informatics on FHIR (Georgia Tech). Its well presented and give a huge amount of additional reading to support the learning in each module. For me it has 'formalised' my on the job experience gained in the past few years.", 'Being in the medical field Its very useful course for me to understand EHR and other Healthcare information.', 'I I really enjoyed the classes and materials Thanks Teacher Thanks Coursera for the opportunity of everyone to study', 'Fun, easy, great pace - about 3 videos per week.  This course is instructive and understandable.  It is not about gene sequencing and statistical modelling. I recommend this to all healthcare professionals.', 'The class was very high level and tailored for clinical staff interested in an overview of Healthcare Informatics.  I was able to complete in 3 days and was surprised that a fee was charged upfront for a short and high level class.  This class was marketed as 9 weeks long. Not being a clinical staff, this class was only minimally helpful.  The quizzes at the end were painful as they expected 100% correct answers where particular words from the instructor had to be remembered.  Compared to the other Coursera classes this was not good enough quality with a compulsory fee.', 'Great course. Most of the content was relevant to my career.', 'Great informative and inspiring course. I am moved to find and utilize data for healthcare improvement.', "An excellent course with a great professor. The information was very simple to understand, and lots of interaction. Also appreciated the weekly reading articles, and the use of video's to help see how information and technology are changing healthcare.", 'There is a lot of new things I have not learned from classroom.', 'very informative course ', 'With this on-line education, I learned how much health information impacts consumers.', 'Excellent course!', 'This course is just perfect,', 'Great course so far!!! Love it', 'The course really helped me in understanding the basics of health informatics and definitely adds value to my CV. The faculty is very well versed and have a good knowledge of the subject. The class of data visualization really helped in evaluating how to visualize data and present it in a good form.', None, None, 'Excelente curso', 'A very high level overview of what needs to be done in the next n number of years to improve the population health by x times.', 'informative , well design quite helpful', 'the data visualization part is useful']</reviews><reviewers>['By Cassy G', 'By Rahool', 'By Thej S', 'By norbert b', 'By Philip T', 'By Ananda s', 'By Claudio D S F', 'By Scott56', 'By Deepa F P', 'By James M R', 'By Okwukwe D I', 'By Stanley O', 'By SinDee', 'By Dr. W H', 'By hojunnam', 'By Dante T', 'By Frankson, U', 'By Mninawe R M', 'By Dr F Z S', 'By Ayesha N', 'By Zhijie W', 'By Luis A S U', 'By vamsi', 'By Farhad A', 'By yaqing z']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 03, 2018', 'Nov 09, 2016', 'Apr 07, 2017', 'Jul 13, 2017', 'Mar 11, 2016', 'Oct 12, 2016', 'Aug 14, 2015', 'Aug 22, 2015', 'Sep 05, 2017', 'Dec 11, 2015', 'Jul 14, 2017', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Oct 06, 2015', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Jan 14, 2017', 'Sep 27, 2015', 'Oct 13, 2015', 'Aug 18, 2015', 'Jun 05, 2016', 'Apr 23, 2017', 'Feb 20, 2017', 'Feb 18, 2018', 'Sep 10, 2015', 'May 26, 2017', 'Apr 23, 2018']</review_date></doc>