<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_86</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/computational-neuroscience</course_url><course_name>Computational Neuroscience</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rajesh P. N. Rao</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course provides an introduction to basic computational methods for understanding what nervous systems do and for determining how they function. We will explore the computational principles governing various aspects of vision, sensory-motor control, learning, and memory. Specific topics that will be covered include representation of information by spiking neurons, processing of information in neural networks, and algorithms for adaptation and learning. We will make use of Matlab/Octave/Python demonstrations and exercises to gain a deeper understanding of concepts and methods introduced in the course. The course is primarily aimed at third- or fourth-year undergraduates and beginning graduate students, as well as professionals and distance learners interested in learning how the brain processes information.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Computational Neuroscience//Artificial Neural Network//Reinforcement Learning//Biological Neuron Model</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Washington</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction &amp; Basic Neurobiology (Rajesh Rao)//What do Neurons Encode? Neural Encoding Models (Adrienne Fairhall)//Extracting Information from Neurons: Neural Decoding (Adrienne Fairhall)//Information Theory &amp; Neural Coding (Adrienne Fairhall)//Computing in Carbon (Adrienne Fairhall)//Computing with Networks (Rajesh Rao)//Networks that Learn: Plasticity in the Brain &amp; Learning (Rajesh Rao)//Learning from Supervision and Rewards (Rajesh Rao)</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.1 Course Introduction', '1.2 Computational Neuroscience: Descriptive Models', '1.3 Computational Neuroscience: Mechanistic and Interpretive Models', '1.4 The Electrical Personality of Neurons', '1.5 Making Connections: Synapses', '1.6 Time to Network: Brain Areas and their Function'], ['2.1 What is the Neural Code?', '2.2 Neural Encoding: Simple Models', '2.3 Neural Encoding: Feature Selection', '2.4 Neural Encoding: Variability', 'Vectors and Functions (by Rich Pang)', 'Convolutions and Linear Systems (by Rich Pang)', 'Change of Basis and PCA (by Rich Pang)', 'Welcome to the Eigenworld! (by Rich Pang)'], ['3.1 Neural Decoding and Signal Detection Theory', '3.2 Population Coding and Bayesian Estimation', '3.3 Reading Minds: Stimulus Reconstruction', 'Fred Rieke on Visual Processing in the Retina', 'Gaussians in One Dimension (by Rich Pang)', "Probability distributions in 2D and Bayes' Rule (by Rich Pang)"], ['4.1 Information and Entropy', '4.2 Calculating Information in Spike Trains', '4.3 Coding Principles', "What's up with entropy? (by Rich Pang)", "Information theory? That's crazy! (by Rich Pang)"], ['5.1 Modeling Neurons', '5.2 Spikes', '5.3 Simplified Model Neurons', '5.4 A Forest of Dendrites', 'Eric Shea-Brown on Neural Correlations and Synchrony', 'Dynamical Systems Theory Intro Part 1: Fixed points (by Rich Pang)', 'Dynamical Systems Theory Intro Part 2: Nullclines (by Rich Pang)'], ['6.1 Modeling Connections Between Neurons', '6.2 Introduction to Network Models', '6.3 The Fascinating World of Recurrent Networks'], ["7.1 Synaptic Plasticity, Hebb's Rule, and Statistical Learning", '7.2 Introduction to Unsupervised Learning', '7.3 Sparse Coding and Predictive Coding', 'Gradient Ascent and Descent (by Rich Pang)'], ['8.1 Neurons as Classifiers and Supervised Learning', '8.2 Reinforcement Learning: Predicting Rewards', '8.3 Reinforcement Learning: Time for Action!', 'Eb Fetz on Bidirectional Brain-Computer Interfaces']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 30 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Great course! Really enjoyed the variety of topics and the just enough computational work in the quiz's. And that Eigen hat had me smiling and laughing about it for a week. ", "This course is a good start for learning computational neuroscience. I have learned how a single neuron processing signal and how to modeling this interesting process through mathematical and computational methods. I also learned the idea and models of the adaption of synapsis and coding of a group of neurons, which form the basis of memory and learning. The course also gave a brief intro to reinforcement learning, unsupervised learning and supervised learning and I can't wait to explore the fascinating world of deep learning. ", 'This is a wonderful start for a biologist , to get idea of concepts of learning . An advanced course focused  more on brain circuitry is suggested. ', None, 'Its a summation of summation of Conputational Neuroscience. Each week of this course could be a whole different course that really delves into the subject and not just presenting it. Video lessons were spamming you super compressed information. Some videos were sloppy and not helpful at all. ', 'It goes from too simple to very complex in few seconds.', 'This course felt really sketchy. Lectures were going way too fast and kept skipping concepts and derivations. Not bad if one only wants a superficial grasp of these concepts, but definitely not worth the price. ', "Very clear explanations by professors. I really liked the design of the class and the lectures are very easy to understand if you are just starting in Neuroscience (they don't throw around complicated jargon)", 'Great learning experience', 'Enlightening! After this course, one know how the architecture came from. ', 'Fantastic course! I enjoy it and love it very much. Thanks Rajesh and Adrienne! ', 'Интересный курс для введения в вычислитетльную нейробиологию)', 'This course is very helpful! I especially enjoy doing the exercise which is well designed and facilitates my understanding of CN. Besides, I find the textbook Theoretical Neuroscience by Dayan and Abbott more understandable after I finished this coursera course. ', "Computational Neuroscience is a well structured, insightful and methodical course. There were so many moments when I was dumbstruck by the power which our brain has, that I've lost the count of them! As a biophysics, signal processing enthusiast, I'm considering to go for higher studies in the field of Neuroscience and this course has just made my decision unequivocal. Big kudos to the instructors Prof. Rao and Prof. Fairhall for their inputs for both, the content of the course and sharing their research material! I can't wait to explore the brain to its fullest! :D", 'Very interesting course, ', 'Quite nice if you follow the recommended textbook - Peter Dayan - with it. The lectures touch important point. ', 'very effective course for Researchers ', 'Amazing Course with difficult challenges , hats off to professors :) ', 'nice course which teach me about what neurons can do and how can we model them with mathmatics', 'Very interesting and well organised course. ', 'I loved this course. It is an excellent introduction to the\nrealm of Computation Neuroscience. The lecturers presented the concepts clearly\nand effectively. Dr. Rao was especially great.  However, those looking to take\nthis course should have some knowledge of Differential Equations, Calculus,\nLinear Algebra, and either Python\nor Matlab before taking this course.', 'Comprehensive and challenging.', 'By far one of the most complete MOOCs in the subject. Highly recommended.', 'This course is an absolute must for those interested in computational neuroscience. The professors are very knowledgeable and the course is very rigorous. The techniques introduced in this course are useful and the supplementary material is enough to last for you months of reading on this topic. ', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Rob C', 'By 王桢', 'By Amit T', 'By DANIEL V', 'By George P', 'By Roberto E', 'By Zeqian L', 'By sbansal6', 'By Fridah G W K', 'By Wei X', 'By Changjia C', 'By Руслан К', 'By Mingchen Y', 'By Vikrant J', 'By ANGELOS A', 'By Paridhi K', 'By faisal k', 'By saurabh k p', 'By 潘宜城', 'By Krishnakanth A', 'By Maxwell G', 'By Adam E', 'By Andrés Z', 'By AmirHossein E', 'By Manya A']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 03, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2018', 'May 27, 2018', 'Feb 05, 2017', 'Jan 13, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2017', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Dec 14, 2018', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Aug 03, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2018', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Nov 04, 2018', 'Mar 16, 2017', 'May 22, 2017', 'Apr 18, 2018', 'Mar 26, 2017', 'Apr 03, 2017']</review_date></doc>