<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_184</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/people-analytics</course_url><course_name>Introduction to People Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ilya Breyman</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is designed to provide you with an understanding of the role of data and technology in human capital management. Every topic in the course will be covered in the most practical way so that learners get hands-on experience. In the course we use the 4Ts principle: Task, Theory, Technique and Technology so that there is always a connection to organizational performance objectives, an overview of underlying theories and principles, and specific tools which help achieve business objectives.

You will learn 
●	what combination of data, technologies, and tools can be used in people management processes to improve organization’s performance
●	how to use some of these tools and how to select the ones that suit your objectives and budget
●	to design individual and team development plans and measure its ROI for the organization
●	how to figure out the qualities that lead employees to their best performance so you know what to encourage in current and look for in new employees
●	how to identify the right channels to recruit your employees or team members
●	what combination of monetary and non-monetary motivation tools work best for your organization 
●	how to predict what people will leave in the near future and how to make sure some of them stay
●	how to measure engagement and make a strong organizational culture improve performance</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Performance//Culture and Assessments//Compensation//Motivation and Engagement//Workforce Planning and Recruitment//Development</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction Video', 'Lecture 1 About the Course', 'Lecture 2 HR Transformation', 'Lecture 3 Course Structure'], ['Lecture 1 Why Performance Matters', 'Lecture 2 Setting Objectives and Measuring Performance', 'Lecture 3 Data Presentation'], ['Lecture 1 Defining Culture', 'Lecture 2 Understanding Culture', 'Lecture 3 Assessing Culture'], ['Lecture 1 Compensation and Performance', 'Lecture 2 Compensation Models', 'Lecture 3 Benchmarking'], ['Lecture 1 Understanding Motivation', 'Lecture 2 Motivation Tools', 'Lecture 3 Engagement'], ['Lecture 1 Workforce Planning Analytics', 'Lecture 2 Recruitment Funnel', 'Lecture 3 Selection Tools'], ['Lecture 1 Analyzing Learning Needs', 'Lecture 2 Designing Training Programs', 'Lecture 3 ROI Calculation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['There should be more practice than theory, a conference call to discuss Assignment after Submitting and Show ideal scenario of Assignment to show us where we went wrong. ', None, 'The worst Coursera course I have taken. Total waste of time. The lectures are boring and have no real content. The supplementary materials are good though. ', None, 'Good introductory for people analytics.', 'Great course to learn about the future of human resource management. ', 'Thank you so much for making this course. It helped me understand the basics and also gain an insight into introduction aspects of people analytics. Kudos to the Professors!', 'Excellent!!!', None, 'good course', 'Excellent course and good study materials/video tutorials.', 'Excellent course that will get you an edge over others. Happy with the lectures.', 'Course relevancy was excellent to HR Operations.  Would have liked additional explanation and detail on assignments. More examples ans cases.', "This course really aligned with work that my organization has been doing for the last four years, and how we view our people support. It's on the leading edge of Human Resources theory and is a great primer for the subject.", 'Very relevant information, good general overview with excellent resources.', 'Дорогие друзья! Это хороший курс, но он еще сырой и много чего можно сделать. Я надеюсь, что вы будете его развивать и всячески совершенствовать. ', 'It´s very basic', 'Good ideas but a huge struggle waiting for other to peer review. Some of the transcripts were difficult to understand.', "The instructors' presentation skills need to be improved.", "I can't even understand what the professors speak. The course can be designed in a better way. A lot of times I can't even find a relationship between your first slide and next slide. ", 'Very weak. You should invest in hands on things... ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Vinita S', 'By Niharika S', 'By Honghai Y', 'By Alejandro S', 'By Mark J E B', 'By Sachin L', 'By Amruta D', 'By sridhar', 'By Artem A', 'By ruta', 'By PRAVEEN R', 'By ankit g', 'By Fran D', 'By Kristen B', 'By Anthony P', 'By Andrew F', 'By Manuel F S G', 'By Marc R', 'By Miranda Y', 'By Ramya R', 'By Maria C P Q']</reviewers><review_date>['May 21, 2019', 'May 30, 2017', 'Apr 26, 2016', 'Sep 22, 2015', 'May 24, 2017', 'Jun 21, 2017', 'Jun 20, 2017', 'Feb 27, 2016', 'Apr 14, 2016', 'Oct 29, 2015', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Nov 22, 2015', 'Apr 18, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'Aug 30, 2016', 'Jul 25, 2018', 'Sep 13, 2019', 'Sep 14, 2017', 'Mar 02, 2018', 'Jan 14, 2018']</review_date></doc>