<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_135</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/introduction-gis-mapping</course_url><course_name>Introduction to GIS Mapping</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Don Boyes</course_instructor><course_introduction>Get started learning about the fascinating and useful world of geographic information systems (GIS)! In this first course of the specialization GIS, Mapping, and Spatial Analysis, you'll learn about what a GIS is, how to get started with the software yourself, how things we find in the real world can be represented on a map, how we record locations using coordinates, and how we can make a two-dimensional map from a three-dimensional Earth. In the course project, you will create your own GIS data by tracing geographic features from a satellite image for a location and theme of your choice. This course will give you a strong foundation in mapping and GIS that will give you the understanding you need to start working with GIS, and to succeed in the other courses in this specialization.

This course is for anyone who wants to learn about mapping and GIS. You don't have to have any previous experience - just your curiosity! The course includes both practical software training and explanations of the concepts you need to know to make informed decisions as you start your journey to becoming a GIS analyst.

You will need a Windows computer with ArcGIS Desktop installed.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Environmental Science and Sustainability</course_category><course_tag>Geographic Information System (GIS)//Cartography//Esri//Mapping//Spatial Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Toronto</course_orgnization><course_chapter>What is a GIS?//Introduction to ArcGIS//Mapping the real world with vector and raster data//Mapping Locations with Coordinate Systems//Flattening the Earth with Map Projections//Project: Creating Your Own Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the specialization', 'Welcome to the course!', 'Maps in your pocket', 'What is a map?', 'What is a GIS?', 'Defining GIS', 'A quick tour of the software', 'Examples of geospatial data', 'Procedures and people'], ['Web map design and content in ArcGIS Online', 'A quick tour of ArcGIS Online', 'Map documents and layers', 'Keeping track of files in ArcMap', 'Jack Dangermond', 'Map scale', 'Scale on a web map', 'Scale, annotation, and visibility', 'Working with map scale in ArcMap', 'Working with map scale in ArcGIS Online'], ['Mapping the real world', 'Vector data model', 'Creating vector data by digitizing in ArcMap', 'Sampling frequency when digitizing', 'Map scale and digitizing', 'Precision, accuracy, and digitizing', 'Raster data model', 'Spatial resolution and data volume', 'Spatial resolution of raster data in ArcMap', 'Vector vs. raster data models'], ['Longitude and latitude', 'Defining the prime meridian', 'Recording lat/long coordinates', 'Converting DMS/DD coordinates', 'The Earth as an ellipsoid', 'Horizontal datum', 'Geographic coordinate system', 'Changing horizontal datums', 'Vertical datum'], ['Purpose of map projections', 'How projections work', 'Associating points from 3D to 2D', 'Projection class', 'Standard line and scale factor', 'Projection case', 'Projection aspect', 'Projection central meridian', "Tissot's indicatrix", 'Equidistant projection', 'Great circles and rhumb lines', 'Projection distance and direction', 'Grid coordinate systems and UTM', 'Projections and ArcGIS', 'Working with map projections', 'Data frames and extent rectangles in ArcMap'], ['$null$']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I really enjoyed this course, the explanations of concepts were clear and straight forward which makes learning a technical subject like this one a lot easier, I look forward to completing the next course in the specialization.', 'Very nice explanations, especially about different coordinate system and projections.', 'Amazing course.', 'Really liked the way concepts are given. Enjoyed the entire journey of Introduction to GIS Mapping! Thank you very much :) ', 'Great class! Good design and wonderful videos!', 'Very detailed and beginner friendly!', 'very simplified it is the perfect place to start your GIS journey.', "I already have some experience with ArcMap, but I want to complete the 4 course series. I was happily surprised that Course 1 contained so much good information that I was not yet super knowledgeable in, particluarly the parts about coordinate and projection systems. That's always confused me, but this course helped me solidify my understanding of how all that works. Even though I already know how to make a map etc. I definitely did NOT see this course as a waste of my time. Great course!", 'I was very excited to see this course is offered and I was also very excited it is offered by UoT, but it was a huge disappointment on many levels. 1. The name of the course is misleading it is "introduction to GIS mapping" but without "GIS". in the entire course only 1 or 2 videos show how to use GIS that is it (planting couple of trees on a Queens Park map.) 2. This is more about theory than practice. The instructor has very good hand of the theory which makes sense because his background is geography. 3. The course tells a lot about \'what\' to do but never shows \'how\' to do it in GIS. 4. If you are looking to learn simple applications  such as change the color of 1 states on a US map to show where you are from, (basic skill) wont be able to do it! videos are good exmples are good explanations are good but no application aspect. 4. You ask for data used in lectures wont get it.  I guess i will fully use the trail period before paying in future for any course!', 'Very Good course. Helpful to learn the basic fundamentals of GIS and to learn to digitize a map for the first time. I recommend it to any beginner who is trying to start working with GIS.', 'This is by far one of the best laid out and presented courses I have every taken.  Don is a master of using graphics and examples to provide a clear understanding of the principles in this often information-dense course.  I am enjoying the program immensely and very much appreciate the skill of its instructor!  I absolutely would recommend this course to anyone diving into the world of GIS.', 'very educative and match my carrer, i love it thanks.', 'Great Instructor!  ', 'Superbly instructed the digital course of its kind', "Great background on what goes into making maps and how to interpret map projections. I learned more from this course than from a very expensive GIS course I took years ago. It gives you time to install and play around with ArcGIS, and it comes with a 1 year student license for the software. Information is well presented, and care clearly went into this course! I'm happy to have done it and I will continue on with the specialization. Thanks Prof. Boyes!", 'Very informative and fun, wish to learn more now.', 'I was looking for a course that would give me a solid entry and introduction to the world of GIS, and I found it in this course. I consider my time doing it as well invested', 'I enjoyed my time doing this course, the course instructor explains very clearly in the simplest terms and I would recommend it to anyone new to the world of GIS.', 'The course was structured well and Don is a very good instructor!', 'The course is excellent. I loved the material, the examples, explanation, and application are very clear. The professor Dr. Boyes is very good too. I am excited to continue to the next course and complete all of the specialization. Recommend this course to anyone who wants to start learning about GIS.', 'Excellent introduction course ', 'I loved this course so much because I learned a lot with it. Thank you Coursera, University of Toronto and Don Boyes to disseminated high quality education around the world.', 'Muy bueno para comprender los conceptos básicos. Me sirvió de mucho para la creación de tablas y geodatabases']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nicholas W', 'By Jasminka K', 'By Gabriel V', 'By Ranjeet S', 'By Lara J', 'By reneryu', 'By Ali W H', 'By jessica R', 'By Shams R', 'By Md. A H', 'By David R', 'By Laurent M ', 'By Xinbo Z', 'By Faisal S', 'By Francis S', 'By Sanjeet K', 'By RASHEED A', 'By Nadia B', 'By Michael E S', 'By Jessica E L D', 'By OCTAVIO A F N', 'By Rafaela d P B R', 'By Gleyman A C G']</reviewers><review_date>['May 28, 2019', 'May 22, 2019', 'Jun 09, 2019', 'Jun 02, 2019', 'Jun 14, 2019', 'Jun 13, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2019', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'Sep 05, 2019', 'Jul 23, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2019', 'Aug 14, 2019', 'Aug 20, 2019', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'Sep 06, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2019', 'Sep 15, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2019']</review_date></doc>