<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_316</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/multiple-regression-analysis-public-health</course_url><course_name>Multiple Regression Analysis in Public Health</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>John McGready, PhD, MS</course_instructor><course_introduction>Biostatistics is the application of statistical reasoning to the life sciences, and it's the key to unlocking the data gathered by researchers and the evidence presented in the scientific public health literature. In this course, you'll extend simple regression to the prediction of a single outcome of interest on the basis of multiple variables. Along the way, you'll be introduced to a variety of methods, and you'll practice interpreting data and performing calculations on real data from published studies.  Topics include multiple logistic regression, the Spline approach, confidence intervals, p-values, multiple Cox regression, adjustment, and effect modification.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Health Informatics</course_category><course_tag>effect modifcation//Proportional Hazards Model//Regression Analysis//Spline approach</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>An Overview of Multiple Regression for Estimation, Adjustment, and Basic Prediction, and Multiple Linear Regression//Multiple Logistic Regression//Multiple Cox Regression//Course Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Multiple Regression: An Overview', 'Multiple Linear Regression: Some Examples', 'Multiple Linear Regression: Basics of Model Estimation, and Handling Uncertainty in the Resulting Estimates', 'Estimate Group Means and Mean Differences for Groups Who Differ in More than One Predictor with Multiple Linear Regression', 'The “Linearity” Assumption and Estimating Amount of Variability Explained by Multiple Predictors', 'Examples from the Literature', 'Investigating Effect Modification with Multiple Linear Regression (Forthcoming)', 'Investigating Effect Modification with Multiple Linear Regression—More Examples, For Those Interested', 'Additional Examples of Multiple Linear Regression'], ['Multiple Logistic Regression: Some Examples', 'Multiple Logistic Regression: Basics of Model Estimation, and Handling Uncertainty in the Resulting Estimates', 'Estimating Group Odds and Proportions, and Odds Ratios for Groups Who Differ in More than One Predictor with Multiple Linear Regression', 'The “Linearity” Assumption and A Brief Note about Prediction with Multiple Logistic Regression', 'Examples from the Literature', 'Investigating Effect Modification with Multiple Logistic Regression, Part 1', 'Investigating Effect Modification with Multiple Logistic Regression, Part 2', 'Additional Examples'], ['Some Examples', 'Basics of Model Estimation and Handling Uncertainty in the Resulting Estimates', 'Estimating Hazard Ratios for Groups who Differ in more than one Predictor with Multiple Cox Regression', 'The "Linearity" Assumption and Prediction with Multiple Cox Regression', 'Examples from the Literature'], ['Biostatistical Consulting Project']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Would love to learn more from Dr. McGready in statistical courses more advanced than the ones offered in this specialization ', 'the course spends a lot of time repeating the same concepts. i would be more convinced if they spend more time in explaining how to make the multiple regressions , how many variables i can add and what are the limitations and how to make a measure of fitness ', 'Great instructor, really informative and engaging. ', 'The course is well structured. The numerous examples and practice questions help the student apply the concepts learned. I love the fact that almost every question was from a real article.', 'Incredible way of teaching biostatistics using by just adding more complexity to the same exercises in a gradual form!', 'The course was five stars, there were some quiz issues and a few numerical issues, but I learned a lot and appreciate the time and effort put into the content.  Thank you!', "Duplicated video in the logistic regression module. I've raised a concern request correction of the issue but no response, and now I've completed the course already."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Anurag M', 'By Shady M S ', 'By Fred L', 'By Ulrick S K K', 'By Francisco C', 'By Cassandra N', 'By Billy C']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 21, 2019', 'May 25, 2019', 'Jul 15, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 31, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019']</review_date></doc>