<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_63</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/bayesian-statistics</course_url><course_name>Bayesian Statistics: From Concept to Data Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Herbert Lee</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course introduces the Bayesian approach to statistics, starting with the concept of probability and moving to the analysis of data. We will learn about the philosophy of the Bayesian approach as well as how to implement it for common types of data. We will compare the Bayesian approach to the more commonly-taught Frequentist approach, and see some of the benefits of the Bayesian approach. In particular, the Bayesian approach allows for better accounting of uncertainty, results that have more intuitive and interpretable meaning, and more explicit statements of assumptions. This course combines lecture videos, computer demonstrations, readings, exercises, and discussion boards to create an active learning experience. For computing, you have the choice of using Microsoft Excel or the open-source, freely available statistical package R, with equivalent content for both options. The lectures provide some of the basic mathematical development as well as explanations of philosophy and interpretation. Completion of this course will give you an understanding of the concepts of the Bayesian approach, understanding the key differences between Bayesian and Frequentist approaches, and the ability to do basic data analyses.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Bayesian Statistics//Bayesian Inference//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Santa Cruz</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Probability and Bayes' Theorem//Statistical Inference//Priors and Models for Discrete Data//Models for Continuous Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course introduction', 'Lesson 1.1 Classical and frequentist probability', 'Lesson 1.2 Bayesian probability and coherence', 'Lesson 2.1 Conditional probability', "Lesson 2.2 Bayes' theorem", 'Lesson 3.1 Bernoulli and binomial distributions', 'Lesson 3.2 Uniform distribution', 'Lesson 3.3 Exponential and normal distributions'], ['Lesson 4.1 Confidence intervals', 'Lesson 4.2 Likelihood function and maximum likelihood', 'Lesson 4.3 Computing the MLE', 'Lesson 4.4 Computing the MLE: examples', 'Introduction to R', 'Plotting the likelihood in R', 'Plotting the likelihood in Excel', 'Lesson 5.1 Inference example: frequentist', 'Lesson 5.2 Inference example: Bayesian', "Lesson 5.3 Continuous version of Bayes' theorem", 'Lesson 5.4 Posterior intervals'], ['Lesson 6.1 Priors and prior predictive distributions', 'Lesson 6.2 Prior predictive: binomial example', 'Lesson 6.3 Posterior predictive distribution', 'Lesson 7.1 Bernoulli/binomial likelihood with uniform prior', 'Lesson 7.2 Conjugate priors', 'Lesson 7.3 Posterior mean and effective sample size', 'Data analysis example in R', 'Data analysis example in Excel', 'Lesson 8.1 Poisson data'], ['Lesson 9.1 Exponential data', 'Lesson 10.1 Normal likelihood with variance known', 'Lesson 10.2 Normal likelihood with variance unknown', 'Lesson 11.1 Non-informative priors', 'Lesson 11.2 Jeffreys prior', 'Linear regression in R', 'Linear regression in Excel (Analysis ToolPak)', 'Linear regression in Excel (StatPlus by AnalystSoft)', 'Conclusion']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 21 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['So, I really wanted to LOVE this class, but instead I found that I merely liked it, and want to use this review as a way to explain why. WHAT I LIKE ABOUT THE CLASS: The material is sufficient for the topic at hand, and is structured in an appropriate way. If you work through everything you\'ll have a decent grasp of exactly what the class is meant to be about. It\'s also pretty well paced. WHAT I DIDN\'T LIKE ABOUT THE CLASS: Dr. Lee usually rushes through or skips discussions what concepts mean before formalizing them mathematically. As a result it\'s very easy to make progress through the class without a good feeling that you actually "get" what Bayesian statistics is really about. Too many of these videos are him chopping wood through the mathematical jingo, when the material DESPERATELY needed a 3-5 minute introductory video about what concepts actually mean or how to think about them. I remember telling my girlfriend during the middle of the class that I found it frustrating because I was progressing through it quickly, and getting the quizzes right, but lacked a good intuition for how to think about Bayesian statistics. So Dr. Lee......work on those presentation skills! Think deeply about how to communicate the essentials of the concepts in each lesson, and THEN start pounding away on the whiteboard!', 'This course gives an introduction to the theoretical basics of Bayesian statistics. Before taking this class, I had a very confused view of the whole Frequentist vs Bayesian "debate". I understand now that Bayesian statistics is really about attaching uncertainties to beliefs and producing a clear definition of this uncertainty (especially through the notion of credible intervals).', "I felt like I just did a lot of calculations. The course was better in the beginning, as I felt the professor actually explained what and why were were doing what we were doing. By the middle of the course, however, I felt that the professor just jotted down equations and went really quickly. I don't actually understand why I was doing the calculations that I was doing. ", "I don't find that the lectures do a good job of relating the material to real world usage. To much focus on equations and too little on the why.", 'Very good overview to the area. Efficient and clear lectures - emphasis on the quizzes that required just a proper amount of focus and time from my personal point of view.', 'Very concise and helpful for an intro to Bayesian statistics. Good level of difficulty to encourage learning. This well prepares further study of more advanced topics such as MCMC and more.', ' a really good  course!', 'If you already know everything about the topic and just forgot some little things or you are very strong in calculus, this may be a nice refresher. Otherwise, not very useful. Really dense and little explanation. I liked the Youtube MIT course on Probability (it includes Bayesian Statistics) much more, since it has good explanation of the concepts. ', 'A well-rounded introductory course in Bayesian Statistics. ', 'Great introduction for beginners', 'The bite-sized arrangement of individual videos are very conducive for learning and self internalisation.', 'Very good material! The Prof explains very easily the contents of the course. Great course! I recommend. E. Martins, Brazil', 'Thanks it was nice learning from wonderfu instructors.', None, 'Good and clear course. I was impressed by the quality of the material.', 'Great course for beginners as well as those that need a refresher on the basics!', 'Very Useful Course', 'Great introductory course. It was challenging but doable for someone who has not take college level mathematics or statistics in a few years. ', 'I found the course very well made and beautifully presented. The material is systematic, the more advanced topics based on the previously learned information without gaps and any need to study additional sources. The examples and the tests provide additional insights. Thank you, prof. Herbert Lee, for this great course!', 'The course if very informative but some previous knowledge and understanding of basic statistics (e.g., distributions) is recommended to fully grasp the concepts delivered through the course. ', 'Great introduction to Bayesian statistics.  Very helpful for me, especially for understanding some of the times when priors might be useful, and how they can aid me.', 'best course for the beginners who want to get started on bayesian inference', 'A great introduction to Bayesian Statistics. For some of the Quiz questions, it would have been helpful to get an error warning in case one might had accidentally used a comma instead of a dot notation.', "It's really a good course for Bayesian Statistics. Exercises are designed in such a way that they can't be passed if you've not understood the topic completely. The workload is manageable and the course content is really well organized."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Jonathan', 'By Scott S', 'By Megan G', 'By DM C', 'By Timo K', 'By Yifei H', 'By Asael B I', 'By Iryna', 'By Nathan A', 'By raymonsahib', 'By Valeth', 'By Eduardo M', 'By Sameen N', 'By Muhammad A J', 'By Niklas J', 'By Robert T', 'By Susenjit G', 'By Michael W', 'By Georgy M', 'By Yiwen ', 'By Brian K', 'By Priyabrata D', 'By Fabian S', 'By Ayush T']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 02, 2018', 'Oct 28, 2018', 'Jul 26, 2017', 'Jun 11, 2018', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2017', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Nov 23, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019']</review_date></doc>