<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_239</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/designexperiments</course_url><course_name>Designing, Running, and Analyzing Experiments</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Scott  Klemmer</course_instructor><course_introduction>You may never be sure whether you have an effective user experience until you have tested it with users. In this course, you’ll learn how to design user-centered experiments, how to run such experiments, and how to analyze data from these experiments in order to evaluate and validate user experiences. You will work through real-world examples of experiments from the fields of UX, IxD, and HCI, understanding issues in experiment design and analysis. You will analyze multiple data sets using recipes given to you in the R statistical programming language -- no prior programming experience is assumed or required, but you will be required to read, understand, and modify code snippets provided to you. By the end of the course, you will be able to knowledgeably design, run, and analyze your own experiments that give statistical weight to your designs.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Design and Product</course_category><course_tag>Experiment//Experimental Design//Statistical Model//R Programming//Statistics</course_tag><course_rating>3.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Basic Experiment Design Concepts//Tests of Proportions//The T-Test//Validity in Design and Analysis//One-Factor Between-Subjects Experiments//One-Factor Within-Subjects Experiments//Factorial Experiment Designs//Generalizing the Response//The Power of Mixed Effects Models</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['01. What You Will Learn in this Course', '02. Basic Experiment Design Concepts'], ['03. Description of a Study of User Preferences', '04. Getting Started with R and RStudio', '05. Exploring Data and a First Test of Proportions', '06. Understanding and Reporting Your First Statistical Test', '07. Exact Tests, Asymptotic Tests, and the Binomial Test', '08. More One-Sample Tests of Proportions', '09. Two-Sample Tests of Proportions'], ['10. Experiment Design Concepts in a Simple A/B Test', '11. Analyzing a Simple A/B Test with a T-Test'], ['12. Designing for Experimental Control', '13. Data Assumptions and Distributions', '14. Testing for ANOVA Assumptions', '15. Mann-Whitney, a Nonparametric T-Test'], ['16. Description of a Study for a Oneway ANOVA', '17. Analyzing and Reporting a Oneway ANOVA', '18. Kruskal-Wallis, a Nonparametric Oneway ANOVA'], ['19. Description of a Study for a Oneway Repeated Measures ANOVA', '20. Counterbalancing Repeated Measures Factors', '21. Long-Format and Wide-Format Data Tables', '22. The Paired T-Test and Wilcoxon Signed-Rank Test', '23. Analyzing a Repeated Measures ANOVA and Friedman Test'], ['24. Description of a Study for a Factorial ANOVA', '25. Understanding Interaction Effects', '26. Analyzing a Factorial ANOVA', '27. The ART, a Nonparametric Factorial ANOVA'], ['28. Introduction to Generalized Linear Models', '29. Analyzing Three Generalized Linear Models'], ['30. Introduction to Mixed Effects Models', '31. Analyzing a Linear Mixed Model', '32. Analyzing a Generalized Linear Mixed Model', '33. Course in Review']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 23 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I feel like the course overall was important. I'm glad I have the basic idea of how I can crunch research data using R. However, the course could be difficult and perhaps a bit deep for many people looking toward UX design. The instructor suffers from the academia cliche of having so much knowledge and skill that he can't always help students on a very introductory level. Case in point reading the class notes (a task usually unimportant and ignored by most users) is required, and yet even those notes are written from a perspective of knowledge of the subject. It's a bit like coming into a Spanish 1 class, looking to learn a bit about Spanish and the professor hands you a syllabus of which parts are written in Spanish. While I recovered from this shock, I think for many this snowballs into growing frustration and failure.", 'I liked the professor. He explained things well. My concern with this course it the understanding of it. I can do command line commands but figuring out which commands to use for each quiz question is complicated. The first few weeks I figured out which sections of the coursera.R file to use. Later weeks were more complicated. Perhaps files with commands and comments on a per week basis would be best. Not giving the answers to the student, but at least giving more context per file would be very helpful.', 'I was enthusiastic about this class but it ended up being useless to me. While the structure allowed me to jump right in R, I felt like without any prior knowledge of statistics, I was just copy pasting without really understanding the tests, and why to use one rather than another. I guess going deeper into what things mean, or adding more context to the tests would help for designers with little background of stats. For example, even though it was explained, it would have been nice that every time we had a new dataset, to take the time to explain what type of survey it was, vs the previous ones, and to map it to the grid. This was assumed as a given, but I feel I would still have trouble figuring out which test to use on my own. So overall this was a good class but missing some content for the beginners.', "The instructor and Teaching Aids haven't participated in the learning Forums for over a year- this is the most difficult course in the Specialization however there is little to no support for the students. I have a background in engineering so I faired well in the course, but for many- not so much! Course would also benefit from a more robust intro to R Programming.  Thank you so much for the course , I really appreciate it! I'm only sending these criticisms in order to help - I personally did very well in the course.", 'The worst course of this specialisation. Instead of emphasising on the principles of statistical methods, this course forces you to use R and RStudio.', 'I\'ve been going through "Interaction Design" courses from University of California, San Diego since course one in order to get the specialisation. And each course was interesting, insightful, challenging. I really want to get the specialisation and I worked hard to get to this point. In total it took me around two years with pauses and breaks.', 'It\'s true that I\'ve learned a lot and will never see experiments the same way again. I have new-found respect for conducting even the most simple surveys. BUT this course goes way too deep into the math and code under the hood. It\'s absolutely ridiculous. I almost dropped out so many times. I had to invest hours of my scarce time to complete tasks that aren\'t suited for an Interaction Designer, but rather for a mathematician. I\'d rather spend more time analysing results and optimising the design of experiments than figuring what on earth I\'m being "explained" about a bunch of intricate formulas. The analysis got completely LOST in that jungle of numbers, weird names and math jargon. Wouldn\'t recommend.', 'A tough course, especially for those who do not code. Thus, lots of work required. Sometimes there were way too many tasks (32). I gave this course 5 stars as it was a very challenging, but lots of different approaches and tests you can learn more and in depth.', 'This course was extremely helpful in understanding which statistical test to use when, with applications specifically for interaction design, which is what I need :) I appreciated the clear relationship between the lectures and the quizzes &amp; assignments. The lectures also were clear. The course was broken up into doable chunks that made it easy to take while still having a full-time job.', "This had been the hardest class ever. I don't even know how I passed but also I don't see how I can remember to use Rcode for future work within HCI", 'At first I should thank Dr,Wobbrock for his efforts. He teaches the course materials well but I think the this course is not well-balanced. Statistics is very wide concept and R Studio is big too. Although the course is longer than other courses of this specialization , i dont think it has the same output.', 'Too technical, with lots of hard concepts to assimilate in a very small time. Exercises are too hard. ', "This course is not amazing at all. It takes so much time to complete plus you do not learn much. You learn to pretty much replace some parts of a code it's already done in R. So you work with code but you don't learn how to code either. I give this course 1 star.", 'I reviewed all previous courses with 5 stars but I had to give 1 star to this course Not because of the instructor and not because of the importance of the material but because of the level it os not well thought through. As a beginner designer information given here without clear explanation of how those studios and softwares work you would be a big problem for anyone who just started getting into this field. Giving us basic skills of using those tools would be more helful rather than asking us to solve problems. I finished all previous courses in less than a month and obtained so many skills and information. I am very frastrated because I was looking forward to finish this specialization. ', 'This course assumes too much knowledge about both programming and statistics. The tone of the instructor makes it seem like its an introductory course, but he does not provide an introduction to the concepts and methods that would give the student a proper grounding to successfully advance through the course. ', 'Great course. You explained the topics very clearly!', 'as a first introduction to the analytical side of quantitative/ qualitative experimentation amazing course, pulls you in... it is tough and requires more time than what is mentioned... but totally worth it.', 'Should cover how to select sample for experiments and perform experimental design test', 'Really hard, but really great!', 'Great!', "This course was an deep dive into data analytics and designing experiments for analytics. Although there was a great requirement to perform the tests by yourself - which i guess some designers don't appreciate - it still was an exciting and challenging experience!", "It's a great course. It is very well structured and provides a foundation of research and I am glad that it is a part of Interaction Design specialization. However, might be extremely challenging for people without Statistics experience.", 'It was very helpful for me, thank you! I thought that I will never be able to make this challenging course, but after completion I think that I have courage to design, run and analyze experiments on practice! ', 'Very good lesson: good way to learn R', 'Have to watch three times to keep up because it is really hard for people without former experiences... Anyway it is worth it']</reviews><reviewers>['By Jared G', 'By Richard H', 'By Audree L', 'By Jon M', 'By Sourav C', 'By Ingvar K', 'By Adolfo R ', 'By Maria K', 'By Julie B', 'By Alfredo H', 'By AMIR R A', 'By Wilame L S J V', 'By Alejandro N', 'By Tamella H', 'By Stephen B', 'By Jacky ( H Z', 'By Faraz A K', 'By Noor S R', 'By Maisa D', 'By Nicolas D G N', 'By Timo S', 'By Olena B', 'By Anna R', 'By Cyril M', 'By ZHUO W']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 07, 2019', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Feb 04, 2018', 'Apr 29, 2019', 'Nov 14, 2017', 'Sep 23, 2017', 'Jun 24, 2018', 'Oct 17, 2018', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Dec 26, 2017', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2017', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Aug 01, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Jul 19, 2017', 'Mar 03, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2016', 'May 18, 2017', 'Mar 01, 2018', 'Jul 26, 2017']</review_date></doc>