<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_24</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/natural-language-processing-tensorflow</course_url><course_name>Natural Language Processing in TensorFlow</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Laurence Moroney</course_instructor><course_introduction>If you are a software developer who wants to build scalable AI-powered algorithms, you need to understand how to use the tools to build them. This Specialization will teach you best practices for using TensorFlow, a popular open-source framework for machine learning.

In Course 3 of the deeplearning.ai TensorFlow Specialization, you will build natural language processing systems using TensorFlow. You will learn to process text, including tokenizing and representing sentences as vectors, so that they can be input to a neural network. You’ll also learn to apply RNNs, GRUs, and LSTMs in TensorFlow. Finally, you’ll get to train an  LSTM on existing text to create original poetry!

The Machine Learning course and Deep Learning Specialization from Andrew Ng teach the most important and foundational principles of Machine Learning and Deep Learning. This new deeplearning.ai TensorFlow Specialization teaches you how to use TensorFlow to implement those principles so that you can start building and applying scalable models to real-world problems. To develop a deeper understanding of how neural networks work, we recommend that you take the Deep Learning Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Natural Language Processing//Tokenization//Machine Learning//Tensorflow//RNNs</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>deeplearning.ai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Sentiment in text// Word Embeddings //Sequence models//Sequence models and literature</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction, A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Introduction', 'Word based encodings', 'Using APIs', 'Notebook for lesson 1', 'Text to sequence', 'Looking more at the Tokenizer', 'Padding', 'Notebook for lesson 2', 'Sarcasm, really?', 'Working with the Tokenizer', 'Notebook for lesson 3', 'Week 1 Wrap up'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Introduction', 'The IMBD dataset', 'Looking into the details', 'How can we use vectors?', 'More into the details', 'Notebook for lesson 1', 'Remember the sarcasm dataset?', 'Building a classifier for the sarcasm dataset', 'Let’s talk about the loss function', 'Pre-tokenized datasets', 'Diving into the code (part 1)', 'Diving into the code (part 2)', 'Notebook for lesson 3'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Introduction', 'LSTMs', 'Implementing LSTMs in code', 'Accuracy and loss', 'A word from Laurence', 'Looking into the code', 'Using a convolutional network', 'Going back to the IMDB dataset', 'Tips from Laurence'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Introduction', 'Looking into the code', 'Training the data', 'More on training the data', 'Notebook for lesson 1', 'Finding what the next word should be', 'Example', 'Predicting a word', 'Poetry!', 'Looking into the code', 'Laurence the poet!', 'Your next task', 'A conversation with Andrew Ng']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["Compared to Andrew's original M/L course, and the most recent Deeplearning specialization, this series of courses is very lightweight.  The material is very good, well organized and clear.  But it can be covered fairly quickly.  This last one, natural language processing, can be completed in an afternoon, all four weeks.  This is a bit annoying, as the courses appear so far apart, I have paid over $40 for each of these three, for what could essentially be a weekend course (all three courses combined).", 'Very elementary introduction to applications and scenarios in nlp. As has already been mentioned in other comments, the whole course can be compressed into no more than two hour long lecture and exercises over an afternoon.', 'NLP basics. Missing a lot of things. This entire course could have been made in to a single weeks 5 mins video.', 'A quick and practical overview of NLP with Tensoflow keras module.', 'Amazing course by Laurence Moroney. But only after finishing Sequence Models by Andrew NG, I was able to understand the concepts taught here.', 'The course if worse than even an  overview course. It just shows you some random code and you have tyo try assignments yourself without any knowledge of nlp. This is not expected from deeplearning.ai.', "I was waiting for a course that covers NLP, this course covers all topics of NLP with added value working with Tensorflowto facilitate implementing projects, and it's well designed, and Dr. Laurence is amazing, his explanations are useful and easy to understand, Thank You!", "I am enrolled and paying 49$ a month for the 4th course in this specialization and it hasn't even been released yet. Not sure how it is fair for them to release a specialization that isn't complete and take people's money while they finish the last course... Other than that... So far, this has been a good series of courses in the Tensor Flow in Practice specialization. Although it feels like a slightly watered-down version of Andrew Ng's 5 course deep learning specialization. ", 'Excellent course to take after completing Deep Learning Specialization ', 'Excellent course to get you started in NLP.', 'Great course as always', 'A very good introduction to NLP using Tensorflow. This is definitely the best of the Tensorflow series so far. Excellent pace and interesting short projects. I would highly recommend this course to any beginner on the subject.', 'I was able to very quickly get a grasp of how to approach text data and gained both an understanding of how to represent language-based data as well as how to apply deep learning to do some pretty amazing things. Great course!', 'This course covers the overview of NLP without going into much mathematical detail. In short time span, many things can be learnt from this course, helpful for the beginners.', 'Great course with fun examples! Probably more valuable after completing Deep Learning Specialization/Sequence Models by Andrew Ng (https://www.coursera.org/learn/nlp-sequence-models)', 'Excelente! ', 'Well balanced short and sweet course with practical programming exercises as well as solid theoretical background superbly presented by outstanding tech experts. Looking forward eager for next courses of this series. Thank you very much!', 'Not challenging , very much beginner level course , shouldnt be tagged as intermediate in my opinion', 'Missing the colab files', 'Lightweight course.  Probably about an hour of real content.', 'One star for the ML poetry and one star for the content. The content can be learned in a few hours. Not much more than a simplistic tutorial on some simple problems. Dilutes the value of Coursera specializations.', 'Very lightweight course - not more than an hour of real content.  Extremely disappointed by this.', 'Awesome. Simple explanation with good example', 'The content was quite good. I felt contented after watching all the videos in the course as I wanted some hands on experience in TensorFlow. Just a small suggestion to increase the volume of the videos. I faced a tough time watching videos on the Coursera app in my mobile. Coming to content wise, an excellent course to begin your path in NLP. Looking forward for the last course in the specialization.', 'very objective course . helped me alot']</reviews><reviewers>['By Tryggvi E', 'By Asad K', 'By Renjith B', 'By Abhilash V', 'By Gogul I', 'By Naman B', 'By Mo R', 'By Daniel H', 'By Mostafa G', 'By Anshuman S', 'By Yuanzhe L', 'By Varun N', 'By Christopher G', 'By Sinha, S', 'By Christian L', 'By Juan C B R', 'By Adhikari M T B A', 'By Harshit S', 'By Matheus T M', 'By Craig T', 'By Irina G', 'By Steve H', 'By Leslie L C H', 'By Subhadeep D', 'By satyam s']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 06, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Jul 04, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jul 07, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 06, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019', 'Jul 23, 2019', 'Jun 20, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Jun 22, 2019', 'Jun 21, 2019', 'Jun 20, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>