<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_170</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/core-database</course_url><course_name>Core Database Concepts</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mohamed Sarwat</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course introduces the world of database systems. It provides the foundation that will enable learners to master skills in data modeling and information, as well as extract information using existing database management systems. The following main topics are covered: database design/modeling, data storage and indexing, query processing/optimization, transaction management, database security, and data analytics.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.1</course_rating><course_orgnization>Arizona State University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started//Basic Database Concepts//Data Storage and Indexing//Transactions and Recovery</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome!', 'Introduction to Data and Data Processing', 'Database Management Systems', 'Data Models'], ['Entity Relationship Model (ER)', 'Database Design: ER to Relational Model', 'Assignment Directions: Create a Movie Database', 'Assignment: Create Movie Recommendation Database', 'Relational Data Model', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: Union', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: Difference', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: Cartesian Product', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: Selection', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: Projection', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: Intersection', 'Relational Algebra: Query Language: θ-Join', 'Part 1: SQL Query Language', 'Part 2: SQL Query Language', 'Assignment Directions: SQL Query for Movie Recomendation', 'Assignment Solution: SQL Query for Movie Recommendation'], ['Introduction to Data Storage', 'Alternative File Organization', 'Hash-based Indexes', 'Index Classification'], ['Principles of Transactions: ACID Properties', 'Concurrency Control', 'Lock-Based Concurrency Control', 'Database Recovery']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I was really let down by this first class. The full course sequence is very relevant to my job and planned direction for career growth, so I was quite happy to see the topics on the syllabus.', 'It\'s more an introduction... They teach us a way of writing code, but then are expecting another one when you write your assessment. They tell us that is preferable to work on a Ubuntu machine... No clue about how could we install the desired postgresql version...It smells like "let\'s make some easy money". First two weeks are ok , the two others are just there to introduce some concepts that we just don\'t see how they are used in a practical way ( what do we insert in our code ?! )... ', 'Firstly, The feedback returned on the programming assignment is not helpful. There is no way to find out what you did wrong. Even though my local database was working perfectly on first submission, I had to make 10 more submissions to get only 10/20. I still have no idea why it ended up working.', 'First programming assignment has problems with the review and is not possible to try to get more information from the response given in the page. The forum was not answered for more than a week.', 'Nice introduction to core concepts.', 'Some test assignments are ambiguous. The content in the Week 4 is not complete, one video file is shorter than it has to be. Lack of support from the platform', 'Overall the course syllabus is really good, however the implementation is very disappoinnting:', 'Really amazing learning experience!!', 'The 2 main assignments are very challenging, you will learn a lot.  You cannot complete this course without learning basic postgres.  Big like, great application', 'Great course with good hands-on exercises. Just a little in-depth knowledge should have been provided.', 'Assignments are good. But Assignment description needs to be a bit more clear.', 'I want to say specially about Professor of this course is best fit personality for core data.I love her. ', 'Not for totally noobs. Well designed course if you want to fill spaces in your education.', 'Great course to learn DB concepts. Lectures are well organized and assignments built up difficulty smoothly. At the end of course, student feels familiar with DB/ tables creation and queries.', 'Good introduction to databases. Got a deeper understanding of storage and retrieval, indexing,... Enjoyed the postgres assignments.', 'Really, it is very useful course with professional professor. Thank you so much Coursera. Thank you so much Dr.Mohammed. I appreciate all what you did. I will be happy if you recommend some books for students in DBMS.', 'It is a great resource to enhance your fundamentals.', 'The quizzes could be more difficult, and more programming assignments would be appreciated.', 'the evaluations of the practice exercises are not clear.', 'Very nice course. I liked the programming assignement. I think the subject matter of the 4th week was covered a bit superficially.', "There's an incomplete video in the last section (locking). Also some weeks required much less time. ", 'The concepts covered in the course were explained well.', 'The course is good for like people who are aleady familiar with a bit of SQL and have knowledge of  software that handles SQL queries. Other than that it would be great if each explenation was followed by more accurate examples of how things happen.  Thank you for your time that you took for preparing this.', 'The course is great but the assignment should be more descriptive.', '讲师覆盖了重要的数据库概念，但是有些地方解释地并不是很清楚，有点读ppt的感觉，可能是缺乏讲课经验吧。']</reviews><reviewers>['By David B', 'By Guillaume R', 'By Alireza T', 'By Manuel G L C', 'By Niall', 'By Maxim Z', 'By Max S', 'By Syed F H', 'By Mark D S S', 'By Aditya P', 'By Naveen K J', 'By Ghullam M', 'By Ilya B', 'By ANNA B', 'By Joke D', 'By Hamzah A S S A ', 'By Harish K T', 'By Borys K', 'By Jose E Q I', 'By Miltiadis S', 'By Pablo A', 'By Laura B', 'By Plamen M', 'By Hamza J', 'By Zhonghua Q']</reviewers><review_date>['May 05, 2019', 'May 31, 2018', 'Jul 17, 2018', 'Jul 07, 2018', 'Mar 19, 2019', 'Nov 03, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Apr 05, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Aug 23, 2018', 'Jun 24, 2018', 'Apr 20, 2019', 'Sep 15, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Oct 26, 2018', 'Nov 01, 2018', 'Aug 05, 2018', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'Jun 01, 2019', 'Jul 07, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2019']</review_date></doc>