<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_95</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-programming</course_url><course_name>Python Programming Essentials</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Scott Rixner</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce you to the wonderful world of Python programming!  We'll learn about the essential elements of programming and how to construct basic Python programs. We will cover expressions, variables, functions, logic, and conditionals, which are foundational concepts in computer programming. We will also teach you how to use Python modules, which enable you to benefit from the vast array of functionality that is already a part of the Python language. These concepts and skills will help you to begin to think like a computer programmer and to understand how to go about writing Python programs.

By the end of the course, you will be able to write short Python programs that are able to accomplish real, practical tasks. This course is the foundation for building expertise in Python programming. As the first course in a specialization, it provides the necessary building blocks for you to succeed at learning to write more complex Python programs.

This course uses Python 3.  While many Python programs continue to use Python 2, Python 3 is the future of the Python programming language. This first course will use a Python 3 version of the CodeSkulptor development environment, which is specifically designed to help beginning programmers learn quickly.  CodeSkulptor runs within any modern web browser and does not require you to install any software, allowing you to start writing and running small programs immediately.  In the later courses in this specialization,  we will help you to move to more sophisticated desktop development environments.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Codeskulptor//Python Syntax And Semantics//Python Programming//Debugging</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Python as a Calculator//Functions//Logic and Conditionals//Python Modules</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome!', 'Course Overview', 'Hello, world!', 'Python Development Environments', 'Numbers', 'Simple Expressions', 'Compound Expressions', 'Variables and Assignment', 'Handling Errors in Python'], ['What is a Function?', 'Calling Functions', 'Defining Functions', 'Local Variables', 'Understanding Function Evaluation', 'Using Print and Return in Functions'], ['Boolean Logic', 'Logical Expressions', 'Comparisons', 'Conditionals', 'More Conditionals', 'Using Python Documentation', 'Following Coding Standards'], ['Python Modules', 'The Datetime Module', 'Coding the Practice Project - Part 1', 'Coding the Practice Project - Part 2', 'RPSLS Video', 'Project Video']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This was a very helpful introduction into Python programming.  I have been working with Stata and R for a while, but I think this course helped review basic good practices while scripting.', 'I liked this course very much. The lessons were easy to follow and the teachers engaging. Will also try their other complementary Python specialisation, Fundamentals of Computing.', 'Awesome Python trainings which helped me in my work!', 'Awesome teaching especially the course was designed in such a way that after the completion of the course the student can definitely feel confident about the particular course he learned .', 'Good introduction to the basics of Python scripting. Step by step explanations and exercises/quizzes help better solidify new concepts learnt. ', 'Very good for start learning Python!', 'Great', 'Very good course, instructor presented it well.', 'Very well done', "Helpful course for learning the basics. Instructors challenge you to think beyond instilling you with coding knowledge. The instructors complement each other's contributions, and both have good (if nerdy, but what do you expect?!) senses of humor. The assessments are challenging and require you to apply what you have learned. If I could give this six stars, I surely would!", 'I advise anyone who wants to learn Python and is new to "coding" to get this course, it has been useful for me, thanks to all instructors.', 'A great course with lots of exercises that helps deepen your understanding of the information. ', 'The tutors were amazing! Guided very nicely from the basics to advanced. Tips given at the end of each week were very helpful.. Only the assessment section needs some improvement where sometimes the correct response was evaluated incorrect. ', 'The instructors are quite articulate, and the course is very well organized. Recommended for absolute beginners.  ', 'This course is very good for learning Python fundamentals.', 'Very clear instruction. Course provides great resources that facilitate success.', 'wonderful class!! i learn it well', 'This course is very good to know the basics and the assignments are good to test us practically. Overall a good course for a beginner who is looking for Python.', 'Very Good The Course', 'This course is perfect for a beginner.I was new but I have got a lot of knowledge.Thanks you so much Rice university and Joe and Warren :)', 'very good', 'Enjoyed working on the course. Looking forward to the next course in the specialization', 'Excellent course', 'Very Good Course and Very useful course.', 'It is simple and strong content as well as both of the constructor is very good']</reviews><reviewers>['By Samuel R', 'By Catalin R C', 'By Si Y L', 'By Dachepally V', 'By Joanne H P C ', 'By Bunke A', 'By lincoln', 'By 林晉宇', 'By Giuseppe D M', 'By Mark J S', 'By Seyfullali C İ', 'By Anders S A', 'By Akshay S', 'By Soroosh A', 'By Anjali G', 'By Stefan Y', 'By KUAN H C', 'By Vivek V A', 'By Jorge O', 'By Ramazan G', 'By Akshay K', 'By Rakshit K', 'By Chen L', 'By Kottha s', 'By MarwaAllam']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 25, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2018', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Jan 17, 2019', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019']</review_date></doc>