<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_27</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/convolutional-neural-networks-tensorflow</course_url><course_name>Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Laurence Moroney</course_instructor><course_introduction>If you are a software developer who wants to build scalable AI-powered algorithms, you need to understand how to use the tools to build them. This course is part of the upcoming Machine Learning in Tensorflow Specialization and will teach you best practices for using TensorFlow, a popular open-source framework for machine learning.

In Course 2 of the deeplearning.ai TensorFlow Specialization, you will learn advanced techniques to improve the computer vision model you built in Course 1. You will explore how to work with real-world images in different shapes and sizes, visualize the journey of an image through convolutions to understand how a computer “sees” information, plot loss and accuracy, and explore strategies to prevent overfitting, including augmentation and dropout. Finally, Course 2 will introduce you to transfer learning and how learned features can be extracted from models. 

The Machine Learning course and Deep Learning Specialization from Andrew Ng teach the most important and foundational principles of Machine Learning and Deep Learning. This new deeplearning.ai TensorFlow Specialization teaches you how to use TensorFlow to implement those principles so that you can start building and applying scalable models to real-world problems. To develop a deeper understanding of how neural networks work, we recommend that you take the Deep Learning Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Inductive Transfer//Augmentation//Dropouts//Machine Learning//Tensorflow</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>deeplearning.ai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Exploring a Larger Dataset//Augmentation: A technique to avoid overfitting//Transfer Learning//Multiclass Classifications</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction, A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Training with the cats vs. dogs dataset', 'Working through the notebook', 'Fixing through cropping', 'Visualizing the effect of the convolutions', 'Looking at accuracy and loss', 'Week 1 Wrap up'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Introducing augmentation', 'Coding augmentation with ImageDataGenerator', 'Demonstrating overfitting in cats vs. dogs', 'Adding augmentation to cats vs. dogs', 'Exploring augmentation with horses vs. humans', 'Week 2 Wrap up'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Understanding transfer learning: the concepts', 'Coding transfer learning from the inception mode', 'Coding your own model with transferred features', 'Exploring dropouts', 'Exploring Transfer Learning with Inception', 'Week 3 Wrap up'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Moving from binary to multi-class classification', 'Explore multi-class with Rock Paper Scissors dataset', 'Train a classifier with Rock Paper Scissors', 'Test the Rock Paper Scissors classifier', 'A conversation with Andrew Ng']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course significantly lacks depth. The topic is covered at a very high-level and represents only a lightweight introduction.  You will not gain any insights into the challenges that someone might face using CNNs on Tensorflow in a real-world scenario.', 'You may look at it as a set of use-cases on how to work with particular types of .ipynb notebooks or how to structure your code, but, unfortunately, lectures are useless and tasks are mechanical rather than challenging. ', "This is the second course of the specialization and still I feel like I haven't been introduced to anything beyond the free tutorials available on tensorflow website. So far the specialization has also been only focused on the keras api of tensorflow which makes me feel that perhaps the name of this specialization has been poorly chosen (perhaps it should be 'Keras in Practice Specialization'). On the positive side, the instructor is eloquent and the learning material is presented in a well and orderly fashion (ignoring some minor cases of redundancy in notebooks; basically copy pasting the whole notebook several times just to introduce a few lines of new code).   ", 'Excellent material superbly presented by world-class experts.', "This is pretty simple. This doesn't give an idea of the real use of keras. also there is no programming assignments.", 'I think I knew more about CNN before this course. ', 'this course is very useful for beginners', "It is a great intro but a very limited course. Short videos and a small number of examples, for example, Transfer learning could be more in-depth. Week 4 really made a few obvious changes in the code. I do think it's great material, but all of it could be made into a 2-week course instead. Thanks for your efforts.", "Great Course! Can't wait for part 3!", "It's a perfect course to learn TensorFlow for CNN, and it is extremely easy to understand. Thank you very much!", 'Many thanks to Andrew Ng and team for the great balance of theoretical background, practical references and hands-on programming exercises. ', 'I enjoyed doing this course on CNN in Tensorflow. Thanks for the lectures by Laurence Moroney. And it is always a pleasure to hear Andrew Ng explain even difficult concepts in simple terms. He is one of my favorite teachers online, and reading about his ML course in a New York Times article back in 2012 or 2013 made me completely change my career direction and motivated me to eventually get into cloud and Big Data! And thanks also for the exercises on codelab. That makes it really convenient to learn and experiment with Machine Learning and Deep Learning.  ', 'Consize notebooks. Clear explanations', 'A patient and coherent introduction.  At the end, you have good working code you can use elsewhere.  Remarkably, the primary lecturer, Laurence Moroney, responds fairly quickly to posts in  the forum.', 'Easy to follow and very good explanations ', 'In the workbook section, the question colab notebook opens up the answer notebook, please rectify the same.', "Great course! I can't wait to going further and deeper. Thanks", 'Clear, concise, well designed', 'Well balanced short and sweet course with practical programming exercises as well as solid theoretical background superbly presented by outstanding tech experts. Looking forward eager for next courses of this series. Thank you very much!', 'Very brief and precisely taught implementing various techniques in Convolution Neural Networks by using Tensorflow. Quite time saving and a good one to boost your skills.', "It's an amazing course, the video lectures are fruitful and the contents of the courses are well designed, the instructor is talented and his explanations are extremely helpful, it's one of the best courses taught on Tensorflow!", "I finally feel confident that I understand the basics of Convolutional neural nets and what function the various layers serve. It took a Polymath computer engineer/science fiction writer to finally break that mental block and get through to me. Take this class you won't regret it.", "It's a great course. I enjoyed it!", 'great', 'got hands on , many stuff of cnn , great content. Thank you team']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nick A', 'By Амаль И', 'By Asad K', 'By Romilly C', 'By jbene m', 'By Irina G', 'By Eslam G', 'By Ostap O', 'By Oliver M', 'By Hoang N M T', 'By Ivelin I', 'By Heman K', 'By Dmitry S', 'By Charlie M', 'By Egon S', 'By Antoreep J', 'By Raffaele G', 'By Zeev S', 'By Adhikari M T B A', 'By Subhadeep D', 'By Mo R', 'By James V', 'By Dora M B', 'By NITESH N', 'By kaushal']</reviewers><review_date>['May 08, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Jul 04, 2019', 'May 15, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Jul 19, 2019', 'Jun 27, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'May 04, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'May 04, 2019', 'May 03, 2019', 'May 01, 2019', 'Apr 24, 2019', 'Apr 21, 2019', 'May 10, 2019', 'May 14, 2019', 'Jun 16, 2019', 'May 20, 2019', 'May 27, 2019', 'Aug 28, 2019', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2019']</review_date></doc>