<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_425</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/intermediate-programming-capstone</course_url><course_name>Capstone: Analyzing (Social) Network Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Christine Alvarado</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this capstone project we’ll combine  all of the skills from all four specialization courses to do something really fun: analyze social networks!  

The opportunities for learning are practically endless in a social network.  Who are the “influential” members of the network?  What are the sub-communities in the network?   Who is connected to whom, and by how many links?   These are just some of the questions you can explore in this project.

We will provide you with a real-world data set and some infrastructure for getting started, as well as some warm up tasks and basic project requirements, but then it’ll be up to you where you want to take the project.  If you’re running short on ideas, we’ll have several suggested directions that can help get your creativity and imagination going.  Finally, to integrate the skills you acquired in course 4 (and to show off your project!) you will be asked to create a video showcase of your final product.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction and Warm up//Project Definition and Scope//Capstone Implementation: Mini-project//Capstone Implementation: Full project checkpoint//Capstone Implementation: Full project final deadline//Capstone oral report</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome and Course Introduction', 'Capstone Project Exemplar', 'Project overview and timeline', 'Introduction to (some) social network data', 'Representing social network data as a graph', 'Warm up algorithm 1: Extracting egonets', 'Warm up algorithm 2: Strongly Connected Components', 'Warm up algorithm 2: Strongly connected components, part 2'], ['Week 2 introduction', 'Project idea: information flow in a social network', 'Project idea: broadcasting to a Twitter network, part 1', 'Project idea: broadcasting to a Twitter network, part 2', 'Project idea: detecting communities', 'Analyzing algorithms before implementing'], ['Week 3 introduction', 'Overview of report'], ['Week 4 introduction'], ['Week 5 introduction', 'Peer review best practices'], ['Week 6 introduction', 'Demo presentation', 'End of Specialization message']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 19 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I really like the fact that we get to decide the capstone and we get to showcase our project.', 'This is basically a do-it-yourself project...you can be lazy, not research and do the bare minimum, or you can take it seriously, read papers and search online and in books if you so please and end up with a beautiful project that is truly of your design, with algorithms that would have seemed impossible before the project but that you now see are not at all that hard and quite enlightening. If you working hard and not do things with a handicap, you can do something amazing wit this guidance!', 'The course will be learned a lot if you are fresh to Java', "Definitely one of the best courses I've had the chance to take on Coursera! ", 'great course I learned lot things thank you for you efforts . ', '  Good course!  ', 'Great presentation of data structures.', 'Good course, really enjoyed the project.', 'I think this is a great specialization to learn more about Java programming and associated technologies such as the Eclipse IDE and Unit Testing. ', 'It was a challenge for me and really useful project! ', 'very good! This project is very helpful!', 'Cannot express how grateful i am to this course series. Will recommend to anyone who has needs!', '.', 'Thank you so much for having this on Coursera. I enjoyed the entire process, and I am very thankful for the course instructors. Great supplementation to my degree.', None, None, 'This was a nice closure to the specialization, but a little too complicated to the point where there were almost no students around to get feedback from or give to.', "It's okay.  I would like to learn something besides graphs which I don't find interesting.  I thought this course was on data structures but it seems to be mostly on graphs which are only one data structure."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Suraj S', 'By Roy G C', 'By 李紹弘', 'By Solange G U', 'By Taoufiq', 'By Gábor C', 'By Wolfgang A', 'By Kudakwashe G', 'By Sudharaka P', 'By Aharon S', 'By Feilin J', 'By Chessie R', 'By Osama S', 'By Noah D G', 'By Lesly A', 'By abhijit p k', 'By Leonel S A S', 'By Leah S']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 07, 2016', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Dec 29, 2017', 'Jul 28, 2017', 'Jul 25, 2016', 'Jan 18, 2017', 'Apr 30, 2016', 'Jun 16, 2016', 'May 25, 2017', 'Apr 10, 2016', 'Jul 05, 2017', 'Aug 28, 2016', 'Jul 28, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2017', 'Apr 04, 2017', 'Apr 10, 2017', 'May 10, 2018']</review_date></doc>