<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_199</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/strategic-business-analytics</course_url><course_name>Foundations of strategic business analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Nicolas Glady </course_instructor><course_introduction>Who is this course for?  
This course is designed for students, business analysts, and data scientists who want to apply statistical knowledge and techniques to business contexts. For example, it may be suited to experienced statisticians, analysts, engineers who want to move more into a business role. 

You will find this course exciting and rewarding if you already have a background in statistics, can use R or another programming language and are familiar with databases and data analysis techniques such as regression, classification, and clustering.
However, it contains a number of recitals and R Studio tutorials which will consolidate your competences, enable you to play more freely with data and explore new features and statistical functions in R.

With this course, you’ll have a first overview on Strategic Business Analytics topics. We’ll discuss a wide variety of applications of Business Analytics. From Marketing to Supply Chain or Credit Scoring and HR Analytics, etc. We’ll cover many different data analytics techniques, each time explaining how to be relevant for your business.

We’ll pay special attention to how you can produce convincing, actionable, and efficient insights. We'll also present you with different data analytics tools to be applied to different types of issues.
By doing so, we’ll help you develop four sets of skills needed to leverage value from data: Analytics, IT, Business and Communication. 

By the end of this MOOC, you should be able to approach a business issue using Analytics by (1) qualifying the issue at hand in quantitative terms, (2) conducting relevant data analyses, and (3) presenting your conclusions and recommendations in a business-oriented, actionable and efficient way.

Prerequisites : 1/ Be able to use R or to program 2/ To know the fundamentals of databases, data analysis (regression, classification, clustering)

We give credit to Pauline Glikman, Albane Gaubert, Elias Abou Khalil-Lanvin (Students at ESSEC BUSINESS SCHOOL) for their contribution to this course design.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Business Analytics//R Programming//Presentation</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>ESSEC Business School</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Strategic Business Analytics//Finding groups within Data//Factors leading to events//Predictions and Forecasting//Recommendation production and prioritization</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the course', 'Becoming a Business Analytics expert', 'Why? It is all about value not data', 'How to leverage data for value - from data to insight'], ['Introduction: what’s the point of finding groups within data?', 'Basic clustering using ad-hoc techniques: the example of product management', "Identifying groups within data: what's the intuition behind clustering? The example of HR Analytics", 'Introduction to Customer Segmentation', 'Presentation of Pauline Glikman', 'Recital M2 - SKU example', 'Recital M2 - HR example', 'Recital M2 - Telecom example', 'Wrap-up:  identifying groups within data'], ['Understanding causes and consequences: introduction', 'Why use Business Analytics to understand the relationship between causes and consequences', 'Understanding what distinguishes two categories', 'Beyond the regression estimates: reporting effects in a visual way', 'Recital M3 - Credit score example', 'Recital M3 - HR example', 'Wrap-up: identifying causes to effects'], ['Predictions &amp; Forecasting: introduction', 'Predicting events: sales, defaults, risks, churn, etc.', 'Using classification and regression techniques to forecast', 'Predicting when an event will happen with survival analysis', 'Introduction to time series and seasonality', 'Recital M4 - Credit Score', 'Recital M4 - HR example', 'Recital M4 - Predictive maintenance example', 'Recital M4 - Chocolate Sales example', 'Wrap-up: forecasting events'], ['Reporting your results: introduction', "It's all about the story", 'One slide / One idea', 'One picture is worth a thousand words', 'Recital M5 - How to present your findings', 'Wrap-up: reporting your results']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Fantastic course. Focused on real life applications.', None, 'Good contents &amp; course support, looking for more', 'Very challenging for a novice in data science and R programming.', 'Very helpful course from career perspective.', None, "A truly fabulous MOOC.  Granted you have to be proficient in R and have an understanding of business practices for maximum benefit but it is well worth gaining such skills just to take this course - you won't regret it.", "Some of the recitals are a little off and glaze over essential details. But, as a pragmatic and practical introduction to advanced techniques in R, I've not come across a better course. Very highly recommended.", 'Its OK', 'Great course which uses R to have you do classification, linear and logistic regression to address business topics.', "I enjoyed this class, but the content feels amateurish. One major detracting factor is grading of the exams- a complete waste of time where there are multiple examples of contradictory slides to the quiz questions. The quizes often ask for information that is beyond the scope of the lectures and steadily becomes a process of just retaking exams until you get a 100%. I don't think the quizes reinforced the material in the lecture but actually took away from the class. This class was at it's best during the recitals, where I actually got to understand the great strategies used in the videos. ", 'Prof. Glady is an excellent lecturer.  The course is very well produced, and the recitals were a great introduction to using code to solve business questions.', "This course does well to balance its focus on strategy and analytics. The analytics aren't overly in-depth, allowing for less technical individuals to reap benefits from the course. I highly recommend this course to consultants and business analysts. ", 'This course is excellent when it provides the citations very fit to theory. And I learned it in well organized structure of knowledge. Thank Prof. Glady and his team very much.', 'Very good!', 'The better course I have ever realized on Coursera. Theorycally strong and truely applicable. ', 'Amazing ', 'V', 'Fantastic examples of applied data analysis', 'Very useful, practical anda easy to follow.', None, '\n', 'Wonderful course.', 'Fantastic course. THis allow you to become an strategic business analytics consultant', "it's address my current problem in my work"]</reviews><reviewers>['By Ponciano R', 'By Affum m s J ', 'By Purushottam Y', 'By Sébastien G', 'By Sumit J', 'By Ricardo M', 'By Gavin C', 'By Paul N', 'By Durga B P', 'By Barnaby L', 'By Edward H', 'By Blaine B', 'By Gordon S', 'By pham m t', 'By Carlos E B A', 'By Mijail K', 'By Pedro M P', 'By Nikos L', 'By Brad G', 'By Man L', 'By Seshadri S K', 'By ELINGUI P U', 'By William K', 'By Antonio P L', 'By Fahad A']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 20, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Apr 27, 2017', 'Nov 24, 2015', 'Jul 30, 2017', 'Aug 15, 2016', 'Apr 02, 2016', 'Jan 21, 2016', 'Sep 28, 2017', 'Jun 28, 2016', 'Oct 13, 2015', 'May 08, 2016', 'Jan 07, 2016', 'Oct 27, 2015', 'Dec 07, 2017', 'Sep 30, 2015', 'Jan 24, 2017', 'Dec 05, 2015', 'Jul 11, 2016', 'Dec 02, 2015', 'Sep 20, 2015', 'Apr 21, 2018']</review_date></doc>