<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_94</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/regression-models</course_url><course_name>Regression Models</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian Caffo, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Linear models, as their name implies, relates an outcome to a set of predictors of interest using linear assumptions.  Regression models, a subset of linear models, are the most important statistical analysis tool in a data scientist’s toolkit. This course covers regression analysis, least squares and inference using regression models. Special cases of the regression model, ANOVA and ANCOVA will be covered as well. Analysis of residuals and variability will be investigated. The course will cover modern thinking on model selection and novel uses of regression models including scatterplot smoothing.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Model Selection//Generalized Linear Model//Linear Regression//Regression Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1: Least Squares and Linear Regression//Week 2: Linear Regression &amp; Multivariable Regression//Week 3: Multivariable Regression, Residuals, &amp; Diagnostics//Week 4: Logistic Regression and Poisson Regression</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Regression', 'Introduction: Basic Least Squares', "Technical Details (Skip if you'd like)", 'Introductory Data Example', 'Notation and Background', 'Linear Least Squares', 'Linear Least Squares Coding Example', "Technical Details (Skip if you'd like)", 'Regression to the Mean'], ['Statistical Linear Regression Models', 'Interpreting Coefficients', 'Linear Regression for Prediction', 'Residuals', 'Residuals, Coding Example', 'Residual Variance', 'Inference in Regression', 'Coding Example', 'Prediction', 'Really, really quick intro to knitr'], ['Multivariable Regression part I', 'Multivariable Regression part II', 'Multivariable Regression Continued', 'Multivariable Regression Examples part I', 'Multivariable Regression Examples part II', 'Multivariable Regression Examples part III', 'Multivariable Regression Examples part IV', 'Adjustment Examples', 'Residuals and Diagnostics part I', 'Residuals and Diagnostics part II', 'Residuals and Diagnostics part III', 'Model Selection part I', 'Model Selection part II', 'Model Selection part III'], ['GLMs', 'Logistic Regression part I', 'Logistic Regression part II', 'Logistic Regression part III', 'Poisson Regression part I', 'Poisson Regression part II', 'Hodgepodge']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['If you thought that the previous course (Statistical Inference) with Brian Caffo was a horrible experience -- think twice and get ready for Regression Models. It is way worse. Imagine an instructor starting his explanation by showing you some (rather involved) formula and immediately jumping to the discussion of  the various terms without actually telling you clearly what this formula is for and how to use it. Then you will get a pretty good idea about the instructor for this course. He is a horrible teacher, who clearly does not understand what teaching is and how it should be done properly. Total waste of time.', 'Really bad. Worst of the whole Data Science spezialization. Bored me to death. Lecture had nothing to do with the quizzes, quizzes had nothing to do with the final assignment, final assignment had nothing to do with the lectures. Fight through it, there is light at the end of the tunnel.', "This is the worst course in the series. Caffo does a terrible job at explaining regression, the final assignment requirements aren't properly addressed, and it appears they didn't quite spend time on how to make it all work (2 pages to test out different regression models, make an inference, and everything else is absurd). I highly recommend avoid this course, and instead go through the R guide on linear regression; in the end, I used those to get through this course.", "Just like the previous course in the specialization path (Statistical Inference) the course delves into some relevant topics however it doesn't feel as properly structured. While on the first week the lectures seem to try to give a basic and comprehensible learning of linear regression, once we start into the more advanced topics it gets confusing.", 'One video is wrongly edited, half of it is repeated. The instructor gives too much information and is difficult to follow, some information is even trivial.', "Personally, I am not a fan of this professor. He over-explains all of the topics, just to tell you at the end of the lecture that you don't need to know the specifics and can do it all with one function. He is very unengaging, difficult to follow, and rushes through lectures. And finally, HE BLOCKS THE SLIDES WITH HIS HEAD SO YOU CAN'T SEE THE NOTES. I feel like out of all the professors in this specialization course, there were so many others who could have taught the material better, especially since this is probably the most important course of the entire specialization. I feel like I only began to understand the material once I finished the course project, and even then I have no idea how regression models work.", 'This module was the maximum. I learned how powerful the use of Regression Models techniques in Data Science analysis is. I thank Professor Brian Caffo for sharing his knowledge with us. Thank you!', 'Honestly the materials of this course are really confusing. So many focus on the mathematical value instead of real examples and scenarios to use the concepts reached. Also it would benefit if there was a clear message coming through, like Machine Learning course where things follow a order.', 'Very math heavy and not super useful for psychology students. ', "I was optimistic about this class because it started out fixing some of the pedagogical mistakes the professor made in Statistical Inference, but by the time we got to week 3, it was pretty clear that the course was trying to accomplish too much in 4 weeks, and instead of focusing on the most important parts of regression and making sure they were taught well and understood clearly, I feel the course tried to do far too much.  The only reason I gave it two stars instead of one star was the course project was relatable - choosing the best transmission for maximizing mpg is a real-world problem that I can (and did) have a discussion with my mother about.  Too many assignments are about something completely inane, like guinea pig teeth or flower petals.  If you're going to inspire students to learn the material, the examples (and data) must be relatable to them.", 'very good practical approach, with good theoretical coverage of most important principles of regression', 'Great course, well taught with very useful examples', 'very good course', 'Amazing course ! finally I have learned how to implement regression in real world analysis', 'Excellent but difficult course. Complex concepts are well presented but it still requires many hours of studying. The topics taught are essential to anyone working or aspiring to work in the field of Data Science.', 'Challenging but highly rewarding course. Prof. Caffo does an excellent job presenting the material in a way that does not require previous background or expertise. The lectures were thorough and the Swirl exercises were very useful. I think the best part of this class is that it truly highlights how powerful and important regression is.', 'The course was incredible. You can learn a lot of skills about regression models and even more. It would be incredible if the course could have more examples or little excercises.', 'Nice outline for regression models.', 'Great Course well designed ', 'A deep review on linear, logistic and regression models. The critical tool for modelling.', 'Awesome class! Highly recommended.', 'Great course for beginners, but definitely not for people with no mathematical background!', 'good course, nice teaching!', 'So far so good; key concepts explained in detail.', 'Excellent course. Thank you Brian, Jeff and Roger.']</reviews><reviewers>['By ALEXEY P', 'By Roman', 'By George C', 'By Ricardo M', 'By Johnny C', 'By Nicholas A', 'By Claudio F S', 'By Joana P', 'By cleoag1', 'By Jeffrey G', 'By André C L', 'By David R', 'By Antonio V', 'By sneha', 'By João F', 'By Matthew S', 'By Yadder A G', 'By Vibhutesh K S', 'By Sanjeev  K', 'By Bruno R d C S', 'By Seyedeh M M', 'By Georgios P', 'By Eric Y', 'By Jose F V G', 'By Javier E S']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 18, 2017', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Apr 30, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2018', 'Sep 25, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2017', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Jan 26, 2018', 'Oct 29, 2017', 'Oct 18, 2017', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Jul 16, 2018']</review_date></doc>