<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_266</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/wharton-business-financial-modeling-capstone</course_url><course_name>Wharton Business and Financial Modeling Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Richard Lambert</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this Capstone you will recommend a business strategy based on a data model you’ve constructed. Using a data set designed by Wharton Research Data Services (WRDS), you will implement quantitative models in spreadsheets to identify the best opportunities for success and minimizing risk. Using your newly acquired decision-making skills, you will structure a decision and present this course of action in a professional quality PowerPoint presentation which includes both data and data analysis from your quantitative models.

Wharton Research Data Services (WRDS) is the leading data research platform and business intelligence tool for over 30,000 corporate, academic, government and nonprofit clients in 33 countries. WRDS provides the user with one location to access over 200 terabytes of data across multiple disciplines including Accounting, Banking, Economics, ESG, Finance, Insurance, Marketing, and Statistics.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Summary Statistics//Financial Modeling//Diversification (Finance)//Investment</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started//Steps 1 and 2: Yahoo Finance//Step 3: Creating an optimal risky portfolio on the efficient frontier//Step 4: Optional exercise using CAPM tables//Step 5: Creating Your Asset Allocation &amp; Final Presentation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Project Description - Read me first!', 'Project Prompt', 'Historical Stock Data'], ['Definition and Uses of Models, Common Functions (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'How Models are Used in Practice (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Mathematical Functions (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Navigating a Spreadsheet and Crafting Formulas (Introduction to Spreadsheets)', 'How To Build an Optimization Model: Hudson Readers Ad Campaign (Modeling Risk and Realities)', 'Data and Visualization: Graphical Representation (Modeling Risk and Realities)'], ['Introducton to Linear Models and Optimization (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Present and Future Value (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Optimization (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Linear Programming (incl. Solver) (Introduction to Spreadsheets)', 'Optimizing with Solver, and Alternative Data Inputs (Modeling Risk and Realities)', 'Adding Risk: Managing Investments at Epsilon Delta Capital (Modeling Risk and Realities)', 'Using Scenarios for Optimizing Under High Uncertainty, Sensitivity Analysis and Efficient Frontier (Modeling Risk and Realities)'], ['Introduction to Regression Models (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Use of Regression Models (Fundamentals of Quantitative Modeling)', 'Correlation and Regression (Introduction to Spreadsheets)'], ['VBTLX and VFIAX Monthly Returns']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course lacks compatibility with the rest of the Specialization. It is tremendously hard and there is no orientation or guidance. Thanks to the support of some colleagues I might be able to finish it. But I ask myself if the extra work was really worthy.', 'This course is very demanding and require high level of concentration with total attention to be able to complete the capstone assignments and project but will deliver practical capability in financial analysis for investment purposes.', 'Excellent course and very good approach for a project to evaluate the learning of the other modules. This is probably the best course of the specialization, as is not only a test, but a simulation of a real life application to help make clients undestand the importance of diversification in portfolio management. ', 'The course was good, but lack of support when I needed. My questions were not answered and had to find out by myself wasting a lot of time.', 'Enjoyed the course thoroughly', 'Glorious. ', 'This is a very helpful course which help me apply what I learnt into practice.', 'This is much more challenging than the previous courses! ', 'best course in the specialization', 'Excellent capstone to review and put in practice all the learned in the past courses. Excellent course to be a invesment manager.', 'This context of this capstone was great. I was able to learn about finance and apply the tools that I learned in preceding courses to complete this project successfully.', 'Great Overall Specialization', 'Much higher quality than the previous courses in this specialization.', 'Really a great set of courses to understand and apply models to many different scenarios.  I was able to use the skills I learned right away in my profession.  Would definitely recommend.', 'Go to core points in Financial Modeling and great knowledge to apply into reality.', 'Brilliant!', 'Good course that helps understand different considerations to take into account when creating models. Well laid out Capstone project to help understand portfolio diversification and Optimal Portfolio.', '课程设置的很好，引导学生自主从公开信息渠道获取信息，并根据现代金融理论，以Sharpe ratio最大化构建自己的资产组合。最后的大作业可以锻炼学生的综合能力，包括数据、论点、论据的组织，展示材料的制作。另外，审阅其他同学的作业有助于帮助整理自己的知识点。非常感谢制作方和老师用心的制作，感谢审阅同学的辛勤劳动！', 'Great lesson of managing a portfolio. Sufficient education of good risk management techniques. The process was very intuitive and much of fun. Again I feel great to have taken it.', 'Very good introductory course in finance. The skills and resources provided in this course are very helpful to people working in technical field. The instructors were did were outstanding in explaining the course material. I learnt a lot from all the courses and always looked forward to the next course.', 'Excellent course that covers a variety of topics in risk and modelling. The capstone project was also key in understanding and presenting the risk/return relationship from a portfolio investment point of view.', 'Its a great course on building portfolios, portfolio optimization and concepts around managing risk while doing so. There is extensive use of excel in practicing above concepts and applying it in real life scenarios which I really liked about it.   ', 'Best course so far', 'This was a great opportunity to get practical experience about calculating the optimal risky portfolio as well as understanding the importance of Portfolio Diversification.', 'Greate Course so Far, A lot Fininance.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Micael D J', 'By Sola O', 'By Jesus O', 'By Filippo L', 'By Kudakwashe M', 'By David M R', 'By SIYUAN Y', 'By Zhongyuan Z', 'By Alessandro L', 'By Jose J E F', 'By Sutej', 'By Jordi V', 'By Pingchuan M', 'By Roman J T', 'By Linh P', 'By Khang V', 'By Anshul V', 'By nil', 'By Zacharias L', 'By Jay B', 'By Gerard E', 'By Rahul', 'By ema', 'By Galib H K', 'By Herson N  M']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 06, 2018', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Dec 06, 2018', 'Jan 13, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2016', 'Jan 24, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2017', 'Sep 26, 2016', 'Sep 08, 2016', 'Sep 12, 2016', 'Nov 02, 2017', 'Feb 13, 2017', 'Aug 07, 2017', 'Jan 09, 2018', 'Sep 12, 2017', 'Apr 21, 2018', 'May 05, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2017', 'Sep 04, 2016']</review_date></doc>