<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_300</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/intelligent-machining</course_url><course_name>Intelligent Machining</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Rahul Rai</course_instructor><course_introduction>Manufacturers are increasingly utilizing machine tools that are self-aware – they perceive their own states and the state of the surrounding environment – and are able to make decisions related to machine activity processes. This is called intelligent machining, and through this course students will receive a primer on its background, tools and related terminology. 

Learn how the integration of smart sensors and controls are helping to improve productivity. You’ll be exposed to various sensors and sensing techniques, process control strategies, and open architecture systems that can be leveraged to enable intelligent machining. This course will prepare you to contribute to the implementation of intelligent machining projects. 

Main concepts of this course will be delivered through lectures, readings, discussions and various videos. 

This is the fifth course in the Digital Manufacturing &amp; Design Technology specialization that explores the many facets of manufacturing’s “Fourth Revolution,”  aka Industry 4.0, and features a culminating project involving creation of a roadmap to achieve a self-established DMD-related professional goal.

To learn more about the Digital Manufacturing and Design Technology specialization, please watch the overview video by copying and pasting the following link into your web browser: https://youtu.be/wETK1O9c-CA</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Physical Science and Engineering.Mechanical Engineering</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Intelligent Machining //Sensors and Sensing Techniques//Process Control Strategies//Future Directions in Advanced Machining</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Intelligent Machining', 'Machining Basics', 'The Evolution of Intelligent Machining', 'Components of Intelligent Machining'], ['Sensors', 'Signal Processing', 'Transforming Data into Information', 'Practical Uses of Machine Learning'], ['Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC)', 'Closed Loop Process Control Systems', 'Introduction to Adaptive Control', 'Commercially Available Software'], ['Intelligent Machining and the Future', 'Tech Talk on Metrology', 'Your 4.0 Roadmap to Success']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 6 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['It is needed to improve the audio cause there are some parts that are no easy to understand due of this.', 'good  experience  withe intelligent machining ', 'Good work ', 'very beneficial for mechanical engineers', '  Good  ', 'Great course with good insights on industry 4.0 and the methods of implementation in our current industries. Also, erudite professors who explain the concepts lucidly are really worth mentioning.', 'this course has been an amazing journey, it has given me a perspective of how automation and digital manufacturing would become the ultimate form of production. ', 'The well-designed course allow to get the common view to Intelligent Machining.', 'AMAZING COURSE', 'I recommend this couse to everybody who wants to learn more about intelligent machining and sensors in the industry.', None, 'I liked the course', 'Great course about Intelligent Machining! A must for technicians and mechanical or industrial engineers', 'Amazing experience and intellectual learning', 'thank you for the course', 'thanks', 'It was a great course for anyone who wants to know generally about Intelligent Machine but just need a little bit more to get deeper in details with intelligent machining and industrial work.', 'The course content could have been more enhanced with some calculation based assignments. This was more on theoretical side.', 'Provides a comprehensive dive into the state and utility of IM.', 'The evaluation section has to be improve a lot since it makes learners to be lethargic in listening the modules.  The course could have include some more information in its content to have a good stuff in Intelligent Machining.', 'Good for beginner awareness', 'Terrible readings, useless lectures. Course lacks information.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Sergio E A M', 'By Abla h ', 'By Muhammad A J', 'By Prahlad K S', 'By Atichat P', 'By Shivoh C', 'By C. A K Y', 'By Gabitova G F', 'By Soumyamitra', 'By Jesus Z F', 'By Meetkumar J P', 'By yashar k s', 'By Vancho D', 'By NATHAN D', 'By Tejash y T G', 'By HARSH K D ', 'By Omar M A E S', 'By Anurag B S', 'By Paul G', 'By HARI K . K', 'By Jigar P', 'By Thomas R']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Sep 14, 2018', 'Oct 02, 2018', 'Jun 24, 2018', 'Mar 27, 2018', 'Oct 28, 2017', 'Apr 30, 2017', 'May 30, 2018', 'Jan 15, 2018', 'May 24, 2019', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Oct 15, 2018', 'Mar 05, 2018', 'Jul 10, 2018', 'Nov 05, 2017', 'Jan 13, 2018', 'Jan 31, 2018']</review_date></doc>