<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_36</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/ml-foundations</course_url><course_name>Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Carlos Guestrin</course_instructor><course_introduction>Do you have data and wonder what it can tell you?  Do you need a deeper understanding of the core ways in which machine learning can improve your business?  Do you want to be able to converse with specialists about anything from regression and classification to deep learning and recommender systems?

In this course, you will get hands-on experience with machine learning from a series of practical case-studies.  At the end of the first course you will have studied how to predict house prices based on house-level features, analyze sentiment from user reviews, retrieve documents of interest, recommend products, and search for images.  Through hands-on practice with these use cases, you will be able to apply machine learning methods in a wide range of domains.

This first course treats the machine learning method as a black box.  Using this abstraction, you will focus on understanding tasks of interest, matching these tasks to machine learning tools, and assessing the quality of the output. In subsequent courses, you will delve into the components of this black box by examining models and algorithms.  Together, these pieces form the machine learning pipeline, which you will use in developing intelligent applications.

Learning Outcomes:  By the end of this course, you will be able to:
   -Identify potential applications of machine learning in practice.  
   -Describe the core differences in analyses enabled by regression, classification, and clustering.
   -Select the appropriate machine learning task for a potential application.  
   -Apply regression, classification, clustering, retrieval, recommender systems, and deep learning.
   -Represent your data as features to serve as input to machine learning models. 
   -Assess the model quality in terms of relevant error metrics for each task.
   -Utilize a dataset to fit a model to analyze new data.
   -Build an end-to-end application that uses machine learning at its core.  
   -Implement these techniques in Python.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Python Programming//Machine Learning Concepts//Machine Learning//Deep Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Washington</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome//Regression: Predicting House Prices//Classification: Analyzing Sentiment//Clustering and Similarity: Retrieving Documents//Recommending Products//Deep Learning: Searching for Images//Closing Remarks</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to this course and specialization', 'Who we are', 'Machine learning is changing the world', 'Why a case study approach?', 'Specialization overview', 'How we got into ML', 'Who is this specialization for?', "What you'll be able to do", 'The capstone and an example intelligent application', 'The future of intelligent applications', 'Starting an IPython Notebook', 'Creating variables in Python', 'Conditional statements and loops in Python', 'Creating functions and lambdas in Python', 'Starting GraphLab Create &amp; loading an SFrame', 'Canvas for data visualization', 'Interacting with columns of an SFrame', 'Using .apply() for data transformation'], ['Predicting house prices: A case study in regression', 'What is the goal and how might you naively address it?', 'Linear Regression: A Model-Based Approach', 'Adding higher order effects', 'Evaluating overfitting via training/test split', 'Training/test curves', 'Adding other features', 'Other regression examples', 'Regression ML block diagram', 'Loading &amp; exploring house sale data', 'Splitting the data into training and test sets', 'Learning a simple regression model to predict house prices from house size', 'Evaluating error (RMSE) of the simple model', 'Visualizing predictions of simple model with Matplotlib', 'Inspecting the model coefficients learned', 'Exploring other features of the data', 'Learning a model to predict house prices from more features', 'Applying learned models to predict price of an average house', 'Applying learned models to predict price of two fancy houses'], ['Analyzing the sentiment of reviews: A case study in classification', 'What is an intelligent restaurant review system?', 'Examples of classification tasks', 'Linear classifiers', 'Decision boundaries', 'Training and evaluating a classifier', "What's a good accuracy?", 'False positives, false negatives, and confusion matrices', 'Learning curves', 'Class probabilities', 'Classification ML block diagram', 'Loading &amp; exploring product review data', 'Creating the word count vector', 'Exploring the most popular product', 'Defining which reviews have positive or negative sentiment', 'Training a sentiment classifier', 'Evaluating a classifier &amp; the ROC curve', 'Applying model to find most positive &amp; negative reviews for a product', 'Exploring the most positive &amp; negative aspects of a product'], ['Document retrieval: A case study in clustering and measuring similarity', 'What is the document retrieval task?', 'Word count representation for measuring similarity', 'Prioritizing important words with tf-idf', 'Calculating tf-idf vectors', 'Retrieving similar documents using nearest neighbor search', 'Clustering documents task overview', 'Clustering documents: An unsupervised learning task', 'k-means: A clustering algorithm', 'Other examples of clustering', 'Clustering and similarity ML block diagram', 'Loading &amp; exploring Wikipedia data', 'Exploring word counts', 'Computing &amp; exploring TF-IDFs', 'Computing distances between Wikipedia articles', 'Building &amp; exploring a nearest neighbors model for Wikipedia articles', 'Examples of document retrieval in action'], ['Recommender systems overview', 'Where we see recommender systems in action', 'Building a recommender system via classification', 'Collaborative filtering: People who bought this also bought...', 'Effect of popular items', 'Normalizing co-occurrence matrices and leveraging purchase histories', 'The matrix completion task', 'Recommendations from known user/item features', 'Predictions in matrix form', 'Discovering hidden structure by matrix factorization', 'Bringing it all together: Featurized matrix factorization', 'A performance metric for recommender systems', 'Optimal recommenders', 'Precision-recall curves', 'Recommender systems ML block diagram', 'Loading and exploring song data', 'Creating &amp; evaluating a popularity-based song recommender', 'Creating &amp; evaluating a personalized song recommender', 'Using precision-recall to compare recommender models'], ['Searching for images: A case study in deep learning', 'What is a visual product recommender?', 'Learning very non-linear features with neural networks', 'Application of deep learning to computer vision', 'Deep learning performance', 'Demo of deep learning model on ImageNet data', 'Other examples of deep learning in computer vision', 'Challenges of deep learning', 'Deep Features', 'Deep learning ML block diagram', 'Loading image data', 'Training &amp; evaluating a classifier using raw image pixels', 'Training &amp; evaluating a classifier using deep features', 'Loading image data', 'Creating a nearest neighbors model for image retrieval', 'Querying the nearest neighbors model to retrieve images', 'Querying for the most similar images for car image', 'Displaying other example image retrievals with a Python lambda'], ["You've made it!", 'Deploying an ML service', 'What happens after deployment?', 'Open challenges in ML', 'Where is ML going?', "What's ahead in the specialization", 'Thank you!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 24 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The materials used in this course are extremely outdated. In order to access the data to do the projects you have to use SFrame, which is only supported up to Python 3.4.x. Python is currently on v 3.7.0. The data should be provided as .txt or .csv to be more universal. The instructors claim that you don't have to use a specific library to do this course, but you have to have at least SFrame in order to access the data! Further I am sure SFrame and Graphlab are good tools, but the course should be taught with open source tools so that the students can continue to use those tools after the course is over. ", 'I spend two days trying to get the graphlap lib working on two OS, and could not. I had to spend couple of hours setting up the aws services to be able to work with the samples.', 'Very relevant material clearly explained by the professors, who are very knowledgeable and engageing. However the installation and usage of the GraphLab module is cumbersome and plagued with bugs. This could still work if there was enough support however I did not find any helpfrom the mentors/tutors who simply did not answer my questions in the Forum thus making my experience even more frustrating. Pity, I certainly hope Coursera can fix it as the class is quite good', 'Such a bad presentation with no help to people with graphiclab tool setup.', 'Too dependent on Sframes and graphlab which does not work most of the times. I had to spend an entire day just figuring out versions of python to make this work.', 'To follow along the course you need to install Graphlab library, which is the biggest challenge.  Also, the support you get from the creators are not good enough.', None, 'Course uses proprietary packages. Better learning from "The Analytics Edge" conducted by MIT at Edx.org', "I enrolled in this specialization to learn machine learning using GraphLab Create. Half way into the specialization the creators sold Turi, GrapLab's parent company, making it non available to the general public (not even by paying) and then all the knowledge devalued. I wish I had known this and I would have enrolled on a different specialization. The creators still give you the possibility of using numpy, scikit learn and pandas but I had already done a lot with GraphLab create. The time I invested on my nights after work became a waste. I was trying to convince the company I worked for to buy licenses for GraphLab create. ", 'The worse course I have ever taken on Coursera. Forcing you to use their own library which is also not open source and free is ridiculous! You will never use graphlab in the future and there are better alternatives available! Totally useless experience. And most of the time vide lectures are just some mumbo jumbo, like showing diapers or napkins for 2 minutes! I have successfully wasted a lot of time on this course.', 'relying on proprietary library and unreliable notebook made this experience painful', 'Requires software called Graphlab Create that would not install on my machine. Unable to complete any of the course material due to this.', 'Good intro to the ML concepts, but my review is negative due to :', 'I just completed the first week of this course and am choosing not to continue. The first week consisted of 75 minutes of video in which we learned a half dozen facts regarding Python syntax and the use of SFrames. This content could have been presented in a single 5 minute video with just a little planning and editing. I realize that the presenters perhaps wanted to ease folks in, but this is silly. There may be good content in the following weeks, but I am not patient enough to find out. Gonna try a different ML class. Sorry guys.  ', "Maybe a good course, but you need to be an IT crack to be able to install the software and make it works. Online help does not help. Irritating! 45USD lost. I don't recommend this course.", '在上這門課之前，其實我就具備了這堂課大多數內容所需的知識，包含這些模型的方法以及數學證明等，因此這門課對我的幫助在於graphlab的使用、各種案例的探討及實踐。', 'Out of date.  Should be retired or updated.', "If you are considering this specialization I would recommend the Andrew Ng course instead and the main reason is that it isn't depend on proprietary ML framework. Despite the good lectures, the assignments don't help you develop the knowledge required for ML developer role.", 'I signed up for this course and began the reading and videos, but once it was time to begin interacting with the technology required (Amazon Web Services) , it appears this course is not longer supported by the instructors.  Most communication on the course seems to have stopped between 1 and 2 years ago.  Recent comments on the discussion forum no longer receive a response.', "This specialization is delayed for months now - very annoying! Don't give them money!", 'The most useless course on Coursera. I have wasted 3 weeks just trying to install Graphlab and the installation seems infinitely tedious. There is no support from Coursera or University of Michigan to install the software ', "I am extremely frustrated with this course. I have spent sooo many days just trying to get the software set up. It's currently week 3 and I can't complete week 1.  I've followed the directions and run in numerous roadblocks, some of which I was able to resolve after searching through the course forums. I shouldn't have to scour the forums to get setup...the instructions should be updated.  Unfortunately, I'm still stuck in week 1, unable to get the software running properly. It's really frustrating.", 'the graphlab can not be installed', 'A good course to understand the basics of Machine Learning. The only issue is the use of Graphlab library. Since it only works on Python 2.7, it is not convenient for people who prefer Python 3 ', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Ravi P', 'By Oscar A R', 'By Gianmaria M', 'By sreeraj c', 'By Sourav S', 'By Jatin K P', 'By Ibrahim M A', 'By Rahul D', 'By Ernie M', 'By Elvin V', 'By Walther A G L M', 'By Andrew W', 'By Theron R F P', 'By Matthew H', 'By strx', 'By Wei-Zhe Y', 'By Susan L', 'By Eugene K', 'By Ron M', 'By Andreas', 'By Pritish K', 'By Sharina C', 'By lianghui t', 'By Karthik M', 'By Brett L']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 08, 2018', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2018', 'Jun 27, 2018', 'Mar 28, 2018', 'Apr 29, 2017', 'Dec 23, 2017', 'Sep 25, 2017', 'Oct 26, 2017', 'Jul 02, 2018', 'Nov 04, 2017', 'Nov 05, 2017', 'Oct 26, 2017', 'Apr 12, 2017', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Nov 05, 2018', 'Feb 10, 2017', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Jan 04, 2017', 'Apr 07, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Oct 17, 2016']</review_date></doc>