<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_81</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/launching-machine-learning</course_url><course_name>Launching into Machine Learning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>Starting from a history of machine learning, we discuss why neural networks today perform so well in a variety of data science problems. We then discuss how to set up a supervised learning problem and find a good solution using gradient descent. This involves creating datasets that permit generalization; we talk about methods of doing so in a repeatable way that supports experimentation.

Course Objectives:
Identify why deep learning is currently popular
Optimize and evaluate models using loss functions and performance metrics
Mitigate common problems that arise in machine learning
Create repeatable and scalable training, evaluation, and test datasets</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Tensorflow//Bigquery//Machine Learning//Data Cleansing</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Practical ML//Optimization//Generalization and Sampling//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Intro to Qwiklabs'], ['Introduction', 'Supervised Learning', 'Regression and Classification', 'Short History of ML: Linear Regression', 'Short History of ML: Perceptron', 'Short History of ML: Neural Networks', 'Short History of ML: Decision Trees', 'Short History of ML: Kernel Methods', 'Short History of ML: Random Forests', 'Short History of ML: Modern Neural Networks'], ['Introduction', 'Defining ML Models', 'Introducing the Natality Dataset', 'Introducing Loss Functions', 'Gradient Descent', 'Troubleshooting a Loss Curve', 'ML Model Pitfalls', 'Lab: Introducing the TensorFlow Playground', 'Lab: TensorFlow Playground - Advanced', 'Lab: Practicing with Neural Networks', 'Loss Curve Troubleshooting', 'Performance Metrics', 'Confusion Matrix'], ['Introduction', 'Generalization and ML Models', 'When to Stop Model Training', 'Creating Repeatable Samples in BigQuery', 'Demo: Splitting Datasets in BigQuery', 'Lab Introduction', 'Lab Solution Walkthrough', 'Lab Introduction', 'Lab Solution Walkthrough'], ['Module Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 7 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great course. Gradient descent and loss function concepts were explained well.', 'The videos are ok, the "Labs" are really bad. You just follow \ninstructions with code to copy into the notebook. Of course, you can \nplay a bit with the code, but you don\'t really learn how to do it \nyourself when the correct answer is already filled in.  Would not \nrecommend.', 'Thanks...', 'Good learning path', 'A great course to boost your confidence on practicing ML. It also teaches you some fresh skills like repeatable dataset partitioning techniques using just SQL.', 'Super fun course. ', 'Another great learning experience and has given me the confidence to keep moving forward.', 'fanstatic course', '5 starz - very good info and pointful. ', 'Good clear course with strong incremental learning.', 'Great lectures and labs thanks. The first lecture block made a lot of great connections between topics and methods past and present yet get the most out of it, one ideally has recently reviewed the theory behind the tradition tools. Otherwise the first block is a bit of a drink from the firehose although one can still pick up the gist message but may not get some of the other enriching points. In any case. Great work and thanks', 'I love the course introducing core concepts and practices in machine learning today as well as some historical development. This course feels more rigorous because some core mathematical foundations are introduced. I kind of hope there could be more theoretical explanation in more depths with some references attached.', 'Great course!', 'This course provides a great introduction to Machine Learning.', 'hands on labs was amazing', 'NA', 'Thumbs Up!', 'This course gave me a good overview of how to work with GCP for ML and also helped in covering a bit of knowledge gaps that I had when I learnt things on my own. ', 'Thank you for such great knowledge sharing. I have really enjoyed the course and have learned a lot from it. The way the speakers explain each and every tiny detail is exceptional. This course make me a step closer to my goals and will help me in my career building as a Machine Learning Engineer. ', 'Decent, Labs took a hit on quality. :S', 'I loved TensorFlow Playgrounds. It made so many concepts visible. I have more intuition into how the number of layers, input features and number of neutrons affect what the model can learn. This is not my first Machine Learning course, and it is helping me fill out many gaps I have in my understanding.', 'Excelente curso, muchas gracias!', 'This is an awesome module. It will open up so much inside story of ML process which is core of the topic with such a simplicity. It greatly increases my interest into this topic and this course :)', 'A very nice overview of ML history and introduction to ML on Google Cloud Platform! Thanks!', 'great visualization course']</reviews><reviewers>['By Raghuram N', 'By Dirk K', 'By Raja R G', 'By pankaj b g', 'By SUJITH V', 'By Shayne C', 'By rohit k s', 'By shabeer m', 'By BHARATHI A', 'By Joel M', 'By Mark B', 'By Zezhou J', 'By Abdul R Y', 'By Garry S', 'By Apoorv R', 'By Harshkumar', 'By Gregory R G J', 'By Kaustubh M H', 'By Arif N', 'By Sujeethan V', 'By Hussian A A', 'By Alan I S R', 'By Pawan K T', 'By C K', 'By Subham T']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 27, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Dec 31, 2018', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Nov 11, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jan 24, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Jul 29, 2018', 'Jul 28, 2018']</review_date></doc>