<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_13</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/linear-algebra-machine-learning</course_url><course_name>Mathematics for Machine Learning: Linear Algebra</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>David Dye</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course on Linear Algebra we look at what linear algebra is and how it relates to vectors and matrices. Then we look through what vectors and matrices are and how to work with them, including the knotty problem of eigenvalues and eigenvectors, and how to use these to solve problems. Finally  we look at how to use these to do fun things with datasets - like how to rotate images of faces and how to extract eigenvectors to look at how the Pagerank algorithm works.
Since we're aiming at data-driven applications, we'll be implementing some of these ideas in code, not just on pencil and paper. Towards the end of the course, you'll write code blocks and encounter Jupyter notebooks in Python, but don't worry, these will be quite short, focussed on the concepts, and will guide you through if you’ve not coded before.

At the end of this course you will have an intuitive understanding of vectors and matrices that will help you bridge the gap into linear algebra problems, and how to apply these concepts to machine learning.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Eigenvalues And Eigenvectors//Basis (Linear Algebra)//Transformation Matrix//Linear Algebra</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Linear Algebra and to Mathematics for Machine Learning//Vectors are objects that move around space//Matrices in Linear Algebra: Objects that operate on Vectors//Matrices make linear mappings//Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors: Application to Data Problems</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction: Solving data science challenges with mathematics', 'Motivations for linear algebra', 'Getting a handle on vectors', 'Operations with vectors', 'Summary'], ['Introduction to module 2 - Vectors', 'Modulus &amp; inner product', 'Cosine &amp; dot product', 'Projection', 'Changing basis', 'Basis, vector space, and linear independence', 'Applications of changing basis', 'Summary'], ['Matrices, vectors, and solving simultaneous equation problems', 'How matrices transform space', 'Types of matrix transformation', 'Composition or combination of matrix transformations', 'Solving the apples and bananas problem: Gaussian elimination', 'Going from Gaussian elimination to finding the inverse matrix', 'Determinants and inverses', 'Summary'], ['Introduction: Einstein summation convention and the symmetry of the dot product', 'Matrices changing basis', 'Doing a transformation in a changed basis', 'Orthogonal matrices', 'The Gram–Schmidt process', 'Example: Reflecting in a plane'], ['Welcome to module 5', 'What are eigenvalues and eigenvectors?', 'Special eigen-cases', 'Calculating eigenvectors', 'Changing to the eigenbasis', 'Eigenbasis example', 'Introduction to PageRank', 'Summary', 'Wrap up of this linear algebra course']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This course is not suited for beginners and people looking for an introductory lecture to Linear Algebra! Unfortunately the topics are extremely hastily presented and lack depth of explanation, sufficient examples and often leave out content required to complete the assignments. The material is not presented in a coherent way, and, for someone new to Linear Algebra like me, requires a great amount of self-study outside the course (e.g. Khan Academy) to comprehend the content. The team of lecturers is very likeable and enthusiastic. However, I do not comprehend where this course seeks to position itself: it is not suited for students new to Linear Algebra, and, not extensive enough for someone seeking to learn underlying mathematics for Machine Learning as this course simply doesn't cover Machine Learning. Finishing this course, I have some vague understanding of certain concepts and I am left longing for proper and structured content that I could feel confident about.", "I can't follow what is happening. There is a huge gap between what is being taught and what is being asked in the assignments.", "Too many sessions and quizzes which appear to require previous knowledge of the taught subject, concept and the details. If I had that knowledge already, I would not be taking the course to begin with. The programming assignment do require previous Python/other programming experience. I would not categorize this as a 'beginner' class. ", " The teacher's explanation videos are excellent, really really clear: it makes you feel as though they really paid attention on how to deliver the content in the most understandable way possible. The teacher speaks clearly, the audio and the subtitles are on point, etc. ", "Disclaimer: If you are familiar with Linear Algebra, you may love this course. This review is not for those people. This review is for the people who went to the course details, saw that the recommended audience was 'Beginner' level, and decided to give it a try, thinking it involved a low barrier of entry. You'd be thinking incorrectly. Here is why.  ", 'The autograding of python notebooks in week 3 does not work. Submission by alternative upload did grade properly either. Just trying over and over to get the test to pass, took longer than coding the assignment. Until this is fixed, I think this course is a unfortunately incomplete. ', 'Mostly a very solid course. There are some poor descriptions of certain concepts, though, and students are expected to fill in some gaps to what I perceive as an unreasonable degree.', 'Great and comprehensive course. Videos are very understable and interesting - however the quizzes jump a few times from 1 to 100 in terms of the difficulty and require further study besides what is taught in this course. ', 'Eigen vector concept was not clearly explained as to how it applies to real world. But in general great course.', 'If you are looking for overview on Linear Algebra, you can save USD 40, refer to free material all over Web.  Some videos on Youtube are visually more capturing than blackboard style teaching here. Knowledge of Python is required for this course, though not obvious from start. Would have been good to begin with end in mine - a 5 minute video to explain why Linear Algebra is required for M/c learning can be motivating. ', 'No one cares about the homework! The Homeworks are not graded properly. Moreover, in the last module the lecturer speaks only without properly writing everything down or explain the subjects mathematically.', 'Amazing course, great instructors. The amount of working linear algebra knowledge you get from this single course is substantial. It has already helped solidify my learning in other ML and AI courses.', "This course is very usefull for beginners in machine learning. I've learned too much from Linear algebra, and that's more important i understood the intuition of linear math. This course contains real usefull exercises in Python that can help me improve my skill in math. ", 'This course is phenomenal, It helped me to refresh a lot of skills that I learned at my college and at the same time I learned a bit on how to introduce all this matrixes into a programming assignment which are by the way extremely hard because I am a novice at programming. It helped me to see other subitems such as Gramm Schmitt and eigenvectors that I did not see on college, I understood them but not a 100%, I guess an 75% is an average. Thanks Coursera and Imperial College London for this awesome course. I had to search other books to comprehend the subject, but next time, be more detailed. ', "The course is very good, almost perfect for my purposes. I liked specially the effort to make the students get the necessary intuition instead of pushing a lot examples as many other MOOC usually do. But I've noticed some negative points. I ask you to take my critic as a sincere effort to improve the course and eliminate some mistakes that really matters to the students. The last quiz seems quite disconnected with the lectures and there isn't a support guide or tutorial not even a mentor answering the questions in the week 5 forum. Some mistakes on videos (eigenvalues and eigenvectors) were confirmed by the lecturer but never corrected. Not even a errata on resources section. Talking about the resources, I think it is very poor. Cousera has many better examples.", 'A very good introduction but some of important content need to use another provider (Kahn academy) to understand completly', 'Lots of unaddressed inconsistencies. ', 'The spends an insane amount of time on easy topics, but glosses over the most difficult conceptual topics in about 3-4 seconds. The quizzes/assessments are either trivially easy, or too difficult to do given what has been covered previously. No relevance for ML is given for the topics covered.', 'Not intuitive or well explained.  Examples are horrible', "Material is good, the exercises are insane, and you'll spend hours Googling stuff that was breezed over in the videos.", "Course is titled incorrectly. The course has nothing to do with machine learning. It's mainly out of context symbol pushing (like most math courses). ", 'One of the best courses i studied in coursera', "This is a great course for those people who want to get started with ML and need a refresher on linear algebra. It's focused on the important part without overwhelming the audience with unnecessary details. I'd highly recommend this course and also the entire specialization.", "Professors teaches in so much friendly manner. This is beginner level course. Don't expect you will dive deep inside the Linear Algebra. But the foundation will become solid if you attend this course.", 'Very good course: well paced, well structured, just the right scope.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Georg K', 'By Atul A', 'By Pirkka P', 'By Juan D', 'By Andrew M', 'By Tim R', 'By Tim K', 'By Christoph A S', 'By Lochan N', 'By naveen s', 'By Ehsan G', 'By Chad S', 'By Марков Д А', 'By Miguel A F B', 'By João C L S', 'By LAURENT G', 'By Ashley W', 'By Darren T', 'By Badrul I', 'By Peter S', 'By Jeffrey J', 'By Baccouche M S', 'By Laszlo C', 'By Nikhil S', 'By Kris S']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 08, 2018', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Apr 23, 2019', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Jan 13, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Apr 28, 2018', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Mar 31, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Sep 21, 2018', 'Mar 08, 2018', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'May 28, 2019']</review_date></doc>