<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_224</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-representation</course_url><course_name>Python Data Representations</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Scott Rixner</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will continue the introduction to Python programming that started with Python Programming Essentials.  We'll learn about different data representations, including strings, lists, and tuples, that form the core of all Python programs.  We will also teach you how to access files, which will allow you to store and retrieve data within your programs. These concepts and skills will help you to manipulate data and write more complex Python programs.

By the end of the course, you will be able to write Python programs that can manipulate data stored in files.  This will extend your Python programming expertise, enabling you to write a wide range of scripts using Python

This course uses Python 3.  While most Python programs continue to use Python 2, Python 3 is the future of the Python programming language. This course introduces basic desktop Python development environments, allowing you to run Python programs directly on your computer. This choice enables a smooth transition from online development environments.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag>Tuple//Python Programming//Debugging//List &amp; Label</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Strings//Basics of Lists//List Manipulation//File Access</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome!', 'Class Structure', 'Python Strings', 'Indexing Strings', 'Searching Strings', 'Slicing Strings', 'Answering Common Python Questions'], ['Lists', 'List Indexing and Slicing', 'Splitting and Joining Strings', 'List Searching', 'Iteration over Lists', "Using Thonny's Debugger", 'Debugging an Example Program'], ['List Mutation', 'Tuples', 'Objects and References', 'Understanding List References', 'Diagnosing List Reference Issues'], ['Opening and Reading Files', 'Reading Files using Iteration', 'Writing Files', 'Working with File Paths', 'Project Video']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent course on python data structures like strings, lists and tuples. Hands on exercises are really superb.', 'Important basics covered - different data types in python and how to read and write CSV files into python. ', 'cool', 'Simple coverage.. but exercises and guidance to them is good', 'Very helpful.', 'Very good course, instructor presented it well.', "It was challenging. Some elements of the projects did not make sense as they were presented, but the instructors gave a decent explanation of why those would be relevant, e.g. something would have already been determined in a real life use of such a function. Definitely increased my understanding of Python and I'm ready and eager to move forward in Rice's certificate program.", 'very good course', 'Great course - Final Project is quite difficult but I learned a lot from it!', 'Excelente componente del Curso. Gran aprendizaje, altamente recomendado. Para principiantes otorga buen nivel para ir desarrollándose en este gran lenguaje de programación.', 'Interesting, Engaging and usefully challenging', 'it is very intersesting course', 'great course. Found it to be really useful', 'Great course and great assignments!', 'Good Stuff.', 'Excellent course. Very nice projects.', 'Great course, but the final test was really difficult.', 'Very well thought out course. Glad I took it.', 'Loved this course and the tutors! I started a lot of online courses but always lost interest as they were focussed on data types etc.. but then this course takes a different route and keeps you engaged all through. I was able to finish the course 1 and 2 of the specialization in 4-5 days ', 'This course has gave me the essential tools to do Python scripting in a professional manner! Recommended!', 'well designed course', 'Excellent course. Gives you an introduction to working with Strings, Lists and Files. And there are lots of exercises to practice.', 'Course design is really helpful', 'Nice', 'Great Course!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Honey S', 'By Joanne H P C ', 'By Farhodjon A', 'By Nishin K V', 'By Zolt S', 'By 林晉宇', 'By Mark J S', 'By siyadsalam', 'By Tal L', 'By Jose D', 'By Felix O', 'By Ankit S', 'By shubhajit b', 'By Mohamed H E', 'By Gabriel F', 'By Rodrigo B M', 'By Crina F B', 'By Ray M', 'By Srinivas R', 'By John O O', 'By Zhe Y', 'By Jean-Claude B', 'By liping', 'By  N B', 'By Mehmet A U']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 18, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2018', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'Aug 08, 2018', 'Jul 23, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'Sep 05, 2018', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Oct 17, 2018', 'Oct 03, 2018', 'Oct 04, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Aug 17, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'Mar 11, 2018', 'Jul 02, 2018', 'May 24, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2018']</review_date></doc>