<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_176</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/functional-mri</course_url><course_name>Principles of fMRI 1</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Martin Lindquist, PhD, MSc</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course covers the design, acquisition, and analysis of Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) data.

A book related to the class can be found here: https://leanpub.com/principlesoffmri</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Statistical Analysis//Statistical Model//Preprocessor</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Module 1: Introduction and Ground Rules', 'Module 2: Goals of fMRI Analysis', 'Module 3: fMRI Data Structure', 'Module 4.1: Psychological Inference Part 1', 'Module 4.2: Psychological Inference Part 2', 'Module 5: Basic Understanding of MR Physics', 'Module 6: Forming an Image', 'Module 7: K Space'], ['Module 8: Signal, Noise, and Bold Physiology', 'Module 9: fMRI Artifacts and Types of Noise', 'Module 10.1: Spatial and Temporal Resolution of Bold Part 1', 'Module 10.2: Spatial and Temporal Resolution of Bold Part 2 ', 'Module 11: Experimental Design', 'Module 12.1: Kinds of Designs Part 1', 'Module 12.2: Kinds of Designs Part 2 ', 'Module 13: Pre-Processing of fMRI Data', 'Module 14: Pre-Processing (continued)'], ['Module 15: General Linear Model', 'Module 16: Applying GLM to fMRI Data', 'Module 17: Details of Building GLM Models', 'Module 18: Linear Basis Sets', 'Module 19: Filtering a Nuisance Covariance', 'Module 20: GLM Estimation', 'Module 21: Noise Models - AR Models', 'Module 22: Inference - Contrasts and T-tests'], ['Module 23: Group-level Analysis I', 'Module 24: Group-level Analysis II', 'Module 25: Group-level Analysis III', 'Module 26: Multiple Comparison Problem in fMRI', 'Module 27: FWER Correction', 'Module 28: FDR Correction', 'Module 29: Pitfalls and Multiple Comparisons']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very fasinat', 'Very densly packed course with many great information. Sometimes it went a bit too fast, though. I wish there was a bit more explanation for some of the more advanced ideas. Still a very good course that made me confident to start analyzing some fMRI data that I have at hand.', "It's not really a beginners course. Reviews most of the important fMRI statistical analysis concepts. Additionally, the information regarding MR Physics involved was invaluable.", 'Too much theory. No practice and practical online sessions on SPM for example.', 'It is really easy going and interesting course. With good explanations that keep you on track easily. I really liked it since the begging and it gave me curiosity to undertake the second one', 'Amazing course. More advanced than I thought it would be, which was excellent. Interested students should know that it has a lot of statistics in it. ', 'A very well structured course starting from the basics of fMRI. It is of great help in understanding what goes into fMRI analysis ', 'very nice', 'This is course gives a very comprehensive understanding of fMRI technology. The course can be further improved by adding some practical or visual assignments instead of quizzes only.', 'thanks', 'I personally like this course very much. I have a overview of the basic fMRI techniques from the course. It is well organised and relatively easy to understand. I would like to recommend to others. Also, thanks for the instructors of the this course: you are very helpful!', None, 'you are the best guys!! You helped me so much in my understanding of fMRI...I wish I did this course years before!!', 'Excelent and helpful.  Great instructors (I like the brains flying around :))', 'It is a brilliant course for fMRI beginners and enthusiasts.', 'A very good introduction, but you would need some decent knowledge in statistics to fully understand the methods part. Standard undergrad psychology courses in statistics should be enough.', None, "It's a fast paced course that presents useful tools to understand fMRI methods and interpretation of findings. There is some mathematical content that will use a background of matrices operations and transformations as a prerequisite. Review some of that and you're good to go.  ", 'Extremely helpful and well guided roundup for any one who is interested in experimenting with FMRI data and experiment.', None, 'Great course. Great overview of fMRI, including the background for statistical tests used.', 'Great course, would be better if it incorporated labs/practical assignments to practice or apply the principles of fMRI onto actual datasets.', 'It has been very useful informations for me. The method used by those teachers  was very good and didactic. Thank you.', None, None]</reviews><reviewers>['By chenqingwei', 'By Marcel D S', 'By Zaeem H', 'By Sadoun', 'By José M P B', 'By Adlyn P', 'By Sameer P', 'By Pranay T', 'By Janzaib M', 'By Esat I', 'By Dengfeng H', 'By Majed A A', 'By Theodor R', 'By Edgar A', 'By ThejasVishnu R', 'By Aleksandr M', 'By Yanming Z', 'By Klebert T d S C', 'By Muhammad T M', 'By Saverio B', 'By Christopher S', 'By Shireen P', 'By Roberto A S S', 'By Jaganth N', 'By Ahmed M M M R']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 28, 2018', 'Jun 26, 2018', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'Jun 10, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Sep 23, 2018', 'Aug 27, 2018', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Oct 24, 2018', 'Sep 20, 2017', 'Mar 28, 2017', 'Oct 17, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2016', 'Jul 03, 2017', 'Feb 02, 2017', 'Aug 25, 2017', 'Oct 21, 2016', 'Feb 26, 2016', 'May 27, 2017']</review_date></doc>