<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_233</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/advanced-r</course_url><course_name>Advanced R Programming</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Roger D. Peng, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course covers advanced topics in R programming that are necessary for developing powerful, robust, and reusable data science tools. Topics covered include functional programming in R, robust error handling, object oriented programming, profiling and benchmarking, debugging, and proper design of functions. Upon completing this course you will be able to identify and abstract common data analysis tasks and to encapsulate them in user-facing functions. Because every data science environment encounters unique data challenges, there is always a need to develop custom software specific to your organization’s mission. You will also be able to define new data types in R and to develop a universe of functionality specific to those data types to enable cleaner execution of data science tasks and stronger reusability within a team.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Logic Programming//R Programming//Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)//Functional Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Advanced R Programming//Functions//Functions: Lesson Choices//Functional Programming//Functional Programming: Lesson Choices//Debugging and Profiling//Object-Oriented Programming</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Advanced R Programming'], ['Control Structures Overview', 'if-else', 'for Loops', 'Nested for loops', 'next, break', 'Summary', 'Functions Overview', 'Code', 'Function interface', 'Default values', 'Re-factoring code', 'Dependency Checking', 'Vectorization', 'Argument Checking', 'R package', 'When Should I Write a Function?', 'Summary'], ['Swirl Lesson'], ['What is Functional Programming?', 'Core Functional Programming Functions', 'Map', 'Reduce', 'Search', 'Filter', 'Compose', 'Partial Application', 'Side Effects', 'Recursion', 'Summary', 'Expressions', 'Environments', 'Execution Environments', 'What is an error?', 'Generating Errors', 'When to generate errors or warnings', 'How should errors be handled?', 'Summary'], ['Swirl Lesson'], ['Debugging Overview', 'traceback()', 'Browsing a Function Environment', 'Tracing Functions', 'Using debug() and debugonce()', 'recover()', 'Final Thoughts on Debugging', 'Summary', 'Profiling Overview', 'microbenchmark', 'profvis', 'Find out more', 'Summary', 'Non-standard evaluation', 'Summary'], ['OOP Overview', 'Object Oriented Principles', 'S3', 'S4', 'Reference Classes', 'Summary', 'Overview', 'Reuse existing data structures', 'Compose simple functions with the pipe', 'Embrace functional programming', 'Design for humans']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I have taken several courses on Coursera and this was by far the worst. First the course contained no lectures. The authors had basically copied segments of their textbooks along with code samples as teaching material. I could have done better by simply reading the textbook myself without paying for the course. Finally the way the final assignment is graded is terrible. It is as if the course organizers have completely washed their hands of any responsibility. You have to grade three peers so that your assignment will get in line to be graded. But there is no time line and the process is completely arbitrary. Students have to actively seek others on the class forum to grade their assignment (they will return the favor ). I really expected more from a course offered by JHU.', 'I learned a lot and appreciate the continued learnings.', 'This course helped the programmer understand some OO concepts and many other features of R that I may not have encountered. Very good, and the final assignment was good. It was worth putting the extra time in to do it correctly.', 'Very knowledge and rigourous course, developed for comprehensive concept building.', "I like this course as it offers some really practical instructions to programming in R, and I think it's a  course that well complements the online book Advanced R written by Hadley Wickham, which focuses more on theories. ", "It is a short and good R course. It goes right to the more advanced stuff. Even a long time user of R will learn new things. The final project is revised by the same students which in my opinion makes it more of a challenge. I've never wanted a homework to be as perfect as this one.", 'Cheerful', 'Great course. Challenging and I learn a lot of new techniques to improve my R skills.', 'Solid overview of the topics in the course description. Does not go into much detail but provides a very nice foundation to build on. The course book is and will be a handy and useful resource, as it allows you to revisit the course materials (minus the exercises) without having to navigate through the course on the platform.', 'Very good, recommended.', 'I have learned a lot . All the courses are neat and precise. It helps me a lot. The materials and  the questions are detailed .', "For me the course provided a quick and easy introduction to the 'purr' package as well as clarity on the current state of R's object oriented programming system.", 'The peer-graded assessment is really helpful for learning OOP implementing in R!', 'More information material will be helpful', 'Excellent course for improving R programming skills. Highly recommended. ', 'this is a must for those who want to improve their programming skills in R. As an advanced course, this is a little bit harder, but don`t give up! ', 'Very useful, I considered myself quite an advanced R user, but this class raised the level, especially with the R as OOB part. Good investment if you are not a beginner.', 'Great course material with engaging assignments. Strongly recommended.', 'The course has given me good insight into the functional and object oriented programming parts of R. ', 'Awesome course! Learned a lot! It is mandatory if you would like to become an experienced R user, not just programmer!', None, 'More advanced, challenging course. Still, enjoyable and enlightening. Mentoring on this course is really helpful too!', 'This course helped me to figure out what additional skills I need to work on to improve my R coding skills.', None, 'It is a good course that forced me to understand the s3 and s4 object of R and have gained an appreciation of "methods belonging to functions not belonging to objects".']</reviews><reviewers>['By Frank A N', 'By Erich F G', 'By Lance D', 'By Mayank V', 'By Xianbin C', 'By Nicolás C', 'By ®γσ, E L H', 'By Kevin K', 'By paoling83', 'By Josef T', 'By Michael w', 'By Marc F', 'By Yang Z', 'By Yaakov M', 'By Conner M', 'By Izandro M M', 'By Francesco D Z', 'By Faizan U F K', 'By Neville A', 'By Petko S', 'By Michael K', 'By Carlos C', 'By Cardy M I', 'By José E L', 'By Jay J Y']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 17, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Sep 22, 2018', 'Nov 09, 2018', 'Sep 06, 2018', 'Jul 04, 2018', 'Apr 06, 2017', 'Apr 13, 2018', 'Feb 23, 2017', 'Jul 19, 2017', 'Apr 25, 2017', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Mar 11, 2018', 'Jun 07, 2017', 'Feb 25, 2017', 'Jan 07, 2017', 'May 18, 2018', 'Apr 20, 2017', 'May 28, 2017', 'Sep 26, 2017', 'May 29, 2017', 'May 08, 2017']</review_date></doc>