<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_137</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/crash-course-in-causality</course_url><course_name>A Crash Course in Causality:  Inferring Causal Effects from Observational Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jason A. Roy, Ph.D. </course_instructor><course_introduction>We have all heard the phrase “correlation does not equal causation.”  What, then, does equal causation?  This course aims to answer that question and more!  

Over a period of 5 weeks, you will learn how causal effects are defined, what assumptions about your data and models are necessary, and how to implement and interpret some popular statistical methods.  Learners will have the opportunity to apply these methods to example data in R (free statistical software environment).

At the end of the course, learners should be able to:
1.  Define causal effects using potential outcomes
2.  Describe the difference between association and causation
3.  Express assumptions with causal graphs
4.  Implement several types of causal inference methods (e.g. matching, instrumental variables, inverse probability of treatment weighting)
5.  Identify which causal assumptions are necessary for each type of statistical method

So join us.... and discover for yourself why modern statistical methods for estimating causal effects are indispensable in so many fields of study!</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Instrumental Variable//Propensity Score Matching//Causal Inference//Causality</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome and Introduction to Causal Effects//Confounding and Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs)//Matching and Propensity Scores//Inverse Probability of Treatment Weighting (IPTW)//Instrumental Variables Methods</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to "A Crash Course in Causality"', 'Confusion over causality', 'Potential outcomes and counterfactuals', 'Hypothetical interventions', 'Causal effects', 'Causal assumptions', 'Stratification', 'Incident user and active comparator designs'], ['Confounding', 'Causal graphs', 'Relationship between DAGs and probability distributions', 'Paths and associations', 'Conditional independence (d-separation)', 'Confounding revisited', 'Backdoor path criterion', 'Disjunctive cause criterion'], ['Observational studies', 'Overview of matching', 'Matching directly on confounders', 'Greedy (nearest-neighbor) matching', 'Optimal matching', 'Assessing balance', 'Analyzing data after matching', 'Sensitivity analysis', 'Data example in R', 'Propensity scores', 'Propensity score matching', 'Propensity score matching in R'], ['Intuition for Inverse Probability of Treatment Weighting (IPTW)', 'More intuition for IPTW estimation', 'Marginal structural models', 'IPTW estimation', 'Assessing balance', 'Distribution of weights', 'Remedies for large weights', 'Doubly robust estimators', 'Data example in R'], ['Introduction to instrumental variables', 'Randomized trials with noncompliance', 'Compliance classes', 'Assumptions', 'Causal effect identification and estimation', 'IVs in observational studies', 'Two stage least squares', 'Weak instruments', 'IV analysis in R']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 26 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I enjoyed the course and learned basics of causal inference. What I missed was more exercises with R in order to gain more practical understanding of the material. In particular, it would be great to have exercises where you get some dataset and your task is to calculate given causal effect and you need to come up with an approach and to execute it. This would mimic more closely problems that you encounter in practice.', 'This course is quite useful for me to get quick understanding of the causality and causal inference in epidemiologic studies. Thanks to Prof. Roy.', 'The content is relaxing and easy to understand, yet extremely useful in real life when you are conducting experiments. The well designed quiz each week only takes a little time, but could help you to diagnose problems and remember the key points. I really love this course.', 'I learned the basics of causality inference and want even more now!', 'Excellent courses. I gain my expectations.', 'I was a novice in causal analysis. But I needed some education in counterfactual estimation. This course provided me with the necessary knowledge and tools. I especially enjoyed the matching, IPTW and IV chapters. Thank you!', 'Not only good for bio stats, it has also profound impact to my understanding of a/b testing in the internet world.', 'The best lecture series of causality', 'Excellent course! Can make it longer though and cover more details and latest advances and issues :-)', 'The material is great. Just wished the professor was more active in the discussion forum. Have not showed up in the forum for weeks. At least there should be a TA or something.', 'Excellent overview on causality inference and handling confounders combined with practical examples and R code.', 'enjoyed it very much', 'Great course for getting your hands dirty with some real causal methods. ', 'Excellent course! The lectures are very clear and easy to follow, and Professor Roy is really good at explaining the concepts in a simple way. The assignments in R are helpful for grasping the theoretical concepts. I would specially recommend this course to data scientist, who might be interested in complementing their predictive analytics skills with the the necessary ones to tackle questions about causality.', 'Good intro of the techniques.', 'This is a great course for anyone interested in learning more about Causality and models for its estimation. I am a physician with limited statistical knowledge, but was able to follow this course with little difficulty, including analysis in R (though I do know how to run STATA and command line). I would recommend this course to anyone interested in performing a propensity matching study.  ', 'To those with some advanced statistics background, this would truly be helpful to catch up econometric thought processes.', 'Amazing Course! Really Helpful. I would love to have a similar full-duration course :D', 'Thanks so much for providing this great lecture.', 'Works best on double speed (from settings menu of each video). Content is delivered in clear and relatable manner using interesting real world examples. ', "One of the best courses in Coursera, Professor with lots of experience in a backpack show how to tackle very complex problem of causal inference. This is a topic every data analyst should know doesn't matter which industry you work or learn.", 'I really enjoyed this course, the pace could be more even in parts. Sometimes the pace could be more even and some more books/reference material for further study would be nice.', 'This course is really fantastic for all levels. Very thorough explanations and helpful illustrations. Many thanks for putting this together!', 'This is an excellent course taught by a very competent professor in a very simple to understand and intuitive way.', 'gives thorough basic intro to causal inference']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mateusz K', 'By Wei F', 'By HEF', 'By Rudy M P', 'By Pichaya T', 'By Arnab S', 'By Hao L', 'By Takahiro I', 'By DR A N', 'By FKG', 'By Michael L', 'By Chang L', 'By Vikram R', 'By Miguel B', 'By Bob H', 'By Herman S', 'By JK', 'By Akash G', 'By Min-hyung K', 'By charlene e', 'By Vlad V', 'By Mark F', 'By Andrew', 'By Abdulaziz T B', 'By Arka B']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 07, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Apr 17, 2018', 'Feb 26, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2017', 'Aug 31, 2017', 'Sep 26, 2017', 'Aug 22, 2017', 'Nov 30, 2017', 'Nov 26, 2017', 'Sep 11, 2017', 'Mar 14, 2018', 'Apr 17, 2018', 'Oct 20, 2017', 'Oct 03, 2017', 'Oct 24, 2017', 'Jun 17, 2018', 'Jul 01, 2017', 'Jul 16, 2017', 'Apr 20, 2018', 'Dec 28, 2017', 'May 16, 2018', 'Aug 12, 2017', 'May 31, 2018']</review_date></doc>