<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_132</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/qualitative-methods</course_url><course_name>Qualitative Research Methods</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Gerben Moerman</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course you will be introduced to the basic ideas behind the qualitative research in social science. You will learn about data collection, description, analysis and interpretation in qualitative research. Qualitative research often involves an iterative process. We will focus on the ingredients required for this process: data collection and analysis.
You won't learn how to use qualitative methods by just watching video's, so we put much stress on collecting data through observation and interviewing and on analysing and interpreting the collected data in other assignments.
Obviously, the most important concepts in qualitative research will be discussed, just as we will discuss quality criteria, good practices, ethics, writing some methods of analysis, and mixing methods.
We hope to take away some prejudice, and enthuse many students for qualitative research.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Social Sciences.Governance and Society</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Amsterdam</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Philosophy of Qualitative Research//Observation//Good Practices &amp; Criteria//Qualitative Interviewing//Qualitative Analysis//Writing, mixing &amp; ethics//Catch up week//Exam week</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.0 Introduction', '1.1 On Elephants', '1.2 Ontology for social actors', '1.3 Ontology for social researchers', '1.4 Epistemology', '1.5 Hermeneutics', '1.6 Phenomenology', '1.7 Pragmatism'], ['2.1 Ethnography', '2.2 Participant Observation', '2.3 Views on Observation', '2.4 Observational Focus', '2.5 Cyclists in Amsterdam', '2.6 Privatizing Public Space', '2.7 Field Notes', '2.8 Fieldwork organisation', '2.9 Observation and Interpretation'], ['3.1 Flexibility', '3.2 Triangulation', '3.3 Abduction', '3.4 Focus on Details and Context', '3.5 Look for Contradiction', '3.6 Reflexivity', '3.7 How Many Cases Are Enough', '3.8 Theoretical Saturation', '3.9 Criteria For Research Quality'], ['4.1 Visions of Interviewing', '4.2 Typologies of Interviews', '4.3 Rapport in interviewing', '4.4 Powergame or Roleplaying', '4.5 Probing and prompting', '4.6 Probing tactics', '4.7 Interviewing, a final thought'], ['5.1 Qualitative Analysis', '5.2 Code and Retrieve', '5.3 Framework Analysis', '5.4 Analytic Induction', '5.5 Grounded Theory', '5.6 Versions of Grounded Theory'], ['6.1 Qualitative writing', '6.2 Mixing Methods', '6.3 How to mix', '6.4 Five Focal Points in Ethics', '6.5 Ethics - Visions &amp; Practices', '6.6 Ethical Boards &amp; Qualitative Research', '6.7 Fraud'], ['Catch up? Or do some more!'], ['Final Exam']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 29 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['It was awesome experience indeed. I have learned lot of things about Qualitative Research Methods. These lessons will help me a lot to do my personal research. Enjoyed that course much.', 'The content could have been more concise and more structured. Some assessments were also not clear, as one interpretation of the assessment would not always lead to scoring maximum points. ', "There was some very useful information and explanations in the course, such as the appropriate way to interpret and generalize qualitative data (something a lot of people often get wrong) and how to mindfully structure qualitative interviews. The lectures themselves were a bit fast and disorganized, and I often had difficulty knowing which information to pay close attention to and take notes on. The exams took me several attempts each because some of the material tested on was glossed over in the lectures, and I was unsure of the correct answer. The course is worth taking overall, there's some good stuff in here, but as it is now it can be a bit difficult and time-consuming.", 'It was very difficult for me to grasp the concepts explained in the course. One of the main reasons is that Professor explained the concepts in an abstract way without giving concrete examples. I have also taken the previous course Quantitative Methods. I would rate quantitative methods 5 out of 5 because the Professor used very simple examples (cat examples) and it helped to grasp the concept a lot. Unfortunately this was not the case in this course. I hope the Professor will do the needful to improve the course.', "Very interesting professor, but uses too much of the time for tangents. Very hard to understand assignments. really enjoyed the writing assignments as a creative project but I don't feel I was able to fully grasp the concepts despite getting good marks. ", 'Very helpful course for social researcher. As a design researcher, I have learnt how to analyse data more effectively.', 'Very very good course, I really enjoyed it and learned a lot. Congratulations to the course designer, to our so adorable professor Gerben Moergen and all the staff. One suggestion: change the assignment in week 5: is impossible, time consuming and at the end boring. ', 'Awesome course. But some portions of the course is not clear or properly structured from a new learners perspective. Assessment is quite rigorous, which I think is quite good only. Few assignment or things are difficult for a beginner to understand or follow.    ', 'Excellent course and interesting topic!', 'The best course on Qualitative Methods. A must for any one conducting serious research using qualitative methods. ', 'a complete joy! thanks!', 'Thank you for the course. The reading you have recommended for the course was really helpful!', "Outstanding lecturer - very engaging and clearly passionate about the subject. I also really enjoyed the practical aspect of some of the assignments - although it does mean you can't leave them to the night before the deadline!", 'It was a great learning experience. Being a sociology student  I had some idea of the basics but the kind of knowledge that has broadened for me is unimaginable and each and every lecture of Prof. Gerben is extremely interesting, ethusiactic and loaded with information. Looking forward to attend his classes in person someday soon.', 'I thoroughly enjoyed the course. I strongly reccomend this course! ', 'Eye-opening.', "I love the course, enjoyed the lectures and the assignments. It's worth doing this MOOC course. ", 'I really enjoyed this course. The professor is full of energy which made learning the material fun. ', 'Not bad. The exam questions could be formulated better.', 'Compared to the  Quantitative Methods, this one was more chaotic and not as structured/ Still, really good and the only thing that could be improved is to have the transcripts in pdfs and not just the ppts. \n\n', 'The course covers a lot of content and is a good introduction to the different aspects of qualitative research. However, i was a bit dissapointed with the content on coding, analysis and interpretation. I expected practical examples on the concepts taught rather than just theory.  At the end, i didnt feel that i had understood the practical aspects that is so required. ', 'I thoroughly enjoyed the course and have learnt a lot. The assignments were really helpful in improving the understanding. However, Providing correct answers for wrong attempts in the quiz would help in clearing our doubts. ', "This course was well designed and the content well chosen--I learned a great deal.  Some of the assignments would benefit from some tweaking --the instructions were not always clear---and I'd love to see the instructor incorporate more recent works of qualitative research, perhaps even touch on some of the AI methods that are emer", 'I got charged without being told...how does that happen?', 'I found this a very useful way of getting a basic introduction to qualitative research methods, without just sitting down with some text books.  The content was engaging and at the right level for me.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Md S H', 'By Bianca V', 'By Rebecca T', 'By Yasar M', 'By 55cuatx@gmail.com', 'By Nguyen T T', 'By VUB', 'By Ankit C', 'By Raditya B W', 'By Anindo B', 'By Stephen F', 'By Nalini', 'By Irene P', 'By sumedha', 'By Dinara Z ', 'By Victor H', 'By Madhulika S', 'By Naomi K', 'By Filip Č', 'By Maria C', 'By David M', 'By Desaraju S S', 'By Laura C', 'By OPARE A', 'By Kelda F']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 14, 2018', 'Mar 31, 2018', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Apr 10, 2018', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Jan 03, 2019', 'Apr 14, 2019', 'Apr 13, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Apr 28, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'Jul 05, 2019', 'Jun 03, 2019', 'Dec 21, 2018']</review_date></doc>