<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_152</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/text-retrieval</course_url><course_name>Text Retrieval and Search Engines</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>ChengXiang Zhai</course_instructor><course_introduction>Recent years have seen a dramatic growth of natural language text data, including web pages, news articles, scientific literature, emails, enterprise documents, and social media such as blog articles, forum posts, product reviews, and tweets. Text data are unique in that they are usually generated directly by humans rather than a computer system or sensors, and are thus especially valuable for discovering knowledge about people’s opinions and preferences, in addition to many other kinds of knowledge that we encode in text. 

This course will cover search engine technologies, which play an important role in any data mining applications involving text data for two reasons. First, while the raw data may be large for any particular problem, it is often a relatively small subset of the data that are relevant, and a search engine is an essential tool for quickly discovering a small subset of relevant text data in a large text collection. Second, search engines are needed to help analysts interpret any patterns discovered in the data by allowing them to examine the relevant original text data to make sense of any discovered pattern. You will learn the basic concepts, principles, and the major techniques in text retrieval, which is the underlying science of search engines.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Information Retrieval (IR)//Document Retrieval//Machine Learning//Recommender Systems</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Orientation//Week 1//Week 2//Week 3//Week 4//Week 5//Week 6</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Welcome Video', 'Course Introduction Video'], ['Lesson 1.1: Natural Language Content Analysis', 'Lesson 1.2: Text Access', 'Lesson 1.3: Text Retrieval Problem', 'Lesson 1.4: Overview of Text Retrieval Methods', 'Lesson 1.5: Vector Space Model - Basic Idea', 'Lesson 1.6: Vector Space Retrieval Model - Simplest Instantiation'], ['Lesson 2.1: Vector Space Model - Improved Instantiation', 'Lesson 2.2: TF Transformation', 'Lesson 2.3: Doc Length Normalization', 'Lesson 2.4: Implementation of TR Systems', 'Lesson 2.5: System Implementation - Inverted Index Construction', 'Lesson 2.6: System Implementation - Fast Search'], ['Lesson 3.1: Evaluation of TR Systems', 'Lesson 3.2: Evaluation of TR Systems - Basic Measures', 'Lesson 3.3: Evaluation of TR Systems - Evaluating Ranked Lists - Part 1', 'Lesson 3.4: Evaluation of TR Systems - Evaluating Ranked Lists - Part 2', 'Lesson 3.5: Evaluation of TR Systems - Multi-Level Judgements', 'Lesson 3.6: Evaluation of TR Systems - Practical Issues'], ['Lesson 4.1: Probabilistic Retrieval Model - Basic Idea', 'Lesson 4.2: Statistical Language Model', 'Lesson 4.3: Query Likelihood Retrieval Function', 'Lesson 4.4: Statistical Language Model - Part 1', 'Lesson 4.5: Statistical Language Model - Part 2', 'Lesson 4.6: Smoothing Methods - Part 1', 'Lesson 4.7: Smoothing Methods - Part 2'], ['Lesson 5.1: Feedback in Text Retrieval', 'Lesson 5.2: Feedback in Vector Space Model - Rocchio', 'Lesson 5.3: Feedback in Text Retrieval - Feedback in LM', 'Lesson 5.4: Web Search: Introduction &amp; Web Crawler', 'Lesson 5.5: Web Indexing', 'Lesson 5.6: Link Analysis - Part 1', 'Lesson 5.7: Link Analysis - Part 2', 'Lesson 5.8: Link Analysis - Part 3'], ['Lesson 6.1: Learning to Rank - Part 1', 'Lesson 6.2: Learning to Rank - Part 2', 'Lesson 6.3: Learning to Rank - Part 3', 'Lesson 6.4: Future of Web Search', 'Lesson 6.5: Recommender Systems: Content-Based Filtering - Part 1', 'Lesson 6.6:  Recommender Systems: Content-Based Filtering - Part 2', 'Lesson 6.7: Recommender Systems: Collaborative Filtering - Part 1', 'Lesson 6.8: Recommender Systems: Collaborative Filtering - Part 2', 'Lesson 6.9: Recommender Systems: Collaborative Filtering - Part 3', 'Lesson 6.10: Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 19 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Although I was very enthusiastic at the beginning of this course, my enthusiasm was soon replaced by disappointment.  There were several reasons for my disappointment:  First, it is very difficult to understand Prof. ChengXiang Zhai.  This is aggravated by the fact that the subtitles of his videos have not been edited and many of these subtitles do not really make any sense.  Furthermore, some of the quizzes check on material that is only covered in the week after the quiz.  Second, and more importantly, I was disappointed by the explanations offered by Prof. Zhai.  Often, he just drops some technical terms without giving any explanation whatsoever.  An example in point is his covering of the Kullback-Leibler divergence.  He just dropped the name but did not offer any definition or explanation.  Unfortunately, there were many more topics that were only covered in such a name dropping way.  In the end, I bought myself the book by Stefan Büttcher and the book by Christopher Manning.  These are excellent books that were also recommended by Prof. Zhai.  For anybody interested in information retrieval I would actually recommend to go directly to these books instead of taking this course.', "Literally this is a dead course. No one is active from course to assist students. You can't complete assignment 1 if you are not good with c++ and STL 'PERIOD'.", 'One of the best courses I have taken on Coursera. Really liked how the quizzes were structured!', "Sir is Amazing. Reviews saying this course lacks practicals are true. Fact is, you will be able to implement them on your own, as sir explained concepts pretty well. This is by far one of the best courses on coursera, comparable to Mr. Ng's course on ML and DL", 'Good one', 'help for building a whole picture about the field', 'very very good', '  It is a great course, highly recommended for those who wants to work in the AI  ', 'Excellent course. The only request I would have is to make honors programming assignment technology independent (I would have wanted to do it in R) and to add feedback on incorrect answers in quizzes so you can learn more easily from your istakes.', "Love the way the professor introduces the concepts, doesn't overwhelm the student!", 'Prof Zhai explains very clearly each models with their pros &amp; cons.', 'A great overview of text retrieval methods. Good coverage of search engines. A longer course will cover search engine better (remember this is a 6 weeker)', 'This course is complemented with a software and text (not mandatory) and good explanation with diagrams...\n', 'Itś a geat course, and the teacher shared his knowlege', 'Very interesting!', 'A well put together course, very rigorous and in-depth...', 'thanks', 'Excellent Introduction to Text Retrieval and Search Engines technologies.', ' Great!', 'much help for deep understanding of TR', 'Great insights in this course... I learned so much!!', 'thanks', 'Good Course', '我太喜欢这种课程编排模式了：导论，视频，测试，考试', 'Excellent course']</reviews><reviewers>['By Karl S', 'By Devender B', 'By Bilguun B', 'By Ashish G', 'By Ramakrishnan C', 'By Lena H', 'By Amrit S D', 'By Luong A T', 'By Codrin K', 'By Rajesh V', 'By Abhijit D', 'By Pankaj M', 'By Hardik J J', 'By Ben L', 'By Vidya S', 'By Isaiah M', 'By August F C', 'By bobblogger@gmail.com', 'By Arefeh Y', 'By leila S', 'By Jared C', 'By Paulina A Q M', 'By RISHABH T', 'By Goya Z', 'By Leandro O d N']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 30, 2018', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Dec 11, 2018', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Apr 13, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'May 13, 2018', 'Jul 11, 2016', 'Apr 04, 2018', 'Aug 29, 2016', 'Jun 26, 2016', 'Dec 25, 2016', 'Jun 24, 2017', 'Jan 08, 2018', 'Jul 07, 2016', 'Aug 16, 2016', 'Nov 07, 2016', 'Aug 13, 2016', 'Jun 08, 2016', 'Oct 11, 2016', 'Dec 18, 2017', 'Aug 13, 2016', 'Oct 03, 2017']</review_date></doc>