<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_154</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/recommender-systems-introduction</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Recommender Systems:  Non-Personalized and Content-Based</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Joseph A Konstan</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course, which is designed to serve as the first course in the Recommender Systems specialization, introduces the concept of recommender systems, reviews several examples in detail, and leads you through non-personalized recommendation using summary statistics and product associations, basic stereotype-based or demographic recommendations, and content-based filtering recommendations. 

After completing this course, you will be able to compute a variety of recommendations from datasets using basic spreadsheet tools, and if you complete the honors track you will also have programmed these recommendations using the open source LensKit recommender toolkit.  

In addition to detailed lectures and interactive exercises, this course features interviews with several leaders in research and practice on advanced topics and current directions in recommender systems.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Summary Statistics//Term Frequency Inverse Document Frequency (TF-IDF)//Microsoft Excel//Recommender Systems</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Minnesota</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Preface//Introducing Recommender Systems//Non-Personalized and Stereotype-Based Recommenders//Content-Based Filtering -- Part I//Content-Based Filtering -- Part II//Course Wrap-up</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Intro to Recommender Systems', 'Intro to Course and Specialization'], ['Movielens Tour', 'Preferences and Ratings', 'Predictions and Recommendations', 'Taxonomy of Recommenders I', 'Taxonomy of Recommenders II', 'Tour of Amazon.com', 'Recommender Systems: Past, Present and Future', 'Introducing the Honors Track', 'Honors: Setting up the development environment'], ['Non-Personalized and Stereotype-Based Recommenders', 'Summary Statistics I', 'Summary Statistics II', 'Demographics and Related Approaches', 'Product Association Recommenders', 'Assignment #1 Intro Video', 'Assignment Intro: Programming Non-Personalized Recommenders'], ['Introduction to Content-Based Recommenders', 'TFIDF and Content Filtering', 'Content-Based Filtering: Deeper Dive', 'Entree Style Recommenders -- Robin Burke Interview', 'Case-Based Reasoning -- Interview with Barry Smyth', 'Dialog-Based Recommenders -- Interview with Pearl Pu', 'Search, Recommendation, and Target Audiences -- Interview with Sole Pera', 'Beyond TFIDF -- Interview with Pasquale Lops'], ['Assignment #2 Introduction: Content-Based Filtering in a Spreadsheet', 'Honors: Intro to programming assignment'], ['Unified Mathematical Model', 'Psychology of Preference &amp; Rating -- Interview with Martijn Willemsen']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['One of the best courses I have taken on Coursera. Choosing Java for the lab exercises makes them inaccessible for many data scientists. Consider providing a Python version.', 'well one thing I am struggling with programming in JAVA. Would not it be handy to have option to do assignment using languages like python/R? which are basically language of choice for data scientists and also easy to have grasp on for newbies. one more thing some time I just get stuck and felt like now way out. I did not get any answer/help form posts on the forum . ', 'Too basic and too repetitive (the videos could be half as long)', 'good exercises &amp; lectures', 'Great course', 'I would like to have more detail and help for honors track especially for people like me who  do not have much programming experience and want to learn how to implement recommender system. I am unable to solve the assignment and i still need some help. Would be great if the solutions of the honors track should be available to those who want to learn and not just for the sake of getting certificate', 'I think I am on the right track to changing my career from java engineer from data scientist, this course is one of the best start point', 'Awesome. Worth it!', 'Курс очень понравился, спасибо большое за такую уникальную возможность вникнуть в суть рекомендательных систем!', 'Nice introduction to recommender systems for those who have never heard about it before. No complex mathematical formula (which can also be seen by some as a downside). ', 'Un profesor excelente y un temario muy bueno. También me han gustado mucho las entrevistas y los recorridos por las páginas web que tienen recomendadores. ', 'great professors and inspiring lectures!', 'Exceptional quality.The course content is comprehensive and practical enough applied at workplaces.', 'Really good course to get started with recommendation systems! ', 'Great, thorough introduction with tracks for both Java programmers and non-programmers.', 'Excellent course taught in simple language.', 'great!! Let me better understand the research and practical fields!', 'Thank you very much!', 'Pretty good', 'An excellent in-depth introduction into the concepts around recommendation systems!', 'I think this is an amazing course for beginners who are interested in recommender systems, I strongly recommend this course to the students and engineers who are working on recommender systems.', "As a software engineer with computer science background I found that course enhancing my knowledge. I'm going to continue the specialization.", 'Fantastic course. Lecturers have extensive experience in this field. Lectures include interviews with people who have successfully implemented recommender systems in their products or who are researching the permutations, challenges and extensions to recommender system development. Not only does the course provide the chance to build your own recommender systems (optional) but also highlights the complexities and opportunities for refining and improving recommendations. I highly recommend this course to anyone building recommendation systems.', 'great overview of the breadth of material to get started', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Benjamin S S', 'By Rashid K', 'By Nicolás A', 'By Mai H S', 'By Mustafa S', 'By sidra n', 'By tao L', 'By sagar s', 'By Тефикова А Р', 'By Daniel P', 'By Sonia F', 'By Shuang L', 'By Seema P', 'By Luis D F', 'By Patrick D', 'By S A', 'By Light0617', 'By Julia E', 'By 姚青桦', 'By Ashwin R', 'By Yuncheng W', 'By Pawel S', 'By Tash B', 'By Dan T', 'By Rosni L']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 13, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2018', 'Jun 28, 2018', 'Jan 20, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2018', 'Jul 22, 2018', 'Oct 04, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2016', 'Dec 08, 2017', 'Feb 06, 2017', 'Nov 21, 2017', 'Jan 07, 2017', 'Apr 17, 2017', 'Jun 25, 2017', 'Jun 30, 2017', 'Jul 19, 2017', 'Nov 08, 2017', 'Oct 16, 2017', 'Jun 26, 2017', 'Nov 03, 2016', 'Dec 11, 2016', 'Jun 27, 2018', 'Oct 31, 2017', 'Oct 04, 2016']</review_date></doc>