<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_164</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/computervision-imageprocessing</course_url><course_name>Image Processing, Features &amp; Segmentation</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Radhakrishna Dasari</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course empowers learners to develop image processing programs and leverage MATLAB functionalities to implement sophisticated image applications. It provides a rich explanation of the fundamentals of computer vision’s lower- and mid-level tasks by examining several principle approaches and their historical roots. By the end of the course, learners are prepared to analyze images in frequency domain. Topics include image filters, image features and matching, and image segmentation.   

This course is ideal for anyone curious about or interested in exploring the concepts of computer vision. It is also useful for those who desire a refresher course in mathematical concepts of computer vision. Learners should have basic programming skills and experience (understanding of for loops, if/else statements), specifically in MATLAB (Mathworks provides the basics here: https://www.mathworks.com/learn/tutorials/matlab-onramp.html).  Learners should also be familiar with the following: basic linear algebra (matrix vector operations and notation), 3D co-ordinate systems and transformations, basic calculus (derivatives and integration) and basic probability (random variables).   
  
Material includes online lectures, videos, demos, hands-on exercises, project work, readings and discussions. Learners gain experience writing computer vision programs through online labs using MATLAB* and supporting toolboxes.

This is the second course in the Computer Vision specialization that lays the groundwork necessary for designing sophisticated vision applications. To learn more about the specialization, check out a video overview at https://youtu.be/OfxVUSCPXd0. 

 * A free license to install MATLAB for the duration of the course is available from MathWorks.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Algorithms</course_category><course_tag>Image Processing//Image Segmentation//Computer Programming//Matlab</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>University at Buffalo</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Image Processing Fundamentals//Image Filters//Image Features &amp; Matching//Image Segmentation</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Image Processing', 'Image Processing Basics', 'Intensity Transformations', 'Color Image Processing'], ['Spatial Image Filtering', 'Filtering in Frequency Domain', 'Multi-Resolution Processing &amp; Compression', 'Morphological Image Processing', 'Advanced Image Processing'], ['Image Features', 'Scale Invariant Image Features', 'Feature Matching', 'Creating a Panorama', 'Texture Matching'], ['Introduction to Image Segmentation', 'State-of-the-Art Image Segmentation', 'Early Segmentation Techniques', 'Segmentation &amp; Clustering', 'Probabilistic Segmentation', 'Graph Cut Segmentation']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 23 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Overall is a very steep learning curve, mostly on discussion among students to figure out the solutions of the assignments. Not much example in the lecture videos.', 'The course is missing a lot of slides that are referenced in the lectures.', '课程太垃圾', "Some parts of the video lectures are missing and the coding exercises don't match what we learn so it's very hard to complete them.", 'I put 2 because the course exists and covers important foundations for anyone who wants to learn computer vision.', "Lectures are incomplete, exercises are not well written. Staff is not helpful. Don't go with Computer Vision Specialization By University of Buffalo it is complete waste of time and money. ", 'Very Bad', "I have not completed the course yet but the lectures are incomplete. It's really difficult to understand the missing parts of the lectures. Please look in to the ambiguity. Thank you. ", 'This course is a fraud ! Coursera should audit the quality of their content to maintain high standards !', 'The material is incomplete as are the lectures. Multiple topics are mentioned as "let us see in the following example about k-means...." from which the lesson just ends or the lecturer jumps to another aspect with no explanation of the material. From initial suspect I would hold the editing team at fault for not adding (what I hope) is material that the professors submitted. I had already paid for a month and as such did not withdraw from this course. Only aspect I learned is names of procedures used and my skills at googling them. ', 'Poor content. Poor quality of video lectures. Poor study material.', 'This meant  to be a great course. ', "This course is far more worse than the first one in the specialization. The MATLAB tool doesn't work. Plain awful.", 'Very less slides and there is lot of grading problems']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mun T Y', 'By Steve S', 'By Liu J', 'By OUHMID F', 'By Brice L', 'By Namit K S', 'By Sai A R', 'By Kush S', 'By Osama H', 'By Melvin D M', 'By Jayant I', 'By Irina R', 'By Mikael B', 'By Ashish D']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 06, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Aug 14, 2019', 'Aug 18, 2019', 'Aug 21, 2019', 'Jun 14, 2019', 'May 31, 2019', 'Jun 19, 2019', 'Jul 28, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2019', 'Aug 17, 2019', 'Sep 12, 2019', 'Sep 13, 2019']</review_date></doc>