<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_29</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/tensorflow-sequences-time-series-and-prediction</course_url><course_name>Sequences, Time Series and Prediction</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Laurence Moroney</course_instructor><course_introduction>If you are a software developer who wants to build scalable AI-powered algorithms, you need to understand how to use the tools to build them. This Specialization will teach you best practices for using TensorFlow, a popular open-source framework for machine learning.

In this fourth course, you will learn how to build time series models in TensorFlow. You’ll first implement best practices to prepare time series data. You’ll also explore how RNNs and 1D ConvNets can be used for prediction. Finally, you’ll apply everything you’ve learned throughout the Specialization to build a sunspot prediction model using real-world data!

The Machine Learning course and Deep Learning Specialization from Andrew Ng teach the most important and foundational principles of Machine Learning and Deep Learning. This new deeplearning.ai TensorFlow Specialization teaches you how to use TensorFlow to implement those principles so that you can start building and applying scalable models to real-world problems. To develop a deeper understanding of how neural networks work, we recommend that you take the Deep Learning Specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Forecasting//Machine Learning//Tensorflow//Time Series//prediction</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>deeplearning.ai</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Sequences and Prediction//Deep Neural Networks for Time Series//Recurrent Neural Networks for Time Series//Real-world time series data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction, A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Time series examples', 'Machine learning applied to time series', 'Common patterns in time series', 'Introduction to time series', 'Train, validation and test sets', 'Metrics for evaluating performance', 'Moving average and differencing', 'Trailing versus centered windows', 'Forecasting'], ['A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Preparing features and labels', 'Preparing features and labels', 'Feeding windowed dataset into neural network', 'Single layer neural network', 'Machine learning on time windows', 'Prediction', 'More on single layer neural network', 'Deep neural network training, tuning and prediction', 'Deep neural network'], ['Week 3 - A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Conceptual overview', 'Shape of the inputs to the RNN', 'Outputting a sequence', 'Lambda layers', 'Adjusting the learning rate dynamically', 'RNN', 'LSTM', 'Coding LSTMs', 'More on LSTM'], ['Week 4 - A conversation with Andrew Ng', 'Convolutions', 'Bi-directional LSTMs', 'LSTM', 'Real data - sunspots', 'Train and tune the model', 'Prediction', 'Sunspots', 'Combining our tools for analysis', 'Congratulations!', 'Specialization wrap up - A conversation with Andrew Ng']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The first week has some interesting discussion of time series data and some traditional non-ML methods for forecasting, but beyond that the course quickly divulges the all too familiar weaknesses of this specialization; lack of depth, elementary discussion, weak insight into common problems that arise during training models, and extremely poorly written quizzes that don't test the learner's gain of knowledge or skills in any meaningful way.", "Finally, wasted my weekend and 40 euros to finish this shitty specialization.  I really dont know the target audience of this specialization.  If you have no background of deep learning, going through some code snippets without any explanation wont help you at all. you  can't know anything behind it. If you already have some knowledge, you will find nothing new and more in this course. 1) The materials are so shallow and without any depth, just reading the slides and codes with errors. Only some high-level keras APIs are covered. The official tensorflow tutorial is much better. 2) The test questions are of no value at all, it cant test any your understanding whether about deep learning or the tool tensorflow. The assignments are poorly designed, the answers contains errors. 3) I strongly doubt the instructor, I think he does not have much ML experience.  Please don't waste your money and time on this specialization. If you want to learn deep learning, go to cs230; cs231n for computer vision; cs224n and cs224u for NLP; cs20 for Tensorflow.", 'Very superficial presentation of the material, and disappointing content given all the initial hype.  Whatever happened to working with WaveNet?  The 4 weeks to complete the course is a massive over-estimate.  Expect to spend not more than a day going through the course.  Quiz questions are very low value and do not test any understanding.', 'Very weak course, shallow, lacks content. Can be "learned" in a few hours, not weeks. Really hoped to see a working ML model for a time sequence,  but the examples shown in this course do not demonstrate why bother with ML. If these examples were middle-school home work, they would be graded D+(keep trying or better use other methods). The instructor doesn\'t come across as an experienced ML practitioner.  ', 'Quite a good light-weighted course on Time Series and Prediction. It was quite helpful for people like me who are seeking ways to implement the concepts.', "This was really a beautifully designed course. They didn't focused on teaching too much of thing at once but build up the base slowly and strongly for better understanding.", 'Unfortunately, These whole Specialization didnt match my expectations. I finished whole Deep Learning Specialization and I LOVED IT. Before starting this one I had very good feeling about this specialization; however I learned very little. Most of the videos are like "this code does this and this code does this and this line does this and this function does this etc. " . A bit disappointed, but still learned some.', "The material is great and the presentation elevated and professional. Few thoughts nonetheless: a) i know time series, came here for specific advice on how to tune models. I was extremely disappointed. Stationarity is mentioned at the very beginning but then it fades as if it was completely irrelevant to ML. b) there is more than one contradiction in the presentation. MAE is going up yet the presenter says that it got better??? That I think would be really confusing, particularly for novice learners. c) black boxes: I acknowledge that there are so many decisions and choices one needs to make when setting up a training model. Wouldn't it be relevant to highlight them and explain how different decisions impact the outcome? This course was failing on that. ", 'Thank you guys for this course!', 'I quickly learned a lot about how to represent time series and sequence data for prediction tasks, and how to combine different deep learning techniques together to get high-quality predictions. Another great course! ', 'Really cool course. Great material. Great presenter. Enjoy!', 'Time series was new material and really appreciated this class for that reason. ', 'It was an amazing experience to learn from such great experts in the field and get a complete understanding of all the concepts involved and also get thorough understanding of the programming skills.', 'Excellent course to take after completing Deep Learning Specialization ', 'Fantastic course, starting from basic fundamentals of statistical forecasting to using Convolutional neural networks. I will use my learnings directly to my job.', 'The specialization was packed with best practice fundamentals and I appreciated the explanations and lab work. My only concern is the lack of business focused problem sets that might bring us more up to speed with industry.', 'I think there should be graded problem sets for effective learning.', 'Thanks for the lesson for me to learn more about Tensorflow! ', 'Great course to get first hand experience of using Tensorflow on deep learning.', 'I recommend it to those who want to start TS analysis with tf.keras. Lots of good stuff to learn.', 'Very useful. Thanks!', 'This course is amazing and above my expectations! Very good exercises, good speed, well communicated. The instructor made me feel very comfortable and was able to take many things away. Excellent content and very knowledgeable instructor!', 'Awesome course.', 'Excellent course and learned a lot', 'Good course to understanding basic of time series implementation in Tensorflow.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Asad K', 'By Fengjun W', 'By Steve H', 'By Irina G', 'By Subhadeep D', 'By Marghoob K', 'By Kaan A', 'By Silviu M', 'By Sergei A', 'By Christopher G', 'By Stewart A', 'By Colin M', 'By Ojas R', 'By Mostafa G', 'By Gurpreet', 'By Daniel E', 'By Kota M', 'By Kevin C', 'By Yuning C', 'By Mahdi P', 'By Oleksandr M', 'By Adhikari M T B A', 'By Mats E', 'By Nilesh M', 'By Sanjay M']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 18, 2019', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 03, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Aug 07, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Aug 12, 2019', 'Aug 13, 2019', 'Aug 14, 2019', 'Aug 15, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2019', 'Aug 16, 2019']</review_date></doc>