<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_241</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/causal-inference</course_url><course_name>Causal Inference</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Michael E. Sobel</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course offers a rigorous mathematical survey of causal inference at the Master’s level.

Inferences about causation are of great importance in science, medicine, policy, and business.  This course provides an introduction to the statistical literature on causal inference that has emerged in the last 35-40 years and that has revolutionized the way in which statisticians and applied researchers in many disciplines use data to make inferences about causal relationships.  

We will study methods for collecting data to estimate causal relationships. Students will learn how to distinguish between relationships that are causal and non-causal; this is not always obvious. We shall then study and evaluate the various methods students can use — such as matching, sub-classification on the propensity score, inverse probability of treatment weighting, and machine learning — to estimate a variety of effects — such as the average treatment effect and the effect of treatment on the treated. At the end, we discuss methods for evaluating some of the assumptions we have made, and we offer a look forward to the extensions we take up in the sequel to this course.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>3.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Columbia University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>MODULE 1: Key Ideas//Module 2: Randomization Inference //MODULE 3: Regression//Module 4: Propensity Score//Module 5: Matching//Module 6: Special Topics</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Overview', 'Lesson 1: Causation', 'Lesson 2: Potential Outcome, Unit and Average Effects', 'Lesson 3: Ignorability: Bridging the Gap Between Randomized Experiments and Observational Studies'], ['Lesson 1: Some Randomized Experiments', 'Lesson 2: Testing the Null Hypothesis of No Treatment Effect', 'Lesson 3: Randomization Inference'], ['Lesson 1: Estimating the Finite Population Average Treatment Effect (FATE) and the Randomized Treatment Effect', 'Lesson 2: Estimating the ATE: A Regression Approach', 'Lesson 3: Estimating the ATE: Regression Analysis with Covariates'], ['Lesson 1: The Propensity Score', 'Lesson 2: Estimating the ATE Using Sub-Classification on the Propensity Score', 'Lesson 3: Estimating the ATE Using Inverse Probability of Treatment Weighting'], ['Lesson 1: Matching 1', 'Lesson 2: More on Matching-Bias and Standard Errors'], ['Lesson 1: Regression Based Estimators and Double Robustness', 'Lesson 2: Machine Learning and Estimation of Treatment Effects', 'Lesson 3: The Unconfoundedness Assumption: Assessment and Sensitivity']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['It is a very good intro to CI with proofs and references to recent developments.', 'It was difficult to follow lectures without any kind of reading ', 'Not having access to slides and materials negates any interest in proceeding with this course.', 'Great course. Really interesting and condensed content. A perfect course for analysts and data scientists. I will be recommending this to a few of my colleagues.  ', 'The selection of material is excellent and the professor covers an amazing amount of ground in a handful of lectures. Currently, however, there are many superficial problems with the course, including repeated errors in the quizzes and lectures that are confusing because the slides are missing. ', "A good course. Lot's of insights on Propensity Score Matching. They show good references to those willing to read some articles. Although quick classes, exercises are easy and very practical. "]</reviews><reviewers>['By Agnes v B', 'By Seo-Woo C', 'By Byron S', 'By Max B', 'By Charles H', 'By Lucas B']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 04, 2019', 'May 15, 2019', 'Oct 30, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Jun 06, 2019']</review_date></doc>