<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_340</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/validity-bias-epidemiology</course_url><course_name>Validity and Bias in Epidemiology</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Filippos Filippidis</course_instructor><course_introduction>Epidemiological studies can provide valuable insights about the frequency of a disease, its potential causes and the effectiveness of available treatments. Selecting an appropriate study design can take you a long way when trying to answer such a question. However, this is by no means enough. A study can yield biased results for many different reasons. This course offers an introduction to some of these factors and provides guidance on how to deal with bias in epidemiological research. In this course you will learn about the main types of bias and what effect they might have on your study findings. You will then focus on the concept of confounding and you will explore various methods to identify and control for confounding in different study designs. In the last module of this course we will discuss the phenomenon of effect modification, which is key to understanding and interpreting study results. We will finish the course with a broader discussion of causality in epidemiology and we will highlight how you can utilise all the tools that you have learnt to decide whether your findings indicate a true association and if this can be considered causal.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>Validity//Interaction (Statistics)//Information bias//Confounding//Selection Bias</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Module 1: Introduction to Validity and Bias//MODULE 2: Confounding//MODULE 3: Dealing with Confounding//MODULE 4: Effect Modification</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Course', 'Validity', 'Selection Bias', 'Information Bias'], ['Introduction to Confounding', 'Criteria for Confounding', 'Criteria for Confounding: An Example'], ['Controlling for Confounding at the Design Stage', 'Controlling for Confounding at the Design Stage: Example', 'Controlling for Confounding at the Analysis Stage', 'Controlling for Confounding at the Analysis Stage: Example', 'Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs)'], ['Effect Modification', 'Confounding vs Effect Modification', 'Causation', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent concise course on the fundamental aspects of epidemiology related to validity, bias, confounding and effect modification.', 'Excellent course, very complete. ', 'This course my favourite out of the 3 within the Epidemiology Specialisation.', 'GOOD', 'Cobrehesive, Illustrated in an easy not complicated approach, I enjoyed it', 'Excellent. Bias, Confounding and Effect modifier are important issues to consider in a research. I indicate for all professionals to learn because is crucial to select scientific studies with confidence grade and as well do researchers more accurate. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Bruno A M P B', 'By Fernando R U G', 'By Deleted A', 'By Ranjeet S M', 'By hala', 'By Deusdenir d S M']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 18, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019']</review_date></doc>