<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_143</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/conversational-experiences-dialogflow</course_url><course_name>Building Conversational Experiences with Dialogflow</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course provides a deep dive into how to create a chatbot using Dialogflow, augment it with Cloud Natural Language API, and operationalize it using Google Cloud tools.

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this course you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Computer Science.Software Development</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to the course//Building conversational experiences with Dialogflow//Defining Intents and Entities//Maintaining context and taking actions//Taking your chatbot to production//Additional Features//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction', 'Getting Started with Google Cloud Platform and Qwiklabs'], ['What is a conversational experience ?', 'Chatbot journey and challenges', 'Build engaging conversational interfaces with Dialogflow', 'Life of a conversation', 'Your chatbot workflow'], ['Defining intents for your agent', 'Identifying entities in your intent', 'Module Review'], ['Maintaining context in your conversation', 'Taking actions with Fulfilment'], ['Taking your chatbot to production', 'Demo: Setup knowledge base in Cloud Datastore', 'Deploying a webhook for fulfilment', 'Building a custom UI', 'Demo: Deploy a webhook and setup custom UI', 'Securing the webhook', 'Demo: Securing the webhook with basic authentication', 'Integrations', 'Module Review'], ['Voice enablement', 'Versions and Environments', 'Knowledge Connector', 'Spelling Correction'], ['Course Review']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["First of all, I naturally learned about Dialogflow, what it can do and I got a little preview of how it does it. It was not at all exhausting and I feel like even though there are two bigger projects in this course, neither was truly finished and neither used the full ppotential of the tool. However, the most annoying part is that every lab requires you to configure everything anew, and especially with labs 4 and 5 I did not really see the need to break them into separate parts, since there was little to do in either of them. I do not know if it was only my problem, but for labs 4 and 5 I could not read the instructions, because they did not load. Another thing is that it seems like the GCP changed its interface a little bit since the course was created and they did not update the instructions accordingly. This is not something that will stop you from completing the course, but it's pretty annoying and somewhat time-consuming. I liked the first week a lot better than the second, because I did not experience any technical problems with it and I felt like I could have really gotten a hands-on experience with Dialogflow.", 'Good introduction. There is some errors in quicklabs.', 'This course we really helpful in understanding the power of Google cloud services I would like to go further with other courses ', 'A good course covering the basics of Dialogflow. The labs on Pizza ordering bot were great and gave a practical hands-on experience of Dialogflow', 'Easy to learn,  excellent structured, it motivates to advance in learn chatbots.', "Good introductory course! I'd like to see in the future more regarding how to implement advanced slot filling features, how to deal with variations/possible permutations in order of parameters, and how to integrate with external api's", 'That was a really good online course. It taught real knowledge in a very effective way. Although I already did some things with Google Dialogflow, I learned a lot of new things and could intensify already existing knowledge. Thank you!', 'This course was very helpful! I highly recommend people who are working on bot-development and virtual agent development should take this course!', 'Very informative and simple to follow along with. You do need to know a small bit of python to follow the logic in the labs. ', 'Good chat bot course', 'Excellent course!!!', "Thanks a lot for this course. I like everything especially the labs It's the most interesting part. I can not wait to start applying what I learn in this project to my final project! ", 'EXCELLENT !!', 'Very useful to start learning it from a scratch to advanced level. Help me a lot for linking external knowledge base sources and publish a web chatbot on my website by using all Google platform.', 'I had to create a POC for miy firm, involving conversational agent. This course was just what I needed to start working. Very Useful and simple.', 'This was a great course and with lots of content tough in an easy way. Maybe there could be a link for the Python script that explains the script.', 'Beautifully designed course! Helped me a great deal to understand how to build conversational experiences across a range of devices using Dialogflow!', 'It was a good course. Covered all necessary topics and explained enough. However, the way labs are setup and limited help when facing errors, it makes difficult to progress.', 'It was Great', 'It was a brilliant course but the only problem I had were with the labs. There were some inconsistencies which made it difficult as a first time user. This occurred only in Week 2 labs. But the content and the explanations were brilliant.', 'The course is overall well structured and provides a good understanding on the capabilities of Dialogflow.', 'The lab activities were not that well prepared. I believe this course should be longer. The hour and a half intended for each lab is not enough to fully explore all of DialogFlow features.', "Lab4 and 5 didn't work, otherwise it is a good course, especially week1 is very helpful!", 'very good experience of developing a chatbot', "This course is basic level and didn't meet my expectation. I am expecting advanced functionalities such as mass import of intents, training pharses and responses via scripting because intents to upload into chatbot may have thousands of records. It is lacking in-depth on governance for how to structure the intents."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Katarzyna S', 'By Carl S', 'By Piyush S', 'By Akshat B', 'By german a n a', 'By Julio Q', 'By Christoph P', 'By Yoshiyuki I', 'By Darryl T ', 'By Abhishek K S', 'By Jonathan C', 'By Heba A H A', 'By SHREERAM A I', 'By Wittaya P', 'By Luca A', 'By Florian Z', 'By Muhammad N B', 'By Abhay S', 'By BYEONGHAK J', 'By Suraj D', 'By ENRICO C', 'By Samantha D', 'By Ting C', 'By k v k', 'By Kyaw K']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 18, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Mar 29, 2019', 'Jun 26, 2019', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Apr 24, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Jul 03, 2019', 'Jul 08, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2019', 'Aug 14, 2019', 'Jun 12, 2019', 'Jun 15, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Jun 12, 2019', 'Aug 19, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2019', 'Sep 13, 2019', 'Sep 15, 2019', 'May 21, 2019', 'Aug 04, 2019']</review_date></doc>