<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_115</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-social-network-analysis</course_url><course_name>Applied Social Network Analysis in Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Romero</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will introduce the learner to network analysis through tutorials using the NetworkX library. The course begins with an understanding of what network analysis is and motivations for why we might model phenomena as networks. The second week introduces the concept of connectivity and network robustness. The third week will explore ways of measuring the importance or centrality of a node in a network. The final week will explore the evolution of networks over time and cover models of network generation and the link prediction problem. 

This course should be taken after: Introduction to Data Science in Python, Applied Plotting, Charting &amp; Data Representation in Python, and Applied Machine Learning in Python.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Graph Theory//Network Analysis//Python Programming//Social Network Analysis</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Michigan</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Why Study Networks and Basics on NetworkX//Network Connectivity//Influence Measures and Network Centralization//Network Evolution</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Networks: Definition and Why We Study Them', 'Network Definition and Vocabulary', 'Node and Edge Attributes', 'Bipartite Graphs', 'TA Demonstration: Loading Graphs in NetworkX'], ['Clustering Coefficient', 'Distance Measures', 'Connected Components', 'Network Robustness', 'TA Demonstration: Simple Network Visualizations in NetworkX'], ['Degree and Closeness Centrality', 'Betweenness Centrality', 'Basic Page Rank', 'Scaled Page Rank', 'Hubs and Authorities', 'Centrality Examples'], ['Preferential Attachment Model', 'Small World Networks', 'Link Prediction']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Going into this course, I was really disappointed that I had to take this course for a Data Science Specialization because at a skin-deep level it seemed very irrelevant, and frankly I was at that state of mind until week 4 of this course. ', 'This course is a good introduction to graph theory. Its contents are interesting and the lecturer did a great job explaining them. So, what is the problem? The problem is that the course is not called "Applied Graph Analysis in Python" but "Applied Social Network Analysis in Python". This incongruity in the title of the course (intentional or not) will generate erroneous expectations in the students, especially if we consider that they have to take the course to finish the specialization. Regarding the assignments, they are divided into two groups: trivial tasks that are solved with a single line of code extracted from the NetworkX manual and more complex tasks related to Machine Learning that do not involve putting into practice the concepts of this course but those of the third course of the specialization. I regret being so tough, but my impression on this course is that it is filler content designed just to have a five course specialization instead of four.', 'The lectures are good. However, the assignments are poor: very simple exercises with toy examples, but far away from real applications. Moreover, I spent most of the time (particularly in the last assignment) trying to deal with the autograder. ', "This is hands down the best taught course in the speciality. The instructor explains concepts in the videos clearly and the assignment questions are structured and interesting. Do note that the assignment in week 4 does pull together the whole specialisation in a real world problem, so if you aren't taking the whole speciality you will need a knowledge of Pandas and SKLearn. Personally I thought it was pitched at just the right level because the ML work is just enough to have to go through the process, without any complicated feature optimisation.", 'This is by far my favorite Coursera course - well organized contents and intuitive example!', 'Great course, maybe even the best on this great specialization!', 'it is good but we are looking  for more real practices ', 'Very useful', 'I got a bit the wrong impression from the title, but it was throughout the course very interesting to learn about Graphs. A welcome addition to the course would be a cheat sheet with the most important quantities. ', 'A completely new area for me, and a really fascinating course.', 'The course and the tutor are great.', 'Great job!', 'Excellent delivery and content.', 'This is a great course for 2 reasons.  The earlier assignments were just difficulty enough to reinforce the lectures.  The last assignment was challenging enough to bring the entire specialization to to satisfying close.  After finishing assignment 4, I really feel that I can apply the learning from this specialization to real work.', 'A nice intro to networks in Python', 'The course covered many relevant topics and was very easy to follow and apply to the real world. ', 'good', 'It was great introducing the networks, but I found most of the assignments too straightforward except for the last weeks.', 'Gave me a very good understanding of the basic concepts ', 'Great course. The lectures are taught clearly. The knowledge gained in this course is very useful in real world.  ', "It was a wonderful course, linked network's models and machine learning.", 'An excellent course that provides a fair knowledge of social networks, the NetworkX package and how to work with networks in Python.', 'great', 'Just the greatest class to sum up what is going on in the crazy network media and using what we have learned.', 'Great!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Aziz J', 'By Oliverio J S J', 'By Luis d l O', 'By David M', 'By Wei W', 'By Daniel W', 'By Ahmad H S', 'By SONIA D', 'By Alexander G', 'By charles l', 'By Nikolay S', 'By Michael K', 'By PREMAL M', 'By CMC', 'By Kristin A', 'By Aya', 'By Akash G', 'By Varga I K', 'By ABDUL N M', 'By Agnes H', 'By Roberto L L', 'By Suyash D', 'By Deleted A', 'By Phillip L C', 'By ZHUOFU L']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 28, 2017', 'Feb 25, 2018', 'Mar 02, 2018', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 15, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Mar 23, 2019', 'Mar 26, 2019', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2019']</review_date></doc>