<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_69</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/statistical-inference</course_url><course_name>Statistical Inference</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian Caffo, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>Statistical inference is the process of drawing conclusions about populations or scientific truths from data. There are many modes of performing inference including statistical modeling, data oriented strategies and explicit use of designs and randomization in analyses. Furthermore, there are broad theories (frequentists, Bayesian, likelihood, design based, …) and numerous complexities (missing data, observed and unobserved confounding, biases) for performing inference. A practitioner can often be left in a debilitating maze of techniques, philosophies and nuance. This course presents the fundamentals of inference in a practical approach for getting things done. After taking this course, students will understand the broad directions of statistical inference and use this information for making informed choices in analyzing data.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Probability and Statistics</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Statistical Inference//Statistical Hypothesis Testing</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1: Probability &amp; Expected Values//Week 2: Variability, Distribution, &amp; Asymptotics//Week: Intervals, Testing, &amp; Pvalues//Week 4: Power, Bootstrapping, &amp; Permutation Tests</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introductory video', '02 01 Introduction to probability', '02 02 Probability mass functions', '02 03 Probability density functions', '03 01 Conditional Probability', "03 02 Bayes' rule", '03 03 Independence', '04 01 Expected values', '04 02 Expected values, simple examples', '04 03 Expected values for PDFs'], ['05 01 Introduction to variability', '05 02 Variance simulation examples', '05 03 Standard error of the mean', '05 04 Variance data example', '06 01 Binomial distrubtion', '06 02 Normal distribution', '06 03 Poisson', '07 01 Asymptotics and LLN', '07 02 Asymptotics and the CLT', '07 03 Asymptotics and confidence intervals'], ['08 01 T confidence intervals', '08 02 T confidence intervals example', '08 03 Independent group T intervals', '08 04 A note on unequal variance', '09 01 Hypothesis testing', '09 02 Example of choosing a rejection region', '09 03 T tests', '09 04 Two group testing', '10 01 Pvalues', '10 02 Pvalue further examples', 'Just enough knitr to do the project'], ['11 01 Power', '11 02 Calculating Power', '11 03 Notes on power', '11 04 T test power', '12 01 Multiple Comparisons', '13 01 Bootstrapping', '13 02 Bootstrapping example', '13 03 Notes on the bootstrap', '13 04 Permutation tests']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is a fucking shitshow. Not only does Brian Caffo not explain anything, he has a tremendous gift to confuse people and make them forget / not understand anymore what they already knew. Great fucking course. Not. Hated it from the first minute.', "When you start statistics with practical examples, people tend to presume certain things (e.g. independence is given like in munchausen example) so I sort of understand this desire to keep every definition abstract/pure for solid foundations but damn, this course goes way too far. I took statistics at uni and this was a refresher on the specialisation track but the way Bayes' rule was covered made me doubt what I knew. Oh also, the instructor does some of my biggest pet peeves which are (1) using his preferred notations without actually reading it out loud first (2) unnecessary use of synonyms which just distract me from what he actually means (3) reading from slides without any context as to how these concepts are used.  ", "The teach methods changed too drastically starting with this course.  Much more prerequisite knowledge is required then is included int his concentration course set. No foundation or warning is given regarding this change and prerequisites.  I had to seek out and spend countless hours on many other learning resources to get through this course and still don't understand what this course was trying to teach.", "The information is so important and useful, but I found the presentation of the material to be fast and not very interesting, and therefore it was hard for me to retain the material. I learned a lot, but I would need to invest a lot more time to realllyyy grasp everything in the course. It wasn't presented in a way that made it easy to learn, so I need to spend more time going back over things to really get it. ", 'At this point in the specialization, I was really worn out by the effort that I needed to put into this course (I solved the homework questions too). While I have no problem with the math, some topics like power should not even have been discussed or should have just been discussed in passing. Caffo spent a whole week on that. After taking the Applied Data Science in Python Specialization, I have a feeling like this course and Regression Models can just be merged, while logistics regression could just be transferred to the machine learning course. ', "I couldn't make it through this course because I can't stand looking at the instructor's face on the screen. It is very distracting. He is also not very clear in his whiteboard explanations, too much scribbling. I prefer courses taught by Roger Peng.", 'Good Course to Learn the statistical Inference ', "This is an excellent course, though it is fast-paced. I didn't have time to watch the lectures and also do the practice exercises in Swirl in the time allotted. As usual, the time estimates for completion are wonky.  I ended up just watching the lectures and taking the tests, which is far from ideal (I am taking some time to do those valuable exercises now that the course is done).  Although I got 100% in the course, I felt the learning experience could have been better as a result.", 'The material is obviously invaluable but I thought the lectures themselves were lacking.', "There're lots of practice on manually construct statistics. I'm not sure if it's necessary to do that since we could just use R code to do it. I think how to interpret it and use these statistics in examples would be more important. There're some examples, but could be more and interpret more in depth if there were less focus on the calculation.", 'My most recent experience with statistics was about 2 years ago, and it was college level statistics. Still, I find this class is hard to keep up sometimes. In general, I felt like the professor explaining too much on the mathematical meaning behind equations instead of talking about the real-world meaning of equation components, and why those calculation make sense.', 'A lot of material to cover - can be a strain, but well explained for the most part.', 'Not my favorite course in the series, but I did learn a lot. I highly recommend following along with the course book provided in the course. The videos alone are not enough. I also recommend printing out a sheet with statistical formulas to use (not provided from the course, but you can find easily on the web). The stat sheet with formula helped me connect all the dots and better understand when to use a formula. ', 'Poorly organized content and the lectures are presented in a confusing way.  The lecturer obviously knows the material well, but is not able to present it well.  He should use more sample problems annd examples.  In addition, I am having trouble getting my submission graded, although I have already graded 6 fellow students.', "The only reason for enrolling is to complete the data science specialization, though it may make you reconsider continuing with it. The instructor and provided materials fail to adequately explain the concepts this course is supposed to cover, and do not prepare students for the quizzes or assignments. If you don't know statistics you won't learn it here. If you know statistics, you don't need this course.   ", "I've taken several statistics, data science, and R courses.  This is one of the worst.  I took others' advice, and I also strongly suggest looking to other sources to learn Statistical Inference before taking this course.  Khan Academy, DataCamp, Udacity, Duke (Coursera), and Columbia (edX) all have great courses.  Though they vary in depth, each leaves you with a good understanding of the concepts they teach.", "Dr Brian DeCaffo is a talented and forward thinking educator. The amount of supplementary material he brings to the course is a bountiful bonus that really helped me grasp concepts. One of the best courses I've taken on Coursera.", 'Outstanding course.Thanks Coursera for providing such a good platform wherein we can attend courses of top instructor/College.', 'really great course! takes a few minutes to get used to Brian after having all courses taught by Roger. I finally understand hypothesis testing and confidence intervals after taking several classes on this topic. ', 'very helpful for my  future', 'Amazing course', 'The course starts from very basic probability piece which is great for beginners and covers all relevant topics. I found that some of the topics difficult to grasp. However I did supplement this course by seeing Youtube videos from jbstatistics and Marins stat lectures.', 'this course really provides me a insight into statistical inference. Thanks, Brian!', "Excellent course if you have some background in math or stats already. This course might be difficult if you don't have that background. The peer graded assignment does a good job tying everything together in my opinion.", 'Not only did this course help me to understand concepts that I have encountered in my job over the length of my career, but it also introduced me to using R Markdown, which will come in handy for future projects.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Roman', 'By Pinar T', 'By Deshina B B', 'By Rebecca K', 'By Yusuf E', 'By Nina', 'By Savitri', 'By Don M', 'By Michael S', 'By Dai Y', 'By Mingda W', 'By Robert K', 'By Andrew', 'By Anthony M', 'By Stephen G', 'By Joshua A B', 'By Tarek L', 'By Surya P T', 'By Angela K', 'By Toshin H', 'By Yash J', 'By Sanil S', 'By LIWANGZHI', 'By Matthew S', 'By Marc T']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 22, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'May 21, 2018', 'Jul 21, 2017', 'Jan 29, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Aug 26, 2018', 'Aug 16, 2018', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'Apr 16, 2019', 'May 05, 2019', 'Sep 03, 2018', 'Oct 25, 2016', 'May 29, 2016', 'Dec 13, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 04, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Jan 18, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019']</review_date></doc>