<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_345</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-project</course_url><course_name>Big Data - Capstone Project</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Ilkay Altintas</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to the Capstone Project for Big Data! In this culminating project, you will build a big data ecosystem using tools and methods form the earlier courses in this specialization. You will analyze a data set simulating big data generated from a large number of users who are playing our imaginary game "Catch the Pink Flamingo". During the five week Capstone Project, you will walk through the typical big data science steps for acquiring, exploring, preparing, analyzing, and reporting. In the first two weeks, we will introduce you to the data set and guide you through some exploratory analysis using tools such as Splunk and Open Office. Then we will move into more challenging big data problems requiring the more advanced tools you have learned including KNIME, Spark's MLLib and Gephi. Finally, during the fifth and final week, we will show you how to bring it all together to create engaging and compelling reports and slide presentations. As a result of our collaboration with Splunk, a software company focus on analyzing machine-generated big data, learners with the top projects will be eligible to present to Splunk and meet Splunk recruiters and engineering leadership.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Big Data//Neo4j//Knime//Splunk</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Simulating Big Data for an Online Game//Acquiring, Exploring, and Preparing the Data//Data Classification with KNIME//Clustering with Spark//Graph Analytics of Simulated Chat Data With Neo4j//Reporting and Presenting Your Work//Final Submission</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Big Data Capstone Project', 'Welcome from Splunk: Rob Reed World Education Evangelist', 'A Summary of Catch the Pink Flamingo', 'A Conceptual Schema for Catch the Pink Flamingo'], ['Downloading the Game Data and Associated Scripts', 'Understanding the CSV Files Generated by the Scripts', 'Optional Review of Splunk', '“Catch the Pink Flamingo” Data Exploration with Splunk', 'Aggregate Calculations Using Splunk', 'Filtering the Data With Splunk'], ['Review:  Classification Using Decision Tree in KNIME', 'Review:  Interpreting a Decision Tree in KNIME', 'Workflow Overview for Building a Decision Tree in KNIME', 'Description of combined_data.csv'], ['Informing business strategies based on client base', 'Practice with PySpark MLlib Clustering'], ['Understanding the Simulated Chat Data Generated by the Scripts', 'Graph Analytics of Catch the Pink Flamingo Chat Data Using Neo4j'], ['Week 5: Bringing It All Together'], ['Congratulations! Some Final Words...']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 19 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Really disappointed with the Virtual Machine related exercises throughout the whole course, not only the capstone, where literally I have spent more time trying to figure out how to make it work and do not get any error message than actually learning big data. Very very frustrating.For sure not going to recommend this course to any friend.', 'This course deserves no starts. There were no instructors answering the many questions raised by the students. There were no explanations for wrong answers, and so no opportunity to learn. I was helping other students understand the assignments, and spent extra time grading submissions as no teaching assistants were available to help.', 'Course is well designed and structured.', "waoh.. it's incredible.. .. I strongly recommend this Capstone Project. Be sure to put on frank effort.", 'Very nice project! Uses a lot of the knowledge acquired in a funny way!!', 'All the sessions were very informative and provided the required knowledge from basics. ', 'This is great platform to enhance your skills with periodic learning even from busy schedule and make yourself in pace with new IT.', "it's really useful to practice what you've learned in the previous course.", 'nice final course to close out the whole specialization program.', 'We can actually take a look in some other methods, when we finalize the course, you can send some bibliography or something else', 'Congratulations for the course preparation and thank you all. It was a very exciting investiment I have performed and I have also learned how to think differently on problem analysis after taking this course.', 'Good course.', 'PERFECT', 'This is very helpful project where i have applied all learning through ouot journey of this course.Though it was time consuming but worth to invest time, which benefits to upskill my knowledge', 'My name is Jose Antonio from Brazil. I am looking for a new Data Scientist career (https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseantonio11).', 'Thank you Coursera and instructors for creating this course. The structure is very good. Looking forward for completing other specializations too. Thank you!!', 'Best course for integrating all the concepts learned during specialization. ', 'Excellent total review of all courses', 'Loved the final Capstone Project.', 'This is all you can expect from an online course, imho:', 'What a challenge, I came into this course as  a London Black Cab Taxi Driver, I thought the knowledge was hard but this capstone was a challenge more intense than the Knowledge of London!!!', 'Big Thank you....', 'This course is really helpful. Hands on project work was great.', 'it was amazing and i have learn a lot from this course', 'This has been excellent Learning experience.Instructor and fellow  members shared their valuable information during the course of the Learning and Capstone Project phase. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Edorta', 'By Dag S', 'By Tejprakash U', 'By Jamiil T A', 'By Rafael F d N', 'By NARESH D', 'By Samir V M', 'By Mahamat N A M', 'By Raunak S', 'By Juan J R M', 'By Caio S', 'By Pijush K G', 'By Mohamed H', 'By Payal', 'By Jose A R N', 'By Krati S', 'By Akshay V', 'By ZIKIF H L', 'By Ankur K', 'By Christoph R', 'By donald m', 'By Venkata B P T', 'By Prasad G', 'By Mahmoud M K', 'By Rambabu A']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 17, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2017', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Nov 24, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Jul 11, 2018', 'Sep 15, 2018', 'Aug 29, 2018', 'Sep 02, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Nov 14, 2018', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Aug 07, 2017', 'Aug 08, 2017', 'Oct 22, 2017', 'Mar 13, 2018', 'Apr 14, 2018', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2017', 'Jul 09, 2017', 'May 16, 2018']</review_date></doc>