<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_204</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-intelligence-tools</course_url><course_name>Business Intelligence Concepts, Tools, and Applications</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jahangir Karimi</course_instructor><course_introduction>This is the fourth course in the Data Warehouse for Business Intelligence specialization. Ideally, the courses should be taken in sequence.  In this course, you will gain the knowledge and skills for using data warehouses for business intelligence purposes and for working as a business intelligence developer. You’ll have the opportunity to work with large data sets in a data warehouse environment and will learn the use of MicroStrategy's Online Analytical Processing (OLAP) and Visualization capabilities to create visualizations and dashboards. 

The course gives an overview of how business intelligence technologies can support decision making across any number of business sectors. These technologies have had a profound impact on corporate strategy, performance, and competitiveness and broadly encompass  decision support systems, business intelligence systems, and visual analytics. Modules are organized around the business intelligence concepts, tools, and applications, and the use of data warehouse for business reporting and online analytical processing, for creating visualizations and dashboards, and for business performance management and descriptive analytics.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Business Intelligence//Data Analysis//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Microstrategy</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado System</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Decision Making and Decision Support Systems//Business Intelligence Concepts and Platform Capabilities//Data Visualization and Dashboard Design// Business Performance Management Systems//BI Maturity, Strategy, and Summative Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction Video Lecture', 'Overview of Decision Making Video Lecture', 'Conceptual Foundations of Decision Making Video Lecture', 'Decision Support Systems Video Lecture', 'Decision Making Support in Practice Video Lecture'], ['BI Concepts Video Lecture', 'BI Platform Capabilities Video Lecture', 'Training Video for Microstrategy Desktop BI Capabilities', 'Business Reporting Video Lecture', 'BI OLAP Styles Video Lecture'], ['Data Visualization Video Lecture', 'Data Visualization Guidlines and Pitfalls Video Lecture', 'Comprehensive Training Video for Showing Data Visualization Steps', 'Performance Dashboards Video Lecture', 'Dashboard Design Guidelines and Pitfalls Video Lecture', 'Comprehensive Training Video for Creating Dashboard Using Advanced Visualization'], ['Business Performance Management Video Lecture', 'Performance Measurement System Video Lecture', 'Balanced Scorecards Versus Six Sigma Video Lecture', 'Training Video for MicroStrategy Desktop Business Performance Analysis', 'Business Analytics Video Lecture'], ['BI Maturity Video Lecture', 'BI Strategy Video Lecture', 'Course Closing Video']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course contains many references to external materials. For answers to some questions in quiz it is necessary to study external materials. I do not have time for this. In my opinion, all the information for the quiz must be contained in the attached presentation.', "this course is great in concept. but the reality was disappointing and will have to improve. the professor gave lots of links to interesting external materials. but his prepared lectures were much briefer and consisted mostly of presenting bullet-point lists. as a result, i found myself studying just to pass the quizes and not to actually enhance my knowledge. :( given the high standard of the other courses in this specialization, i'm sure it will be better next time....", None, 'Basically just a product demo and the lecturer was very hard to comprehend.', "This course is not interesting when compared to previous courses 1,2 and 3. Its hard to comprehend the lectures and the training videos provided for Microstrategy doesn't provide much support when it comes to assignments. I feel that the overall exposure to Microstrategy tool we get through this course is very minimal.", "Very slow course, there are significant redundancies. The resource links are often obsolete, and there's a really high number of errors on slides - the kinds that would really mess up somebody's career, if they worked in BI.", "Is this course an advertisement for Microstrategy ? A lot of videos come directly from the company. I don't have anything against that company, but business and learning are 2 very different things. The link with Microstrategy seems to have led to lazyness : so many low-effort contents (assignments directly taken out of the Microstrategy website, poor structure of shared documents, etc.), endless auto-promotion of the book of the teacher. I really felt like the CEO of Microstrategy was kind enough to share with me his views on BI (which might be the goal of Microstrategy with their partnership with the university). I am not happy having paid for this. The other courses of the specialization are great though. Please remove and rework this particular Course 4 from the specialization.", 'a very low quality course', 'Compared to the other Coursera course I attended ,this one is by far the least useful one. The instructor is super brief and his slides are mostly made of a list of acronyms!', 'Very good intro to BI concepts and Microstrategy.', 'The materials was good', 'Business Intelligence given me new life to me', 'Great course, good to know Microstrategy tool.', 'Thank you for all.', None, '  The Course is well laid out with plenty of assignments that allow you master the BI by using Microstrategy.  Thanks to professor Karimi, it was by far the best BI course that I have ever taken. ', 'Great course. To the point.', 'Loved it.', 'Great course! The professor is very knowledgeable and the materials are up to date with the current industry trends. I was able to apply the concepts learnt in this course in my job.', 'Enjoyable course much to learn', '\n', 'Direct and briefed to the point.', 'Good Course', 'Nice Course', 'Great, many resources.. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Рустам Р', 'By Robert L', 'By Jason B', 'By Michael P', 'By Meena S K', 'By ILYA S', 'By Olivier R', 'By Yuval Z', 'By aycha t', 'By Heath W', 'By BENSON E A', 'By SANJEEVE K G', 'By Matheus Z', 'By Alexander K', 'By Juan C G', 'By Navid A', 'By Maximilian M', 'By Salil T', 'By Bidyut H', 'By Shivam S', 'By Akshay D', 'By Mahmoud K', 'By Kalyani K', 'By RANA S P S', 'By Marek P']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 10, 2018', 'May 31, 2016', 'Jan 25, 2017', 'Oct 02, 2016', 'Jul 25, 2018', 'Feb 19, 2018', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Jan 06, 2018', 'Sep 26, 2016', 'Mar 24, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jul 27, 2018', 'May 30, 2017', 'May 15, 2017', 'Mar 25, 2016', 'Jun 25, 2018', 'Aug 08, 2016', 'Mar 25, 2016', 'Jun 29, 2017', 'Jun 23, 2016', 'Apr 20, 2016', 'May 25, 2016', 'Jun 06, 2016', 'Oct 30, 2016']</review_date></doc>