<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_106</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/ai</course_url><course_name>Applied AI with DeepLearning</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Romeo Kienzler</course_instructor><course_introduction>&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this course you agree to the End User License Agreement as set out in the FAQ.  Once enrolled you can access the license in the Resources area &lt;&lt;&lt;

This course, Applied Artificial Intelligence with DeepLearning, is part of the IBM Advanced Data Science Certificate which IBM is currently creating and gives you easy access to the invaluable insights into Deep Learning models used by experts in Natural Language Processing, Computer Vision, Time Series Analysis, and many other disciplines. We’ll learn about the fundamentals of Linear Algebra and Neural Networks. Then we introduce the most popular DeepLearning Frameworks like Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, DeepLearning4J and Apache SystemML. Keras and TensorFlow are making up the greatest portion of this course. We learn about Anomaly Detection, Time Series Forecasting, Image Recognition and Natural Language Processing by building up models using Keras on real-life examples from IoT (Internet of Things), Financial Marked Data, Literature or Image Databases. Finally, we learn how to scale those artificial brains using Kubernetes, Apache Spark and GPUs.

IMPORTANT: THIS COURSE ALONE IS NOT SUFFICIENT TO OBTAIN THE "IBM Watson IoT Certified Data Scientist certificate". You need to take three other courses where two of them are currently built. The Specialization will be ready late spring, early summer 2018

Using these approaches, no matter what your skill levels in topics you would like to master, you can change your thinking and change your life. If you’re already an expert, this peep under the mental hood will give your ideas for turbocharging successful creation and deployment of DeepLearning models. If you’re struggling, you’ll see a structured treasure trove of practical techniques that walk you through what you need to do to get on track. If you’ve ever wanted to become better at anything, this course will help serve as your guide.

Prerequisites: Some coding skills are necessary. Preferably python, but any other programming language will do fine. Also some basic understanding of math (linear algebra) is a plus, but we will cover that part in the first week as well.

If you choose to take this course and earn the Coursera course certificate, you will also earn an IBM digital badge.  To find out more about IBM digital badges follow the link ibm.biz/badging.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Machine Learning//Deep Learning//Long Short-Term Memory (ISTM)//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to deep learning//deep learning frameworks//DeepLearning Applications//scaling and deployment</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['A warm welcome from John Cohn, IBM Fellow Watson IoT', 'Introduction - Romeo Kienzler', 'Introduction - Ilja Rasin', 'Introduction - Niketan Pansare', 'Introduction - Tom Hanlon', 'Course Logistics', 'Cloud Architectures for AI and DeepLearning', 'Linear algebra', 'Deep feed forward neural networks', 'Convolutional Neural Networks', 'Recurrent neural networks', 'LSTMs', 'Auto encoders and representation learning', 'Methods for neural network training', 'Gradient Descent Updater Strategies', 'How to choose the correct activation function', 'The bias-variance tradeoff in deep learning'], ['Intoduction to TensorFlow', 'Neural Network Debugging with TensorBoard', 'Automatic Differentiation', 'Introduction video', 'Keras overview', 'Sequential models in keras', 'Feed forward networks', 'Recurrent neural networks', 'Beyond sequential models: the functional API', 'Saving and loading models', 'What is SystemML (1/2) ?', 'What is SystemML (2/2) ?', 'Demo - How to use Apache SystemML on IBM DSX (1/3)', 'Demo - How to use Apache SystemML on IBM DSX (2/3)', 'Demo - How to use Apache SystemML on IBM DSX (3/3)', 'Introduction to DeepLearning4J', 'Demo: Running Java in Data Science Experience', 'DL4J Neural Network Code Example, Mnist Classifier', 'PyTorch Installation', 'PyTorch Packages', 'Tensor Creation and Visualization of Higher Dimensional Tensors', 'Math Computation and Reshape', 'Computation Graph, CUDA', 'Linear Model'], ['Introduction to Anomaly Detection', 'How to implement an anomaly detector (1/2)', 'How to implement an anomaly detector (2/2)', 'How to deploy a real-time anomaly detector', 'Introduction to Time Series Forecasting', 'Stateful vs. Stateless LSTMs', 'Batch Size', 'Number of Time Steps, Epochs, Training and Validation', 'Trainin Set Size', 'Input and Output Data Construction', 'Designing the LSTM network in Keras', 'Anatomy of a LSTM Node', 'Number of Parameters', 'Training and loading a saved model', 'Classifying the MNIST dataset with Convolutional Neural Networks', 'Image classification with Imagenet and Resnet50', 'Autoencoder - understanding Word2Vec', 'Text Classification with Word Embeddings'], ['Run Keras Models in Parallel on Apache Spark using Apache SystemML', 'Creating and Scaling a Keras Model in ApacheSpark using DL4J', 'Creating and Scaling a Keras Model in ApacheSpark using DL4J (Demo)', 'Computer Vision with IBM Watson Visual Recognition', 'Text Classification with IBM Watson Natural Language Classifier']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['No clarity in lectures. IBM platform set up is too complicated and confusing.', "Uninformative, undidactic, very poorly explained. One of the worst courses I've taken.", ' I like very much the architecture-based approach of these courses/ specialization.', 'This is an excellent course in teaching me not only the deep learning principles but also practical usecases and various frameworks.', "This course is good for people who want to learn ML as a black box, also the scaling part was really rush. I'd advice the constructors to take full sessions for apache spark and DL4J separatly. Overall i enjoyed.", "Could not do assignments because the IBM Cloud was terribly shlow or crashed. Eventually it did load but i had to find out that my old IBM Cloud account had expired and could not be moved to the new free and unlimed offer. I need to open a new account with a different e-mail account ... Are you kidding? I'm not sure if the crashes were related to this problem but all in all this was an experience that convinced me to stay clear of the IBM cloud. ", 'Module sequence could have been better sequenced... ', 'mais propaganda dos serviços da ibm do que conteúdo... honestamente, eu fiquei mais tempo brigando com a interface do watson pra conseguir executar os notebooks na versão que os caras usam do que programando', 'I am sorry to say, but this by far the most unimpressive course I have taken at coursera.  If I just wanted someone to go through a jupyter notebook, without caring to explain much,  why do I need to take a course.   Compared to other excellent courses I have taken/audited at coursera, I would rate this as sub par.  Worst part about this was, it sounded very incoherent. Seems like no body actually verified the content and assignments to actually make sure they are consistent. ', 'Great course and superb professor Romeo. !! ', 'A nice intro to TensorFlow, Keras, SystemML, DL4J and Apache Spark!', None, 'good', 'Great course with several hands-on assignments. Highly recommend.', 'The course is great!', 'No easy...But was supprise to have got enrolle for the course: Applied AI with DeepLearning', 'Awesome knowledge !!', 'Excellent way of teaching concepts', 'Very good data science specialization covering many interesting advanced technologies!', 'Good rich  examples, but videos are hard to understand. Some instructors talk to fast even on    0.75 video speed, other talk to slow and due to accent subtitles full of *INAUDIBLE* parts. Also it will be good if  instructors will pay more attention when replying on forums. When i receive exactly same solution which i tried and it did not work, i left pretty confused', 'Curso muito bom! Recomendo! Parabéns principalmente ao senhor Romeo, pelo desenvolvimento do curso.', 'Very Helpfull and Full support from the instructor', 'Useful information course have. There are some challenges. ', 'very effective with hands on experience', 'This course presents a good overview of various practical approaches used in nowadays AI.']</reviews><reviewers>['By sada n', 'By RUBEN A', 'By Edoardo B', 'By Quang N L', 'By Saurabh K', 'By Merem Y', 'By Bryon B', 'By Matheus S', 'By Muhammad', 'By Khawar A A', 'By Riku S', 'By Ayesha S', 'By Waleed M S A A A G', 'By Ramachandra R K', 'By Fernando C', 'By Ray H A L', 'By PURNANAND    W', 'By Azeezur R', 'By Sven', 'By Frakc S', 'By Marcus S', 'By subham m', 'By mahmut k', 'By Bhaswar B', 'By Ivan P']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 20, 2018', 'Oct 18, 2018', 'Aug 22, 2018', 'Apr 09, 2019', 'Dec 20, 2018', 'May 10, 2018', 'May 03, 2018', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Mar 24, 2018', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Feb 22, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Oct 19, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Mar 21, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2018', 'Apr 29, 2018', 'Apr 16, 2018', 'Apr 21, 2018', 'Apr 06, 2018']</review_date></doc>