<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_279</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-collection-framework</course_url><course_name>Framework for Data Collection and Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Frauke Kreuter, Ph.D.</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will provide you with an overview over existing data products and a good understanding of the data collection landscape. With the help of various examples you will learn how to identify which data sources likely matches your research question, how to turn your research question into measurable pieces, and how to think about an analysis plan. Furthermore this course will provide you with a general framework that allows you to not only understand each step required for a successful data collection and analysis, but also help you to identify errors associated with different data sources. You will learn some metrics to quantify each potential error, and thus you will have tools at hand to describe the quality of a data source. Finally we will introduce different large scale data collection efforts done by private industry and government agencies, and review the learned concepts through these examples. This course is suitable for beginners as well as those that know about one particular data source, but not others, and are looking for a general framework to evaluate data products.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Collection//Data Quality//Data Analysis//Data Generating Process</course_tag><course_rating>4.2</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Maryland, College Park</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Research Designs and Data Sources//Measurements and Analysis Plan//Quality Framework//Application of TSE Framework to Existing Surveys</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Research Question Design', 'Types of Data', 'Examples of Found Data', 'Visualizing the Data Generation Process', 'Data Curation', 'Data Analysis', 'Access Issues', 'Access Resources', 'Summary'], ['Issues with Inductive Reasoning', 'Planning on What You Want to Observe', 'Planning on How to Collect Data', 'New Modes', 'Web and Google', 'Choosing a Mode'], ['Quality of Data', 'Inference', 'Survey Life Cycle from a Design Perspective - Measurement', 'Survey Life Cycle from a Design Perspective - Representation', 'Survey Lifecycle from a Process Perspective', 'Survey Lifeycle from a Quality Perspective', 'Survey Lifecycle from a Quality Perspective (II) - Metrics', 'Survey Lifecycle from a Quality Perspective (III) - Coverage and Sampling'], ['NCVS', 'NSDUH', 'SCA', 'NAEP', 'BRFSS', 'CES', 'SHARE', 'ESS']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['perfect', ' BEST', 'This was fast and comprehensive.  I had trouble getting through the length of some of the readings, but there were all relevant.  I love the combination of short videos, outlines, readings and quizzes.  This definitely was more than just a certification.  I have increased my confidence in meetings on this topic and my mastery in my field.', 'This provided a great overview of the survey design course. ', 'This great course and a good foundation for the specialization. The lecturer is amazing and experienced. I really enjoyed this one.', 'The course is wounder full and highly informative.', 'Excellent introductory course!', 'This is a rare course that teaches data collection framework from the ground up.', 'This is an excellent introductory course.  It provides the learners with all the basic information required to understand surveys.', 'Great course within the specialization on survey data collection and analysis', 'Great overview of designed and organic data collection! I feel more confident interpreting and understanding survey results and providing input on community-based research projects. Some of the readings were challenging for me because I have not studied statistics, but it was a welcome challenge. I plan to return to some of the course materials after completing a stats 101 course. ', 'thank you', 'Well made course content. One recommendation, please include more examples.', 'Great overview of data collection and analysis. ', 'Compreh', 'I', 'This course is no joke. I struggled. I do not have a background in statistics or research but took it as pro dev for what I do in my job as a system administrator (admin for our university\'s survey tool). Excellent content, great introduction. Opened my eyes to how much I DON"T know. Will be pursuing the rest of the specialization.', 'Stunning cutting-edge topic to convey Data Science results.', 'Awesome course,awesome presenter!', 'One of the most informative courses I have ever taken. ', 'Great overview of the survey process. Instructor presented information in a concise manner. Highly recommended. ', 'Wonderful beginners guide to the Framework for Data Collection and Analysis. The lecturer was superb!', 'very enjoyable. Excellent scene-setter for more in depth treatments of other aspects of survey-led quant research.', "It's very interesting information about survey design!", 'Excellent course with sufiecient materials provided']</reviews><reviewers>['By Musharavati E M', 'By JOSHUA E ', 'By Lindsey Z', 'By Jonathan T', 'By Abdirahman M', 'By Nazakat A', 'By Jaime A', 'By Do H L', 'By Ahmed I', 'By Oussama M', 'By Meagan S', 'By Eshak I M B', 'By Rahul R', 'By Chaundra W', 'By Romulo N U', 'By Karene G', 'By Michelle C', 'By Juan M', 'By OGBUOJI P', 'By Zubair F A', 'By Samuel K A', 'By Teh L L', 'By Eric H', 'By aline p m', 'By Thomas A K']</reviewers><review_date>['Feb 25, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Apr 11, 2019', 'Aug 23, 2017', 'Aug 28, 2017', 'Aug 09, 2016', 'Jun 22, 2016', 'Aug 07, 2016', 'Oct 27, 2017', 'Mar 25, 2017', 'May 08, 2017', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Jul 24, 2016', 'Aug 18, 2017', 'Dec 28, 2016', 'Jan 30, 2017', 'Nov 28, 2016', 'Jul 21, 2017', 'Feb 23, 2017', 'Aug 11, 2016', 'Oct 30, 2017', 'Apr 15, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'Sep 04, 2017']</review_date></doc>