<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_235</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-science-k-means-clustering-python</course_url><course_name>Foundations of Data Science: K-Means Clustering in Python</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr Matthew Yee-King</course_instructor><course_introduction>Organisations all around the world are using data to predict behaviours and extract valuable real-world insights to inform decisions. Managing and analysing big data has become an essential part of modern finance, retail, marketing, social science, development and research, medicine and government.

This MOOC, designed by an academic team from Goldsmiths, University of London, will quickly introduce you to the core concepts of Data Science to prepare you for intermediate and advanced Data Science courses. It focuses on the basic mathematics, statistics and programming skills that are necessary for typical data analysis tasks. 

You will consider these fundamental concepts on an example data clustering task, and you will use this example to learn basic programming skills that are necessary for mastering Data Science techniques. During the course, you will be asked to do a series of mathematical and programming exercises and a small data clustering project for a given dataset.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>K-Means Clustering//Machine Learning//Programming in Python</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week 1: Foundations of Data Science: K-Means Clustering in Python//Week 2: Means and Deviations in Mathematics and Python//Week 3: Moving from One to Two Dimensional Data//Week 4: Introducing Pandas and Using K-Means to Analyse Data//Week 5: A Data Clustering Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome and Introduction', 'Introduction to Data Science', 'What is Data?', 'Types of Data', 'Machine Learning', 'Supervised vs Unsupervised Learning', 'K-Means Clustering', 'Preparing your Data', 'A Real World Dataset'], ['2.0: Week 2 Introduction', '2.1 – Introduction to Mathematical Concepts of Data Clustering', '2.2 – Mean of One Dimensional Lists', '2.3 – Variance and Standard Deviation', '2.4 Jupyter Notebooks', '2.5 Variables', '2.6 Lists', '2.7 Computing the Mean', '2.8 Better Lists: NumPy', '2.9 Computing the Standard Deviation', 'Week 2 Conclusion'], ['Week 3 Introduction', '3.1 Multidimensional Data Points and Features', '3.2 Multidimensional Mean', '3.3 Dispersion: Multidimensional Variables', '3.4 Distance Metrics', '3.5 Normalisation', '3.6 Outliers', '3.7 Basic Plotting', '3.7a Storing 2D Coordinates in a Single Data Structure', '3.8 Multidimensional Mean', '3.9 Adding Graphical Overlays', '3.10 Calculating the Distance to the Mean', '3.11 List Comprehension', '3.12 Normalisation in Python', '3.13 Outliers and Plotting Normalised Data', 'Week 3 Conclusion'], ['Week 4 Introduction', '4.1: Using the Pandas Library to Read csv Files', '4.1a: Sorting and Filtering Data Using Pandas', '4.1b: Labelling Points on a Graph', '4.1c: Labelling all the Points on a Graph', '4.2: Eyeballing the Data', '4.3: Using K-Means to Interpret the Data', 'Week 4: Conclusion'], ['Introduction to Week 5', '5.1 Can a Machine Detect Fake Notes?', '5.2 Working for a Client', '5.3 How to Organize Work on Your Project', '5.4 Dealing With Difficulties', '5.5 No Data no Data Science: Introduction of the Dataset', '5.6 Modelling', '5.7 Presenting the Project Results', '5.8 Concluding Remarks']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 26 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course is at right level for a beginner (python and analytics) while going into details around K means clustering ', '184/5000', 'Good introduction to k-means clustering using Python. Easy for follow.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Aditya', 'By Guillermo A R', 'By Anton S']</reviewers><review_date>['Jun 04, 2019', 'Sep 10, 2019', 'Aug 17, 2019']</review_date></doc>