<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_73</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/sas-programming-basics</course_url><course_name>Getting Started with SAS Programming</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Stacey Syphus</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course is for users who want to learn how to write SAS programs to access, explore, prepare, and analyze data. It is the entry point to learning SAS programming for data science, machine learning, and artificial intelligence. It is a prerequisite to many other SAS courses.

By the end of this course, you will know how to use SAS Studio to write and submit SAS programs that access SAS, Microsoft Excel, and text data. You will know how to explore and validate data, prepare data by subsetting rows and computing new columns, analyze and report on data, export data and results to other formats, use SQL in SAS to query and join tables.

Prerequisites:
Learners should have experience using computer software. Specifically, you should be able to understand file structures and system commands on your operating systems and access data files on your operating systems. No prior SAS experience is needed.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>SAS</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview and Data Setup//Essentials//Accessing Data//Exploring and Validating Data//Preparing Data//Analyzing and Reporting on Data//Exporting Results//Using SQL in SAS</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Course!', 'Demo: Programming in SAS', 'Practicing in This Course', 'How to Set Up the Course Files in SAS OnDemand for Academics', 'How to Set Up Course Files for SAS University Edition'], ['Overview', 'SAS Programming Interfaces', 'Demo: Programming with SAS Studio', 'SAS Program Structure', 'SAS Program Syntax', 'Demo: Understanding SAS Program Syntax', 'Demo: Finding and Resolving Syntax Errors'], ['Overview', 'Types of Data', 'What is a SAS Table?', 'Required Column Attributes for SAS Tables', 'Listing Table and Column Attributes', 'Accessing Data in a Program', 'Using a Library to Read SAS Data', 'Automatic SAS Libraries', 'Demo: Exploring Automatic SAS Libraries', 'Using a Library to Read Other File Types', 'Demo: Using a Library to Read Excel Files', 'Importing Unstructured Data', 'Demo: Importing a Comma-Delimited (CSV) File', 'Importing an Excel File'], ['Overview', 'Exploring Data with Procedures', 'Demo: Exploring Data with SAS Procedures', 'Filtering Rows with the WHERE Statement', 'Combining Expressions in a WHERE Statement', 'Demo: Filtering Rows with Basic Operators', 'Using Special WHERE Operators', 'Creating and Using Macro Variables', 'Demo: Filtering Rows Using Macro Variables', 'Formatting Data Values in Results', 'Common Formats for Numeric Values', 'Common Formats for Date Values', 'Demo: Formatting Data Values in Results', 'Sorting Data', 'Identifying and Removing Duplicates', 'Demo: Identifying and Removing Duplicate Values'], ['Overview', 'Using the DATA Step to Create a SAS Data Set', 'DATA Step Processing', 'Demo: Working with the DATA Step', 'Demo: Using Expressions to Create New Columns', 'Using Numeric Functions to Create Columns', 'Demo: Using Character Functions', 'Demo: Using Date Functions', 'Demo: Conditional Processing with IF-THEN', 'Conditional Processing with IF-THEN/ELSE', 'Creating Character Columns with the LENGTH Statement', 'Processing Multiple Statements with IF-THEN/DO', 'Demo: Processing Multiple Statements with IF-THEN/DO'], ['Overview', 'Using Titles and Footnotes', 'Using Macro Variables and Functions in Titles and Footnotes', 'Applying Temporary Labels to Columns', 'Segmenting Reports', 'Demo: Enhancing Reports', 'Applying Permanent Labels to Columns', 'Demo: Creating Frequency Reports and Graphs', 'Demo: Creating Two-Way Frequency Reports', 'Demo: Creating a Summary Statistics Reports', 'Creating an Output Summary Table'], ['Overview', 'Exporting Data', 'Demo: Exporting Data to an Excel Workbook', 'Using the SAS Output Delivery System', 'Exporting Results to CSV', 'Demo: Exporting Results to Excel', 'Exporting Results to PowerPoint and Microsoft Word', 'Demo: Exporting Results to PDF'], ['Overview', 'SQL and SAS', 'PROC SQL Syntax', 'Filtering and Sorting Output', 'Demo: Reading and Filtering Data with SQL', 'Creating and Deleting Tables in SQL', 'Creating Inner Joins in SQL', 'Demo: Joining Tables with PROC SQL', 'Using Table Aliases', "You've Finished the Course!"]]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 25 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great course for the learners who do not have any programming experience. This course is a hand holding techinique where anyone can learn the programming easily. The practise Exercise were great to brush up. I like the course very much. Thank You! Coursera. KEEP IT UP!.', 'Very helpful! The videos and demos are so on point. ', "Great introduction to SAS, heavy focused on deep understanding of what's happening behind the scenes and how data is processed. The course offers a lot of interactive coding experience with SAS Studio platform through many activities and code-based quizes. Starting from zero level, but I think it may require a bit of understanding of some basic programming concepts as variables, loops, conditional statements, code compilation and execution.", 'for beginners it is a great course ', 'Very good course, provides all essential details ', 'Really great course, with good flow and very good exercises!', 'Best course to get clear idea about SAS Basic.', 'I like the learning structure with demo and exercises. It takes only few days to finish, friendly to beginner and  you will have great basic concepts about sas. ', 'This is  a very useful course!', 'This is great! Easy to follow and understand. The instructor has a nice serene voice and easy to understand.', 'This course offers a solid foundation to anyone who is interested in beginning to use SAS. I have found the demos, activites and practices to be fairly easy yet still required me to use my brain.', 'Excellent introduction to SAS.  Many thanks to Coursera and SAS for all the course content and software.', 'I expected a complicated start but was pleasantly eased in.', 'very helpful beginner course on SAS', 'Very helpful and well organized class!', 'great courses for a green hand', 'Very nice course to establish the basics of SAS programming.  Thanks!', 'Amazing handful course', 'Muy bueno el curso, excelente manera de iniciarse en el mundo de SAS. ', 'This course really helped me learn basics of SAS programming. Thank you Coursera and SAS for providing great course content.', 'Excellent Course', 'Nice and easy introduction to SAS for beginners.', ' I had a great time learning and understanding the power of SAS, its versatility, flexibility and functionality, to know how data is being accessed, explored, prepared, analyzed, reported and exported into any format for end users. It is a great tool to understand data and from there, make decisions which has impact on others: ourselves, our businesses, our communities, our families. Thank you, Coursera team and SAS instructors for making this powerful tool available to others. ', "This course was amazing!  I feel very confident with the foundation of SAS Programming skills I've obtained from this course, and I am able to use SAS to perform analysis that was previously cumbersome and tedious.  I cannot recommend this course enough!", 'This is an exceptional introduction to SAS programming. Anyone who is wishing to start out with SAS must definitely take this course. It will set one on a great path to immense learning. Thanks for offering this course.']</reviews><reviewers>['By SAYANTA S R', 'By Patricia V', 'By Krzysztof P', 'By Rakesh K', 'By Mujataba S', 'By Daniel W', 'By Anitha t', 'By RUI C', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Javier L', 'By Brian M', 'By Alan S', 'By Arthur M', 'By Jie B', 'By Eric R', 'By NINGXIN L', 'By Vivek P', 'By Mohamed A', 'By Daniel A S M', 'By P N V B S R', 'By Ravindra S N', 'By Elżbieta', 'By Edgar G R', 'By Danielle B', 'By Karan G']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 28, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Jun 04, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jan 09, 2019', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Feb 20, 2019', 'Feb 21, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Feb 27, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Mar 27, 2019']</review_date></doc>