<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_301</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/introduction-to-deep-learning-with-keras</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Deep Learning &amp; Neural Networks with Keras</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Aklson</course_instructor><course_introduction>Looking to start a career in Deep Learning? Look no further. This course will introduce you to the field of deep learning and help you answer many questions that people are asking nowadays, like what is deep learning, and how do deep learning models compare to artificial neural networks? You will learn about the different deep learning models and build your first deep learning model using the Keras library.

After completing this course, learners will be able to:
•	describe what a neural network is, what a deep learning model is, and the difference between them.
•	demonstrate an understanding of unsupervised deep learning models such as autoencoders and restricted Boltzmann machines.
•	demonstrate an understanding of supervised deep learning models such as convolutional neural networks and recurrent networks.
•	build deep learning models and networks using the Keras library.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Deep Learning//Artificial Neural Network//Artificial Intelligence (AI)//Machine Learning//keras</course_tag><course_rating /><course_orgnization>IBM</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Neural Networks and Deep Learning//Artificial Neural Networks//Keras and Deep Learning Libraries//Deep Learning Models//Course Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome', 'Introduction to Deep Learning', 'Neurons and Neural Networks', 'Artificial Neural Networks'], ['Gradient Descent', 'Backpropagation', 'Vanishing Gradient', 'Activation Functions'], ['Deep Learning Libraries', 'Regression Models with Keras', 'Classification Models with Keras'], ['Shallow Versus Deep Neural Networks', 'Convolutional Neural Networks', 'Recurrent Neural Networks', 'Autoencoders'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The teaching is not deep enough to solve the Week 5 assignment, please take note you need to plumb in other Keras courses.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Lam C V D']</reviewers><review_date>['Sep 08, 2019']</review_date></doc>