<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_244</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/survival-analysis-r-public-health</course_url><course_name>Survival Analysis in R for Public Health</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Alex Bottle</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to Survival Analysis in R for Public Health!

The three earlier courses in this series covered statistical thinking, correlation, linear regression and logistic regression. This one will show you how to run survival – or “time to event” – analysis, explaining what’s meant by familiar-sounding but deceptive terms like hazard and censoring, which have specific meanings in this context. Using the popular and completely free software R, you’ll learn how to take a data set from scratch, import it into R, run essential descriptive analyses to get to know the data’s features and quirks, and progress from Kaplan-Meier plots through to multiple Cox regression. You’ll use data simulated from real, messy patient-level data for patients admitted to hospital with heart failure and learn how to explore which factors predict their subsequent mortality. You’ll learn how to test model assumptions and fit to the data and some simple tricks to get round common problems that real public health data have. There will be mini-quizzes on the videos and the R exercises with feedback along the way to check your understanding.

Prerequisites

Some formulae are given to aid understanding, but this is not one of those courses where you need a mathematics degree to follow it. You will need basic numeracy (for example, we will not use calculus) and familiarity with graphical and tabular ways of presenting results. The three previous courses in the series explained concepts such as hypothesis testing, p values, confidence intervals, correlation and regression and showed how to install R and run basic commands. In this course, we will recap all these core ideas in brief, but if you are unfamiliar with them, then you may prefer to take the first course in particular, Statistical Thinking in Public Health, and perhaps also the second, on linear regression, before embarking on this one.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>Understand common ways to choose what predictors go into a regression model//Run and interpret Kaplan-Meier curves in R//Construct a Cox regression model in R</course_tag><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>The Kaplan-Meier Plot //The Cox Model//The Multiple Cox Model//The Proportionality Assumption</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Course', 'What is Survival Analysis?', 'The KM plot and Log-rank test', 'What is Heart Failure and How to run a KM plot in R'], ['Intro to Cox Model', 'How to run Simple Cox model in R', 'Introduction to Missing Data'], ['Interpreting the output from multiple Cox model'], ['How to assess Cox model fit', 'Cox proportional hazards assumption', 'Summary of Course']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This course does not discuss different types of survival model such as competitive event models. It only discusses very basic ideas such as the hazard function and the cox model which could be discussed in like 20 minutes. There are a lot of unnecessary discussion around multivariate regression and missing values that belong to a course on regression analysis and not survival analysis. The R code is a bit faulty and could be improved. Overall, I don't think this could be a good course on survival analysis.", 'Very nice introductory course on survival analysis in R. Exercises were well designed.', 'Excellent course to learn about survival analysis, with very explicit explications of the application of the models on R', 'Good and practical introduction to survival analysis. I liked the emphasis on how to deal with practical data sets and data problems.', 'High-quality, thoroughly-designed, hands-on, introductory course.  ', 'There are few videos and too much text. The exercises have not been well prepared and some outcomes and results have not been discussed, in particular for different types of residuals in the last week.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Aboozar H', 'By Faisal A', 'By Assal h', 'By Victoria', 'By Basilio G P', 'By Amir A H']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 06, 2019', 'Jul 22, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 27, 2019', 'May 13, 2019', 'May 16, 2019']</review_date></doc>