<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_242</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/business-data</course_url><course_name>Exploring and Producing Data for Business Decision Making</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Fataneh Taghaboni-Dutta</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course provides an analytical framework to help you evaluate key problems in a structured fashion and will equip you with tools to better manage the uncertainties that pervade and complicate business processes. Specifically, you will be introduced to statistics and how to summarize data and learn concepts of frequency, normal distribution, statistical studies, sampling, and confidence intervals.

While you will be introduced to some of the science of what is being taught, the focus will be on applying the methodologies. This will be accomplished through the use of Excel and data sets from many different disciplines, allowing you to see the use of statistics in very diverse settings. The course will focus not only on explaining these concepts, but also understanding the meaning of the results obtained.

Upon successful completion of this course, you will be able to:

•	Summarize large data sets in graphical, tabular, and numerical forms.
•	Understand the significance of proper sampling and why you can rely on sample information.
•	Understand why normal distribution can be used in so many settings.
•	Use sample information to infer about the population with a certain level of confidence about the accuracy of the estimations.
•	Use Excel for statistical analysis.

This course is part of the iMBA offered by the University of Illinois, a flexible, fully-accredited online MBA at an incredibly competitive price. For more information, please see the Resource page in this course and onlinemba.illinois.edu.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Essentials</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Microsoft Excel//Statistical Analysis//Normal Distribution</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Orientation//Module 1: Introduction and Summarizing Data//Module 2: Descriptive Statistics and Probability Distributions//Module 3: Sampling and Central Limit Theorem//Module 4: Inference</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Exploring and Producing Data for Business Decision Making!', 'Excel Data Analysis Toolpak'], ['1-1.1. Basic Terminology', '1-2.1. Summarizing Data: Frequency Tables', '1-2.2. Frequency Tables in Excel: Quantitative Data', '1-2.3. Frequency Tables in Excel: Qualitative Data', '1-2.4. Presenting Frequency Tables as a Bar Graph in Excel', '1-3.1. Summarizing Data: Histograms', '1-3.2. Histograms in Excel', '1-4.1. Summarizing Data: Pie Charts', '1-4.2. Pie Charts in Excel', '1-5.1. Summarizing Data: Scatter Plots', '1-5.2. Scatter Plots in Excel'], ['2-1.1. Measures of Central Tendencies', '2-1.2. Mean and Median in Excel', '2-2.1. Measures of Dispersion', '2-2.2. Standard Deviation in Excel', '2-3.1. Percentiles and Z-Score', '2-3.2. Z-Score in Excel', '2-4.1. Discrete and Continuous Random Variables', '2-4.2. Expected Value in Excel', '2-5.1. Normal Distribution', '2-5.2. Normal Distribution in Excel', '2-5.3. Standard Normal Distribution in Excel', '2-5.4. "Less Than" in Excel', '2-5.5. "Greater Than" in Excel', '2-5.6. "Between Values" in Excel', '2-5.7. Finding Z for a Given Probability (INV) in Excel', '2-6.1. Standard Normal Distribution Table'], ['3-1.1. Producing Data', '3-2.1. Sampling', '3-2.2 Sampling Function in Excel', '3-3.1. Central Limit Theorem and Sampling Means', '3-3.2. Animating the Central Limit Theorem', '3-3.3. Sampling Distribution and Empirical Rule in Excel', '3-4.1. Central Limit Theorem – Sampling Proportion'], ['4-1.1. Confidence Interval Basics', '4-2.1. Confidence Interval for Means', '4-2.2. Confidence Interval for Mean in Excel', '4-2.3. Impact of Confidence Level Illustrated in Excel', '4-3.1. Confidence Interval for Population Proportion', '4-3.2. Confidence Interval for Population Proportion in Excel', '4-3.3. Confidence Interval Animation in Excel', '4-3.4. Starting Salary Example in Excel', '4-4.1. Sample Size', '4-4.2. Sample Size Proportion in Excel', '4-4.3. Sample Size Mean in Excel', '4-4.4. Sample Size Effect in Excel']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 22 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Good intro to statistical foundations. Would be great if all questions that involve Excel were in one Excel file', 'Good  basic statistics  course, knowledge can be easily applied right from the start', 'Great foundational learning on statistics and how to apply for real life data analysis. Especially with understanding how to use Excel to facilitate the formulas and graphical representations. Appreciate having a consumable set of coursework that helped me learn and achieve completion (this does a lot for your confidence level at my age :)) I plan to continue on my Data Analyst learning path and appreciate that this course gave me a good start. ', 'Really learned a lot of new things, real world solutions.', 'I really enjoyed the course. The professor explained the topics very clearly and made a difficult topic very interesting and compelling.', 'Tough, but provides excellent examples along the way that are broken down to create understanding. Very informative course! ', 'Great class!', None, 'good practical experience with Statistics. Thanks', 'This is a very informative course. Easy to follow and understand. Lots of real examples. Strong recommendation.', 'Course is well organized to give a good overview of statistics.  ', 'Great Course', 'Very well taught and explained. One of the best statistics courses I have taken. As a non math student I have tried many books to understand statistics, but they were all intimidating. This course and the follow-up course on Inferential was my Holy Grail to learning and understanding Statistics. Hats off to the Prof. FATANEH TAGHABONI-DUTTA for the wonderful course and the way she helped approached it.', 'Excellent, easy to understand and the skills are very practical!', 'Very good course, perfectly interlinking theory and practice of statistic decision making.', 'Do you want clear\nexplanations and many examples to understand sampling process and confidence\ninterval magic? Then this course is the best one for you to get understanding and\npractice.', 'A very well taught course. Prof. Fataneh Taghaboni-Dutta is one of the best professors on the Coursera platform.', 'Excellent production and highly effective teaching! Anyone who deal with number-based business decision making should take this course. Thanks!', 'Love this professor ', 'Great Coverage of Statistical Methods with appropriate examples of using them in management....', 'Great course content and teaching. I highly recommend. ', None, 'Both courses about statistics are great. A lot of useful information and professor gives very detailed explanations with useful examples. ', 'Great class!', 'V']</reviews><reviewers>['By Jacques P P', 'By CONSTANTINO A C M', 'By ROBERTA N', 'By Keith K D', 'By Joe F', 'By Briana T', 'By Andrew J', 'By Veronica S', 'By Sivaswami J', 'By Li Y', 'By Rakesh D', 'By PRADEEP G', 'By Jai P', 'By Siya L', 'By Daniel C', 'By Dmitriy K', 'By Himanshu P', 'By Zhiyong ( S', 'By Chris M', 'By Francisca M', 'By Subrat G', 'By Yuduan L', 'By Aneliya M', 'By James S', 'By Todd J F']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 08, 2019', 'Jun 28, 2017', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Apr 04, 2019', 'Apr 06, 2019', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Apr 08, 2019', 'Apr 09, 2019', 'Apr 10, 2019', 'Apr 12, 2019', 'Dec 09, 2018', 'Sep 28, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2018', 'Aug 11, 2016', 'Aug 17, 2017', 'Aug 24, 2017', 'May 23, 2017', 'Nov 06, 2017', 'Apr 12, 2018', 'May 20, 2017', 'Aug 27, 2016', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'May 06, 2018', 'Apr 01, 2018']</review_date></doc>