<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_108</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/intro-tensorflow</course_url><course_name>Intro to TensorFlow</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>We introduce low-level TensorFlow and work our way through the necessary concepts and APIs so as to be able to write distributed machine learning models. Given a TensorFlow model, we explain how to scale out the training of that model and offer high-performance predictions using Cloud Machine Learning Engine.

Course Objectives:
Create machine learning models in TensorFlow
Use the TensorFlow libraries to solve numerical problems
Troubleshoot and debug common TensorFlow code pitfalls
Use tf.estimator to create, train, and evaluate an ML model
Train, deploy, and productionalize ML models at scale with Cloud ML Engine</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Application Programming Interfaces (API)//Estimator//Machine Learning//Tensorflow//Cloud Computing</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction//Core TensorFlow//Estimator API//Scaling TensorFlow models//Summary</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction', 'Intro to Qwiklabs'], ['Introduction', 'What is TensorFlow', 'Benefits of a Directed Graph', 'TensorFlow API Hierarchy', 'Lazy Evaluation', 'Graph and Session', 'Evaluating a Tensor', 'Visualizing a graph', 'Tensors', 'Variables', 'Lab Intro: Writing low-level TensorFlow programs', 'Lab Solution', 'Introduction', 'Shape problems', 'Fixing shape problems', 'Data type problems', 'Debugging full programs', 'Intro: Debugging full programs', 'Demo: Debugging Full Programs'], ['Introduction', 'Estimator API', 'Pre-made Estimators', 'Demo: Housing Price Model', 'Checkpointing', 'Training on in-memory datasets', 'Lab Intro: Estimator API', 'Lab Solution: Estimator API', 'Train on large datasets with Dataset API', 'Lab Intro: Scaling up TensorFlow ingest using batching', 'Lab Solution: Scaling up TensorFlow ingest using batching', 'Big jobs, Distributed training', 'Monitoring with TensorBoard', 'Demo: TensorBoard UI', 'Serving Input Function', 'Recap: Estimator API', 'Lab Intro: Creating a distributed training TensorFlow model with Estimator API', 'Lab Solution: Creating a distributed training TensorFlow model with Estimator API'], ['Introduction', 'Why Cloud AI Platform?', 'Train a Model', 'Monitoring and Deploying Training Jobs', 'Lab Intro: Scaling TensorFlow with Cloud AI Platform', 'Lab Solution: Scaling TensorFlow with Cloud AI Platform'], ['Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['/!\\ THIS COURSE IS A FRAUD /!\\', "even though the instructors present in a great way, especially the labs  seem to be quite confusing and the videos couldn't prepare me so well for what expects me in the lab", 'The introduction to TensorFlow was good. Lab needs improvement; it would be helpful to have code templates that needs to be filled in by us to get credit for the lab, instead of just executing the code. Content in Estimator API module needs a bit more depth/explanation in my opinion.', 'While it is a fairly basic and informative course, I could was left disappointed with a few things', 'Although the videos and content in general is OK, the environment and setup of Google DataLab for each lab is really disgusting – takes about 10 minutes to start with the proper exercise.', "Don't think I'll remember much of what I've seen two weeks from now. Most of the time in the course was spent on spinning up the google cloud stuff. All the labs are done for you so no need to use your own brain. I'm very disappointed.", 'labs were not properly working...', 'Labs vms are to slow.  Speaker is difficult to understand.  Mic varies and speech pattern is not clear.  The presentations need some graphics rather than a guy talking.  Sketch out the ideas on a white board rather than  talking 5 minutes to a single slide.', 'Good introductory course on Tensorflow. ', 'Pretty helpful in getting to know the various levels of abstractions  of tensorflow API and  avoiding various pitfalls while building the Tensorflow model ', 'The course could have more programming components.', 'Sadly disappointing. I was hoping for a more detailed presentation of TensorFlow and its capacities. But no words about the Keras level, TensorHub, and other TensorFlow really useful parts. Instead, we have a gentle "hello world" type of introduction to TensorFlow low level and estimation layers, and how to deploy an application to Google Cloud. Now it\'s not bad, just disappointing.', 'This course is more focused on integration of other google services in TF rather then being an Intro to TF.', 'It is an easy course. The course could have been harder with graded exercises. ', "This course is not for those starting out with Machine Learning; its language is very technical and not learner-friendly. Furthermore,  for the labs, a new log in is generated for each lab so that you need to setup the virtual machine new each time, which takes forever. Furthermore, the labs are not structured well as they don't accurately reflect what was taught in the same section. ", 'nothing fancy or special or deep. just a superficial introduction.', 'really love the exercises and code labs', 'the vid on why cloud ML was great: e.g. taking things to a new level by offering distributed training to users', 'Great course!', 'Excelente un gran curso introductorio ', 'great course, with clear instructions!', 'Very practical and useful content.', 'Amazing course! The short length of videos makes it lot easier for students to follow! Google is honestly the best at whatever it does! :)', 'Great Course', 'This was a great introduction to the Estimator API, which is a prefect place to start for new TensorFlow developers.']</reviews><reviewers>['By nicolas j', 'By MIchael', 'By Sudesh A', 'By Nithin S', 'By Juan M P', 'By Miika M', 'By George', 'By john f d', 'By Raghuram N', 'By Aditya h', 'By Richard K', 'By Marc M v W', 'By Muhammad A R', 'By Ankoor B', 'By Eddie G', 'By Ehsan F', 'By meganlee', 'By Mark B', 'By Abdul R Y', 'By Kevin D F C', 'By Joel M', 'By André G P', 'By Putcha L N R', 'By Aman K S', 'By Yonatan N']</reviewers><review_date>['Dec 08, 2018', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Jul 14, 2018', 'Jan 10, 2019', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Aug 06, 2018', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Apr 29, 2019', 'Aug 11, 2018', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Sep 29, 2018', 'May 29, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Nov 30, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 19, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Feb 18, 2019']</review_date></doc>