<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_96</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/gcp-exploring-preparing-data-bigquery</course_url><course_name>Exploring ​and ​Preparing ​your ​Data with BigQuery</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Google Cloud Training</course_instructor><course_introduction>Welcome to the Coursera specialization, From Data to Insights with Google Cloud Platform brought to you by the Google Cloud team. I’m Evan Jones (a data enthusiast) and I’m going to be your guide.

This first course in this specialization is Exploring and Preparing your Data with BigQuery. Here we will see what the common challenges faced by data analysts are and how to solve them with the big data tools on Google Cloud Platform. You’ll pick up some SQL along the way and become very familiar with using BigQuery and Cloud Dataprep to analyze and transform your datasets.

This course should take about one week to complete, 5-7 total hours of work.  By the end of this course, you’ll be able to query and draw insight from millions of records in our BigQuery public datasets. You’ll learn how to assess the quality of your datasets and develop an automated data cleansing pipeline that will output to BigQuery. Lastly, you’ll get to practice writing and troubleshooting SQL on a real Google Analytics e-commerce dataset to drive marketing insights.

&gt;&gt;&gt; By enrolling in this specialization you agree to the Qwiklabs Terms of Service as set out in the FAQ and located at: https://qwiklabs.com/terms_of_service &lt;&lt;&lt;</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Information Technology.Data Management</course_category><course_tag>Bigquery//Google Cloud Platform//Cloud Computing//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Google Cloud</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to From ​Data ​to ​Insights ​with ​Google ​Cloud Platform: ​Exploring ​and ​Preparing ​your ​Data//Module 1: Introduction ​to ​Data ​on Google ​Cloud ​Platform//Module 2: ​Big ​Data ​Tools ​Overview//Module 3: ​Exploring ​your ​Data ​with SQL//Module 4: ​Google ​BigQuery ​Pricing//Module 5: ​Cleaning ​and ​Transforming your ​Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction: From Data to Insights with Google Cloud Platform specialization'], ['Highlight \u200bAnalytics \u200bChallenges \u200bFaced \u200bby \u200bData \u200bAnalysts', 'Compare \u200bBig \u200bData \u200bOn-Premise \u200bvs \u200bon \u200bthe \u200bCloud', 'Real-World \u200bUse \u200bCases', 'Navigate \u200bGoogle \u200bCloud \u200bPlatform \u200bProject \u200bBasics'], ['Walkthrough \u200bData \u200bAnalyst \u200bTasks, \u200bChallenges, \u200band \u200bIntroduce \u200bGoogle Cloud \u200bPlatform \u200bData \u200bTools', 'Demo: BigQuery Tips and Tricks on Public Datasets', 'Explore \u200b9 \u200bFundamental \u200bGoogle \u200bBigQuery \u200bFeatures', 'Walkthrough: Data Architecture Diagram', 'Compare \u200bGCP \u200bTools \u200bfor \u200bAnalysts, \u200bData \u200bScientists, \u200band \u200bData \u200bEngineers', 'Meet Qwiklabs, your on-demand labs platform', 'Lab Walkthrough - Exploring Ecommerce Data', 'Demo: Beyond the BigQuery Web UI'], ['Intro to Google Analytics ecommerce dataset', 'Compare Common Data Exploration Techniques', 'Query Basics', 'Intro to Functions', 'Demo: Explore Schemas in the BigQuery UI', 'Filters, Aggregates, and Duplicates', 'Data Types, Date Functions, and NULLs', 'Wildcard Filters with LIKE', 'Lab Walkthrough - Enable Standard SQL', 'Lab Walkthrough -  Query Validator, Aliases, and Commas', 'Lab Walkthrough - Logical Errors, Group Bys, Wildcard Filters', 'Lab Walkthrough - Ordering, Calculated fields, Filtering after Aggregating', 'Lab Walkthrough - Finding top selling products, Filtering NULLs'], ['Walkthrough of a BigQuery Job', 'Calculate \u200bBigQuery \u200bPricing: \u200bStorage, \u200bQuerying, \u200band \u200bStreaming \u200bCosts', 'Demo: Try out the Price Calculator', 'Reserved Slots', 'Query Validator, Quotas, and Common Pitfalls', 'Optimize \u200bQueries \u200bfor \u200bCost'], ['Examine \u200bthe \u200b5 \u200bPrinciples \u200bof \u200bDataset \u200bIntegrity', 'Characterize \u200bDataset \u200bShape \u200band \u200bSkew', 'Clean \u200band \u200bTransform \u200bData \u200busing \u200bSQL', 'Clean \u200band \u200bTransform \u200bData \u200busing \u200ba \u200bnew \u200bUI: \u200bIntroducing \u200bCloud \u200bDataprep', 'Demo: CloudDataprep on Ecommerce Dataset', 'Lab Walkthrough - Connecting BigQuery data to Cloud Dataprep', 'Lab Walkthrough -  Exploring Ecommerce Data Fields and Values with a UI', 'Lab Walkthrough - Building Data Transformation Recipes with a UI', 'Lab Walkthrough - Running and Scheduling Dataprep Jobs to BigQuery', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 10 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["This is the best course I've ever taken from Coursera! Lecture/Demo/Lab instruction are VERY CLEAR! and I love the humor. :) Hope to have another course by the same teacher. ", 'Excellent instructor + great content. ', 'I think this is a rare example of good course for Google Cloud BigQuery. I would recommend this one instead of "Serverless Data Analysis with Google BigQuery and Cloud Dataflow"', 'The UI and the datasets have changed what caused a big confusion', 'Contents are not based on new BigQuery UI', 'very nicely designed course for beginners , instructor was really very good', 'easy and nice.', 'Excellent Tutorials, full of information. Loved the course and the instructor.', 'Great! I learned a lot! Very good to start in data analysis', 'Excellent course and great lab sessions', 'Excelente, muy completo y práctico. Gran profesor. ', 'Very well structured!', 'Some of labs make me confuse but the overall is good.', 'Good intro course.', 'I enjoyed the course after completing two other specializations in GCP architecture and data engineering.  This course, and the series to follow, will help tie everything to together from a data analyst perspective.', 'It was very much informative and useful.', 'I love how this course was well structured. The labs helped excellently in getting hands-on experience with the tools. I highly recommend this one for starting out any analyzing with BigQuery', "Excellent instructor. Some of the labs were patchy in terms of steps probably because the underlying tools are changing so fast. I am an old-school guy and I'm simply amazed at the new breed of tools available with GCP and Trifacta.", 'Nice to start with', 'It would be interesting: do not lose the data worked on the labs, I do not know if giving an account for training or something like that, the labs are very good but it is a pity that I as a student does not have access to the practices I have done.\n', 'Great format and course if you want to start learning BigQuery and how everything connects in Google Cloud Plataform', 'Slightly boring and not aimed at beginners', 'good for overview bigquery', "Great intro to SQL BigQuery and Dataprep!  I can't wait to start the next course.  The presenter is awesome and very easy to understand and learn from. Thank you to everyone at Google that makes these course fun to take and easy to learn.", 'Great course learned lots of good stuff']</reviews><reviewers>['By LIJUN L', 'By Pradeep S', 'By Viktor H', 'By Agnes C', 'By Yohei O', 'By Shivam K', 'By Paolo T', 'By PrashantDixit', 'By Joseline C S', 'By Vahid R', 'By Arie H A', 'By Selby S', 'By Nguyen V T H', 'By Oleg Z', 'By Chris R', 'By Krishna P R A', 'By Ridhima S', 'By Ranjit P', 'By Ryszard K', 'By Jorge C S', 'By Ana P M', 'By Nathan D C P', 'By Ngo D V', 'By William S', 'By Vishnu V']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 08, 2018', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jun 30, 2019', 'Jun 08, 2019', 'Oct 27, 2018', 'Nov 18, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Jan 27, 2019', 'Jan 28, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Nov 07, 2018', 'Nov 08, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2019', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Jan 25, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Feb 10, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019']</review_date></doc>