<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_258</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/geospatial</course_url><course_name>Maps and the Geospatial Revolution</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Dr. Anthony C. Robinson</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn how advances in geospatial technology and analytical methods have changed how we do everything, and discover how to make maps and analyze geographic patterns using the latest tools.

The past decade has seen an explosion of new mechanisms for understanding and using location information in widely-accessible technologies. This Geospatial Revolution has resulted in the development of consumer GPS tools, interactive web maps, and location-aware mobile devices. These radical advances are making it possible for people from all walks of life to use, collect, and understand spatial information like never before.
 
This course brings together core concepts in cartography, geographic information systems, and spatial thinking with real-world examples to provide the fundamentals necessary to engage with Geography beyond the surface-level. We will explore what makes spatial information special, how spatial data is created, how spatial analysis is conducted, and how to design maps so that they’re effective at telling the stories we wish to share. To gain experience using this knowledge, we will work with the latest mapping and analysis software to explore geographic problems.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Map//Geographic Information System (GIS)//Cartography//Map Projection</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Pennsylvania State University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started//The Changing Nature of Place//Spatial is Special//Understanding Spatial Data//Doing Spatial Analysis//Making Great Maps</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Introduction'], ['Lesson 1 - Lecture 1', 'Lesson 1 - Lecture 2'], ['Lesson 2 - Lecture 1', 'Lesson 2 - Lecture 2'], ['Lesson 3 - Lecture 1', 'Lesson 3 - Lecture 2'], ['Lesson 4 - Lecture 1', 'Lesson 4 - Lecture 2'], ['Lesson 5 - Lecture 1', 'Lesson 5 - Lecture 2']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I thought the course had good overall information and provided an online mapping tool using ArcGIS despite access and technical issues which I recorded in the forums. I felt getting rushed at the end of the course for the major map project and peer review and final exam all in the last week. The map project itself should be Week 3, peer review Week 4, then final exam Week 5. All students should use the same ArcGIS Online too for the final map project, instead of allowing everybody a free-for-all to use whatever map tool they wanted to including images. I was steered to be more lenient in reviewing submissions of simple PDF or image map without interactive content. This made for an awkward and rushed peer review with little time to address access or technical issues. The final map project should be standardized for all students using ArcGIS Online for an equal playing field and applied learning. ', 'This was a great introductory class to geospatial thinking. I really like how the class is set up, the content is easy to digest and explained in an exciting manner. ', 'WOW', 'The best GIS courses and nicest teacher here! You will receive tons of  knowledge and resources for self-learning. GIS is my major and thanks to Pro.Anthony, I know more about it and I‘m inspired by him. You will also gain a lot of fun here because the classes are easily accepted by newcomers and humorous atmosphere. Highly recommend it!!', 'I liked this course. I gained new knowledge every week and I solidified the old ones. I recommend it to other students. I enjoyed these weeks a lot. Thank you very much for the new knowledge, it was a great course.', 'It was good courses.', 'A Fancy course for learning the basic of cartography and interpreting maps!! ', 'Instructor really made this course. If you want to learn about map theory and WHY maps are interesting and important, you need to check out this course. Dr. Anthony Robinson did a commendable job keeping the material compelling and the class a worthwhile venture. I can only hope he will hold more courses in the future.', 'I had some previous training on GIS, but still I have found this course interesting, enlightening on some aspects , instructive on many others and, above all,  very well organized and designed for distance learning. Totally worth the time.', 'Great course , completely covers all the fundamentals and provides interesting insights properly. Recommended to all geospatial enthusiasts.', 'So amazing!! Would 100% recommend for anyone with an interest in Geography and Geospatial analysis.', 'Course present a very good overview of maps and geospatial relationship.', 'Very interesting course!', '\nIs a very important course that illustrates Geospatial RevolutionIt also shows important facts about maps\n\n', "Very useful course. But it's cool to add some more urban planning focus. ", 'Very good Basic course for GIS ', 'Love the knowledge, the humor, the inspiration. Overall, Dr. Robinson has taught us a great deal about how to make great maps, how to leverage location info (many sorts) and how to link info together to reveal interesting and insightful findings. I am very grateful I have taken the course and looking forward to being able to make use of it. ', 'Great course', 'Explored and experienced a good learning through this course.', 'An excellent introductory course that covers basic theories and concepts about mapping and engages you with a useful map creation assignment during the last week of the course.  Lectures, videos, and texts and a list of resources all useful.', 'Great content, good structure and inspiring lectures. ', None, 'Great intro to GIS', 'Awesome MOOC', 'Great introduction to GIS, and geospacial concepts. I would definitely recommend it to someone trying to get a feeling for what GIS is.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Kenneth B', 'By Cody S', 'By MOHAMED A A A', 'By Finn', 'By Nevena Y I', 'By Abdullah B', 'By David A R R', 'By Dylan F', 'By Ricardo G', 'By Saurav G', 'By carly w', 'By Roney A B', 'By Changhoo S', 'By Luayi S A G', 'By Artem S', 'By wesam', 'By Chen W', 'By José M', 'By Rajalakshmi', 'By Asako Y', 'By Benjamin', 'By Márton B B', 'By Mark A', 'By AYOUB L', 'By Danny C']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 06, 2017', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'Aug 15, 2018', 'Oct 11, 2018', 'Sep 25, 2018', 'Mar 29, 2017', 'Feb 07, 2017', 'May 31, 2017', 'May 03, 2018', 'Jun 10, 2018', 'Jul 12, 2017', 'Aug 05, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2017', 'Dec 15, 2016', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Feb 03, 2017', 'Mar 01, 2017', 'Sep 07, 2017', 'Mar 06, 2018', 'Mar 04, 2018', 'Feb 27, 2017', 'Sep 20, 2017', 'May 31, 2017', 'Jul 26, 2017']</review_date></doc>