<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_325</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/study-designs-epidemiology</course_url><course_name>Study Designs in Epidemiology</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Filippos Filippidis</course_instructor><course_introduction>Choosing an appropriate study design is a critical decision that can largely determine whether your study will successfully answer your research question. A quick look at the contents page of a biomedical journal or even at the health news section of a news website is enough to tell you that there are many different ways to conduct epidemiological research. 
In this course, you will learn about the main epidemiological study designs, including cross-sectional and ecological studies, case-control and cohort studies, as well as the more complex nested case-control and case-cohort designs. The final module is dedicated to randomised controlled trials, which is often considered the optimal study design, especially in clinical research. You will also develop the skills to identify strengths and limitations of the various study designs. By the end of this course, you will be able to choose the most suitable study design considering the research question, the available time, and resources.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>Randomized Controlled Trial//Case-Control Study//Study designs//Cohort</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction to Study Designs: Ecological and Cross-Sectional Studies//Case Control Studies//Cohort Studies and Nested Studies//Randomised Controlled Trials</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Epidemiological Study Designs', 'Epidemiological Studies', 'Ecological Studies', 'Cross-sectional Studies'], ['Case-control Studies: An Overview', 'Measures of Association in Case-control Studies', 'Calculating Odds Ratios'], ['Cohort Studies: An Overview', 'Measures of Association in Cohort Studies', 'Calculating Relative Risks', 'Nested Case-control Study', 'Case-cohort Study Design'], ['Randomised Controlled Trials: An Overview', 'The Randomisation Process', 'Blinding in Randomised Controlled Trials', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 6 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['best course', 'Actually this course is very important for those professionals who work in Epidemiology, and in research, as I mentioned earlier in this course, delve into each of the types of studies designs in epidemiology, its approach and its diverse uses in our daily work. research. Allowing me to have more solid tools in my knowledge to be able to identify in a timely manner the different variables in the different types of study designs in epidemiology. Very grateful to Dr. Filippos Filippidis and his collaborators.', 'Excellent course with all the basic concepts relevant to epidemiological study designs. ', "I think I'm in love... with Epidemiology. With each subsequent course, my thirst to understand epidemiology deepens. Thank you for this opportunity ", 'Thank you for making the quizzes multiple choice. ', 'I am grateful to the entire team that put this course together. I have been introduced to new concepts such as nested case-control and case cohort studies; that I shall apply in designing more cost effective studies. I have also gained a deeper understanding of how things could go wrong in the implementation of a randomised controlled trial potentially leading to wrong conclusions. Thank you team.', 'Excelente, simple y fácil de aprender', 'excelente', 'Wonderful! The didactics is very well done, congratulations to the responsible team. Even with developing statistical skills, understanding of program content is very effective.  ']</reviews><reviewers>['By MEENAKUMARI', 'By Juan A R R', 'By Fernando R U G', 'By Chioma T E C ', 'By Angela B', 'By Kazibwe A', 'By Cristian E N C', 'By Andrés F R B', 'By Deusdenir d S M']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 23, 2019', 'May 13, 2019', 'May 17, 2019', 'May 30, 2019', 'Jun 02, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Aug 14, 2019', 'Sep 02, 2019']</review_date></doc>