<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_111</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/big-data-machine-learning</course_url><course_name>Machine Learning With Big Data</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mai Nguyen</course_instructor><course_introduction>Want to make sense of the volumes of data you have collected?  Need to incorporate data-driven decisions into your process?  This course provides an overview of machine learning techniques to explore, analyze, and leverage data.  You will be introduced to tools and algorithms you can use to create machine learning models that learn from data, and to scale those models up to big data problems.

At the end of the course, you will be able to:
•	Design an approach to leverage data using the steps in the machine learning process.
•	Apply machine learning techniques to explore and prepare data for modeling.
•	Identify the type of machine learning problem in order to apply the appropriate set of techniques.
•	Construct models that learn from data using widely available open source tools.
•	Analyze big data problems using scalable machine learning algorithms on Spark.

Software Requirements: 
Cloudera VM, KNIME, Spark</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Machine Learning</course_category><course_tag>Machine Learning Concepts//Knime//Machine Learning//Apache Spark</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California San Diego</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome//Introduction to Machine Learning with Big Data//Data Exploration//Data Preparation//Classification//Evaluation of Machine Learning Models//Regression, Cluster Analysis, and Association Analysis</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Machine Learning With Big Data', 'Summary of Big Data Integration and Processing'], ['Machine Learning Overview', 'Categories Of Machine Learning Techniques', 'Machine Learning Process', 'Goals and Activities in the Machine Learning Process', 'CRISP-DM', 'Scaling Up Machine Learning Algorithms', 'Tools Used in this Course'], ['Data Terminology', 'Data Exploration', 'Data Exploration through Summary Statistics', 'Data Exploration through Plots', 'Exploring Data with KNIME Plots', 'Data Exploration in Spark'], ['Data Preparation', 'Data Quality', 'Addressing Data Quality Issues', 'Feature Selection', 'Feature Transformation', 'Dimensionality Reduction', 'Handling Missing Values in KNIME', 'Handling Missing Values in Spark'], ['Classification', 'Building and Applying a Classification Model', 'Classification Algorithms', 'k-Nearest Neighbors', 'Decision Trees', 'Naïve Bayes', 'Classification using Decision Tree in KNIME', 'Classification in Spark'], ['Generalization and Overfitting', 'Overfitting in Decision Trees', 'Using a Validation Set', 'Metrics to Evaluate Model Performance', 'Confusion Matrix', 'Evaluation of Decision Tree in KNIME', 'Evaluation of Decision Tree in Spark'], ['Regression Overview', 'Linear Regression', 'Cluster Analysis', 'k-Means Clustering', 'Association Analysis', 'Association Analysis in Detail', 'Machine Learning With Big Data - Final Remarks', 'Cluster Analysis in Spark']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 16 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["It's a very basic course. In my opinion, if you have done some research by yourself this won't provide you new knowledge about the topic. The assignments can be done by a 5 year old and they don't even make you put an effort into it. In my opinion, not worth the money.", 'Very Good Course with an excellent Trainer, it was well designed and right pace. Thank you Mai Nguyen', 'Thank you for teaching me', 'The Course was great giving a good overview of all Machine Learning Concepts. It is good starting point to understand Basics and Deep dive into Learning. ', 'The courses was really easy to understand and useful for anyone who want to get insight about big data with machine learning.', 'Excellent course. The teacher is extremely good! ', 'This course is amazing and recommend to other students!', 'Nice', 'Great Course!', 'Great', 'Great Learning', "J'ai vraiment apprécié ce cours bien expliquer et très pédagogique !", 'Really nice course.', 'Excellent course and material.  It was  really great learning for me.', 'Excelent materials.', 'Clear, efficient, not exhaustive but very complete.', 'This course is quite good and easy to follow', 'Fantastic course and for users new to Spark an amazing hands-on introduction providing actual programming experience', 'good', 'The best course in the specialization. ML instructor was very crisp and smiplistic. ', 'This is a very good introductory course that benefits from excellent teaching and materials. It is highly recommended.', 'Excellent course, I learned a lot about machine learning with big data, but most importantly I feel ready to take it into more complex level although I realized there is lots to learn.', 'Amazing training on ML for people starting their first experiences with the topic. Practical and easy to understand examples that can be further extended by the student.', 'This course strikes the right balance between theory and practice of introductory ML. The instructors have done a tremendous job of presenting the material. ', 'It was very interesting course. I enjoyed learning. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Joaquim P', 'By Bhola N R', 'By Mohd A A', 'By Ramesh T V R', 'By Mahamat N A M', 'By Shimon A', 'By Wookjin J', 'By Mohammed I', 'By Sudipta S S', 'By Sajeed K', 'By Sachin M S', 'By salma R', 'By Debanita D', 'By Harinarayanan P', 'By Luis A R', 'By Marc-André S', 'By Jude O', 'By Markus.schwarz.de@gmail.com', 'By selvaraj', 'By Prajwal S N', 'By Thomas M', 'By Prospero-Martin R', 'By Roberto G C', 'By Prasanna U', 'By MUMTAZ H']</reviewers><review_date>['May 28, 2019', 'Dec 18, 2018', 'Dec 23, 2018', 'Dec 25, 2018', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Feb 05, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Feb 12, 2019', 'Feb 16, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Dec 16, 2018', 'Mar 20, 2019', 'Mar 21, 2019', 'Jul 18, 2018', 'Aug 14, 2018', 'Jul 19, 2018', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Aug 25, 2018', 'Sep 08, 2018']</review_date></doc>