<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_213</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-science-project</course_url><course_name>Data Science Capstone</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jeff Leek, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>The capstone project class will allow students to create a usable/public data product that can be used to show your skills to potential employers. Projects will be drawn from real-world problems and will be conducted with industry, government, and academic partners.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Science//Machine Learning//R Programming//Natural Language Processing</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Overview, Understanding the Problem, and Getting the Data//Exploratory Data Analysis and Modeling//Prediction Model//Creative Exploration//Data Product //Slide Deck//Final Project Submission and Evaluation </course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to the Capstone Project', 'Welcome from SwiftKey', 'You Are a Data Scientist Now', 'Introduction to Task 0: Understanding the Problem', 'Introduction to Task 1: Getting and Cleaning the Data', 'Regular Expressions: Part 1 (Optional)', 'Regular Expressions: Part 2 (Optional)'], ['Introduction to Task 2: Exploratory Data Analysis', 'Introduction to Task 3: Modeling'], ['Introduction to Task 4: Prediction Model'], ['Introduction to Task 5: Creative Exploration'], ['Introduction to Task 6: Data Product'], ['Introduction to Task 7: Slide Deck'], ['Congratulations!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The whole specialization is a bit of a mixed bag... Many of the courses rely too heavily on teaching R programming and not sufficiently on data science concepts (such statistics or machine learning). The instructors (specially Peng) spent way too much time detailing R syntax that could have been picked up by the students on their own from other resources available on the web...', 'On the Capstone Course, those who are reading this review I would say, skip everything (videos) and directly start writing codes and building the app. Otherwise this course is somewhat unnecessarily stretched too much, it could have been cut way short. I will tell you what I did: I skipped everything, got the gist of the objective, scanned through the codes and worked on my idea. ', "The project topic itself is interesting, but longer (structured as 7 weeks); not much guidance until you find the right threads from mentors in the discussion forum from a few years ago or repeatedly google stackoverflow; it is much more technical than the rest of the course; and doesn't really use much of what was learned during the meat of the specialization's statistics/regression/ML courses, other than data science principles and tools (though new R libraries were needed).  These issues aside, the project was an interesting challenge to complete nonetheless.  Overall this specialization is now a few years old, and the plethora of 4 and 5 star reviews across all courses seem generous and out-dated.  Materials are not being updated, forums are a mess of years-old threads with not much current activity; there is a feeling of waning interest and participation. This was clearly cutting edge material and course back in 2014-6, if JH/Coursera intend to continue offering it, the material needs some refresh and reordering, tougher grading rubrics (I saw a lot of inconsistency and poor quality which met the rubric criteria, alongside great quality work), and more active involvement from lecturers and mentors (and, please fix the typos).", 'Very disappointed with this final course. Little to no support. Discussion Forum provides some level of help but you are basically on your own.', "I spent 80 hrs on this course. I hated so many things. 1. There was lot of uncertainty in the course. For example we didn't know how far to go with NLP. And I constantly came across in the forum where people were complaining about how there was 0 guidance and had no idea what to do. Saviours were those few people who put up help posts on the forum and sharded thier trecherous experience going down different paths. 3. The topic was already hard enough NLP, something I had no clue about and then there was this additional problem all the fucing time about memory. Jesus! One of the most painful courses primarily due to overload, lack of clear instructions and their refusal to edit one letter in the course since 5 years! Fuck them!", "This class is challenging and a lot of people complained so I'll tell you my approach since I was able to complete it on the first try in my free time from my full time job. Not having any knowledge of Natural Language Programming, I found Youtube videos and presentations from the Stanford class taught by Dan Jurafsky and Christopher Manning. Study it up to the explanation of n-grams, it should be enough for the class.  I completed the first weeks in few days so I had more time to actually build the model and the app (you'll need more than the scheduled weeks if you have no prior experience). I found valuable resources in the course forum. Then you're pretty much on your own, identify the best packages, how to use them, look on Stack Overflow when you get stuck. Start using a very small set of data so you can quickly build the model and the app until you get something that works. After that you can improve the model by using more data, finding the balance between processing time, app  time response and prediction accuracy. Everyone understands the limitation of the project so give importance to quickness rather than accuracy.", "The final project is interesting. Text input prediction is a very flexible topic. It could be deep, or simple. I hope in the future more practical models will be introduced during the course. Now we are asked to explore it almost solely by ourselves, which usually isn't the case at work, where one would seldom have to research on or develop something from scratch. Also I hope it will focus more on data analysis and visualization than developing an actual app. Shiny is a good tool to do interactive plotting, but not handy enough for UI development. I believe most people will never be asked to develop UI in Shiny at work. Finally I'd like to thank all the instructors who designed and delivered these 10 Data Science courses. I have learnt a lot from them.", 'Good project. One can learn a lot ,doing this project', 'Great course and fun project!', 'Great for Beginners ', 'Very well structured. Recommend! Learnt a lot!', 'It was really helpful', 'Challenging, you are almost left alone by yourself, but i cannot deny that i learned a lot by doing it', 'Great way to end the specialization because it forces students to think on their own and be resourceful. It is a totally different type of analysis than on any previous course so it was a great learning experience', 'a very good concluding course for those have learnt the fundamentals of Data Science.', 'Brilliant course, the final chapter for the data science specialization. Spent lot of time making my final project, but it wirth it. Glad that I found this specialization a year ago. ', 'Cool', 'This specialization was great and its capstone project was challenging and awesome. ', 'E', 'Excellent course', 'Amazing course for Data Science Enthusiasts', 'The Capstone Project was very informative', 'Everything I expected from a final project: challenging, interesting, well organized. I loved it!', 'In this last module I have learned a lot. It was demanding and quite tricky as you were asked to take your own decisions as there is no best answer at all. I learned to decide what I want and to create an appropriate solution. The best lesson so far along this specialization track.', 'GREAT opportunity to apply all of the knowledge that I learned over the last year or so.  Thank you so much for the guidance the opportunity to learn something new!!!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Marcio G', 'By Piyush V', 'By Paul R', 'By Jose A V C', 'By Thej K R', 'By Roberto G', 'By Wenjing L', 'By Saurabh Y', 'By Ryan J', 'By Shubham B', 'By Vinod', 'By Subha G', 'By Luis F P A', 'By Samuel Q', 'By Raunak S', 'By Keidzh S', 'By Efejiro A', 'By Mohammad A', 'By Prabhakar B', 'By Javier E S', 'By Praveen S', 'By Praveen S', 'By Adán L P', 'By Lucas', 'By Erich F G']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 21, 2017', 'Mar 26, 2018', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Apr 16, 2016', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2017', 'Apr 26, 2019', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2018', 'Dec 12, 2018', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Jan 08, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 23, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Jan 15, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 01, 2018', 'Jul 29, 2018', 'Jul 30, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2018', 'Sep 05, 2018']</review_date></doc>