<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_104</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/accounting-analytics</course_url><course_name>Accounting Analytics</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Brian J Bushee</course_instructor><course_introduction>Accounting Analytics explores how financial statement data and non-financial metrics can be linked to financial performance.  In this course, taught by Wharton’s acclaimed accounting professors, you’ll learn how data is used to assess what drives financial performance and to forecast future financial scenarios. While many accounting and financial organizations deliver data, accounting analytics deploys that data to deliver insight, and this course will explore the many areas in which accounting data provides insight into other business areas including consumer behavior predictions, corporate strategy, risk management, optimization, and more. By the end of this course, you’ll understand how financial data and non-financial data interact to forecast events, optimize operations, and determine strategy. This course has been designed to help you make better business decisions about the emerging roles of accounting analytics, so that you can apply what you’ve learned to make your own business decisions and create strategy using financial data. </course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Finance</course_category><course_tag>Accounting//Analytics//Earnings Management//Finance</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Pennsylvania</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Ratios and Forecasting//Earnings Management//Big Data and Prediction Models//Linking Non-financial Metrics to Financial Performance</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Module 1 Overview 1.0', 'Review of Financial Statements (Optional) 1.1', 'Sources for Financial Statement Information (Optional) 1.2', 'Ratio Analysis: Case Overview 1.3', 'Ratio Analysis: Dupont Analysis 1.4', 'Ratio Analysis: Profitability and Turnover Ratios 1.5', 'Ratio Analysis: Liquidity Ratios 1.6', 'Forecasting 1.7', 'Accounting-based Valuation (Optional) 1.8'], ['Module Overview: Earnings Management 2.0', 'Overview of Earnings Management 2.1', 'Revenue Recognition Red Flags: Revenue Before Cash Collection 2.2', 'Revenue Recognition Red Flags: Revenue After Cash Collection 2.3', 'Expense Recognition Red Flags: Capitalizing vs. Expensing 2.4', 'Expense Recognition Red Flags: Reserve Accounts and Write-Offs 2.5'], ['Module 3 Overview 3.0', 'Discretionary Accruals: Model 3.1', 'Discretionary Accruals: Cases 3.2', 'Discretionary Expenditures: Models 3.3', 'Discretionary Expenditures: Refinements and Cases 3.4', 'Fraud Prediction Models 3.5', "Benford's Law 3.6"], ['Introduction: Connecting Numbers to Non-financial Performance Measures 4.0', 'Linking Non-financial Metrics to Financial Performance: Overview 4.1', 'Steps to Linking Non-financial Metrics to Financial Performance 4.2', 'Setting Targets 4.3', 'Comprehensive Examples 4.4', 'Incorporating Analysis Results in Financial Models 4.5', 'Using Analytics to Choose Action Plans 4.6', 'Organizational Issues 4.7']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 14 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['First of all, I really enjoyed Professor Ittner\'s presentations.  Sadly, his presentation was only 25% of the course.  Professor Ittner was very direct but also was very engaging in how he delivered his content.  I had a good feeling that I could really understand the material he was teaching.  If I could give a rating for just Professor Ittner, I would give a 5 star rating.  Now, this is why I am giving this course a 1 star rating.  But I do have to say, going into the depths of Accounting Analytics is not easy.  You really need to have a good grasp of Accounting otherwise you will get lost.  Professor Bushee did not make the first 3 weeks really easy to get through.  While I enjoyed his examples &amp; case studies, he simply did not do a great job of really explaining and illustrating the concepts he was teaching.  And worst of all, he setup a digitally generated classroom where he had his computer generated students ask pointless questions, make pointless statements, or answer with pointless statements/answers.  I really wish I had the time to analyze how much of the course time he spent doing this, I would estimate that it\'s around 10% but it could very well be higher.  There are so many different examples to pick form, but I\'ll just pick a few here.  "I didn\'t read the Iliad or Odyssey some I\'m not going to ask you to" in reference why in regression there are Greek letter used for coefficients (it\'s a fair assumption that someone taking this class understands coefficients), a 30 second exchange where a PC generate student says that they\'re "stocked" to run some regression followed by Proffessor Bushee informing us that "we\'re going to run some narly regressions", Professor Bushee saying he doesn\'t know how to perform Earning Management Analysis on Mars but he certainly knows how to do it on Earth, and a joke why people don\'t like accountants.  These segments add absolutely zero value.  They lengthen the time of the course.  To make maters worse, I\'m sure Proffessor Bushee had to spend even more time creating this additional interaction together.', 'the worst instructor and the most of the lectures are not materials are not enough to get you through to pass the quiz!', 'Really, a practical course. It will help me to improve my decision making capacity based on critical analysis of any situation. Thanks Wharton, University of Pennsylvania and Coursera for making those critical thinks easy for us. Hope it will improve my capability to be a successful Manager.', 'Prof Bushee is the accounting professor that we wish we all had in undergrad / postgrad! His accolades at the school were clearly well earned!!', 'I loved the Accounting part of the course. It was quite hard for me (non-accounting person), however I really enjoyed the form of the lectures and the content itself (the earnings management + its revealing). Great materials Professor Bushee!', 'useful in terms of how to dig into accounting statements', "Very poor service to response to my problem. I'm asked to pay to upgrade after completing the quiz when I'm already a paid subscriber. Nobody can tell me what's wrong and resolve it! I'm wasting my time waiting!!!", 'Advanced level', 'Excellent', 'This course is highly recommended. I gain lots and lots of knowledge with regards to accounting analytics, such as different tools and techniques in ratio analysis and earning management , prediction model and gain and develops new insights and understanding of financial and non-financial performance.', 'Excellent course.', 'Great subject matter', 'It was one of the toughest course in this specialization. But the course was intriguing and opened new horizons. It increased the understanding of financial metrics and their importance. Cases were helpful in understanding the course material.', 'Thank You Professer Brian Bushee ,&amp; Itter your guidence lecture  and study material will help me a lot in achiving my further goals ', 'Fantstic course. I learnt alot by particiption in this course. I am very happy', 'I personally found that course the most useful. Not just because it gives you the frame and the foundations of Financial Analysis, but also because it gives the insight of the importance of other non-financial metrics in the financial performance.', 'It has been a great course with great information', "It's a little bit difficult to understand what is the accounting. Because I don't have knowledge about that. But I got the overall aspect of How can I access when I want to analyze the data. Thanks", 'GREAT', 'Amazing amazing amazing! Thank you for being this didactic and enthusiastic with the content', 'Thank you. The course is awesome.', 'Course is very exciting and it provide a great opportunity to use analysis in the practical problems.', 'Excellente course, I learned a lot!!!', 'The lecture is very to understand for those who does not have strong background in accounting.', 'Prof. Brilliant as usual as I saw you few years back... One can fall in love with your charm of making students ready for next challenge !']</reviews><reviewers>['By Nick S', 'By Emad S', 'By Rakib H C', 'By Brent A', 'By Krzysztof S', 'By Marco B', 'By Kwek W C', 'By Christian F P', 'By Shaharol N B M', 'By Francis I Y', 'By Jesus C B D C D P', 'By George V', 'By abrar', 'By Akhtar A K', 'By HAMZAT H N', 'By Joaquín C M', 'By Salma A', 'By 박정아', 'By Manasvee M K', 'By Rodrigo A', 'By Zeeshan F', 'By Harish K', 'By CARLOS I I B', 'By Thuy V L', 'By Mahesh B ']</reviewers><review_date>['Apr 26, 2017', 'Feb 09, 2019', 'May 26, 2019', 'Aug 29, 2018', 'Feb 19, 2016', 'Jan 30, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Dec 26, 2018', 'Nov 20, 2018', 'Nov 10, 2018', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Jan 22, 2019', 'Feb 26, 2019', 'Mar 10, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Dec 28, 2018', 'Aug 09, 2018', 'Aug 07, 2018', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Oct 15, 2018', 'Oct 17, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2018']</review_date></doc>