<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_438</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/understanding-china-history-part-2</course_url><course_name>Understanding China, 1700-2000: A Data Analytic Approach, Part 2</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>James Z. Lee</course_instructor><course_introduction>The purpose of this course is to summarize new directions in Chinese history and social science produced by the creation and analysis of big historical datasets based on newly opened Chinese archival holdings, and to organize this knowledge in a framework that encourages learning about China in comparative perspective.

Our course demonstrates how a new scholarship of discovery is redefining what is singular about modern China and modern Chinese history. Current understandings of human history and social theory are based largely on Western experience or on non-Western experience seen through a Western lens. This course offers alternative perspectives derived from Chinese experience over the last three centuries. We present specific case studies of this new scholarship of discovery divided into two stand-alone parts, which means that students can take any part without prior or subsequent attendance of the other part.

Part 1 (https://www.coursera.org/learn/understanding-china-history-part-1) focuses on comparative inequality and opportunity and addresses two related questions ‘Who rises to the top?’ and ‘Who gets what?’. 

Part 2 (this course) turns to an arguably even more important question ‘Who are we?’ as seen through the framework of comparative population behavior - mortality, marriage, and reproduction – and their interaction with economic conditions and human values. We do so because mortality and reproduction are fundamental and universal, because they differ historically just as radically between China and the West as patterns of inequality and opportunity, and because these differences demonstrate the mutability of human behavior and values.

Course Overview video: https://youtu.be/dzUPRyJ4ETk</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.4</course_rating><course_orgnization>The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Orientation and Module 1: Who Are We and Who Survives//Module 2: Who Reproduces and Who Marries//Module 3: Who Cares and Course Conclusion//Final Exam and Farewell</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.1 Who Are We? An Introduction', '1.2: Big Data and the Scholarship of Discovery', '1.3: Big Data, New Facts and Classic Social Theory', '1.4: New Data and Eurasian Comparisons', '2.1: Who Survives: Life Under Pressure', '2.2: Mortality: Geographic and Socioeconomic Comparisons', '2.3: Mortality and Who We Are'], ['3.1: Who Reproduces: Prudence and Pressure', '3.2: Reproduction and Conscious Choice', '3.3: Reproduction and Adoption', '3.4: Reproduction: Geographic and Socioeconomic Comparisons', '4.1: Who Marries: Similarity in Difference', '4.2: Universal Female and Restricted Male Marriage', '4.3: Alternative Marriage Forms', '4.4: Marriage and Socioeconomic Comparisons'], ['5.1: Who Cares: State, Kinship and Family', '5.2: Effects of Living with Kin (by Hao DONG)', '5.3: Family System in Comparative Perspective (by Hao DONG)', '5.4: Kin Influence Across East Asian Family Systems (by Hao DONG)', '6.1: Conclusion: The Salient Legacy of China’s Past'], ['A Farewell Message from Professor James Lee', 'Rate this course']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 5 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course was very well put together and expanded my knowledge of both Chinese and non-Chinese society elements. It was also an excellent example of a productive use of data from widely varying sources and what can be learned from carefully analyzing it.  ', 'nice', 'NICE COURSE WITH SOME INTERESTING INFORMATION.  THANKS FOR ORGANIZING THIS COURSE.', 'Brilliant course. High quality information, comprehensive bibliography and interesting tests. Visionary, complex and controversial. Not to be missed if you are interested in China.', 'Great Course', 'good info based on actual statistics.', 'Very interesting! Valuable!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ben C', 'By lichuangye', 'By JOHN Q', 'By Jialin B', 'By Amal A E I', 'By Joy S', 'By AlexDeseole']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 23, 2017', 'Apr 04, 2017', 'Nov 19, 2017', 'May 23, 2018', 'Sep 06, 2018', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Dec 01, 2017']</review_date></doc>