<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_227</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/measuring-disease-epidemiology</course_url><course_name>Measuring Disease in Epidemiology</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Filippos Filippidis</course_instructor><course_introduction>Epidemiological research is ubiquitous. Even if you don’t realise it, you come across epidemiological studies and the impact of their findings every single day. You have probably heard that obesity is increasing in high income countries or that malaria is killing millions of people in low income countries. It is common knowledge that smoking causes cancer and that physical activity is protective against heart disease. These facts may seem obvious today, but it took decades of epidemiological research to produce the necessary evidence. In this course, you will learn the fundamental tools of epidemiology which are essential to conduct such studies, starting with the measures used to describe the frequency of a disease or health-related condition. You will also learn how to quantify the strength of an association and discuss the distinction between association and causation. In the second half of the course, you will use this knowledge to describe different strategies for prevention, identify strengths and weaknesses of diagnostic tests and consider when a screening programme is appropriate.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Public Health</course_category><course_tag>incidence//Epidemiology//Prevalence//association</course_tag><course_rating>4.6</course_rating><course_orgnization>Imperial College London</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Measures of disease frequency//Measures of association//Attributable risk and strategies for prevention//Disease detection and screening</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Epidemiology', 'Odds', 'Prevalence', 'Cumulative Incidence', 'Incidence rate'], ['Association and Causation', 'Relative Measures of Association', 'Absolute Measures of Association', 'Relative and Absolute Measures of Association', 'Ratios Versus Differences'], ['Attributable Risk', 'Population Attributable Risk', 'The Prevention Paradox'], ['Sensitivity and Specificity', 'Predictive Values', 'Calculation of Diagnostic Test Metrics', 'Screening', 'Evaluating Screening', 'Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Thank you for the excellent course materials, quizzes, and discussions. They have been extremely useful in updating my knowledge. Please keep the good work going.', 'Great introduction on measuring disease in Epidemiology. You can learn about absolute and relative measures of association, measures of frequency, diagnostic tests and much more, with many quizzes for you to practice and learn the concepts.', 'This was a very complete course, absolutely worth the time and effort.', 'I really learned a lot from this course.', 'The course is amazing. The facilitator was very detailed and was able to clearly explain the various subject matter clearly. Also, the quizzes were true tests of knowledge and were quite challenging so as to ensure you actually understood the topic and if not, the need to go back and understand. I recommend the course totally.', "A very good primer with the essentials of epidemiological principles covered.  This isn't an easy subject, but it is made easy to understand. The content covered requires care to fully grasp the material and understand the subtleties. Watching the lectures once usually isn't enough to fully grasp the material, which is fine since they're very brief and have all the necessary information in them.  Useful for anyone working with health data or reading papers on health.", 'Quizzes are difficult, requiring far too much time. ', 'An excellent course, very practical and professional. I recommend it.', 'Easy to understand, very useful ', 'A clear and concise framework about epidemiological measurements definition, meaning &amp; applications, including measurements of associations, health impacts, and validity of screening tests. I figured most practice questions may adapted and simplified from real studies, with clear instructions on performing calculations. ', 'Very straight forward and interesting. The professor is great at answering questions and providing helpful tips to complete the course. ', 'very good ', 'An excellent course for those interested in Epidemiology and the permanent update in health. ', 'It was great experience to pursue this course', 'F', 'Very clear, lots of exercises', 'Worst course of the platform!']</reviews><reviewers>['By Rajalakshmi R', 'By Bruno A M P B', 'By Fernando R U G', 'By Chioma T E C ', 'By GAFARI, O Y', 'By C K', 'By Angela B', 'By Juan A R R', 'By Cristian E N C', 'By Wanyu H', 'By George M R R', 'By Avana P', 'By Deusdenir d S M', 'By Ranjeet S M', 'By Adèle W', 'By Tim R', 'By Nicolas C T']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 06, 2019', 'May 20, 2019', 'May 30, 2019', 'Sep 06, 2019', 'Sep 07, 2019', 'Jun 02, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Jul 01, 2019', 'Jul 24, 2019', 'Jul 28, 2019', 'Jul 27, 2019', 'Jul 31, 2019', 'Aug 09, 2019', 'Aug 24, 2019', 'Jul 09, 2019', 'Mar 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>