<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_62</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/analytics-tableau</course_url><course_name>Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Daniel Egger</course_instructor><course_introduction>One of the skills that characterizes great business data analysts is the ability to communicate practical implications of quantitative analyses to any kind of audience member.  Even the most sophisticated statistical analyses are not useful to a business if they do not lead to actionable advice, or if the answers to those business questions are not conveyed in a way that non-technical people can understand.  

In this course you will learn how to become a master at communicating business-relevant implications of data analyses.  By the end, you will know how to structure your data analysis projects to ensure the fruits of your hard labor yield results for your stakeholders.  You will also know how to streamline your analyses and highlight their implications efficiently using visualizations in Tableau, the most popular visualization program in the business world.  Using other Tableau features, you will be able to make effective visualizations that harness the human brain’s innate perceptual and cognitive tendencies to convey conclusions directly and clearly.  Finally, you will be practiced in designing and persuasively presenting business “data stories” that use these visualizations, capitalizing on business-tested methods and design principles.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Analysis//Tableau Software//Data Visualization (DataViz)//Visualization (Computer Graphics)</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Duke University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>About this Specialization and Course//Asking The "Right Questions"//Data Visualization with Tableau//Dynamic Data Manipulation and Presentation in Tableau//Your Communication Toolbox: Visualizations, Logic, and Stories//Final Project</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['About this Specialization', 'Welcome to the Course!'], ['Tips for Becoming a Data Analyst', 'Asking the Right Questions', 'Rock Projects', 'S.M.A.R.T. Objectives', 'Listening to Stakeholders During Elicitation', 'Stakeholder Expectations Matter', 'Using SPAPs to Structure Your Thinking, Part 1', 'Using SPAPs to Structure Your Thinking, Part 2'], ['Use Data Visualization to Drive Your Analysis', 'Why Tableau?', 'Meet Your Salary Data', 'Meet Your Dognition Data', 'Our Analysis Plan', 'Salaries of Data-Related Jobs: Your First Graph', 'Formatting and Exporting Your First Graph', 'Digging Deeper Using the Rows and Columns Shelves', 'Understanding the Marks Card', 'Removing Outliers Using Scatterplot and Filtering and Groups', 'Analyzing Data-Related Salaries in Different States Using Filtering and Groups', 'When to Use Line Graphs', 'Dates as Hierarchical Dimensions or Measures', 'Analyzing Data-Related Salaries Over Time Using Date Hierarchies', 'Analyzing Data-Related Salaries Over Time Using Trend Lines', 'Analysing Data-Related Salaries Over Time Using Box Plots'], ['Customizing and Sharing New Data in Tableau', 'Tableau Calculation Types', 'How to Write Calculations', 'Calculations that Make Filtering More Efficient', 'Identifying Companies that Pay Less than the Prevailing Wage', 'Blending Price Parity Data with Our Salary Data', 'Adjusting Data-related Salaries for Cost of Living', 'Calculating Which States Have the Top Adjusted Salaries within Job Subcategories', 'Using Parameters to Define Top States', 'Calculating Which Companies Have the Top Adjusted Salaries within Job Subcategories', 'Designing a Dashboard to Determine Where You should Apply for Data-related Job', 'Visual Story Points in Tableau'], ['Using Visualization Science to Influence Business Decisions', 'The Storyboarding Hourglass', 'Making Your Data Story Come Alive', 'Storyboarding Your Presentation', 'The Best Stress-Testers are Teams', 'Overgeneralization and Sample Bias', 'Misinterpretations Due to Lack of Controls', 'Correlation Does Not Equal Causation', 'How Correlations Impact Business Decisions', 'Choosing Visualizations for Story Points', 'The Neuroscience of Visual Perception Can Make or Break Your Visualization', 'Misinterpretations Caused by Colorbars', 'Visual Contrast Directs Where Your Audience Looks', 'Formatting Slides to Communicate Data Stories', 'Formatting Presentations to Communicate Data Stories', 'Delivering Your Data Story'], ['Background Information for Peer Review Assignment']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 26 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["The course included a lot of material that wasn't relevant for someone (like me) who is only interested in learning how to visualise and communicate data using Tableau. ", 'Unprecedented high speaking speed. ', 'Excellent course! Has interviews from people in the industry. Lays out a structure to tackle real problems. Worked on a real data set in the capstone project for week 5. 5 starts to the instructor and the course!', 'One of the most useful courses for me in the way of becoming an advanced data analyst. The content is very good structured and includes practical examples which sometimes are very challenging. I recommend this course to everybody who want to learn tableau as well as good presentation skills in any field.', "  To learn about Tableau, you can just join Tableau community or learn from youtube. But why this course, because you will learn more than just tableau, you will learn how to have a 'feeling' on your data till you know what to look from the data after elicitation. The graded Quiz is very helpful.", 'fantastic course! I very useful insight on how to make compelling data visual presentations with Tableau', 'It helps a lot for my projects.', 'very clear instructors and good practice exercises', 'Practical oriented course. Tips provided by Professor Dr. Jana Borg for presentations to Top Management of Company are very useful.', 'Great course!!!!', 'wonderful design of content, good business examples. ', 'I found the class very easy to follow, yet informative and truly helpful.', 'That was a very useful and interesting class! Presenter did a great job, and her materials were very use helpful and relevant!', 'Great!', 'Love Tableau.  Very challenging class, but if you make it you will know how to use Tableau.', 'Excellent course', "great introduction to using Tableau (if you're like me and never used it).  Jana gives an excellent lecture (never boring or mono-toned).  ", 'Well organized, taught and presented. Thank you!', 'Very complete', 'Awesome course!', 'Excellent instruction by Ms. Schach Borg - Very helpful, and encourages you to keep going and complete the course. Found many helpful topics, but will help if it were a bit in-depth optional glossary into the data-manipulation steps as well.', 'Awesome course for those who wish to learn Tableau. Real-life project / dataset , in-depth exercises and a free 6-month license for Tableau desktop makes it extremely easy to practice, play and get expertise with both data analysis and Tableau software. The tips and resources for giving great presentations are like icing on the cake! ', "Nice alternative to Tableau's webinars. While not necessary for certification, handy for real world application.", 'Best course of the specialization so far, you can tell the instructor specializes in engaging presentations. I felt like I was never lost, but always challenged.', 'Strongly recommend this course. The stuff you learned here is not only about Tableau but also how to give presentations, how to create stories that are appealing.']</reviews><reviewers>['By lotte h', 'By Michael A', 'By Saurabh V', 'By Vardges Z', 'By Pang S Y', 'By Nuno L', 'By 赵涵', 'By Shoola D', 'By Balachandra P H', 'By Ponciano R', 'By Lei Z', 'By carol', 'By Evgeny V', 'By M. J J G M', 'By Mike A', 'By Javier C', 'By Kathryn M L', 'By Farah A', 'By Daniel R H', 'By Enes D', 'By Jayanth K', 'By Anupama P V', 'By Alexander Z', 'By Christopher C', 'By ctvv3010']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 31, 2019', 'Oct 16, 2016', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Nov 22, 2018', 'Nov 25, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 02, 2019', 'Jul 17, 2018', 'Jun 12, 2018', 'Nov 20, 2015', 'Mar 29, 2016', 'Mar 07, 2016', 'Jul 18, 2017', 'May 02, 2016', 'Feb 16, 2016', 'Feb 18, 2016', 'Feb 16, 2016', 'Jan 27, 2016', 'Feb 03, 2016', 'Aug 25, 2017', 'Dec 17, 2015', 'May 04, 2016', 'Aug 15, 2016', 'Mar 25, 2019']</review_date></doc>