<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_88</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-analytics-business</course_url><course_name>Introduction to Data Analytics for Business</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>David Torgerson</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course will expose you to the data analytics practices executed in the business world. We will explore such key areas as the analytical process, how data is created, stored, accessed, and how the organization works with data and creates the environment in which analytics can flourish.

What you learn in this course will give you a strong foundation in all the areas that support analytics and will help you to better position yourself for success within your organization. You’ll develop skills and a perspective that will make you more productive faster and allow you to become a valuable asset to your organization.

This course also provides a basis for going deeper into advanced investigative and computational methods, which you have an opportunity to explore in future courses of the Data Analytics for Business specialization.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Model//Data Quality//Data Analysis//SQL</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Colorado Boulder</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Data and Analysis in the Real World//Analytical Tools//Data Extraction Using SQL//Real World Analytical Organizations</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to the Course', 'Introduction to the Specialization', '0. Introduction to Data &amp; Analysis in Real World', '1. Thinking about Analytical Problems', '2. Conceptual Business Models', '3. The information-Action Value Chain (Part 1)', '4. The information-Action Value Chain (Part 2)', '5. Real World Events and Characteristics', '6. Data Capture by Source Systems'], ['0. Introduction - Analytical Technologies', '1. Data Storage and Databases', '2. Big Data &amp; the Cloud', '3. Virtualization, Federation, and In-Memory Computing', '4. The Relational Database', '5. Data Tools Landscape', '6. The Tools of the Data Analyst'], ['0. Introduction - Data Extraction Using SQL', '1. Introduction to SQL', '2. Aggregating and Sorting Data in SQL', '3. Extracting Data from Multiple Tables', '4. Stacking Data with UNION Command', '5. Extending SQL Queries Using Operators', '6. Using SQL Subqueries'], ['0. Introduction to Real World Analytical Orgs', '1. Analytical Organizations – Roles', '2. Analytical Organizations – Structures', '3. Data Governance', '4. Data Privacy', '5. Data Quality']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 18 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['I enjoyed this course, and I learned a number of new skills and ideas that will be a direct benefit to me in my career.  My only suggestion for improving the course would be to revamp the quizzes.  For the most part, they were straight-forward, but in too many cases there were questions where material that was presented as subjective in lectures was made to be very objective on the quiz.  It was needlessly "hard" for the wrong reasons.  Quiz me on the material, but don\'t try to trip me up, that\'s not why I\'m here.  I\'m a professional, and I don\'t have time to re-take quizzes unnecessarily.', 'I wish there was more emphasis on practical learning and more time spent on SQL rather than all the theory (which was useful but I wish there was more practical stuff in the course).', 'Course is not so hard as I expected , bcs I had a very poor background in data analytics. evrth is clear and easy to catch!', 'Great course! This is exactly what I was looking for, a course that with familarize me with Data Analytics as needed in everyday business use. The course has a broad coverage, introducing the various concepts used in data analytics. I feel this is a great starting point for someone new in this field and wishes to take it further.', 'I enjoyed the course and learned a lot. I found the info. on data analytic structures, models and thinking through problems to be most helpful and applicable to my current job. The SQL section is light; I needed supplemental SQL training/practice, to better understand it.', 'This Course has been delivered excellently by the Instructor. The examples were really helpful to understand the Concept. Great Learning Experience.', 'With no doubt Great effort  is exerted in this course yet still it jumps over the ideas to give you the most you can get but this approach can get the take home message or the overall picture but when you are quizzed about details and concepts you find yourself in need to recheck the videos multiple times or check outer resources to catch what you overwhelmingly missed ', 'Pretty interesting and useful content.', 'Great experience, as it was my first course in Coursera!', 'Great course which covers most of the data analytics foundations. Though i think a week on sql was not necessary.', 'Great instructor and course material. Thanks for such opportunity!!', 'Great insights on the utility of data analytics &amp; its relevance to business!!', 'very good, learned a lot from this', 'Outstanding', 'GOOD COURSE', 'A very good course for someone who is a beginner in Data Analytics.. Covers most of the concepts important for a good foundation. ', 'Very beneficial and more interesting.', 'Really informative and exiting', 'Excellent introductory course on data analytics', 'A great overview on the fundamentals of data analytics with assignments and good quality questions in the quizzes that allow me to apply the new knowledge. The assignment has helped me to understand better. ', 'These guys are good.', 'This course has been very interesting and very focused in what is important. Even the part more  theoretical has been also  a learning experience. My favorite module was the SQL practice.', 'Thank you for this wonderful course.', 'Great', 'Great Course for Analytics']</reviews><reviewers>['By Eric Z', 'By Nimit K', 'By Gulnaz B', 'By Richa K', 'By Colin P', 'By Pradeep G', 'By Ahmed T E', 'By Timofey I', 'By Martín A V', 'By Neeraj K S', 'By anil p', 'By Amit S', 'By Gretony F G', 'By Mushfiquzzaman C', 'By Warqua K', 'By Swati S', 'By AISHWARYA B', 'By Olamiji S', 'By Boye O', 'By Pei H L', 'By Ivan Z', 'By Carmen A H', 'By Bishal G', 'By Giordano N', 'By Aayush G']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 13, 2019', 'Jun 05, 2018', 'May 05, 2019', 'Aug 30, 2018', 'Aug 31, 2018', 'Mar 28, 2019', 'Oct 25, 2018', 'Dec 05, 2018', 'Nov 06, 2018', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Jan 21, 2019', 'Feb 19, 2019', 'Feb 06, 2019', 'Feb 14, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 15, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Nov 15, 2018', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Jul 29, 2018', 'Jul 28, 2018', 'Jul 15, 2017', 'Nov 03, 2016', 'Jan 04, 2018']</review_date></doc>