<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_197</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/deep-learning-business</course_url><course_name>Deep Learning for Business</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jong-Moon Chung</course_instructor><course_introduction>Your smartphone, smartwatch, and automobile (if it is a newer model) have AI (Artificial Intelligence) inside serving you every day. In the near future, more advanced “self-learning” capable DL (Deep Learning) and ML (Machine Learning) technology will be used in almost every aspect of your business and industry. So now is the right time to learn what DL and ML is and how to use it in advantage of your company. This course has three parts, where the first part focuses on DL and ML technology based future business strategy including details on new state-of-the-art products/services and open source DL software, which are the future enablers. The second part focuses on the core technologies of DL and ML systems, which include NN (Neural Network), CNN (Convolutional NN), and RNN (Recurrent NN) systems. The third part focuses on four TensorFlow Playground projects, where experience on designing DL NNs can be gained using an easy and fun yet very powerful application called the TensorFlow Playground. This course was designed to help you build business strategies and enable you to conduct technical planning on new DL and ML services and products.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Business.Business Strategy</course_category><course_tag>Artificial Intelligence (AI)//Artificial Neural Network//Machine Learning//Deep Learning</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>Yonsei University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Deep Learning Products &amp; Services //Business with Deep Learning &amp; Machine Learning//Deep Learning Computing Systems &amp; Software//Basics of Deep Learning Neural Networks//Deep Learning with CNN &amp; RNN //Deep Learning Project with  TensorFlow Playground</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['1.0 Introduction to Deep Learning for Business', '1.1 Future Industry Evolution &amp; Artificial Intelligence', '1.2 IBM Watson', '1.3 Amazon Echo, Echo Dot, Alexa', '1.4 LettuceBot / 1.5 Athelas / 1.6 AIVA (Artificial Intelligence Virtual Artist) / 1.7 Apple watchOS 4, HomePod speaker'], ['2.1 Business Considerations in the Machine Learning Era', '2.2 Business Strategy with Machine Learning &amp; Deep Learning', '2.3 Why is Deep Learning Popular Now?', '2.4 Characteristics of Businesses with DL &amp; ML'], ['3.1 Deep Learning Open Source Software / 3.2 Google TensorFlow', '3.3 Microsoft CNTK (Cognitive Toolkit) / 3.4 NVIDIA DGX-1', '3.5 Google AlphaGo', '3.6 ILSVRC (ImageNet Large Scale Visual Recognition Challenge)'], ['4.1 What is Deep Learning &amp; Machine Learning?', '4.2 NN (Neural Network)', '4.3 Neural Network Learning (Backpropagation)'], ['5.1 Deep Learning with CNN (Convolutional Neural Network)', '5.2 Deep Learning with RNN (Recurrent Neural Network)'], ['6.1 Introduction to TensorFlow Playground', '6.2 Project Setup, Project 1, and Project 2', '6.3 Project 3 and Project 4']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 8 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Fun course and quick overview of Neural Networks and Deep Learning history and environments. Also includes popular applications of Deep Learning.', 'This course is really good for student who want to have insight on digital business environment, how is the future of business will be look like, and what to prepare to face it. Furthermore this course cover from information,knowledge to valuable skill . Just simply a great course.', 'The course doe snot actually cover much on how DL can be applied in the business world.', 'Excellent course! Useful and easy to understand course materials! I highly recommend and appreciate!', 'Very interesting, I liked it a lot and I was able to know the basis of Deep Learning.', 'Thank you for the great class! It is  a very clear and well organized class. ', 'Thank you this course is very useful for a DL beginner like me. I recommend to my friends', 'Even though I do not have the background of Computer Engineering or Science I was able to understand from the professor and the final project truly was able to explain everything for me. ', 'Very good insight into deep learning for non-IT folks. After having completed this course I feel like having a much better understanding of the underlying concepts and applications in business. The course content also is quite up-to-date with the latest developments in the field of AI. Some videos felt a bit rushed through, but overall it has been a quite pleasant learning expericence. Thank you! ', 'Nice course', 'Somehow this stunning Course has sparked a brand new source of interest aobut these sort of topics. Amazingly, they are changing our lives, for good!!', 'Amazing lectures! Detailed description of each topic coupled with mind blowing graded assignments! :)', 'very good summary. and also very simple', 'I can understand the overview of Deep Learning, the professor has good skill to transfer his knowledge!', 'Fue muy interesante como nace todo acerca de learning machine ', 'Excellent Easy to follow', 'Wonderful', 'Great course', 'Great introductory course to know about applications of DL and some of the technology underneath.', 'This is a great course and very helpful for beginners in this subject area.', 'This course is extremely interesting as you are taught the basic and details of what Deep Learning stand for. ', 'Pretty interesting course. Very informative on Deep Learning and Neural Network concepts/', 'Gives very good view of industry application of Deep Learning in as easy way.', 'Excellent intro course to learn DL', 'It is a good introductory course for business.  ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Michael G', 'By Fikri A', 'By Flavio F', 'By ALDAMURATOV J', 'By Jose L C', 'By Solhyon B', 'By Olivier M', 'By Nada M A E A', 'By J. A', 'By Антон А Е', 'By Juan M', 'By Rashmi N', 'By Arno_', 'By Sunuk P', 'By Yensy L R', 'By Mahmoud A', 'By Mohamed E', 'By ABDUL B Q', 'By Miguel', 'By Lingjun K', 'By nicolasspaniol@gmail.com', 'By ARJUN B', 'By vivekanand t', 'By ajay j', 'By Kristina ']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 16, 2019', 'Nov 24, 2017', 'Oct 10, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Feb 24, 2019', 'Feb 28, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2019', 'Mar 16, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Oct 13, 2018', 'Oct 02, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2017', 'Nov 20, 2017', 'Jan 23, 2018', 'Dec 24, 2017', 'Apr 20, 2018', 'Dec 18, 2017', 'Jan 10, 2018', 'Jul 03, 2018', 'Oct 23, 2017', 'Apr 27, 2018', 'Oct 21, 2017', 'Nov 10, 2017', 'Jan 30, 2018']</review_date></doc>