<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_374</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/r-data-visualization</course_url><course_name>Building Data Visualization Tools</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Roger D. Peng, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>The data science revolution has produced reams of new data from a wide variety of new sources. These new datasets are being used to answer new questions in way never before conceived. Visualization remains one of the most powerful ways draw conclusions from data, but the influx of new data types requires the development of new visualization techniques and building blocks. This course provides you with the skills for creating those new visualization building blocks. We focus on the ggplot2 framework and describe how to use and extend the system to suit the specific needs of your organization or team. Upon completing this course, learners will be able to build the tools needed to visualize a wide variety of data types and will have the fundamentals needed to address new data types as they come about.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Mapping//Ggplot2//Data Visualization (DataViz)//R Programming</course_tag><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Welcome to Building Data Visualization Tools//Plotting with ggplot2//Mapping and interactive plots//The grid Package//Building New Graphical Elements</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Building Data Visualization Tools'], ['Introduction', 'Initializing a ggplot object', 'Plot aesthetics', 'Creating a basic ggplot plot', 'Geoms', 'Using multiple geoms', 'Constant aesthetics', 'Example plots', 'Extensions of ggplot2', 'Introduction', 'Guidelines for good plots', 'Scales and color', 'To find out more'], ['Introduction', 'Basics of Mapping', 'ggmap, Google Maps API', 'Mapping US counties and states', 'More advanced mapping– Spatial objects', 'Where to find more on mapping with R', 'Overview of htmlWidgets', 'plotly package', 'Creating your own widget'], ['Introduction', 'Overview of grid graphics', 'Grobs', 'Viewports', 'Grid graphics coordinate systems', 'The gridExtra package', 'Where to find more about grid graphics'], ['Introduction', 'Why Build a New Theme?', 'Default Theme', 'Building a New Theme', 'Summary', 'Introduction', 'Building a Geom', 'Example: An Automatic Transparency Geom', 'Building a Stat', 'Example: Normal Confidence Intervals', 'Combining Geoms and Stats', 'Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 9 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['  Great course  ', 'I could plot in R before and many of the topics discussed in this course I already had a working grasp on. Still, the course helped me really gave me a whole new depth of knowledge on the packages that plotting is build around in R. Highly recommended!', 'Nice', 'A nice course', 'Last assignment is hard but enjoyed.', 'good challenges', 'the last task is very challenging', 'Good material. Thanks a lot for this course.', 'Excellent course.', "Great course! You'll learn a lot about the graphic capabilities of R. However, I think there are some things that need to be explained before one goes on to complete the final project. ", None, 'It is a very good course, but feels a bit more hands-off than the other 3 preceding courses in the Mastering Software Development in R certificate.', 'very useful, especially the final practical exam.', 'the course content is just copy from the book', 'This course introduced to me the advanced capabilities of data visualization in R, especially using GGPLOT. It was bit of a struggle in the course project as the examples in the Mastering Software development e-book were little simplistic in nature. Overall, very satisfied that I can create my own geom. The key learning was on creating visualization using spatial data. ', 'Content on ggplot2 framework is solid. However, no video or explanation to complement the textbook, students are expected to learn by reading solely.', 'The peer-reviewed assign', 'I have been progressing through all the courses in this specialization and, overall, the courses have been of tremendous value to me. However, it\'s really not the courses themselves but the book that goes along with the courses that deserves the four and five star ratings I have previously given (these courses are really nothing more than "read the book" and "take the assignments"). Nevertheless, the knowledge gained is not easily available elsewhere. 80% of this visualization course (i.e. the book) was excellent and I give it top marks. The other 20%, starting with the grid system section to the end of the book, was terrible. These sections need a complete rewrite as they are barely comprehensible and certainly not comprehensive. The final assignment does not test you on how much you learned in the course, rather it tests you on how much time you spend on your own finding other relevant sources of information on the internet to figure it out. Also, I don\'t understand why creating a custom geom would be a more important software development skill than R Shiny for example, given that having the ability to develop interactive apps is critical to visualization.  I will give this course 3 1/2 stars, rounded down to 3 since coursera won\'t allow a half star. I hope the authors take what I have to say as an opportunity for improvement since I have benefited tremendously from this specialization so far and I would like to see it improved in certain areas.', "I wish there were videos and not just reading a website but the content is really top notch.  I will definitely be using what I've learned in the future.", 'So first of all, the material for this course in the bookdown document are very good - well structured, with good sources. My concern is that the Coursera course does not go a lot beyond, basically just referring to the document and adding quizzes + graded assignment in the last week. The assignment, however, is nice and challenging and requires people to understand the materials.', "You'll learn how to make a custom geom, and apply what you learned to an interesting dataset.", 'The way last exam is presented makes student lean towards unconcise programming', 'This course is not as satisfactory as the second one, "Advanced R Programming". You spend most of the time reading the book they wrote. There is no video lecture or interactive quiz. The most annoying part is the peer-reviewed assignment part. This is a coding project where you need to create your own geom. I understand that building your own geom is an advanced topic in visualization using R. However, at least for me, I rarely have this need in my work. The example and the dataset they use for the project isn\'t very interesting neither. Overall, I think this course should not be included in the specialization.', 'Apart from the book the courses does not offer me anything. No videos, no active forum, no explanation. Also the assessment is not interesting and there is no much information in the teaching material in order to be able to do the assessment.', 'Great gap between teaching and what is required to pass the course. Unnecessarily difficult. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By JEEWESH K J', 'By Conner M', 'By Ganapathi N K', 'By Oswaldo N C', 'By Kunasekaran N', 'By Yaakov M', 'By José A G R', 'By José E L', 'By Gopal S', 'By Antonio M G', 'By KEVIN E A C', 'By Sandjaja B', 'By Francesco D Z', 'By Ruoding W', 'By Prakhar P', 'By Shengdi W', 'By Ankai X', 'By Shawn M', 'By Steve E', 'By Zdenek K', 'By Kevin D', 'By Niklaas B v G', 'By Chao G', 'By Georgios P', 'By Maurizio C']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 01, 2017', 'Sep 21, 2017', 'Jun 06, 2018', 'Jul 26, 2017', 'May 19, 2017', 'May 02, 2017', 'Mar 05, 2017', 'Jun 19, 2017', 'May 28, 2017', 'Nov 17, 2018', 'Jul 10, 2017', 'May 01, 2018', 'Aug 01, 2017', 'Sep 18, 2017', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Jan 23, 2019', 'Mar 05, 2019', 'Mar 01, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2018', 'Jan 09, 2017', 'Jul 16, 2017', 'Oct 14, 2017', 'Jul 10, 2019', 'Mar 03, 2017', 'Oct 12, 2017']</review_date></doc>