<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_172</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/python-genomics</course_url><course_name>Python for Genomic Data Science</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mihaela Pertea, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>This class provides an introduction to the Python programming language and the iPython notebook. This is the third course in the Genomic Big Data Science Specialization from Johns Hopkins University.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Bioinformatics//Biopython//Python Programming//Genomics</course_tag><course_rating>4.3</course_rating><course_orgnization>Johns Hopkins University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Week One//Week Two//Week Three//Week Four</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Lecture 1: Overview of Python', 'Lecture 2.1 - First Steps Toward Programming Part 1', 'Lecture 2.2 - First Steps Toward Programming Part 2', 'Lecture 2.3 - First Steps Toward Programming Part 3 (8:57)', 'Lecture 2.4 - First Steps Toward Programming Part 4 (9:58)'], ['Lecture 3.1: Data Structures Part 1 (11:58)', 'Lecture 3.2: Data Structures Part 2 (10:41)', 'Lecture 4.1: Ifs and Loops Part 1 (11:26)', 'Lecture 4.2: Ifs and Loops Part 2 (15:28)'], ['Lecture 5.1: Functions Part 1 (5:54)', 'Lecture 5.2: Functions Part 2 (8:20)', 'Lecture 5.3: Functions Part 3 (13:24)', 'Lecture 6: Modules and Packages (10:32)'], ['Lecture 7.1: Communicating with the Outside Part 1 (6:41)', 'Lecture 7.2: Communicating with the Outside Part 2 (7:38)', 'Lecture 7.3: Communicating with the Outside Part 3 (17:42)', 'Lecture 8: Biopython (13:32)']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['This course started out very good but spiraled out of control quickly. There was no detail in the later materials (Weeks 3 and 4) in uses/applications which made it virtually impossible to finish the course without spending an incredible amount of time outside of the class attempting to learn material. The early quizzes were not bioinformatics focused and required a fairly sophisticated level of machine learning to answer some of the questions. In regards to the later material, there should be much more detail. For example on learning how to create dictionaries. That was AWESOME! But nothing beyond how to create them and how to use them. This is NOT a beginner course. Also, the female instructor was awful, she read from a que so much that it was easier to just download the PDF and read it myself. ', 'A really good class for a complete beginner. The first three weeks was great for anyone that has is a beginner in Python. Although the last week took giant steps and was a little bit unclear, especially with the introduction to Biopython. If you are new with Python, this it is a great course, but be aware of the last week being very difficult! I also hope that there can be another course that could go more in depth and explore the functions of Biopython. But besides the difficulty of the last week, this course was really great.', 'Class videos provide good information for a beginning programmer, but quizzes are certainly beyond beginner level and cover material not covered in lectures.  Potential for a great set of courses, but needs work.', 'Compared to the lectures, the final exam was very difficult. It would be great if the professors provide more practical examples in the lectures similar to exam questions.  ', "If you don't already know some programming, then don't take this course.   Without some idea of the concepts involved when you go in you will be setting yourself up for failure.   This course is very poorly taught.", "Errors and glitches in the first two quizes that aren't fixed ('Don't worry, be happy, it's just a formating error, ignore the literal text displayed and just  use your imagination to interpret what we thought we meant to say') have left me too unimpressed to spend more time wondering if I need to debug my code or debug their quizes. ", 'excellent course for the beginners in python', 'An excellent introductory course for Python!', 'Great Python refreshment course!', 'This was an in-depth course about python. Being a doctor, it was tough grasping all the content. And considering the short amount of time I have, this course taught me a lot; however I needed lot of external help to finish it thoroughly. Thank you so much for this one, it will really help me in my future endeavors. ', 'Great course focused on python for genomic studies!!!!', 'Great introduction to python for biologists. The final exam is a good challenge for beginners.', 'Challenging but interesting!', 'good starting point to learn python to analysis Genomics data. ', 'Really useful and appropriate for beginners. Thank you so much', None, None, 'Great resource with relevant topics ', 'very good class', 'Excellent beginners course for those wanting to write personalised scripts in Python to analyse genomic data.', 'Muy buena introducción a Python', 'Thanks for giving an overview of Python. It was really Helpful', "Great introduction to genomic data science using Python. The questions were challenging enough to make you work and wasn't too difficult that you get blocked.", "Really good introduction to Python, Genomics in the two together.  This was the first Python course - of many - I've since done and then gone on to use Python professionally and for my own 'Hacker/Maker' projects.", 'The final quiz was very challenging, but the lectures were simply put.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Brandon W', 'By Stephanie T E', 'By Robert D', 'By Diti D', 'By Andrew M', 'By Michael G', 'By Nitin S', 'By Giovani B F', 'By Rafal W', 'By Animesh U', 'By Lila M R P', 'By Gabriel d S G', 'By Olushola ( A', 'By yijin', 'By Jaffar K', 'By Borys J', 'By Matt C', 'By Roman S', 'By Chunyu Z', 'By Daniela L C', 'By Juan J S G', 'By sandeep s', 'By Ammar A', 'By Michael J M', 'By Valdir B J']</reviewers><review_date>['Jul 23, 2018', 'Jan 06, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Jul 19, 2019', 'May 13, 2017', 'Apr 14, 2016', 'Jan 04, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Mar 22, 2019', 'Mar 25, 2019', 'Feb 08, 2019', 'Aug 10, 2016', 'Oct 14, 2017', 'Mar 02, 2016', 'Nov 03, 2016', 'Sep 29, 2016', 'Apr 21, 2017', 'Feb 19, 2017', 'Feb 10, 2016', 'Apr 11, 2016', 'Mar 07, 2017', 'Dec 05, 2016', 'May 01, 2016', 'May 11, 2016', 'Feb 17, 2018']</review_date></doc>