<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_307</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/distributed-database</course_url><course_name>Distributed Database Systems</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Mohamed Sarwat</course_instructor><course_introduction>The increased capabilities of a collection of logically interrelated databases distributed over a computer network enable scalable data processing. This course addresses the components of these systems, covering the following main topics: distributed database architectures, distributed data storage and indexing, distributed and parallel query processing/optimization, and concurrency control in distributed Parallel Database Systems.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.0</course_rating><course_orgnization>Arizona State University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Getting Started//Principles of Distributed Database Systems//Advanced Distributed Database Systems//Parallel DataBase Systems</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Lecture: Welcome!', 'Introduction to Data and Data Processing'], ['Why Distribution?', 'Introduction to Fragmentation', 'Introduction to Replication', 'Assignment Directions: Data Fragmentation', 'Assignment Solution: Data Fragmentation'], ['Introduction to Query Processing in a Distributed Database', 'Distributed Query Processing', 'Total Cost of Query Execution Plan', 'Assignment Directions: Query Processing', 'Assignment Solution: Query Processing'], ['Introduction to Parallel DBMS', 'The Different Types of DBMS Parallelism', 'Parallel Sorting and Joins', 'Assignment Solution: Parallel Sort and Parallel Join']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 11 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Great Course! ', 'Utterly interesting. Simply put conveys the needed fundamentals of DDS easily and accurately.', 'The assignments are challenging but at the same time you will learn python programming with postgres which is a plus. However, not much is explained about the assignment implementations in the lectures, so be ready to work on your own on this one. The video lectures give the database concepts, but a little more explanation could have been better.  Overall 4.5/5 from my side.', 'A few times I felt like the videos cut off, which was a shame. Overall the programming exercises were really great. I love that we got a tester because looking at those functions helped answer some questions I still had.', 'Assignments are very vaguely described, making it difficult to focus on the problem at hand and instead more on syntax, naming conventions etc', 'The material was a good overview of distributed databases, but the assignments felt un-organized.  The instructions were vague at best and downright confusing at worst.', 'The content of the videos is good but the assignments are frustrating and border on useless.  There are a lot of good and unanswered clarification questions in the infrequently used discussion forums.  The assignment solution videos do not cover the actual solution to the assignment.  Even just posting an example solution file would have made me much more willing to continue taking courses.', 'Poor materials and hands on exercises.']</reviews><reviewers>['By ANNA B', 'By Juan M', 'By Aditya P', 'By jacob p r', 'By Daniel G M', 'By Ryan M', 'By Justin H', 'By Jorge L P F']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 30, 2018', 'Jun 06, 2018', 'Apr 19, 2019', 'Sep 05, 2019', 'Jun 18, 2019', 'Aug 05, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Jan 29, 2019']</review_date></doc>