<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_142</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/social-economic-networks</course_url><course_name>Social and Economic Networks:  Models and Analysis</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Matthew O. Jackson</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn how to model social and economic networks and their impact on human behavior.  How do networks form, why do they exhibit certain patterns, and how does their structure impact diffusion, learning, and other behaviors?   We will bring together models and techniques from economics, sociology, math, physics, statistics and computer science to answer these questions.

The course begins with some empirical background on social and economic networks, and an overview of concepts used to describe and measure networks. Next, we will cover a set of models of how networks form, including random network models as well as strategic formation models, and some hybrids. We will then discuss a series of models of how networks impact behavior, including contagion, diffusion, learning, and peer influences.

You can find a more detailed syllabus here:  http://web.stanford.edu/~jacksonm/Networks-Online-Syllabus.pdf 

You can find a short introductory videao here: http://web.stanford.edu/~jacksonm/Intro_Networks.mp4</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Social Sciences.Economics</course_category><course_tag>Social Network//Game Theory//Network Analysis//Network Theory</course_tag><course_rating>4.8</course_rating><course_orgnization>Stanford University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Introduction, Empirical Background and Definitions  //Background, Definitions, and Measures Continued//Random Networks//Strategic Network Formation//Diffusion on Networks//Learning on Networks//Games on Networks//Final Exam</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['An Introduction to the Course', '1.1: Introduction', '1.2: Examples and Challenges ', '1.2.5 Background Definitions and Notation (Basic - Skip if familiar  8:23)', '1.3: Definitions and Notation ', '1.4: Diameter ', '1.5: Diameter and Trees ', '1.6: Diameters of Random Graphs (Optional/Advanced 11:12)', '1.7: Diameters in the World ', '1.8: Degree Distributions ', '1.9: Clustering ', '1.10: Week 1 Wrap'], ['2.1: Homophily', '2.2: Dynamics and Tie Strength ', '2.3: Centrality Measures ', '2.4: Centrality – Eigenvector Measures ', '2.5a: Application - Centrality Measures ', '2.5b: Application – Diffusion Centrality ', '2.6: Random Networks ', '2.7: Random Networks - Thresholds and Phase Transitions ', '2.8: A Threshold Theorem (optional/advanced 13:00)', '2.9: A Small World Model ', '2.10 Week 2 Wrap'], ['3.1: Growing Random Networks', '3.2: Mean Field Approximations ', '3.3: Preferential Attachment ', '3.4: Hybrid Models ', '3.5: Fitting Hybrid Models ', '3.6: Block Models ', '3.7: ERGMs ', '3.8: Estimating ERGMs ', '3.9: SERGMs ', '3.10: SUGMs ', '3.11: Estimating SUGMs (Optional/Advanced 21:03)', '3.12: Week 3 Wrap'], ['4.1: Strategic Network Formation', '4.2: Pairwise Stability and Efficiency ', '4.3: Connections Model ', '4.4: Efficiency in the Connections Model (Optional/Advanced 12:41)', '4.5: Pairwise Stability in the Connections Model ', '4.6:  Externalities and the Coauthor Model ', '4.7: Network Formation and Transfers ', '4.8: Heterogeneity in Strategic Models ', '4.9: SUGMs and Strategic Network Formation (Optional/Advanced 13:47)', '4.10: Pairwise Nash Stability (Optional/Advanced 11:34)', '4.11: Dynamic Strategic Network Formation (Optional/Advanced 11:57)', '4.12: Evolution and Stochastics (Optinoal/Advanced 16:05)', '4.13: Directed Network Formation (Optional/Advanced 16:38)', '4.14: Application Structural Model (Optional/Advanced 35:06)', '4.15: Week 4 Wrap'], ['5.1: Diffusion', '5.2: Bass Model', '5.3: Diffusion on Random Networks ', '5.4: Giant Component Poisson Case ', '5.5: SIS Model', '5.6: Solving the SIS Model ', '5.7: Solving the SIS Model - Ordering (Optional/Advanced 24:16)', '5.8a: Fitting a Diffusion Model to Data (Optional/Advanced 22:47)', '5.8b: Application:  Financial Contagions (Optional/Advanced 12:47)', '5.8c: Application: Financial Contagions - Simulations (Optional/Advanced 13:41)', '5.9: Diffusion Summary ', '5.10: Week 5 Wrap'], ['6.1: Learning', '6.2: DeGroot Model ', '6.3: Convergence in DeGroot Model ', '6.4: Proof of Convergence Theorem (Optional/Advanced 10:25)', '6.5: Influence ', '6.6: Examples of Influence ', '6.7: Information Aggregation ', '6.8: Learning Summary ', '6.9: Week 6 Wrap'], ['7.1: Games on Networks', '7.2: Complements and Substitutes ', '7.3: Properties of Equilibria ', '7.4: Multiple Equilibria ', '7.5: An Application ', '7.6: Beyond 0-1 Choices ', '7.7: A Linear Quadratic Model ', '7.8: RepeatedGames and Networks ', '7.9: Week 7 Wrap ', '7.9b: Course Wrap'], ['Final']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 25 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['A very comprehensive course, taught in a very engaging manner by a top-caliber researcher and professor. An improvement would be adding a separate problem set for each lecture topic, to more thoroughly test specific understanding immediately after the teaching.  Also, some of the Gephi instructions were not quite clear enough.', None, 'greaaaat course ', 'Very nice and useful course. ', 'This lecture is a Great Introduction to Economic Networks.', 'needs more practical exercises', 'The topic is quite interesting and Professor explains the concepts and theories in a quite understandable way. It is easy to follow the contents and offers me with a basic idea of the modeling of network effect. A very help course and highly recommend! ', 'Great course! Teacher gave very good explanations. Examples are very useful. I would love to take a more advanced course of social and economic networks.', 'Excellent Course! Clear videos with many motivated problem sets. The advanced problem sets are exactly like university problem sets. Do be aware that sometimes parts of proofs are omitted or only touched on briefly to get to the main teaching points - these moments are made clear in lectures. While I enjoyed the practical exercises I did feel that extensions to these exercises are warranted.', 'a very good excellent on social network analysis', 'Awesome course with lots of applications!', 'Provides an in depth knowlledge about topics.', "Very interesting and applicable subject matter taught in a very engaging way. Prof. O'Jackson is clearly incredibly capable in network analysis and game theory and he teaches the concepts in a remarkably concise and understandable manner.", "Lucidly taught by Prof. Jackson. I learned a whole deal of stuff that helps me make sense of some of the literature in economics that uses ideas from network analysis. My background is in economics (Master's degree).", 'Excellent. Completely changed how I perceive the world.', 'Very intresting', 'Really enjoyed this course. The professor is really good and covers quite a lot of ground during the lectures. Good way to get into complex networks! Probably gonna do some studying on my own now :)', None, 'Great course by Matt Jackson, who is one of the leading scholars in this area! Thanks!', 'Exceptional Course and very good teaching !!!', 'Wonderful course ', '非常好的理论课，听完对复杂网络在经济社会中的应用有一个非常general的理解，希望可以加入一些coding案例来帮助理解。', 'The course is a helpful first step in the field of network science. Presenting clearly many complex ideas that are important for understanding current research.', 'An excellent and very useful course. Recommend with no reserves to anyone willing to understand the world from a well structured perspective', 'Отличный курс, дает полное представление о теме.']</reviews><reviewers>['By Noah J W', 'By Taras Z', 'By Rijul K', 'By Sebastián F', 'By kazuyuki h', 'By pranav n', 'By Yuze J', 'By Margarita R C G', 'By Paolo B', 'By Mansimran S A', 'By Ignacio O', 'By Yadnesh S', 'By David C', 'By Vikram D K', 'By Wuqiong F', 'By Богдан', 'By Manoel H R', 'By Erikson A', 'By Sihua D', 'By Venkatraman R', 'By John B', 'By Junchao M', 'By Avi C', 'By Prohnițchi V', 'By Листопад П М']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 17, 2018', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Dec 03, 2018', 'Dec 22, 2018', 'Dec 27, 2018', 'Sep 05, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Oct 18, 2018', 'Sep 30, 2018', 'Oct 01, 2018', 'Oct 04, 2018', 'Nov 04, 2018', 'Jul 12, 2018', 'Apr 24, 2017', 'Nov 07, 2016', 'Nov 25, 2016', 'Nov 02, 2017', 'May 15, 2017', 'Sep 18, 2016', 'Aug 10, 2017', 'Sep 10, 2017', 'Nov 08, 2017', 'Sep 04, 2016', 'Jun 21, 2017', 'Oct 23, 2016']</review_date></doc>