<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_319</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/gis-capstone</course_url><course_name>Geospatial Analysis Project</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Nick Santos</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this project-based course, you will design and execute a complete GIS-based analysis – from identifying a concept, question or issue you wish to develop, all the way to final data products and maps that you can add to your portfolio. Your completed project will demonstrate your mastery of the content in the GIS Specialization and is broken up into four phases:

Milestone 1: Project Proposal - Conceptualize and design your project in the abstract, and write a short proposal that includes the project description, expected data needs, timeline, and how you expect to complete it.

Milestone 2: Workflow Design - Develop the analysis workflow for your project, which will typically involve creating at least one core algorithm for processing your data. The model need not be complex or complicated, but it should allow you to analyze spatial data for a new output or to create a new analytical map of some type.

Milestone 3: Data Analysis – Obtain and preprocess data, run it through your models or other workflows in order to get your rough data products, and begin creating your final map products and/or analysis.

Milestone 4: Web and Print Map Creation – Complete your project by submitting usable and attractive maps and your data and algorithm for peer review and feedback.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Geographic Information System (GIS)//Data Analysis//Project//Map Analysis//Project Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of California, Davis</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Overview and Milestone 1: Project Proposal//Milestone 1: Project Proposal Submission//Milestone 2: Planning Your Workflow//Milestone 3: Data Analysis//Milestone 3: Data Analysis Continue//Milestone 3: Data Analysis Submission//Milestone 4: Creating Your Maps//Milestone 4: Creating Your Maps Submission</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Course Overview', 'Project Proposal Overview', 'Vector-Based Suitability Analysis (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Classifying Imagery and Derived Products (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)'], ['$null$'], ['Planning Your Workflow Overview', 'What is ModelBuilder? (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Creating Toolboxes and Tools with ModelBuilder (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Setting Up a Larger Model (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Using Interface Tools as Geoprocessing Tools in ModelBuilder (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Feature Layers and Selections in Models (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Branching, Preconditions, and Viewing Progress Interactively (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Polishing Models for Reuse (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)', 'Advanced Models and Exporting Models to Python (Review from Imagery, Automation, and Applications)'], ['Data Analysis Overview'], ['Assessing Data Quality and Uncertainty (Review from Data Formats, Design, &amp; Quality)', 'Data Quality (Review from Data Formats, Design, &amp; Quality)', 'Metadata (Review from Fundamentals of GIS)'], ['$null$'], ['Creating Your Maps Overview', 'Uploading Rasters to ArcGIS Online', 'Loading Layers in ArcGIS Online (Review from GIS Data Formats, Design, and Quality)', 'Applying Symbology in ArcGIS Online (Review from GIS Data Formats, Design, and Quality)', 'Map Annotations and Scaling in ArcGIS Online (Review from GIS Data Formats, Design, and Quality)', 'Saving and Sharing Maps with ArcGIS Online (Review from GIS Data Formats, Design, and Quality)'], ['Course Summary']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Very good course, although I would like to see the assignments for the final project/course not being peer reviewed but rather by professionals. That would make the certificate even more valuable. Peer review has some large disadvantages. Nevertheless, the experience in GIS that I gained by doing this project is huge. Thanks a lot!', 'A good course with clear instructional materials and excellent presentation. However the reason it does not get 5 stars is that when I signed up to the GIS specialisation in April 2016 I was led to believe that course instructors would review my capstone project. Indeed, this was one of the incentives for me in signing on to the specialisation. I realise that with the number of students undertaking the course this did not become very practical, so that the capstone project was peer reviewed instead. I found this somewhat disappointing though as the feedback gained was often quite limited and it reduced the value of the Certificate. ', 'I found this Project really useful. It was the opportunity to put in practice a lot of things that I learnt  from the previous courses. Time allocated for it is appropriate. Through whole Specialization I appreciate cooperation and help from the peers and instructors. I appreciate also possibility to get Student License for ArcGIS Software. ', 'A very good, in-depth course. Well written, clear objectives and courses. Nick Santos is a very good instructor. For me it was an introduction into GIS. I have two years of professional training as an Hydrographic Surveyor, but this really was all new to me and it was a pleasure to follow the courses.', 'The grading system was not very efficient and there were so many plagiarized submissions.', 'Very resourceful course for those who want to learn GIS.', 'This is an integrated project to go through the knowledge aquired during the entire specialization. I partaked in many MOOCs but this one in GIS has been one of the best I had never taken.', 'Excellent. It is organized like a real project and makes you follow all the necessary steps to achieve your objectives.', 'Great...', 'Excellent course and excellent specialization! I got new knowledge and great pleasure from studying! Many thanks to Coursera, UC Davis and personally to Nick Santos!', 'Perfect "cap" on the end of a great specialization. ', None, 'Outstanding! ', 'it really was a great experience', None, 'i loved participating in this course. I really learned a lot. :) thank you', 'Great class, helpful professor and admin! ', 'Thank you very much for presenting me at the GIS course on the famous coursera website\n', 'Great project platform to showcase what we learnt in the courses', 'thanks', 'Excellent course, I learnt a lot! Thanks', 'Great course!', 'Nice and very Knowledgeable course Thanks Team', 'Excellent course, I really liked pursuing the project of my choice and facing and demolishing all the challenges I faced on my way to the completion of the project.', 'excellent ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Marit d L', 'By Gary S', 'By Bojan C', 'By Maarten B', 'By Gokce S', 'By Md. S', 'By Moctar D', 'By Juan C G H', 'By JOHNI M', 'By Dmitry E', 'By Cort C', 'By David M', 'By Jesús A A E', 'By Kareem_Essayyed_Ali', 'By Aurora H', 'By Aakash B R', 'By Aleck T v M', 'By sayed s E', 'By Henloy A', 'By Ahmed M A A', 'By yasmine', 'By Gintare M', 'By kailash p', 'By Pratyush', 'By Syed M Z S']</reviewers><review_date>['Oct 22, 2018', 'Mar 18, 2017', 'Jun 12, 2017', 'Jun 02, 2017', 'Mar 12, 2019', 'Nov 18, 2016', 'Jun 06, 2017', 'May 02, 2018', 'Feb 28, 2017', 'May 30, 2017', 'Nov 13, 2017', 'Mar 12, 2017', 'Aug 29, 2017', 'Feb 09, 2018', 'Nov 23, 2016', 'Nov 21, 2016', 'Nov 22, 2016', 'Dec 24, 2018', 'Feb 02, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Dec 02, 2018', 'Oct 06, 2018', 'May 08, 2018', 'Nov 23, 2017', 'Nov 20, 2016']</review_date></doc>