<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_147</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/descriptive-statistics-statistical-distributions-business-application</course_url><course_name>Basic Data Descriptors, Statistical Distributions, and Application to Business Decisions</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Sharad Borle</course_instructor><course_introduction>The ability to understand and apply Business Statistics is becoming increasingly important in the industry. A good understanding of Business Statistics is a requirement to make correct and relevant interpretations of data. Lack of knowledge could lead to erroneous decisions which could potentially have negative consequences for a firm. This course is designed to introduce you to Business Statistics. We begin with the notion of descriptive statistics, which is summarizing data using a few numbers. Different categories of descriptive measures are introduced and discussed along with the Excel functions to calculate them. The notion of probability or uncertainty is introduced along with the concept of a sample and population data using relevant business examples. This leads us to various statistical distributions along with their Excel functions which are then used to model or approximate business processes. You get to apply these descriptive measures of data and various statistical distributions using easy-to-follow Excel based examples which are demonstrated throughout the course.

To successfully complete course assignments, students must have access to Microsoft Excel. 
________________________________________
WEEK 1
Module 1: Basic Data Descriptors
In this module you will get to understand, calculate and interpret various descriptive or summary measures of data. These descriptive measures summarize and present data using a few numbers. Appropriate Excel functions to do these calculations are introduced and demonstrated.

Topics covered include:
•	Categories of descriptive data
•	Measures of central tendency, the mean, median, mode, and their interpretations and calculations
•	Measures of spread-in-data, the range, interquartile-range, standard deviation and variance
•	Box plots
•	Interpreting the standard deviation measure using the rule-of-thumb and Chebyshev’s theorem
________________________________________
WEEK 2
Module 2: Descriptive Measures of Association, Probability, and Statistical Distributions
This module presents the covariance and correlation measures and their respective Excel functions. You get to understand the notion of causation versus correlation. The module then introduces the notion of probability and random variables and starts introducing statistical distributions.

Topics covered include:
•	Measures of association, the covariance and correlation measures; causation versus correlation
•	Probability and random variables; discrete versus continuous data
•	Introduction to statistical distributions
________________________________________
WEEK 3
Module 3: The Normal Distribution
This module introduces the Normal distribution and the Excel function to calculate probabilities and various outcomes from the distribution. 

Topics covered include:
•	Probability density function and area under the curve as a measure of probability
•	The Normal distribution (bell curve), NORM.DIST, NORM.INV functions in Excel
________________________________________
WEEK 4
Module 4: Working with Distributions, Normal, Binomial, Poisson
In this module, you'll see various applications of the Normal distribution. You will also get introduced to the Binomial and Poisson distributions. The Central Limit Theorem is introduced and explained in the context of understanding sample data versus population data and the link between the two.

Topics covered include:
•	Various applications of the Normal distribution
•	The Binomial and Poisson distributions
•	Sample versus population data; the Central Limit Theorem</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Statistics//Statistical Analysis//Normal Distribution//Poisson Distribution</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Rice University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Basic Data Descriptors//Descriptive Measures of Association, Probability, and Statistical Distributions//The Normal Distribution//Working with Distributions (Normal, Binomial, Poisson), Population and Sample Data</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Meet the Professor', 'Descriptive Statistics', 'Descriptive Statistics Continued', 'Introduction to the Box Plot and Standard Deviation', 'The Standard Deviation "Rule of Thumb"', 'Testing the "Rule of Thumb"', "Chebyshev's Theorem", 'Week 1 Recap'], ['Covariance', 'Correlation', 'Causation', 'Probability and Random variables', 'Statistical Distributions', 'Week 2 Recap'], ['Probability Density Function and Area Under the Curve', 'The Normal Distribution', 'The NORM.DIST Function', 'The NORM.DIST Function Continued', 'The NORM.INV Function'], ['Applying the Normal Distribution, Standard Normal Distribution', 'Population and Sample data', 'Central Limit Theorem', 'The Binomial Distribution', 'Business Application of the Binomial Distribution', 'Poisson Distribution', 'Weeks 3 and 4 Recap']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 12 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['The course was very well structured. It helped a lot in understanding the basics of all the distribution and using them efficiently in excel!', 'Wish had more exercises but this was an excellent course. Teacher is excellent', 'Very useful concepts in statistical distributions.', 'A truly fascinating course. Keep in mind, this is an introductory course, and it is very useful for either refreshing your memory, or teach something useful and practical.', 'Excellent Content, takes me back to the college days', 'People with Statistics background will enjoy this course and the whole specialization as well.', 'Great course. Excellent Instructor', 'very helpful if you actually think about all the things learned. ', 'The course content was concise enough to breeze through it in under a dozen hours (for an engineer). The assignments and practice quizzes were very helpful. I was a bit disappointed that the content was very basic, but then again, this was not advertised as an advanced course. ', 'While not super-duper comprehensive, I appreciated all the business applications and practice.  Good stuff.', 'Absolutely a powerful and awesome course.', None, 'It was a very good Excel and statistics refersher course for me.', 'The course is excellent! It gives you knowledge that you can immediately apply in the real world. Thanks!', 'One of the best courses It has been my pleasure to complete! And by pleasure, I mean I really enjoyed the learning process. Nicely articulated through video lectures and handouts (for future reference), this course makes seemingly abstract concepts very clear and easy to comprehend. Lays the groundwork for hitherto unthinkable applications in a vast array of business scenarios. The quizzes reinforce the learning through videos.', 'Very clear explanation of basic statistical concepts with very well designed quizes and exercises.', 'good', 'concrete example and direct application. using excel, it should be easy to conduct basic statistical analysis. I learned so much.', 'Professor Sharod Borle is a fantastic professor. I learned a lot of new concepts from this course.', 'All is excellent!', "Over a short span of a month, it feels as though I've progressed from extremely less to significantly good knowledge on Data descriptors and statistical distributions on a business perspective thanks to the course. ", 'an excellent course!', 'Great course!', 'Great course and great instructor.  Very clear explanations of each topic.  ', 'good']</reviews><reviewers>['By Mitthi J S', 'By Jean-Philippe M', 'By Lalit G', 'By Lin Y', 'By Kalaiselvan P', 'By Shady N S T', 'By Emil R', 'By 张悦', 'By Sabarish V', 'By Taylor N', 'By Shittu I', 'By enrique a r', 'By Atis R', 'By José R H', 'By ARVIND K S', 'By Klaus G', 'By jittu s', 'By sutan a m', 'By Nazmus S S', 'By Benjamìn A G', 'By Ramasubramaniyam S', 'By Paritosh D', 'By Esther K', 'By John D I', 'By Penny W']</reviewers><review_date>['Aug 06, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Jul 26, 2019', 'Jul 21, 2019', 'Nov 26, 2018', 'Nov 28, 2018', 'Jan 11, 2019', 'Dec 29, 2018', 'Jan 12, 2019', 'Jan 14, 2019', 'Feb 07, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Apr 01, 2019', 'Mar 14, 2019', 'Mar 13, 2019', 'Mar 17, 2019', 'Mar 18, 2019', 'Dec 21, 2018', 'Feb 03, 2019', 'Sep 26, 2018', 'Sep 16, 2018', 'Aug 13, 2018', 'Aug 28, 2018', 'Aug 17, 2018']</review_date></doc>