<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_363</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/information-visualization-applied-perception</course_url><course_name>Information Visualization: Applied Perception</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Enrico Bertini </course_instructor><course_introduction>This module aims at introducing fundamental concepts of visual perception applied to information visualization. These concepts help the student ideate and evaluate visualization designs in terms of how well they leverage the capabilities of the human perceptual machinery.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag /><course_rating>4.9</course_rating><course_orgnization>New York University Tandon School of Engineering</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Applied Perception for Information Visualization//Effectiveness of Visual Channels//Color Perception and Color Spaces//Using Color in Visualization</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Introduction to Specialization Video', 'Introduction to the Course Video', 'What is “Applied Perception”?  Why Study It?', 'Human Visual Processing System', 'Saccadic Eye Movement', 'Role of Attention In Visual Perception', 'Visual Queries', 'What We Can Easily See', 'Recapitulation of Key Concepts', 'Mapping Between Data Properties', 'Expressiveness of Visual Channel', 'Example 1 of How to Express Quantity With Different Channels', 'Example 2 of How to Express the Idea of Order With Different Channels', 'Example 3 of How to Express Categories With Different Channels'], ['Effectiveness of Visual Channels', 'Experiments in "Graphical Perception"', 'Implications for Design (Accuracy)', 'Discriminability', 'Implications for Design (Discriminability)', 'Salience (Pop-out)', 'Non Preattentive Features', 'Implications for Design (Salience)', 'Separability', 'Implications for Design (Separability)', 'Grouping: Similarity and Proximity', 'Grouping: Connection and Enclosure', 'Hierarchy Within Grouping Techniques', 'Grouping: Closure and Continuity', 'Recapitulation'], ['Visualizing data with color', 'Few Examples: Misusing Color in Visualization', 'Color Perception', 'Color Specification', 'Color Space: RGB', 'Color Space: HSV / HSL', 'Color Space:  CIE Lab/ Luv Part 1', 'Color Space: CIE Lab/ Luv Part 2', 'Color Space: CIE Lch/ HCL', 'Quick Summary'], ['Using Color in Visualization', 'Quantitative Color Scales', 'Multi-hue Sequential Scales', 'Categorical Color Scales Part 1', 'Categorical Color Scales Part 2', 'Diverging Color Scales', 'Using Color to Highlight &amp; Emphasize', 'Perceptual Issues With Color', 'Effect of Size', 'Contrast Effects', 'Luminance for Contrast', 'Background and Perception', 'Color Tools', 'Interview with Bernice Rogowitz']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent course for someone who is getting into data visualisation or business intelligence tools. Very well curated for the best of learning experience. Thanks a lot to Enrico Bertini and others!', 'A very complete and instructive course.', 'Overall, a very informative course with some in-depth technical insight into certain aspects of information visualization. I like the pace, and feel that the jargon is explained well enough even for beginners. I especially liked the modules on color spaces as these are areas I have had a problem understanding previously.', 'Great course with essential material! The content is presented in a very thorough and engaging way by Bertini. ', "Excellent and amazing course! You won't regret of taking it", 'All the courses in this specialization are great ! Go and learn them all !', 'I liked the approach of this course through human perception in Information Visualization and how they illustrate the subjects with everyday examples.', "In this course I've learnt about visual channels  and its properties: accuracy, discriminability, salience, separability, among others. Then it goes to explain very well how the color is perceived and its effects on visualization. Color spaces are covered in full as well. ", 'The information visualisation cource.  I look on coursera give me the Useful information about the courses I will grow in my career in new direction thank you thank you for the more help for for me and my information visualisation I am very thankful coursera  to join me in coursera. Thank you coursera.', 'I enjoy the lectures. The professor has a good speaking and teaching style which keeps me interested. Lots of concrete math examples which make it easier to understand. Very good slides which are well formulated and easy to understand', 'I really enjoyed this course. One of the better courses I have done.', 'Good learning materials for beginners that are willing to learn about visualization', 'This is a great continuation to the specialization, it seems to drag along longer though and maintaining interest is a little bit difficult sometimes. The PEER reviews are also a pain to complete. ']</reviews><reviewers>['By Ruban B', 'By Mathieu L', 'By Ryan J R', 'By Trud F A', 'By Saulet Y', 'By Ian W', 'By María A T H', 'By Santiago S', 'By ALIBHAI F C', 'By Jafed E', 'By Jacques J', 'By JAMES R P B', 'By Vishnu P P S']</reviewers><review_date>['Mar 27, 2019', 'Apr 03, 2019', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Nov 13, 2018', 'Jan 07, 2019', 'Sep 06, 2018', 'Oct 18, 2018', 'Jun 11, 2019', 'Jun 16, 2019', 'Jul 06, 2019', 'Aug 02, 2019', 'Sep 14, 2019', 'Jul 12, 2019']</review_date></doc>