<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_102</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/datavisualization</course_url><course_name>Data Visualization</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>John C. Hart</course_instructor><course_introduction>Learn the general concepts of data mining along with basic methodologies and applications. Then dive into one subfield in data mining: pattern discovery. Learn in-depth concepts, methods, and applications of pattern discovery in data mining. We will also introduce methods for pattern-based classification and some interesting applications of pattern discovery. This course provides you the opportunity to learn skills and content to practice and engage in scalable pattern discovery methods on massive transactional data, discuss pattern evaluation measures, and study methods for mining diverse kinds of patterns, sequential patterns, and sub-graph patterns.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Data Visualization Software//Tableau Software//Data Virtualization//Data Visualization (DataViz)</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Course Orientation//Week 1: The Computer and the Human//Week 2: Visualization of Numerical Data//Week 3: Visualization of Non-Numerical Data//Week 4: The Visualization Dashboard</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Welcome to Data Visualization!', 'Syllabus', 'About the Discussion Forums', 'Updating Your Profile', 'Social Media', 'Resources'], ['Week 1 Introduction', '1.1.1. Some Books on Data Visualization', '1.1.2. Overview of Visualization', '1.2.1. 2-D Graphics', 'SVG-example', '1.2.2. 2-D Drawing', '1.2.3. 3-D Graphics', '1.2.4. Photorealism', '1.2.5. Non-Photorealism', '1.3.1. The Human', '1.3.2. Memory', '1.3.3. Reasoning', '1.3.4. The Human Retina', '1.3.5. Perceiving Two Dimensions', '1.3.6. Perceiving Perspective'], ['Week 2 Introduction', '2.1.1. Data', '2.1.2. Mapping', '2.1.3. Charts', '2.2.1. Glyphs (Part 1)', '2.2.1. Glyphs (Part 2)', '2.2.2. Parallel Coordinates', '2.2.3. Stacked Graphs (Part 1)', '2.2.3. Stacked Graphs (Part 2)', "2.3.1. Tufte's Design Rules", '2.3.2. Using Color'], ['Week 3 Introduction', '3.1.1. Graphs and Networks', '3.1.2. Embedding Planar Graphs', '3.1.3. Graph Visualization', '3.1.4. Tree Maps', '3.2.1. Principal Component Analysis', '3.2.2. Multidimensional Scaling', '3.3.1. Packing'], ['Week 4 Introduction', '4.1.1. Visualization Systems', '4.1.2. The Information Visualization Mantra: Part 1', '4.1.2. The Information Visualization Mantra: Part 2', '4.1.2. The Information Visualization Mantra: Part 3', '4.1.3. Database Visualization Part: 1', '4.1.3. Database Visualization Part: 2', '4.1.3. Database Visualization Part: 3', '4.2.1. Visualization System Design']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 15 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Good course but need some thing to do:', 'Too much background information, not enough information critical to applicable demands.', 'most horrible specialization in coursera! Time wasted', 'seemed to me the best course of the specialization', 'The lectures introduces various ways of visualizing data.', 'Very nice course. It encourages you to learn different data visualization tools for completing the assignments. And, peer graded assignments are too beneficial since, they give you a sight of how other peers are completing their work and all. Lecture videos too are awesome!!', 'Really like this course which leads me to Tableau. After the course, I take about 8 hours to learn Tableau and I think my ability of data visualization ballooned.', 'Good course, very well structured and with interesting assignments. Some (especially first) lessons are more of a general culture but most are very helpful and allow to learn a lot of things.', 'Very solid data visualization class for people interesting in visualization. It explains a lot of knowledge under the hood. Not that fit for people who just want to learn some tools and quick skills. It is computer science. ', 'Bueno para obtener ideas de que hacer, pero necesitas saber programar a nivel basico', 'The fundamental concept part and assignments are good.', 'nice course', "Ce cours est plein de connaissances utiles et permet d'acquérir  un background important en matière de visualisation de données", 'Very interesting and engaging', 'This knowledge is fantastic.', 'Excelent general concepts of data mining along with basic methodologies and applications, congratulations...¡¡¡', 'it is good.,', 'I like it! Very useful!', 'Interesting course for getting started with complex graphing principles.  The instructor was easy to follo', 'Good course ', 'Very good knowledge on visualization. Never though these many indepth concepts are involved in visualizations. ', 'Good primer on data visualization.', 'Excellent introduction, well paced and interesting', 'nide course', 'Great']</reviews><reviewers>['By Pāvels G', 'By James A L', 'By Rex O O', 'By Rahul M', 'By Ian W', 'By Sachita P', 'By Cheng-shuo Y', 'By Mykola K', 'By GANG L', 'By Andres S', 'By Chen Q', 'By Srijan G', 'By KOUSSONDA A K', 'By Teresa E A M', 'By MOHD S', 'By Mario J R M', 'By liz a', 'By Юхновский И А', 'By Brandi R', 'By Morla M S', 'By Yogesh B C A S', 'By Phillip J V', 'By Alain C', 'By Birendra S', 'By Gonzalo R']</reviewers><review_date>['May 04, 2018', 'Aug 06, 2018', 'Aug 30, 2018', 'Feb 08, 2018', 'Aug 10, 2018', 'Jan 16, 2018', 'Nov 27, 2017', 'Apr 06, 2018', 'Dec 07, 2017', 'Sep 24, 2018', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Nov 19, 2018', 'Dec 10, 2018', 'Jan 26, 2019', 'Feb 04, 2019', 'Jan 05, 2019', 'Feb 11, 2019', 'Feb 17, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 07, 2019', 'Sep 04, 2018', 'Oct 09, 2018', 'Sep 22, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018']</review_date></doc>