<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_110</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/clinical-data-management</course_url><course_name>Data Management for Clinical Research</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Stephany Duda, PhD</course_instructor><course_introduction>This course presents critical concepts and practical methods to support planning, collection, storage, and dissemination of data in clinical research.

Understanding and implementing solid data management principles is critical for any scientific domain. Regardless of your current (or anticipated) role in the research enterprise, a strong working knowledge and skill set in data management principles and practice will increase your productivity and improve your science. Our goal is to use these modules to help you learn and practice this skill set. 

This course assumes very little current knowledge of technology other than how to operate a web browser. We will focus on practical lessons, short quizzes, and hands-on exercises as we explore together best practices for data management.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Health.Research</course_category><course_tag>Survey Design//Data Collection//Data Management//Clinical Data Management</course_tag><course_rating>4.7</course_rating><course_orgnization>Vanderbilt University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Research Data Collection Strategy//Electronic Data Capture Fundamentals//Planning a Data Strategy for a Prospective Study//Practicing What We've Learned: Implementation//Post-Study Activities and Other Considerations//Data Collection with Surveys</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['How the Course Works', 'Course Introduction', 'Defining the Space', 'Research Data Planning 1', 'Research Data Planning 2', 'Approaches to Data Collection'], ['Standardization of Study Processes', 'Validated Instruments', 'Data Standards: What Can Standards Do for You?', 'Data Standards: Basic Concepts and Overview', 'IRB, HIPAA, and FISMA', 'GCP and 21 CFR Part 11', 'Introduction to Electronic Data Capture (EDC)', 'EDC Concepts: Data Exports, Logging, User Rights, Project Creation', 'EDC Concepts: Data Imports, Scheduling, Reports, Internationalization'], ['Overview of the Study', 'Study Procedures', 'Baseline Data and Demographics', 'Visit Data', 'Review of Variables and Forms', 'Logging in to REDCap', 'Walkthrough: Creating a Project and Adding the First Variables', 'Walkthrough: Adding Fields to the Baseline Form', 'Walkthrough: Adding File Fields and Formatting'], ['Walkthrough: Creating Visit Forms', 'Walkthrough: Copying Variables, Renaming Forms', 'Walkthrough: Using the Shared Library, Longitudinal Events, Optional Modules, and User Rights', 'Walkthrough: Testing the REDCap Project', 'Example Study Wrap-Up', 'Mid Study Activities 1', 'Mid Study Activities 2', 'Data Quality', 'Data Quality Monitoring'], ['Wrapping Up Your Study', 'Sharing Your Work', 'De-identifying Data', 'De-identifying Dates', 'Common Information Systems Used in Health Care', 'Neuroimaging Data Management', 'mHealth in Developing Countries', 'Data Management for Multi-Center or Network Studies', 'Resource-Limited Settings and Global Health', 'Challenges of Collecting Data in Resource-Constrained Settings', 'Data Privacy in Global Research', 'International Data Sharing'], ['Benefits, Scope, and Validated Instruments', 'Survey Design', 'Survey Procedures and Implementation', 'Survey Testing, Administration, and Analysis', 'Survey Overview and REDCap Setup', 'Survey Testing and Distribution', 'Thank you for participating!']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 25 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>['Excellent learning.', 'Quite illuminating.', 'exceptional for putting this into practice! \n\n', 'Great Course for beginners! ', 'Excellent study material, in-between lecture questionnares, quizzes and constructive assignements provided with the best of teachers and instructors. I would rate it one of the top quality course in Coursera platform. The interactive teaching platform is absolutely wonderful.', 'This course is very useful for those who are interested in learning CDM.', 'The course gives you a broad introduction to the field of data management in clinical research. The teachers are clear and slow-paced, they go into details but give also a very nice overview on several important topics, such as privacy concerns, US and global guidelines for data administration, ethical concerns and things to keep in mind when working in a scientific environment. I found particularly valuable the hand-on experience with assignments in the REDCap demo server!', 'Great course, regardless the role you have in the research; you do improve your data management skill set. A fantastic course for beginners who are trying to increase their productivity.', 'Very helpful intro to REDCap. Highly recommend for anyone using the platform for clinical research to take this course prior to beginning your study.', 'I learned a lot from this course.', 'I give 5 stars to this course because the information was precise, accurate, not to repetitive and since I already have background on this topic I understood deeply some scenarios, they were clear. Thank you', '\nRecommended for all those who want to dedicate themselves to data management\n\n', 'Great introduction to all the basics of data management- the foundation of clinical research.  Really found this course to be helpful and to think of things usually taken for granted.', 'Good Course Work.', 'Excellent course that gives an overview of data management in clinical research and used an EDC called REDCap to demonstrate the practical application of the theory. Its a course I will strongly recommend for a beginner in the field of clinical research. ', 'Great Great Great Course!', 'This was great course to get knowledge on how to start and build a well structured study for clinical purposes as well as teaches you real world examples with the REDCap software', 'Very interesting and useful course', 'excellent overview of clinical data management', 'Thank You for a very useful course!', '.', "This is a great introductory course to data management for clinical research. It is very well structured and the lectures (and lecturers) are all very clear and easy to follow. Step by step, you are guided through the main principals of data management in the field of clinical research. This is my first course through Coursera, and I'm very excited to check what other courses they offer (-:", 'Great Course. Love it!', 'Exceptional information presented by knowledgeable instructors. I will highly recommend the course to students who are interested in data management for clinical research.', None]</reviews><reviewers>['By Mayank P', 'By Felix C B', 'By Lidia E', 'By Kopano ', 'By Aishwarya G', 'By Aparna S', 'By Stella S G', 'By Jorge E V V', 'By Norman G I', 'By Pankaj V', 'By Andres L P P', 'By MERCEDES V', 'By Tim W', 'By KARTHIKEYAN P', 'By Atemnkeng A', 'By Redha A H', 'By Varun C', 'By Carlos D G L', 'By Joseph C', 'By Kerti S', 'By Leonard D M', 'By Adina G', 'By Nsaibirni R F J', 'By Denniswise A', 'By barbara l']</reviewers><review_date>['Nov 19, 2018', 'Jan 31, 2019', 'Feb 01, 2019', 'Nov 21, 2018', 'Nov 23, 2018', 'Nov 12, 2018', 'Feb 13, 2019', 'Feb 25, 2019', 'Mar 04, 2019', 'Mar 09, 2019', 'Mar 11, 2019', 'Dec 17, 2018', 'Aug 12, 2018', 'Aug 12, 2018', 'Aug 15, 2018', 'Jul 21, 2018', 'Sep 01, 2018', 'Aug 24, 2018', 'Sep 09, 2018', 'Sep 10, 2018', 'Sep 15, 2018', 'Sep 11, 2018', 'Oct 05, 2018', 'Oct 07, 2018', 'Jul 10, 2017']</review_date></doc>