<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<doc><id>Coursera_333</id><course_url>https://www.coursera.org/learn/data-analysis-tools</course_url><course_name>Data Analysis Tools</course_name><course_platform>Coursera</course_platform><course_instructor>Jen Rose</course_instructor><course_introduction>In this course, you will develop and test hypotheses about your data. You will learn a variety of statistical tests, as well as strategies to know how to apply the appropriate one to your specific data and question. Using your choice of two powerful statistical software packages (SAS or Python), you will explore ANOVA, Chi-Square, and Pearson correlation analysis. This course will guide you through basic statistical principles to give you the tools to answer questions you have developed. Throughout the course, you will share your progress with others to gain valuable feedback and provide insight to other learners about their work.</course_introduction><course_category>Browse.Data Science.Data Analysis</course_category><course_tag>Chi-Squared (Chi-2) Distribution//Data Analysis//Statistical Hypothesis Testing//Analysis Of Variance (ANOVA)</course_tag><course_rating>4.5</course_rating><course_orgnization>Wesleyan University</course_orgnization><course_chapter>Hypothesis Testing and ANOVA//Chi Square Test of Independence//Pearson Correlation//Exploring Statistical Interactions</course_chapter><course_sub_chapter>[['Lesson 1 - The role of probability in inference', 'Lesson 2 - From sample to population', 'Lesson 3 - Steps in hypothesis testing', 'Lesson 4 - What is a p value?', 'Lesson 5 - How to choose a statistical test', 'Lesson 6 - Ideas behind ANOVA', 'SAS Lesson 7 - ANOVA: Explanatory variable with 2 levels', 'SAS Lesson 8 - ANOVA: Explanatory variables with more than 2 levels', 'SAS Lesson 9 - Post hoc tests for ANOVA', 'SAS Lesson 10 - ANOVA summary', 'Python Lesson 7 - ANOVA: Explanatory variables with two levels', 'Python Lesson 8 - ANOVA: Explanatory variables with more than 2 levels', 'Python Lesson 9 - Post hoc tests for ANOVA', 'Python Lesson 10 - ANOVA Summary'], ['Lesson 1 - Ideas behind the Chi Square test of independence', 'SAS Lesson 2 - Chi Square Test of independence in practice', 'SAS Lesson 3 - Post hoc tests for Chi Square tests of independence', 'SAS Lesson 4 - Chi Square summary', 'Python Lesson 2 - Chi Square test of independence in practice', 'Python Lesson 3 - Post hoc tests for Chi Square tests of independence', 'Python Lesson 4 - Chi Square summary'], ['Lesson 1 - Pearson Correlation', 'Lesson 2 - Correlation Example', 'SAS Lesson 3 - Calculating Correlation', 'Python Lesson 3 - Calculating Correlation'], ['SAS Lesson 1 - Defining moderation, a.k.a. statistical interaction', 'SAS Lesson 2 - Testing moderation in the context of ANOVA', 'SAS Lesson 3 - Testing moderation in the context of chi square', 'SAS Lesson 4 - Testing moderation in the context of correlation', 'Python Lesson 1 - Defining moderation, a.k.a. statistical interaction', 'Python Lesson 2 - Testing moderation in the context of ANOVA', 'Python Lesson 3 - Testing moderation in the context of Chi-Square', 'Python Lesson 4 - Testing moderation in the context of correlation', 'A Question of Causation (Used with Permission from Annenberg Learner)']]</course_sub_chapter><course_time>Approx. 13 hours to complete</course_time><reviews>["I had no idea that the mundane statistical methods that I had learned in my college would be SO powerful in real life! This course is amazing. If you have a bit of a statistical background, you're gonna fall in love with this course. The instructors have ensures that every concept is covered, and by the end of the course, you are well versed in basic data analysis", 'too mechanistic. not much creative modules.', "The material itself isn't bad, but the course instructors never respond to questions. What's the point of the class if I can't get my questions answered?", 'Good Course , simple but effective videos', 'Very nice!', 'It is not very deep, but it certainly helps to understand / consolidate some basic analysis / statistical tools.', 'It is an amazing course where you can learn about manage tools, to analyze data. You can learn properly, it is a class made step by step. I recommend this a lot ', 'Very well done. The videos are well explained, with nice illustrations and examples to clearly understand each concept. The assignments are self directed and do not take too much time to write every week. I really recommend this month-long course for anyone who struggles with basic statistic and wants to know how and when to run an ANOVA, Chi-Square, Pearson Correlation.', 'great!', 'Being as beginner I found through this course I am able to setup my base. Thanks', None, 'Amazing course for intermediate , well designed course material very good information about the different types of hypothesis testing.', 'It is a very nice course for learning the SAS and Python. thank you all.', 'The manner how the course was done is very good. It was evenly paced. The only difficulty i encountered is when i try to submit assignments because for some reasons the internet in our area is so slow and i failed to create a tumblr account after several attempts. Also Im having difficulty with SAS also so i used other STAT software available on my laptop, it gives same outputs too. Great course!', 'interesting', 'Excellent course and excellent specialization.  The classes were well taught and easy to understand.  ', 'Intersting Mentor.', 'Great information presented very clearly with many learning aids provided. ', 'This is a good basic intro to both statistical concepts (correlations, analysis of variance (ANOVA) ), but also presents the methods for coding these tools in Python or SAS in a very accessible and easy to follow way. ', 'I am just starting. But i like how peer review is made the core model of the entire specialization though :)', "Just love this whole specialisation! videos are great, lessons are great... it's just a great course! highly recommended to anyone looking to dive into the field of data analysis!", 'Nice Course  Thanks :)  ', None, 'A great course! Thanks.', "This is an awesome course (as well as all of the courses in the Specialization I've taken so far)."]</reviews><reviewers>['By Mukkesh G', 'By Victoria', 'By Jason M', 'By bijith k', 'By Arnold A', 'By Ricardo M', 'By Ruben D S P', 'By Benjamin D', 'By Emanuela P', 'By Nikhil T', 'By Paul C', 'By santhanam', 'By igor s', 'By Norvie T J', 'By Guan', 'By MICHAEL N', 'By Rajat K', 'By Sally T', 'By Alex S', 'By Vijai K S', 'By Guillermo R', 'By Nitin K', 'By MANOJ K', 'By Xie Q', 'By Saint-Clair d C L']</reviewers><review_date>['Jan 14, 2019', 'Jun 14, 2016', 'May 21, 2016', 'Oct 22, 2016', 'Jun 09, 2016', 'Aug 14, 2016', 'Jul 21, 2017', 'Jun 27, 2016', 'Jan 06, 2016', 'Jun 21, 2018', 'Nov 05, 2016', 'Mar 18, 2016', 'Jul 30, 2017', 'Dec 19, 2015', 'Dec 28, 2015', 'Apr 21, 2017', 'Oct 08, 2016', 'Aug 07, 2017', 'Nov 18, 2015', 'Dec 17, 2015', 'Oct 05, 2017', 'Aug 17, 2016', 'Feb 22, 2016', 'Aug 12, 2016', 'Aug 08, 2017']</review_date></doc>